<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc2f71b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2"><num value="2991b–2">§ 2991b–2.</num><heading> Establishment of Administration for Native Americans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2f71b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established in the Department of Health and Human Services (referred to in this subchapter as the “Department”) the Administration for Native Americans (referred to in this subchapter as the “Administration”), which shall be headed by a Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans (referred to in this subchapter as the “Commissioner”). The Administration shall be the agency responsible for carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2f71b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Commissioner</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2f71b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2f71b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide for financial assistance, loan funds, technical assistance, training, research and demonstration projects, and other activities, described in this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2f71ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> serve as the effective and visible advocate on behalf of Native Americans within the Department, and with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government regarding all Federal policies affecting Native Americans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2f71bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> with the assistance of the Intra-Departmental Council on Native American Affairs established by subsection (d)(1), coordinate activities within the Department leading to the development of policies, programs, and budgets, and their administration affecting Native Americans, and provide quarterly reports and recommendations to the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2f71bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> collect and disseminate information related to the social and economic conditions of Native Americans, and assist the Secretary in preparing an annual report to the Congress about such conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2f71bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> give preference to agencies described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2991b/a">section 2991b(a) of this title</ref> that are eligible for assistance under this subchapter, in entering into contracts for technical assistance, training, and evaluation under this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2f71be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> encourage agencies that carry out projects under this subchapter, to give preference to Native Americans, in hiring and entering into contracts to carry out such projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2f71bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Intra-Departmental Council on Native American Affairs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc2f71c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is established in the Office of the Secretary the Intra-Departmental Council on Native American Affairs. The Commissioner shall be the chairperson of such Council and shall advise the Secretary on all matters affecting Native Americans that involve the Department. The Director of the Indian Health Service shall serve as vice chairperson of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc2f71c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The membership of the Council shall be the heads of principal operating divisions within the Department, as determined by the Secretary, and such persons in the Office of the Secretary as the Secretary may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc2f71c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In addition to the duties described in subsection (c)(3), the Council shall, within 180 days following <date date="1992-09-30">September 30, 1992</date>, prepare a plan, including legislative recommendations, to allow Tribal governments and other organizations described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2991b/a">section 2991b(a) of this title</ref> to consolidate grants administered by the Department and to designate a single office to oversee and audit the grants. Such plan shall be submitted to the committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives having jurisdiction over the Administration for Native Americans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2f71c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2991b–2/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Staffing levels</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall assure that adequate staff and administrative support is provided to carry out the purpose of this subchapter. In determining the staffing levels of the Administration, the Secretary shall consider among other factors the unmet needs of the Native American population, the need to provide adequate oversight and technical assistance to grantees, the need to carry out the activities of the Council, the additional reporting requirements established, and the staffing levels previously maintained in support of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc2f71c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/452/tVIII/s803B">Pub. L. 88–452, title VIII, § 803B</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/375/tVIII/s822/3">Pub. L. 102–375, title VIII, § 822(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-09-30">Sept. 30, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1296">106 Stat. 1296</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/171/s5/4">Pub. L. 103–171, § 5(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-02">Dec. 2, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1992">107 Stat. 1992</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/261/s5/d/3">Pub. L. 116–261, § 5(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-30">Dec. 30, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3314">134 Stat. 3314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc2f71c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc2f71c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc2f71c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/261">Pub. L. 116–261</ref> substituted “Tribal” for “tribal”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/171/s5/4/A">Pub. L. 103–171, § 5(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “agencies described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2991b/a">section 2991b(a) of this title</ref> that” for “individuals who”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/171/s5/4/B">Pub. L. 103–171, § 5(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “Native Americans,” for “such individuals”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
