<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc369db9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2996k"><num value="2996k">§ 2996k.</num><heading> Coordination</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may direct that appropriate support functions of the Federal Government may be made available to the Corporation in carrying out its activities under this subchapter, to the extent not inconsistent with other applicable law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbc369dba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/452/tX/s1012">Pub. L. 88–452, title X, § 1012</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/355/s2">Pub. L. 93–355, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-07-25">July 25, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/388">88 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc369dbb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbc369dbc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbc369dbd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11874. Delegation of Functions to Director of Office of Management and Budget</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11874 eff. <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, 40 F.R. 31737, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by Section 1012 of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, as amended by the Legal Services Corporation Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/stat/88/388">88 Stat. 388</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2996k">42 U.S.C. 2996k</ref>), and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">Section 301 of Title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and as President of the United States, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget is hereby designated and empowered to exercise the authority vested in the President by said Section 1012 of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, as amended [this section], to direct that appropriate support functions of the Federal Government may be made available to the Legal Services Corporation in carrying out its activities, to the extent not inconsistent with other applicable law. Such functions shall be provided under terms and conditions as may be agreed upon by the Legal Services Corporation and the Federal agencies involved.</p>
<signature>
<name>Gerald R. Ford.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
