<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5fde81c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1"><num value="299a–1">§ 299a–1.</num><heading> Research on health disparities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde81d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde81e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> conduct and support research to identify populations for which there is a significant disparity in the quality, outcomes, cost, or use of health care services or access to and satisfaction with such services, as compared to the general population;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde81f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> conduct and support research on the causes of and barriers to reducing the health disparities identified in paragraph (1), taking into account such factors as socioeconomic status, attitudes toward health, the language spoken, the extent of formal education, the area or community in which the population resides, and other factors the Director determines to be appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde820-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> conduct and support research and support demonstration projects to identify, test, and evaluate strategies for reducing or eliminating health disparities, including development or identification of effective service delivery models, and disseminate effective strategies and models;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde821-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> develop measures and tools for the assessment and improvement of the outcomes, quality, and appropriateness of health care services provided to health disparity populations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde822-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> in carrying out <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s299a/c">section 299a(c) of this title</ref>, provide support to increase the number of researchers who are members of health disparity populations, and the health services research capacity of institutions that train such researchers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde823-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> beginning with fiscal year 2003, annually submit to the Congress a report regarding prevailing disparities in health care delivery as it relates to racial factors and socioeconomic factors in priority populations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde824-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and demonstration projects</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde825-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (a), the Director shall conduct and support research and support demonstrations to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde826-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identify the clinical, cultural, socioeconomic, geographic, and organizational factors that contribute to health disparities, including minority health disparity populations, which research shall include behavioral research, such as examination of patterns of clinical decisionmaking, and research on access, outreach, and the availability of related support services (such as cultural and linguistic services);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde827-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> identify and evaluate clinical and organizational strategies to improve the quality, outcomes, and access to care for health disparity populations, including minority health disparity populations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde828-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> test such strategies and widely disseminate those strategies for which there is scientific evidence of effectiveness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde829-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> determine the most effective approaches for disseminating research findings to health disparity populations, including minority populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde82a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of certain strategies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out this section, the Director shall implement research strategies and mechanisms that will enhance the involvement of individuals who are members of minority health disparity populations or other health disparity populations, health services researchers who are such individuals, institutions that train such individuals as researchers, members of minority health disparity populations or other health disparity populations for whom the Agency is attempting to improve the quality and outcomes of care, and representatives of appropriate tribal or other community-based organizations with respect to health disparity populations. Such research strategies and mechanisms may include the use of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde82b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> centers of excellence that can demonstrate, either individually or through consortia, a combination of multi-disciplinary expertise in outcomes or quality improvement research, linkages to relevant sites of care, and a demonstrated capacity to involve members and communities of health disparity populations, including minority health disparity populations, in the planning, conduct, dissemination, and translation of research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde82c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provider-based research networks, including health plans, facilities, or delivery system sites of care (especially primary care), that make extensive use of health care providers who are members of health disparity populations or who serve patients in such populations and have the capacity to evaluate and promote quality improvement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde82d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> service delivery models (such as health centers under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254b">section 254b of this title</ref> and the Indian Health Service) to reduce health disparities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5fde82e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> innovative mechanisms or strategies that will facilitate the translation of past research investments into clinical practices that can reasonably be expected to benefit these populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde82f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Quality measurement development</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde830-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To ensure that health disparity populations, including minority health disparity populations, benefit from the progress made in the ability of individuals to measure the quality of health care delivery, the Director shall support the development of quality of health care measures that assess the experience of such populations with health care systems, such as measures that assess the access of such populations to health care, the cultural competence of the care provided, the quality of the care provided, the outcomes of care, or other aspects of health care practice that the Director determines to be important.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde831-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Examination of certain practices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall examine the practices of providers that have a record of reducing health disparities or have experience in providing culturally competent health services to minority health disparity populations or other health disparity populations. In examining such practices of providers funded under the authorities of this chapter, the Director shall consult with the heads of the relevant agencies of the Public Health Service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde832-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 36 months after <date date="2000-11-22">November 22, 2000</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the state-of-the-art of quality measurement for minority and other health disparity populations that will identify critical unmet needs, the current activities of the Department to address those needs, and a description of related activities in the private sector.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5fde833-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde834-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “health disparity population” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s285t">section 285t of this title</ref>, except that in addition to the meaning so given, the Director may determine that such term includes populations for which there is a significant disparity in the quality, outcomes, cost, or use of health care services or access to or satisfaction with such services as compared to the general population.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5fde835-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s299a–1/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “minority”, with respect to populations, refers to racial and ethnic minority groups as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6">section 300u–6 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5fde836-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IX, § 903, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/525/tII/s201/a/2">Pub. L. 106–525, title II, § 201(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-22">Nov. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2505">114 Stat. 2505</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10334/c/3/B">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10334(c)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/974">124 Stat. 974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5fde837-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5fde838-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb5fde839-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 299a–1, <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tIX/s903">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IX, § 903</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVI/s6103/a">Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2190">103 Stat. 2190</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/410/s3">Pub. L. 102–410, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-10-13">Oct. 13, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2094">106 Stat. 2094</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tXIV/s1422/a">Pub. L. 103–43, title XIV, § 1422(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/172">107 Stat. 172</ref>, related to public dissemination of information about studies and projects prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/106/129">Pub. L. 106–129</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s299c–3">section 299c–3 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 903 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s299c">section 299c of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/99/117">Pub. L. 99–117</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior sections 299a–2 and 299a–3 were omitted in the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/106/129">Pub. L. 106–129</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 299a–2, <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tIX/s904">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IX, § 904</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVI/s6103/a">Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2191">103 Stat. 2191</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/410/s4/a">Pub. L. 102–410, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-13">Oct. 13, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2095">106 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tXX/s2013/1">Pub. L. 103–43, title XX, § 2013(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/214">107 Stat. 214</ref>, related to health care technology assessment. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s299b–5">section 299b–5 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 299a–3, <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tIX/s905">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IX, § 905</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/115/tIV/s409">Pub. L. 105–115, title IV, § 409</ref>, <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2371">111 Stat. 2371</ref>, established demonstration program regarding centers for education and research on therapeutics. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s299b–1/b">section 299b–1(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5fde83a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref> substituted “285t” for “287c–31”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
