<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb679f600-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19"><num value="300aa–19">§ 300aa–19.</num><heading> Advisory Commission on Childhood Vaccines</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb679f601-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established the Advisory Commission on Childhood Vaccines. The Commission shall be composed of:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb679f602-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Nine members appointed by the Secretary as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb679f603-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Three members who are health professionals, who are not employees of the United States, and who have expertise in the health care of children, the epidemiology, etiology, and prevention of childhood diseases, and the adverse reactions associated with vaccines, of whom at least two shall be pediatricians.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb679f604-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Three members from the general public, of whom at least two shall be legal representatives of children who have suffered a vaccine-related injury or death.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb679f605-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Three members who are attorneys, of whom at least one shall be an attorney whose specialty includes representation of persons who have suffered a vaccine-related injury or death and of whom one shall be an attorney whose specialty includes representation of vaccine manufacturers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb679f606-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the National Institutes of Health, the Assistant Secretary for Health, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (or the designees of such officials), each of whom shall be a nonvoting ex officio member.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall select members of the Commission within 90 days of <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>. The members of the Commission shall select a Chair from among the members.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb679f607-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Term of office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appointed members of the Commission shall be appointed for a term of office of 3 years, except that of the members first appointed, 3 shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, 3 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, and 3 shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb679f608-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall first meet within 60 days after all members of the Commission are appointed, and thereafter shall meet not less often than four times per year and at the call of the chair. A quorum for purposes of a meeting is 5. A decision at a meeting is to be made by a ballot of a majority of the voting members of the Commission present at the meeting.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb679f609-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Members of the Commission who are officers or employees of the Federal Government shall serve as members of the Commission without compensation in addition to that received in their regular public employment. Members of the Commission who are not officers or employees of the Federal Government shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate in effect for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule for each day (including traveltime) they are engaged in the performance of their duties as members of the Commission. All members, while so serving away from their homes or regular places of business, may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as such expenses are authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref> for employees serving intermittently.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb679f60a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide the Commission with such professional and clerical staff, such information, and the services of such consultants as may be necessary to assist the Commission in carrying out effectively its functions under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb679f60b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb679f60c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> advise the Secretary on the implementation of the Program,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb679f60d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> on its own initiative or as the result of the filing of a petition, recommend changes in the Vaccine Injury Table,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb679f60e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> advise the Secretary in implementing the Secretary’s responsibilities under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–27">section 300aa–27 of this title</ref> regarding the need for childhood vaccination products that result in fewer or no significant adverse reactions,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb679f60f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> survey Federal, State, and local programs and activities relating to the gathering of information on injuries associated with the administration of childhood vaccines, including the adverse reaction reporting requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–25/b">section 300aa–25(b) of this title</ref>, and advise the Secretary on means to obtain, compile, publish, and use credible data related to the frequency and severity of adverse reactions associated with childhood vaccines, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb679f610-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–19/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> recommend to the Director of the National Vaccine Program research related to vaccine injuries which should be conducted to carry out this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb679f611-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XXI, § 2119, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/660/tIII/s311/a">Pub. L. 99–660, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3771">100 Stat. 3771</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4302/b/1">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4302(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-221">101 Stat. 1330–221</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/168/tII/s201/g">Pub. L. 102–168, title II, § 201(g)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-26">Nov. 26, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1104">105 Stat. 1104</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/531/tIII/s312/d/14">Pub. L. 102–531, title III, § 312(d)(14)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3505">106 Stat. 3505</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb679f612-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb679f613-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb679f614-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a), “<date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>” substituted for “the effective date of this subpart” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/99/660/s323">section 323 of Pub. L. 99–660</ref>, as amended, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300aa–1">section 300aa–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb679f615-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/531">Pub. L. 102–531</ref> substituted “Centers for Disease Control and Prevention” for “Centers for Disease Control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/168">Pub. L. 102–168</ref> inserted “present at the meeting” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> substituted “effective date of this subpart” for “effective date of this part” in last sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb679f616-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb679f617-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Commissions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory commissions established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a commission established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such commission is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a commission established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/641/s6">Pub. L. 93–641, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2275">88 Stat. 2275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s217a">section 217a of this title</ref>, provided that an advisory committee established pursuant to the Public Health Service Act shall terminate at such time as may be specifically prescribed by an Act of Congress enacted after <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb679f618-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
