<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb6b59e9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42"><num value="300gg–42">§ 300gg–42.</num><heading> Guaranteed renewability of individual health insurance coverage</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59e9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in this section, a health insurance issuer that provides individual health insurance coverage to an individual shall renew or continue in force such coverage at the option of the individual.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> General exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A health insurance issuer may nonrenew or discontinue health insurance coverage of an individual in the individual market based only on one or more of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonpayment of premiums</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The individual has failed to pay premiums or contributions in accordance with the terms of the health insurance coverage or the issuer has not received timely premium payments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Fraud</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The individual has performed an act or practice that constitutes fraud or made an intentional misrepresentation of material fact under the terms of the coverage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The issuer is ceasing to offer coverage in the individual market in accordance with subsection (c) and applicable State law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Movement outside service area</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a health insurance issuer that offers health insurance coverage in the market through a network plan, the individual no longer resides, lives, or works in the service area (or in an area for which the issuer is authorized to do business) but only if such coverage is terminated under this paragraph uniformly without regard to any health status-related factor of covered individuals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Association membership ceases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of health insurance coverage that is made available in the individual market only through one or more bona fide associations, the membership of the individual in the association (on the basis of which the coverage is provided) ceases but only if such coverage is terminated under this paragraph uniformly without regard to any health status-related factor of covered individuals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for uniform termination of coverage</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59ea7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Particular type of coverage not offered</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any case in which an issuer decides to discontinue offering a particular type of health insurance coverage offered in the individual market, coverage of such type may be discontinued by the issuer only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6b59ea8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the issuer provides notice to each covered individual provided coverage of this type in such market of such discontinuation at least 90 days prior to the date of the discontinuation of such coverage;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6b59ea9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the issuer offers to each individual in the individual market provided coverage of this type, the option to purchase any other individual health insurance coverage currently being offered by the issuer for individuals in such market; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6b59eaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in exercising the option to discontinue coverage of this type and in offering the option of coverage under subparagraph (B), the issuer acts uniformly without regard to any health status-related factor of enrolled individuals or individuals who may become eligible for such coverage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59eab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Discontinuance of all coverage</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59eac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), in any case in which a health insurance issuer elects to discontinue offering all health insurance coverage in the individual market in a State, health insurance coverage may be discontinued by the issuer only if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6b59ead-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the issuer provides notice to the applicable State authority and to each individual of such discontinuation at least 180 days prior to the date of the expiration of such coverage, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6b59eae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> all health insurance issued or delivered for issuance in the State in such market are discontinued and coverage under such health insurance coverage in such market is not renewed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59eaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on market reentry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a discontinuation under subparagraph (A) in the individual market, the issuer may not provide for the issuance of any health insurance coverage in the market and State involved during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the discontinuation of the last health insurance coverage not so renewed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59eb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for uniform modification of coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the time of coverage renewal, a health insurance issuer may modify the health insurance coverage for a policy form offered to individuals in the individual market so long as such modification is consistent with State law and effective on a uniform basis among all individuals with that policy form.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6b59eb1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–42/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Application to coverage offered only through associations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In applying this section in the case of health insurance coverage that is made available by a health insurance issuer in the individual market to individuals only through one or more associations, a reference to an “individual” is deemed to include a reference to such an association (of which the individual is a member).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb6b59eb2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XXVII, § 2742, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tI/s111/a">Pub. L. 104–191, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1982">110 Stat. 1982</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb6b59eb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb6b59eb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb6b59eb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable with respect to health insurance coverage offered, sold, issued, renewed, in effect, or operated in the individual market after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, regardless of when a period of creditable coverage occurs, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s111/b">section 111(b) of Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–41">section 300gg–41 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
