<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb6371fa6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4"><num value="300h–4">§ 300h–4.</num><heading> Optional demonstration by States relating to oil or natural gas</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6371fa7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval of State underground injection control program; alternative showing of effectiveness of program by State</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of the Administrator’s approval or disapproval under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–1">section 300h–1 of this title</ref> of that portion of any State underground injection control program which relates to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6371fa8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the underground injection of brine or other fluids which are brought to the surface in connection with oil or natural gas production or natural gas storage operations, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6371fa9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any underground injection for the secondary or tertiary recovery of oil or natural gas,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">in lieu of the showing required under subparagraph (A) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–1/b/1">section 300h–1(b)(1) of this title</ref> the State may demonstrate that such portion of the State program meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h/b/1">section 300h(b)(1) of this title</ref> and represents an effective program (including adequate recordkeeping and reporting) to prevent underground injection which endangers drinking water sources.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6371faa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Revision or amendment of requirements of regulation; showing of effectiveness of program by State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Administrator revises or amends any requirement of a regulation under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h">section 300h of this title</ref> relating to any aspect of the underground injection referred to in subsection (a), in the case of that portion of a State underground injection control program for which the demonstration referred to in subsection (a) has been made, in lieu of the showing required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–1/b/1/B">section 300h–1(b)(1)(B) of this title</ref> the State may demonstrate that, with respect to that aspect of such underground injection, the State program meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h/b/1">section 300h(b)(1) of this title</ref> and represents an effective program (including adequate recordkeeping and reporting) to prevent underground injection which endangers drinking water sources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6371fab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Primary enforcement responsibility of State; voiding by Administrator under duly promulgated rule</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb6371fac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–1/b/3">Section 300h–1(b)(3) of this title</ref> shall not apply to that portion of any State underground injection control program approved by the Administrator pursuant to a demonstration under subsection (a) of this section (and under subsection (b) of this section where applicable).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb6371fad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If pursuant to such a demonstration, the Administrator approves such portion of the State program, the State shall have primary enforcement responsibility with respect to that portion until such time as the Administrator determines, by rule, that such demonstration is no longer valid. Following such a determination, the Administrator may exercise the authority of subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–1">section 300h–1 of this title</ref> in the same manner as provided in such subsection with respect to a determination described in such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb6371fae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Before promulgating any rule under paragraph (2), the Administrator shall provide opportunity for public hearing respecting such rule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb6371faf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIV, § 1425, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/502/s2/a">Pub. L. 96–502, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2737">94 Stat. 2737</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 99–339, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/653">100 Stat. 653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb6371fb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb6371fb1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb6371fb2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/339">Pub. L. 99–339</ref> inserted “or natural gas storage operations, or” after “production”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
