<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb6371fb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300h–5"><num value="300h–5">§ 300h–5.</num><heading> Regulation of State programs</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, the Administrator shall modify regulations issued under this chapter for Class I injection wells to identify monitoring methods, in addition to those in effect on <date date="1985-11-01">November 1, 1985</date>, including groundwater monitoring. In accordance with such regulations, the Administrator, or delegated State authority, shall determine the applicability of such monitoring methods, wherever appropriate, at locations and in such a manner as to provide the earliest possible detection of fluid migration into, or in the direction of, underground sources of drinking water from such wells, based on its assessment of the potential for fluid migration from the injection zone that may be harmful to human health or the environment. For purposes of this subsection, a class I injection well is defined in accordance with 40 CFR 146.05 as in effect on <date date="1985-11-01">November 1, 1985</date>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb6371fb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIV, § 1426, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 99–339, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/653">100 Stat. 653</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tII/s2021/f">Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2021(f)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/727">109 Stat. 727</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/182/tV/s501/f/2">Pub. L. 104–182, title V, § 501(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-06">Aug. 6, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1691">110 Stat. 1691</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb6371fb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb6371fb6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb6371fb7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/182">Pub. L. 104–182</ref> directed technical amendment of section catchline and subsec. (a) designation. The provision directing amendment of subsec. (a) designation could not be executed because section does not contain a subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out subsec. (a) designation and heading before “Not later than” and struck out heading and text of subsec. (b). Text read as follows: “The Administrator shall submit a report to Congress, no later than September 1987, summarizing the results of State surveys required by the Administrator under this section. The report shall include each of the following items of information:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) The numbers and categories of class V wells which discharge nonhazardous waste into or above an underground source of drinking water.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) The primary contamination problems associated with different categories of these disposal wells.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) Recommendations for minimum design, construction, installation, and siting requirements that should be applied to protect underground sources of drinking water from such contamination wherever necessary.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
