<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb63c0185-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4"><num value="300i–4">§ 300i–4.</num><heading> Supply disruption prevention, detection and response</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63c0186-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Disruption of supply or safety</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator, in coordination with the appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government, shall review (or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements to provide for a review of) methods and means by which terrorists or other individuals or groups could disrupt the supply of safe drinking water or take other actions against water collection, pretreatment, treatment, storage and distribution facilities which could render such water significantly less safe for human consumption, including each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63c0187-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Methods and means by which pipes and other constructed conveyances utilized in public water systems could be destroyed or otherwise prevented from providing adequate supplies of drinking water meeting applicable public health standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63c0188-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Methods and means by which collection, pretreatment, treatment, storage and distribution facilities utilized or used in connection with public water systems and collection and pretreatment storage facilities used in connection with public water systems could be destroyed or otherwise prevented from providing adequate supplies of drinking water meeting applicable public health standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63c0189-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Methods and means by which pipes, constructed conveyances, collection, pretreatment, treatment, storage and distribution systems that are utilized in connection with public water systems could be altered or affected so as to be subject to cross-contamination of drinking water supplies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63c018a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Methods and means by which pipes, constructed conveyances, collection, pretreatment, treatment, storage and distribution systems that are utilized in connection with public water systems could be reasonably protected from terrorist attacks or other acts intended to disrupt the supply or affect the safety of drinking water.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63c018b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Methods and means by which information systems, including process controls and supervisory control and data acquisition and cyber systems at community water systems could be disrupted by terrorists or other groups.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63c018c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative sources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The review under this section shall also include a review of the methods and means by which alternative supplies of drinking water could be provided in the event of the destruction, impairment or contamination of public water systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63c018d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements and considerations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300i–3">section 300i–3 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63c018e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Administrator shall ensure that reviews carried out under this section reflect the needs of community water systems of various sizes and various geographic areas of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63c018f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Administrator may consider the vulnerability of, or potential for forced interruption of service for, a region or service area, including community water systems that provide service to the National Capital area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63c0190-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as practicable after reviews carried out under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300i–3">section 300i–3 of this title</ref> have been evaluated, the Administrator shall disseminate, as appropriate as determined by the Administrator, to community water systems information on the results of the project through the Information Sharing and Analysis Center, or other appropriate means.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63c0191-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300i–4/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300i–3">section 300i–3 of this title</ref> not more than $15,000,000 for the fiscal year 2002 and such sums as may be necessary for the fiscal years 2003 through 2005.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb63c0192-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIV, § 1435, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/188/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 107–188, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/686">116 Stat. 686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
