<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb6d49840-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11"><num value="300jj–11">§ 300jj–11.</num><heading> Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49841-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established within the Department of Health and Human Services an Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (referred to in this section as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a National Coordinator who shall be appointed by the Secretary and shall report directly to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49842-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The National Coordinator shall perform the duties under subsection (c) in a manner consistent with the development of a nationwide health information technology infrastructure that allows for the electronic use and exchange of information and that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d49843-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> ensures that each patient’s health information is secure and protected, in accordance with applicable law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d49844-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> improves health care quality, reduces medical errors, reduces health disparities, and advances the delivery of patient-centered medical care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d49845-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> reduces health care costs resulting from inefficiency, medical errors, inappropriate care, duplicative care, and incomplete information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d49846-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provides appropriate information to help guide medical decisions at the time and place of care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d49847-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> ensures the inclusion of meaningful public input in such development of such infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d49848-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> improves the coordination of care and information among hospitals, laboratories, physician offices, and other entities through an effective infrastructure for the secure and authorized exchange of health care information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d49849-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> improves public health activities and facilitates the early identification and rapid response to public health threats and emergencies, including bioterror events and infectious disease outbreaks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d4984a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> facilitates health and clinical research and health care quality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d4984b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> promotes early detection, prevention, and management of chronic diseases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d4984c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> promotes a more effective marketplace, greater competition, greater systems analysis, increased consumer choice, and improved outcomes in health care services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6d4984d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> improves efforts to reduce health disparities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4984e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of the National Coordinator</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4984f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Standards</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The National Coordinator shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6d49850-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> review and determine whether to endorse each standard, implementation specification, and certification criterion for the electronic exchange and use of health information that is recommended by the HIT Advisory Committee under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–12">section 300jj–12 of this title</ref> for purposes of adoption under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14">section 300jj–14 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6d49851-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> make such determinations under subparagraph (A), and report to the Secretary such determinations, not later than 45 days after the date the recommendation is received by the Coordinator; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6d49852-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> review Federal health information technology investments to ensure that Federal health information technology programs are meeting the objectives of the strategic plan published under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49853-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> HIT policy coordination</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49854-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall coordinate health information technology policy and programs of the Department with those of other relevant executive branch agencies with a goal of avoiding duplication of efforts and of helping to ensure that each agency undertakes health information technology activities primarily within the areas of its greatest expertise and technical capability and in a manner towards a coordinated national goal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49855-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> HIT Advisory Committee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall be a leading member in the establishment and operations of the HIT Advisory Committee and shall serve as a liaison between that Committee and the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49856-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49857-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall, in consultation with other appropriate Federal agencies (including the National Institute of Standards and Technology), update the Federal Health IT Strategic Plan (developed as of <date date="2008-06-03">June 3, 2008</date>) to include specific objectives, milestones, and metrics with respect to the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49858-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The electronic exchange and use of health information and the enterprise integration of such information.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49859-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The utilization of an electronic health record for each person in the United States by 2014.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4985a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The incorporation of privacy and security protections for the electronic exchange of an individual’s individually identifiable health information.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4985b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Ensuring security methods to ensure appropriate authorization and electronic authentication of health information and specifying technologies or methodologies for rendering health information unusable, unreadable, or indecipherable.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4985c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Specifying a framework for coordination and flow of recommendations and policies under this part among the Secretary, the National Coordinator, the HIT Advisory Committee, and other health information exchanges and other relevant entities.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4985d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> Methods to foster the public understanding of health information technology.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4985e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> Strategies to enhance the use of health information technology in improving the quality of health care, reducing medical errors, reducing health disparities, improving public health, increasing prevention and coordination with community resources, and improving the continuity of care among health care settings.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4985f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/A/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> Specific plans for ensuring that populations with unique needs, such as children, are appropriately addressed in the technology design, as appropriate, which may include technology that automates enrollment and retention for eligible individuals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49860-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Collaboration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The strategic plan shall be updated through collaboration of public and private entities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49861-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Measurable outcome goals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The strategic plan update shall include measurable outcome goals.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49862-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall republish the strategic plan, including all updates.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49863-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Website</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The National Coordinator shall maintain and frequently update an Internet website on which there is posted information on the work, schedules, reports, recommendations, and other information to ensure transparency in promotion of a nationwide health information technology infrastructure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49864-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49865-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall keep or recognize a program or programs for the voluntary certification of health information technology as being in compliance with applicable certification criteria adopted under this part. Such program shall include, as appropriate, testing of the technology in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17911/b">section 17911(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49866-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification criteria described</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this subchapter, the term “certification criteria” means, with respect to standards and implementation specifications for health information technology, criteria to establish that the technology meets such standards and implementation specifications.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49867-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Health information technology for medical specialties and sites of service</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49868-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The National Coordinator shall encourage, keep, or recognize, through existing authorities, the voluntary certification of health information technology under the program developed under subparagraph (A) for use in medical specialties and sites of service for which no such technology is available or where more technological advancement or integration is needed.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49869-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific medical specialties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall accept public comment on specific medical specialties and sites of service, in addition to those described in clause (i), for the purpose of selecting additional specialties and sites of service as necessary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4986a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Health information technology for pediatrics</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than 18 months after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with relevant stakeholders, shall make recommendations for the voluntary certification of health information technology for use by pediatric health providers to support the health care of children. Not later than 2 years after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>, the Secretary shall adopt certification criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14">section 300jj–14 of this title</ref> to support the voluntary certification of health information technology for use by pediatric health providers to support the health care of children.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4986b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions of certification</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>, the Secretary, through notice and comment rulemaking, shall require, as a condition of certification and maintenance of certification for programs maintained or recognized under this paragraph, consistent with other conditions and requirements under this subchapter, that the health information technology developer or entity—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4986c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> does not take any action that constitutes information blocking as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–52/a">section 300jj–52(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4986d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provides assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that such developer or entity, unless for legitimate purposes specified by the Secretary, will not take any action described in clause (i) or any other action that may inhibit the appropriate exchange, access, and use of electronic health information;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4986e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> does not prohibit or restrict communication regarding—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d4986f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the usability of the health information technology;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49870-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the interoperability of the health information technology;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49871-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the security of the health information technology;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49872-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> relevant information regarding users’ experiences when using the health information technology;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49873-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> the business practices of developers of health information technology related to exchanging electronic health information; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49874-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> the manner in which a user of the health information technology has used such technology;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49875-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> has published application programming interfaces and allows health information from such technology to be accessed, exchanged, and used without special effort through the use of application programming interfaces or successor technology or standards, as provided for under applicable law, including providing access to all data elements of a patient’s electronic health record to the extent permissible under applicable privacy laws;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49876-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> has successfully tested the real world use of the technology for interoperability (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj">section 300jj of this title</ref>) in the type of setting in which such technology would be marketed;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49877-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><chapeau> provides to the Secretary an attestation that the developer or entity—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49878-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vi/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> has not engaged in any of the conduct described in clause (i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49879-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vi/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> has provided assurances satisfactory to the Secretary in accordance with clause (ii);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d4987a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vi/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> does not prohibit or restrict communication as described in clause (iii);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d4987b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vi/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> has published information in accordance with clause (iv);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d4987c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vi/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> ensures that its technology allows for health information to be exchanged, accessed, and used, in the manner described in clause (iv); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d4987d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vi/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> has undertaken real world testing as described in clause (v); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d4987e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/D/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> submits reporting criteria in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–19a/b">section 300jj–19a(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4987f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/5/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance with conditions of certification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may encourage compliance with the conditions of certification described in subparagraph (D) and take action to discourage noncompliance, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49880-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports and publications</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49881-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on additional funding or authority needed</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2009-02-17">February 17, 2009</date>, the National Coordinator shall submit to the appropriate committees of jurisdiction of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on any additional funding or authority the Coordinator or the HIT Policy Committee or HIT Standards Committee requires to evaluate and develop standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria, or to achieve full participation of stakeholders in the adoption of a nationwide health information technology infrastructure that allows for the electronic use and exchange of health information.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49882-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall prepare a report that identifies lessons learned from major public and private health care systems in their implementation of health information technology, including information on whether the technologies and practices developed by such systems may be applicable to and usable in whole or in part by other health care providers.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49883-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessment of impact of HIT on communities with health disparities and uninsured, underinsured, and medically underserved areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall assess and publish the impact of health information technology in communities with health disparities and in areas with a high proportion of individuals who are uninsured, underinsured, and medically underserved individuals (including urban and rural areas) and identify practices to increase the adoption of such technology by health care providers in such communities, and the use of health information technology to reduce and better manage chronic diseases.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49884-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation of benefits and costs of the electronic use and exchange of health information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall evaluate and publish evidence on the benefits and costs of the electronic use and exchange of health information and assess to whom these benefits and costs accrue.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49885-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Resource requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall estimate and publish resources required annually to reach the goal of utilization of an electronic health record for each person in the United States by 2014, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49886-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the required level of Federal funding;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49887-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> expectations for regional, State, and private investment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49888-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the expected contributions by volunteers to activities for the utilization of such records; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb6d49889-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/6/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the resources needed to establish a health information technology workforce sufficient to support this effort (including education programs in medical informatics and health information management).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4988a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The National Coordinator may provide financial assistance to consumer advocacy groups and not-for-profit entities that work in the public interest for purposes of defraying the cost to such groups and entities to participate under, whether in whole or in part, the National Technology Transfer Act of 1995 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s272">15 U.S.C. 272</ref> note).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002515">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002515"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4988b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Governance for nationwide health information network</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The National Coordinator shall establish a governance mechanism for the nationwide health information network.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4988c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Support for interoperable networks exchange</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4988d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The National Coordinator shall, in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology and other relevant agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services, for the purpose of ensuring full network-to-network exchange of health information, convene public-private and public-public partnerships to build consensus and develop or support a trusted exchange framework, including a common agreement among health information networks nationally. Such convention may occur at a frequency determined appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4988e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishing a trusted exchange framework</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4988f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than 6 months after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>, the National Coordinator shall convene appropriate public and private stakeholders to develop or support a trusted exchange framework for trust policies and practices and for a common agreement for exchange between health information networks. The common agreement may include—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49890-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a common method for authenticating trusted health information network participants;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49891-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a common set of rules for trusted exchange;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49892-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> organizational and operational policies to enable the exchange of health information among networks, including minimum conditions for such exchange to occur; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb6d49893-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> a process for filing and adjudicating noncompliance with the terms of the common agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49894-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The National Coordinator, in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall provide technical assistance on how to implement the trusted exchange framework and common agreement under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49895-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Pilot testing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The National Coordinator, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall provide for the pilot testing of the trusted exchange framework and common agreement established or supported under this subsection (as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17911">section 17911 of this title</ref>). The National Coordinator, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, may delegate pilot testing activities under this clause to independent entities with appropriate expertise.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49896-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of a trusted exchange framework and common agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after convening stakeholders under subparagraph (A), the National Coordinator shall publish on its public Internet website, and in the Federal register,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002516">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002516"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “Register,”.</note> the trusted exchange framework and common agreement developed or supported under subparagraph (B). Such trusted exchange framework and common agreement shall be published in a manner that protects proprietary and security information, including trade secrets and any other protected intellectual property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49897-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Directory of participating health information networks</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49898-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than 2 years after convening stakeholders under subparagraph (A), and annually thereafter, the National Coordinator shall publish on its public Internet website a list of the health information networks that have adopted the common agreement and are capable of trusted exchange pursuant to the common agreement developed or supported under paragraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002517">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002517"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “subparagraph”.</note> (B).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d49899-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall, through notice and comment rulemaking, establish a process for health information networks that voluntarily elect to adopt the trusted exchange framework and common agreement to attest to such adoption of the framework and agreement.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4989a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of the trusted exchange framework and common agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">As appropriate, Federal agencies contracting or entering into agreements with health information exchange networks may require that as each such network upgrades health information technology or trust and operational practices, such network may adopt, where available, the trusted exchange framework and common agreement published under subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4989b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4989c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/F/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> General adoption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require a health information network to adopt the trusted exchange framework or common agreement.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4989d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/F/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Adoption when exchange of information is within network</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require a health information network to adopt the trusted exchange framework or common agreement for the exchange of electronic health information between participants of the same network.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4989e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/F/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing frameworks and agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The trusted exchange framework and common agreement published under subparagraph (C) shall take into account existing trusted exchange frameworks and agreements used by health information networks to avoid the disruption of existing exchanges between participants of health information networks.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d4989f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/F/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Application by Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding clauses (i), (ii), and (iii), Federal agencies may require the adoption of the trusted exchange framework and common agreement published under subparagraph (C) for health information exchanges contracting with or entering into agreements pursuant to subparagraph (E).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d498a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c/9/F/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of ongoing work</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall ensure the consideration of activities carried out by public and private organizations related to exchange between health information exchanges to avoid duplication of efforts.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d498a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Detail of Federal employees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d498a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon the request of the National Coordinator, the head of any Federal agency is authorized to detail, with or without reimbursement from the Office, any of the personnel of such agency to the Office to assist it in carrying out its duties under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d498a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of detail</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any detail of personnel under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6d498a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not interrupt or otherwise affect the civil service status or privileges of the Federal employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6d498a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be in addition to any other staff of the Department employed by the National Coordinator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d498a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Acceptance of detailees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Office may accept detailed personnel from other Federal agencies without regard to whether the agency described under paragraph (1) is reimbursed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d498a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Chief Privacy Officer of the Office of the National Coordinator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2009-02-17">February 17, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall appoint a Chief Privacy Officer of the Office of the National Coordinator, whose duty it shall be to advise the National Coordinator on privacy, security, and data stewardship of electronic health information and to coordinate with other Federal agencies (and similar privacy officers in such agencies), with State and regional efforts, and with foreign countries with regard to the privacy, security, and data stewardship of electronic individually identifiable health information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb6d498a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XXX, § 3001, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/5/dA/tXIII/s13101">Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIII, § 13101</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/230">123 Stat. 230</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 4001(b), 4002(a), 4003(b), (e)(2)(A)(i), (ii), (C), <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1158">130 Stat. 1158</ref>, 1159, 1165, 1174.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb6d498a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb6d498aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb6d498ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Technology Transfer Act of 1995 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s272">15 U.S.C. 272</ref> note), referred to in subsec. (c)(7), probably means <ref href="/us/pl/104/113/s12/d">section 12(d) of Pub. L. 104–113</ref>, known as the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s272">section 272 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb6d498ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/e/2/C/i">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(e)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–12">section 300jj–12 of this title</ref>” for “under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–13">section 300jj–13 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/e/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(e)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “HIT Advisory Committee” for “HIT Standards Committee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/e/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(e)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The National Coordinator shall be a leading member in the establishment and operations of the HIT Policy Committee and the HIT Standards Committee and shall serve as a liaison among those two Committees and the Federal Government.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/e/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(e)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, which directed amendment of this section by substituting “HIT Advisory Committee” for “HIT Policy Committee and the HIT Standards Committee” wherever appearing, was executed to cl. (v) by making the substitution for “HIT Policy Committee, the HIT Standards Committee”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4001/b">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4001(b)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(D), (E). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4002/a">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4002(a)</ref>, added subpars. (D) and (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/e/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(e)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, which directed amendment of this section by substituting “HIT Advisory Committee” for both “HIT Policy Committee” and “HIT Standards Committee” wherever appearing, but not within the term “HIT Policy Committee or the HIT Standards Committee”, was not executed to subpar. (A) as provided in the exception, notwithstanding text that reads “HIT Policy Committee or HIT Standards Committee”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/b">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(b)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb6d498ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb6d498ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Provider Digital Contact Information Index</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIV/s4003/c">Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title IV, § 4003(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1167">130 Stat. 1167</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIV/s4003/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this subsection as the ‘Secretary’) shall, directly or through a partnership with a private entity, establish a provider digital contact information index to provide digital contact information for health professionals and health facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of existing index</inline>.—</heading><content>In establishing the initial index under paragraph (1), the Secretary may utilize an existing provider directory to make such digital contact information available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contact information</inline>.—</heading><content>An index established under this subsection shall ensure that contact information is available at the individual health care provider level and at the health facility or practice level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The purpose of this subsection is to encourage the exchange of electronic health information by providing the most useful, reliable, and comprehensive index of providers possible. In furthering such purpose, the Secretary shall include all health professionals and health facilities applicable to provide a useful, reliable, and comprehensive index for use in the exchange of health information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>In no case shall exclusion from the index of providers be used as a measure to achieve objectives other [than] the objectives described in subparagraph (A).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
