<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb63e4bfb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2"><num value="300j–2">§ 300j–2.</num><heading> Grants for State programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4bfc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Public water systems supervision programs; applications for grants; allotment of sums; waiver of grant restrictions; notice of approval or disapproval of application; authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4bfd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> From allotments made pursuant to paragraph (4), the Administrator may make grants to States to carry out public water system supervision programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4bfe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> No grant may be made under paragraph (1) unless an application therefor has been submitted to the Administrator in such form and manner as he may require. The Administrator may not approve an application of a State for its first grant under paragraph (1) unless he determines that the State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4bff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has established or will establish within one year from the date of such grant a public water system supervision program, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> will, within that one year, assume primary enforcement responsibility for public water systems within the State.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">No grant may be made to a State under paragraph (1) for any period beginning more than one year after the date of the State’s first grant unless the State has assumed and maintains primary enforcement responsibility for public water systems within the State. The prohibitions contained in the preceding two sentences shall not apply to such grants when made to Indian Tribes.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A grant under paragraph (1) shall be made to cover not more than 75 per centum of the grant recipient’s costs (as determined under regulations of the Administrator) in carrying out, during the one-year period beginning on the date the grant is made, a public water system supervision program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In each fiscal year the Administrator shall, in accordance, with regulations, allot the sums appropriated for such year under paragraph (5) among the States on the basis of population, geographical area, number of public water systems, and other relevant factors. No State shall receive less than 1 per centum of the annual appropriation for grants under paragraph (1): <i>Provided</i>, That the Administrator may, by regulation, reduce such percentage in accordance with the criteria specified in this paragraph: <i>And provided further</i>, That such percentage shall not apply to grants allotted to Guam, American Samoa, or the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The prohibition contained in the last sentence of paragraph (2) may be waived by the Administrator with respect to a grant to a State through fiscal year 1979 but such prohibition may only be waived if, in the judgment of the Administrator—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the State is making a diligent effort to assume and maintain primary enforcement responsibility for public water systems within the State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the State has made significant progress toward assuming and maintaining such primary enforcement responsibility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> there is reason to believe the State will assume such primary enforcement responsibility by <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The amount of any grant awarded for the fiscal years 1978 and 1979 pursuant to a waiver under this paragraph may not exceed 75 per centum of the allotment which the State would have received for such fiscal year if it had assumed and maintained such primary enforcement responsibility. The remaining 25 per centum of the amount allotted to such State for such fiscal year shall be retained by the Administrator, and the Administrator may award such amount to such State at such time as the State assumes such responsibility before the beginning of fiscal year 1980. At the beginning of each fiscal years 1979 and 1980 the amounts retained by the Administrator for any preceding fiscal year and not awarded by the beginning of fiscal year 1979 or 1980 to the States to which such amounts were originally allotted may be removed from the original allotment and reallotted for fiscal year 1979 or 1980 (as the case may be) to States which have assumed primary enforcement responsibility by the beginning of such fiscal year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The Administrator shall notify the State of the approval or disapproval of any application for a grant under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> within ninety days after receipt of such application, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not later than the first day of the fiscal year for which the grant application is made,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever is later.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purpose of making grants under paragraph (1), there are authorized to be appropriated $125,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2020 and 2021.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reservation of funds by the administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator assumes the primary enforcement responsibility of a State public water system supervision program, the Administrator may reserve from funds made available pursuant to this subsection an amount equal to the amount that would otherwise have been provided to the State pursuant to this subsection. The Administrator shall use the funds reserved pursuant to this paragraph to ensure the full and effective administration of a public water system supervision program in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State loan funds.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reservation of funds</inline>.—</heading><content>For any fiscal year for which the amount made available to the Administrator by appropriations to carry out this subsection is less than the amount that the Administrator determines is necessary to supplement funds made available pursuant to paragraph (8) to ensure the full and effective administration of a public water system supervision program in a State, the Administrator may reserve from the funds made available to the State under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300j–12">section 300j–12 of this title</ref> (relating to State loan funds) an amount that is equal to the amount of the shortfall. This paragraph shall not apply to any State not exercising primary enforcement responsibility for public water systems as of <date date="1996-08-06">August 6, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/a/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duty of administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Administrator reserves funds from the allocation of a State under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall carry out in the State each of the activities that would be required of the State if the State had primary enforcement authority under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300g–2">section 300g–2 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4c0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Underground water source protection programs; applications for grants; allotment of sums; authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> From allotments made pursuant to paragraph (4), the Administrator may make grants to States to carry out underground water source protection programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No grant may be made under paragraph (1) unless an application therefor has been submitted to the Administrator in such form and manner as he may require. No grant may be made to any State under paragraph (1) unless the State has assumed primary enforcement responsibility within two years after the date the Administrator promulgates regulations for State underground injection control programs under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h">section 300h of this title</ref>. The prohibition contained in the preceding sentence shall not apply to such grants when made to Indian Tribes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A grant under paragraph (1) shall be made to cover not more than 75 per centum of the grant recipient’s cost (as determined under regulations of the Administrator) in carrying out, during the one-year period beginning on the date the grant is made, and underground water source protection program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In each fiscal year the Administrator shall, in accordance with regulations, allot the sums appropriated for such year under paragraph (5) among the States on the basis of population, geographical area, and other relevant factors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb63e4c14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For purposes of making grants under paragraph (1) there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, $7,500,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>, $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1978 and 1979, $7,795,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, $18,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, and $21,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>. For the purpose of making grants under paragraph (1) there are authorized to be appropriated not more than the following amounts:<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c2,L0,tp0,p7,7/8,s10,12,tp0,p7,7/8,s10,12; " id="idb63e4c15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 160pt;" />
<html:col style="width:46pt ; max-width:46pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:7pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 160.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:left;">Fiscal year:</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:46.0pt ; max-width:46.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Amount</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>  1987</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">$19,700,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>  1988</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">19,700,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>  1989</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">20,850,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>  1990</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">20,850,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>  1991</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">20,850,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>  1992–2003</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">15,000,000.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4c16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “public water system supervision program” means a program for the adoption and enforcement of drinking water regulations (with such variances and exemptions from such regulations under conditions and in a manner which is not less stringent than the conditions under, and the manner in, which variances and exemptions may be granted under sections 300g–4 and 300g–5 of this title) which are no less stringent than the national primary drinking water regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300g–1">section 300g–1 of this title</ref>, and for keeping records and making reports required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300g–2/a/3">section 300g–2(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb63e4c18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “underground water source protection program” means a program for the adoption and enforcement of a program which meets the requirements of regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h">section 300h of this title</ref>, and for keeping records and making reports required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–1/b/1/A/ii">section 300h–1(b)(1)(A)(ii) of this title</ref>. Such term includes, where applicable, a program which meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4">section 300h–4 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4c19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> New York City watershed protection program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4c1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator is authorized to provide financial assistance to the State of New York for demonstration projects implemented as part of the watershed program for the protection and enhancement of the quality of source waters of the New York City water supply system, including projects that demonstrate, assess, or provide for comprehensive monitoring and surveillance and projects necessary to comply with the criteria for avoiding filtration contained in 40 CFR 141.71. Demonstration projects which shall be eligible for financial assistance shall be certified to the Administrator by the State of New York as satisfying the purposes of this subsection. In certifying projects to the Administrator, the State of New York shall give priority to monitoring projects that have undergone peer review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4c1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 5 years after the date on which the Administrator first provides assistance pursuant to this paragraph, the Governor of the State of New York shall submit a report to the Administrator on the results of projects assisted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4c1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Matching requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Federal assistance provided under this subsection shall not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of the protection program being carried out for any particular watershed or ground water recharge area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb63e4c1d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300j–2/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this subsection for each of fiscal years 2003 through 2010, $15,000,000 for the purpose of providing assistance to the State of New York to carry out paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb63e4c1e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIV, § 1443, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/523/s2/a">Pub. L. 93–523, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-16">Dec. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1684">88 Stat. 1684</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/190">Pub. L. 95–190</ref>, §§ 2(b), (c), 5(a), <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1393">91 Stat. 1393</ref>, 1395; <ref href="/us/pl/96/63/s2">Pub. L. 96–63, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-09-06">Sept. 6, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/411">93 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/502">Pub. L. 96–502</ref>, §§ 2(c), 4(d), <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2738">94 Stat. 2738</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/tIII">Pub. L. 99–339, title III</ref>, §§ 301(b), (c), 302(d), <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/664">100 Stat. 664</ref>, 666; <ref href="/us/pl/104/182/tI">Pub. L. 104–182, title I</ref>, §§ 120(c), 124, 128, <date date="1996-08-06">Aug. 6, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1651">110 Stat. 1651</ref>, 1653, 1659; <ref href="/us/pl/108/328/s1">Pub. L. 108–328, § 1</ref>, <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1273">118 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/tII/s2014">Pub. L. 115–270, title II, § 2014</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3854">132 Stat. 3854</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb63e4c1f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb63e4c20-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb63e4c21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/115/270">Pub. L. 115–270</ref> substituted “$125,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2020 and 2021” for “$100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1997 through 2003”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/328">Pub. L. 108–328</ref> substituted “2003 through 2010” for “1997 through 2003”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/104/182/s124/1">Pub. L. 104–182, § 124(1)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “For purposes of making grants under paragraph (1) there are authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, $25,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1977-06-30">June 30, 1977</date>, $35,000,000 for fiscal year 1978, $45,000,000 for fiscal year 1979, $29,450,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, $32,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, and $34,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>. For the purposes of making grants under paragraph (1) there are authorized to be appropriated not more than the following amounts:</p>
<html:table class="Quoted" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c2,L0,tp0,p6,6/7,s11,13,tp0,p6,6/7,s11,13; " id="idb63e4c22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 163pt;" />
<html:col style="width:43pt ; max-width:43pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 163.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:left;">“Fiscal year:</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:43.0pt ; max-width:43.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Amount</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> 1987</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">$37,200,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> 1988</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">37,200,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> 1989</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">40,150,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> 1990</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">40,150,000  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> 1991</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">40,150,000”.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/182/s124/2">Pub. L. 104–182, § 124(2)</ref>, added pars. (8) and (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/182/s120/c">Pub. L. 104–182, § 120(c)</ref>, inserted table item relating to fiscal years 1992 through 2003.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/182/s128">Pub. L. 104–182, § 128</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/s302/d/1">Pub. L. 99–339, § 302(d)(1)</ref>, inserted provision that prohibitions contained in preceding two sentences not apply to such grants when made to Indian Tribes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/s301/b">Pub. L. 99–339, § 301(b)</ref>, authorized appropriations for grants under par. (1) of not more than $37,200,000 for fiscal years 1987 and 1988 and of not more than $40,150,000 for fiscal years 1989 to 1991.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/s302/d/2">Pub. L. 99–339, § 302(d)(2)</ref>, inserted provision that prohibition contained in preceding sentence not apply to such grants when made to Indian Tribes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/s301/c">Pub. L. 99–339, § 301(c)</ref>, authorized appropriations for grants under par. (1) of not more than $19,700,000 for fiscal years 1987 and 1988 and of not more than $20,850,000 for fiscal years 1989 to 1991.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/502/s4/d">Pub. L. 96–502, § 4(d)</ref>, substituted provisions that no grant may be made to any State under par. (1) unless the State has assumed primary enforcement responsibility within two years after the date the Administrator promulgates regulations for State underground injection control programs under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h">section 300h of this title</ref> for provisions that the Administrator may not approve an application of a State for its first grant under par. (1) unless he determines that the State has established or will establish within two years from the date of such grant an underground water source protection, and will, within such two years, assume primary enforcement responsibility for underground water sources within the State and that no grant may be made to a State under par. (1) for any period beginning more than two years after the date of the State’s first grant unless the State has assumed and maintains primary enforcement responsibility for underground water sources within the State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/502/s2/c">Pub. L. 96–502, § 2(c)</ref>, inserted provision that such term includes, where applicable, a program which meets requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300h–4">section 300h–4 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/96/63/s2/a">Pub. L. 96–63, § 2(a)</ref>, authorized appropriation of $29,450,000, $32,000,000, and $34,000,000 for fiscal years ending <date date="1980-09-30">Sept. 30, 1980</date>, through 1982, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/96/63/s2/b">Pub. L. 96–63, § 2(b)</ref>, authorized appropriation of $7,795,000, $18,000,000, and $21,000,000 for fiscal years ending <date date="1980-09-30">Sept. 30, 1980</date>, through 1982, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s5/a">Pub. L. 95–190, § 5(a)</ref>, added pars. (5) and (6). Former par. (5) redesignated (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190">Pub. L. 95–190</ref>, §§ 2(b), 5(a), redesignated former par. (5) as (7) and authorized appropriations for fiscal years 1978 and 1979.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s2/c">Pub. L. 95–190, § 2(c)</ref>, inserted provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years 1978 and 1979.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
