<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb6d6e210-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14"><num value="300jj–14">§ 300jj–14.</num><heading> Process for adoption of endorsed recommendations; adoption of initial set of standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e211-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Process for adoption of endorsed recommendations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e212-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of endorsed standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the date of receipt of standards, implementation specifications, or certification criteria endorsed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–11/c">section 300jj–11(c) of this title</ref>, the Secretary, in consultation with representatives of other relevant Federal agencies, shall jointly review such standards, implementation specifications, or certification criteria and shall determine whether or not to propose adoption of such standards, implementation specifications, or certification criteria.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e213-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination to adopt standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6d6e214-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to propose adoption of any grouping of such standards, implementation specifications, or certification criteria, the Secretary shall, by regulation under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, determine whether or not to adopt such grouping of standards, implementation specifications, or certification criteria; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb6d6e215-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not to propose adoption of any grouping of standards, implementation specifications, or certification criteria, the Secretary shall notify the National Coordinator and the HIT Advisory Committee in writing of such determination and the reasons for not proposing the adoption of such recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e216-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide for publication in the Federal Register of all determinations made by the Secretary under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e217-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Adoption of standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e218-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall, through the rulemaking process consistent with subsection (a)(2)(A), adopt an initial set of standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria for the areas required for consideration under section 300jj–12(b)(2)(B) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002518">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002518"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title. The rulemaking for the initial set of standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria may be issued on an interim, final basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e219-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of current standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria adopted before <date date="2009-02-17">February 17, 2009</date>, through the process existing through the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology may be applied towards meeting the requirement of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e21a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Subsequent standards activity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall adopt additional standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria as necessary and consistent with the schedule published under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–12/b/4">section 300jj–12(b)(4) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6d6e21b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–14/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Deference to standards development organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In adopting and implementing standards under this section, the Secretary shall give deference to standards published by standards development organizations and voluntary consensus-based standards bodies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb6d6e21c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XXX, § 3004, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/5/dA/tXIII/s13101">Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIII, § 13101</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/240">123 Stat. 240</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIV/s4003/d">Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title IV, § 4003(d)</ref>, (e)(2)(A)(i), (D), <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1168">130 Stat. 1168</ref>, 1174, 1175.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb6d6e21d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb6d6e21e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb6d6e21f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj–12/b/2/B">Section 300jj–12(b)(2)(B) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), related to areas of health information technology required to be considered by the HIT Policy Committee and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIV/s4003/e/1">Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title IV, § 4003(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1168">130 Stat. 1168</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb6d6e220-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/e/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(e)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “HIT Advisory Committee” for “HIT Standards Committee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/e/2/D">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(e)(2)(D)</ref>, substituted “300jj–12(b)(4)” for “300jj–13(b)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s4003/d">Pub. L. 114–255, § 4003(d)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb6d6e221-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb6d6e222-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Leveraging Electronic Health Records To Improve Patient Care</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIV/s4005">Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title IV, § 4005</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1180">130 Stat. 1180</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tIV/s4005">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement Relating to Registries.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>To be certified in accordance with title XXX of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300jj">42 U.S.C. 300jj</ref> et seq.), electronic health records shall be capable of transmitting to, and where applicable, receiving and accepting data from, registries in accordance with standards recognized by the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology, including clinician-led clinical data registries, that are also certified to be technically capable of receiving and accepting from, and where applicable, transmitting data to certified electronic health record technology in accordance with such standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the certification of registries beyond the technical capability to exchange data in accordance with applicable recognized standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this Act [see Tables for classification], the term ‘clinician-led clinical data registry’ means a clinical data repository—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> that is established and operated by a clinician-led or controlled, tax-exempt (pursuant to section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c">26 U.S.C. 501(c)</ref>]), professional society or other similar clinician-led or -controlled organization, or such organization’s controlled affiliate, devoted to the care of a population defined by a particular disease, condition, exposure or therapy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that is designed to collect detailed, standardized data on an ongoing basis for medical procedures, services, or therapies for particular diseases, conditions, or exposures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> that provides feedback to participants who submit reports to the repository;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> that meets standards for data quality including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> systematically collecting clinical and other health care data, using standardized data elements and having procedures in place to verify the completeness and validity of those data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> being subject to regular data checks or audits to verify completeness and validity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> that provides ongoing participant training and support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Health Information Technology Developers With Respect to Patient Safety Organizations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In applying part C of title IX of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s299b–21">42 U.S.C. 299b–21</ref> et seq.), a health information technology developer shall be treated as a provider (as defined in section 921 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s299b–21">42 U.S.C. 299b–21</ref>]) for purposes of reporting and conducting patient safety activities concerning improving clinical care through the use of health information technology that could result in improved patient safety, health care quality, or health care outcomes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report concerning best practices and current trends voluntarily provided, without identifying individual providers or disclosing or using protected health information or individually identifiable information, by patient safety organizations to improve the integration of health information technology into clinical practice.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
