<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb65afc13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6"><num value="300u–6">§ 300u–6.</num><heading> Office of Minority Health</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established an Office of Minority Health. The Office of Minority Health as existing on <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>, shall be transferred to the Office of the Secretary in such manner that there is established in the Office of the Secretary, the Office of Minority Health, which shall be headed by the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health who shall report directly to the Secretary, and shall retain and strengthen authorities (as in existence on <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>) for the purpose of improving minority health and the quality of health care minorities receive, and eliminating racial and ethnic disparities. In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary, acting through the Deputy Assistant Secretary, shall award grants, contracts, enter into memoranda of understanding, cooperative, interagency, intra-agency and other agreements with public and nonprofit private entities, agencies, as well as Departmental and Cabinet agencies and organizations, and with organizations that are indigenous human resource providers in communities of color to assure improved health status of racial and ethnic minorities, and shall develop measures to evaluate the effectiveness of activities aimed at reducing health disparities and supporting the local community. Such measures shall evaluate community outreach activities, language services, workforce cultural competence, and other areas as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to improving the health of racial and ethnic minority groups, the Secretary, acting through the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Assistant Secretary”), shall carry out the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Establish short-range and long-range goals and objectives and coordinate all other activities within the Public Health Service that relate to disease prevention, health promotion, service delivery, and research concerning such individuals. The heads of each of the agencies of the Service shall consult with the Deputy Assistant Secretary to ensure the coordination of such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Enter into interagency agreements with other agencies of the Public Health Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Support research, demonstrations and evaluations to test new and innovative models.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Increase knowledge and understanding of health risk factors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Develop mechanisms that support better information dissemination, education, prevention, and service delivery to individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, including individuals who are members of racial or ethnic minority groups.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Ensure that the National Center for Health Statistics collects data on the health status of each minority group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> With respect to individuals who lack proficiency in speaking the English language, enter into contracts with public and nonprofit private providers of primary health services for the purpose of increasing the access of the individuals to such services by developing and carrying out programs to provide bilingual or interpretive services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc1d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> Support a national minority health resource center to carry out the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb65afc1e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Facilitate the exchange of information regarding matters relating to health information and health promotion, preventive health services, and education in the appropriate use of health care.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb65afc1f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Facilitate access to such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb65afc20-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Assist in the analysis of issues and problems relating to such matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb65afc21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/8/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Provide technical assistance with respect to the exchange of such information (including facilitating the development of materials for such technical assistance).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Carry out programs to improve access to health care services for individuals with limited proficiency in speaking the English language. Activities under the preceding sentence shall include developing and evaluating model projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc23-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Advise in matters related to the development, implementation, and evaluation of health professions education in decreasing disparities in health care outcomes, including cultural competency as a method of eliminating health disparities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc24-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory Committee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc25-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the Advisory Committee on Minority Health (in this subsection referred to as the “Committee”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Committee shall provide advice to the Deputy Assistant Secretary carrying out this section, including advice on the development of goals and specific program activities under paragraphs (1) through (10) of subsection (b) for each racial and ethnic minority group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc27-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Chair</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The chairperson of the Committee shall be selected by the Secretary from among the members of the voting members of the Committee. The term of office of the chairperson shall be 2 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc28-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Committee shall be composed of 12 voting members appointed in accordance with subparagraph (B), and nonvoting, ex officio members designated in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The voting members of the Committee shall be appointed by the Secretary from among individuals who are not officers or employees of the Federal Government and who have expertise regarding issues of minority health. The racial and ethnic minority groups shall be equally represented among such members.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The nonvoting, ex officio members of the Committee shall be such officials of the Department of Health and Human Services as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each member of the Committee shall serve for a term of 4 years, except that the Secretary shall initially appoint a portion of the members to terms of 1 year, 2 years, and 3 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a vacancy occurs on the Committee, a new member shall be appointed by the Secretary within 90 days from the date that the vacancy occurs, and serve for the remainder of the term for which the predecessor of such member was appointed. The vacancy shall not affect the power of the remaining members to execute the duties of the Committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Members of the Committee who are officers or employees of the United States shall serve without compensation. Members of the Committee who are not officers or employees of the United States shall receive compensation, for each day (including travel time) they are engaged in the performance of the functions of the Committee. Such compensation may not be in an amount in excess of the daily equivalent of the annual maximum rate of basic pay payable under the General Schedule (under title 5) for positions above GS–15.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain requirements regarding duties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendations regarding language</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Proficiency in speaking English</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Deputy Assistant Secretary shall consult with the Director of the Office of International and Refugee Health, the Director of the Office of Civil Rights, and the Directors of other appropriate departmental entities regarding recommendations for carrying out activities under subsection (b)(9).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Health professions education regarding health disparities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Deputy Assistant Secretary shall carry out the duties under subsection (b)(10) in collaboration with appropriate personnel of the Department of Health and Human Services, other Federal agencies, and other offices, centers, and institutions, as appropriate, that have responsibilities under the Minority Health and Health Disparities Research and Education Act of 2000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Equitable allocation regarding activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary shall ensure that services provided under such subsection are equitably allocated among all groups served under this section by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Cultural competency of services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure that information and services provided pursuant to subsection (b) are provided in the language, educational, and cultural context that is most appropriate for the individuals for whom the information and services are intended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants and contracts regarding duties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary acting through the Deputy Assistant Secretary may make awards of grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts to public and nonprofit private entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Process for making awards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Deputy Assistant Secretary shall ensure that awards under paragraph (1) are made, to the extent practical, only on a competitive basis, and that a grant is awarded for a proposal only if the proposal has been recommended for such an award through a process of peer review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation and dissemination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Deputy Assistant Secretary, directly or through contracts with public and private entities, shall provide for evaluations of projects carried out with awards made under paragraph (1) during the preceding 2 fiscal years. The report shall be included in the report required under subsection (f) for the fiscal year involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than February 1 of fiscal year 1999 and of each second year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, a report describing the activities carried out under this section during the preceding 2 fiscal years and evaluating the extent to which such activities have been effective in improving the health of racial and ethnic minority groups. Each such report shall include the biennial reports submitted under subsections (e)(3) and (f)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002369">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002369"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> for such years by the heads of the Public Health Service agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1999-02-01">February 1, 1999</date>, and biennially thereafter, the heads of the Public Health Service agencies shall submit to the Deputy Assistant Secretary a report summarizing the minority health activities of each of the respective agencies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “racial and ethnic minority group” means American Indians (including Alaska Natives, Eskimos, and Aleuts); Asian Americans; Native Hawaiians and other Pacific Islanders; Blacks; and Hispanics.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb65afc3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Hispanic” means individuals whose origin is Mexican, Puerto Rican, Cuban, Central or South American, or any other Spanish-speaking country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb65afc3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2016.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb65afc40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XVII, § 1707, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/527/s2">Pub. L. 101–527, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-06">Nov. 6, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2312">104 Stat. 2312</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/557/tIV/s401/a/1">Pub. L. 101–557, title IV, § 401(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2770">104 Stat. 2770</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 105–392, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3582">112 Stat. 3582</ref>, 3585; <ref href="/us/pl/106/525/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 106–525, title IV, § 403</ref>, title VI, § 601, <date date="2000-11-22">Nov. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2509">114 Stat. 2509</ref>, 2511; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10334/a/1">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10334(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/971">124 Stat. 971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb65afc41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb65afc42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb65afc43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The General Schedule, referred to in subsec. (c)(7), is set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Minority Health and Health Disparities Research and Education Act of 2000, referred to in subsec. (d)(1)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/106/525">Pub. L. 106–525</ref>, <date date="2000-11-22">Nov. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2495">114 Stat. 2495</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2000 Amendments note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsections (e)(3) and (f)(2), referred to in subsec. (f)(1), were in the original “sections 201(e)(3) and 201(f)(2)”, and were translated to reflect the probable intent of Congress, because section 201 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>, does not contain subsections, and subsections (e)(3) and (f)(2) of this section require biennial reporting.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb65afc44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 300u–6, <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tXVII/s1707">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XVII, § 1707</ref>, as added <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/95/626/tV/s502">Pub. L. 95–626, title V, § 502</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3593">92 Stat. 3593</ref>; amended <date date="1979-07-10">July 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/96/32/s6/k">Pub. L. 96–32, § 6(k)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/84">93 Stat. 84</ref>, related to project grants to State Councils on Physical Fitness for physical fitness improvement, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/98/551/s2/c">Pub. L. 98–551, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2816">98 Stat. 2816</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb65afc45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10334/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–148, § 10334(a)(1)(A)</ref>, amended text of subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “There is established an Office of Minority Health within the Office of Public Health and Science. There shall be in the Department of Health and Human Services a Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health, who shall be the head of the Office of Minority Health. The Secretary, acting through such Deputy Assistant Secretary, shall carry out this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10334/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–148, § 10334(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (h) and struck out former subsec. (h). Prior to amendment, text of subsec. (h), which consisted only of a par. (1), read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for fiscal year 1998, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1999 through 2002.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/106/525/s403/1">Pub. L. 106–525, § 403(1)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/525/s403/2">Pub. L. 106–525, § 403(2)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (1) through (10)” for “paragraphs (1) through (9)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/525/s403/3">Pub. L. 106–525, § 403(3)</ref>, amended heading and text of par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health shall consult with the Director of the Office of International and Refugee Health, the Director of the Office of Civil Rights, and the Directors of other appropriate departmental entities regarding recommendations for carrying out activities under subsection (b)(9) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/525/s601">Pub. L. 106–525, § 601</ref>, substituted “Asian Americans;” for “Asian Americans and” and inserted “Native Hawaiians and other” before “Pacific Islanders;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s201/c/1">Pub. L. 105–392, § 201(c)(1)</ref>, struck out “Establishment of” before “Office” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s201/c/2">Pub. L. 105–392, § 201(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Public Health and Science” for “the Assistant Secretary for Health”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s201/a">Pub. L. 105–392, § 201(a)</ref>, added subsecs. (b) to (h) and struck out former subsecs. (b) to (f), which related, respectively, to duties of Secretary, certain requirements regarding duties, grants and contracts regarding duties, reports, and funding.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/101/557">Pub. L. 101–557</ref> added par. (8).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb65afc46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb65afc47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Labor and Human Resources of Senate changed to Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of Senate by Senate Resolution No. 20, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-19">Jan. 19, 1999</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb65afc48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/557/tIV/s401/a/2">Pub. L. 101–557, title IV, § 401(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2771">104 Stat. 2771</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/557/tIV/s401/a/2">“The amendments made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of the Disadvantaged Minority Health Improvement Act of 1990 [<date date="1990-11-06">Nov. 6, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb65afc49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10334/a/2">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10334(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/971">124 Stat. 971</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10334/a/2">“There are transferred to the Office of Minority Health in the office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, all duties, responsibilities, authorities, accountabilities, functions, staff, funds, award mechanisms, and other entities under the authority of the Office of Minority Health of the Public Health Service as in effect on the date before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>], which shall continue in effect according to the terms in effect on the date before such date of enactment, until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the Secretary, a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb65afc4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/641/s6">Pub. L. 93–641, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2275">88 Stat. 2275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s217a">section 217a of this title</ref>, provided that an advisory committee established pursuant to the Public Health Service Act shall terminate at such time as may be specifically prescribed by an Act of Congress enacted after <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb65afc4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10334/a/3">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10334(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/972">124 Stat. 972</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10334/a/3">“Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>], and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the activities carried out under section 1707 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300u–6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6</ref>] (as amended by this subsection) during the period for which the report is being prepared. Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and biennially thereafter, the heads of each of the agencies of the Department of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health a report summarizing the minority health activities of each of the respective agencies.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb65afc4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/527/s1/b">Pub. L. 101–527, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-06">Nov. 6, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2311">104 Stat. 2311</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/527/s1/b">
<inline>“The Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> racial and ethnic minorities are disproportionately represented among individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the health status of individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, including racial and ethnic minorities, in the United States is significantly lower than the health status of the general population of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> minorities suffer disproportionately high rates of cancer, stroke, heart diseases, diabetes, substance abuse, acquired immune deficiency syndrome, and other diseases and disorders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the incidence of infant mortality among minorities is almost double that for the general population;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Blacks, Hispanics, and Native Americans constitute approximately 12 percent, 7.9 percent, and 0.01 percent, respectively, of the population of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Blacks, Hispanics, and Native Americans in the United States constitute approximately 3 percent, 4 percent, and less than 0.01 percent, respectively, of physicians, 2.7 percent, 1.7 percent, and less than 0.01 percent, respectively, of dentists, and 4.5 percent, 1.6 percent, and less than 0.01 percent, respectively, of nurses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the number of individuals who are from disadvantaged backgrounds in health professions should be increased for the purpose of improving the access of other such individuals to health services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> minority health professionals have historically tended to practice in low-income areas and to serve minorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> minority health professionals have historically tended to engage in the general practice of medicine and specialties providing primary care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> reports published in leading medical journals indicate that access to health care among minorities can be substantially improved by increasing the number of minority health professionals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> increasing the number of minorities serving on the faculties of health professions schools can be an important factor in attracting minorities to pursue a career in the health professions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="12">“(12)</num><content> diversity in the faculty and student body of health professions schools enhances the quality of education for all students attending the schools;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="13">“(13)</num><content> the Report of the Secretary’s Task Force on Black and Minority Health (prepared for the Secretary of Health and Human Services and issued in 1985) described the health status problems of minorities, and made recommendations concerning measures that should be implemented by the Secretary with respect to improving the health status of minorities through programs for providing health information and education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="14">“(14)</num><content> the Office of Minority Health, created in 1985 by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, should be authorized pursuant to statute and should receive increased funding to support efforts to improve the health of individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, including minorities, including the implementation of the recommendations made by the Secretary’s Task Force on Black and Minority Health.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
