<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb6647171-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300x"><num value="300x">§ 300x.</num><heading> Formula grants to States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6647172-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300x/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose described in subsection (b), the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services, shall make an allotment each fiscal year for each State in an amount determined in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x–7">section 300x–7 of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall make a grant to the State of the allotment made for the State for the fiscal year if the State submits to the Secretary an application in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x–6">section 300x–6 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb6647173-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300x/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose of grants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A funding agreement for a grant under subsection (a) is that, subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x–5">section 300x–5 of this title</ref>, the State involved will expend the grant only for the purpose of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6647174-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300x/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> providing community mental health services for adults with a serious mental illness and children with a serious emotional disturbance as defined in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x–1/c">section 300x–1(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6647175-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300x/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> carrying out the plan submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x–1/a">section 300x–1(a) of this title</ref> by the State for the fiscal year involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6647176-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300x/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> evaluating programs and services carried out under the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb6647177-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300x/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> planning, administration, and educational activities related to providing services under the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb6647178-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XIX, § 1911, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/321/tII/s201/2">Pub. L. 102–321, title II, § 201(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/378">106 Stat. 378</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tVIII/s8001/a">Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title VIII, § 8001(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1225">130 Stat. 1225</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb6647179-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb664717a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb664717b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 300x, <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tXIX/s1911">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XIX, § 1911</ref>, as added <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIX/s901">Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 901</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/543">95 Stat. 543</ref>; amended <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/98/509/tI">Pub. L. 98–509, title I</ref>, §§ 101, 106(a), <ref href="/us/stat/98/2353">98 Stat. 2353</ref>, 2358; <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tII/s2021">Pub. L. 100–690, title II, § 2021</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4194">102 Stat. 4194</ref>, authorized appropriations in fiscal years 1990 and 1991 for purpose of carrying out this subpart and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–11">section 290aa–11 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/321/s201/2">Pub. L. 102–321, § 201(2)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb664717c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255">Pub. L. 114–255</ref> added par. (1) and redesignated former pars. (1) to (3) as (2) to (4), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb664717d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb664717e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Part effective <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, with programs making awards providing financial assistance in fiscal year 1993 and subsequent years effective for awards made on or after <date date="1992-10-01">Oct. 1, 1992</date>, and with provision that <ref href="/us/pl/102/321/s205/a">section 205(a) of Pub. L. 102–321</ref>, set out below, regarding allotments made for fiscal year 1992 under this part as in effect on the day before <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, applies with respect to the program established in this part, see section 801(b), (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/102/321">Pub. L. 102–321</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1992 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s236">section 236 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb664717f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">State Guidance Related to Individuals With Serious Mental Illness and Children With Serious Emotional Disturbance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/44/tII/s208">Pub. L. 119–44, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2025-12-01">Dec. 1, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/681">139 Stat. 681</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/44/tII/s208">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review of Use of Certain Funding</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-01">Dec. 1, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’), acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall conduct a review of State use of funds made available under the Community Mental Health Services Block Grant program under subpart I of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x">42 U.S.C. 300x</ref> et seq.) (referred to in this section as the ‘block grant program’) for first episode psychosis activities. Such review shall consider the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> How States use funds for evidence-based treatments and services according to the standard of care for individuals with early serious mental illness and children with a serious emotional disturbance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The percentages of the State funding under the block grant program expended on early serious mental illness and first episode psychosis, and the number of individuals served under such funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report and Guidance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the completion of the review under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report describing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the findings of the review under subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any recommendations for changes to the block grant program that would facilitate improved outcomes for individuals with serious mental illness and children with serious emotional disturbance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the report is submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall update the guidance provided to States under the block grant program on coordinated specialty care and other evidence-based mental health care services for individuals with serious mental illness and children with a serious emotional disturbance, based on the findings and recommendations of such report.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb6647180-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Provisions Regarding Funding</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/321/s205">Section 205 of Pub. L. 102–321</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/352/s2/c">Pub. L. 102–352, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-08-26">Aug. 26, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/939">106 Stat. 939</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/408/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 102–408, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1992-10-13">Oct. 13, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2091">106 Stat. 2091</ref>, provided that, with respect to allotments made for fiscal year 1992 under this part, as in effect on the day before <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, any portion of the total of such allotments that has not been paid to the States as of the first day of the fourth quarter of such fiscal year be reallotted with the result that the total allotment made for a State for fiscal year 1992 be the amount indicated for the State in a specified table, authorized Secretary of Health and Human Services to make a grant to a State of the reallotment if the State agrees that the grant be subject to all conditions upon which allotments and payments under this part, as in effect on the day before <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, are made for fiscal 1992, with specified exceptions, permitted transfers of allotments made in fiscal years 1993 and 1994 between this part and subpart II, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x–21">section 300x–21 of this title</ref>, under certain circumstances, defined terms as used, and directed funding, subject to a limitation, of a program for pregnant and postpartum women for fiscal year 1993.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb6647181-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Allotment Formula</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/321/s707">Section 707 of Pub. L. 102–321</ref> directed Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into a contract with National Academy of Sciences, or if such Academy declines, with another public or nonprofit private agency, for purpose of conducting a study or studies concerning statutory formulae under which funds made available under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300x–21">section 300x–21 of this title</ref> are allocated among States and territories, specified findings to be made by the study or studies, directed Secretary to ensure that not later than 6 months after <date date="1992-07-10">July 10, 1992</date>, the study was completed and a report submitted to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives and Committee on Labor and Human Resources of Senate, and directed entity preparing the report to consult with Comptroller General with Comptroller General to review the study after its submittal and within three months make appropriate recommendations concerning such report to such committees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
