<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb672c90d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4"><num value="300z–4">§ 300z–4.</num><heading> Grants for demonstration projects for services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb672c90e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In approving applications for grants for demonstration projects for services under this subchapter, the Secretary shall give priority to applicants who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c90f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> serve an area where there is a high incidence of adolescent pregnancy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c910-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> serve an area with a high proportion of low-income families and where the availability of programs of care for pregnant adolescents and adolescent parents is low;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c911-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> show evidence—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb672c912-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of an applicant who will provide care services, of having the ability to bring together a wide range of needed core services and, as appropriate, supplemental services in comprehensive single-site projects, or to establish a well-integrated network of such services (appropriate for the target population and geographic area to be served including the special needs of rural areas) for pregnant adolescents or adolescent parents; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb672c913-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of an applicant who will provide prevention services, of having the ability to provide prevention services for adolescents and their families which are appropriate for the target population and the geographic area to be served, including the special needs of rural areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c914-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> will utilize to the maximum extent feasible existing available programs and facilities such as neighborhood and primary health care centers, maternity homes which provide or can be equipped to provide services to pregnant adolescents, agencies serving families, youth, and children with established programs of service to pregnant adolescents and vulnerable families, licensed adoption agencies, children and youth centers, maternal and infant health centers, regional rural health facilities, school and other educational programs, mental health programs, nutrition programs, recreation programs, and other ongoing pregnancy prevention services and programs of care for pregnant adolescents and adolescent parents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c915-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> make use, to the maximum extent feasible, of other Federal, State, and local funds, programs, contributions, and other third-party reimbursements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c916-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> can demonstrate a community commitment to the program by making available to the demonstration project non-Federal funds, personnel, and facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c917-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> have involved the community to be served, including public and private agencies, adolescents, and families, in the planning and implementation of the demonstration project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c918-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> will demonstrate innovative and effective approaches in addressing the problems of adolescent premarital sexual relations, pregnancy, or parenthood, including approaches to provide pregnant adolescents with adequate information about adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb672c919-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors to be considered in making grants; special needs of rural areas</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb672c91a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The amount of a grant for a demonstration project for services under this subchapter shall be determined by the Secretary, based on factors such as the incidence of adolescent pregnancy in the geographic area to be served, and the adequacy of pregnancy prevention services and programs of care for pregnant adolescents and adolescent parents in such area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb672c91b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In making grants for demonstration projects for services under this subchapter, the Secretary shall consider the special needs of rural areas and, to the maximum extent practicable, shall distribute funds taking into consideration the relative number of adolescents in such areas in need of such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb672c91c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration; Federal share</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb672c91d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A grantee may not receive funds for a demonstration project for services under this subchapter for a period in excess of 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb672c91e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb672c91f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Subject to paragraph (3), a grant for a demonstration project for services under this subchapter may not exceed—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c920-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 70 per centum of the costs of the project for the first and second years of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c921-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 60 per centum of such costs for the third year of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c922-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> 50 per centum of such costs for the fourth year of the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb672c923-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> 40 per centum of such costs for the fifth year of the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb672c924-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Non-Federal contributions required by subparagraph (A) may be in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb672c925-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s300z–4/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may waive the limitation specified in paragraph (2)(A) for any year in accordance with criteria established by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb672c926-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title XX, § 2005, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIX/s955/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 955(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/584">95 Stat. 584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
