<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc4284be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013"><num value="3013">§ 3013.</num><heading> Federal agency consultation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc4284bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Assistant Secretary, in carrying out the objectives and provisions of this chapter, shall coordinate, advise, consult with, and cooperate with the head of each department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government proposing or administering programs or services substantially related to the objectives of this chapter, with respect to such programs or services. In particular, the Assistant Secretary shall coordinate, advise, consult, and cooperate with the Secretary of Labor in carrying out subchapter IX and with the Corporation for National and Community Service in carrying out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The head of each department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government proposing to establish programs and services substantially related to the objectives of this chapter shall consult with the Assistant Secretary prior to the establishment of such programs and services. To achieve appropriate coordination, the head of each department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government administering any program substantially related to the objectives of this chapter, particularly administering any program referred to in subsection (b), shall consult and cooperate with the Assistant Secretary in carrying out such program. In particular, the Secretary of Labor shall consult and cooperate with the Assistant Secretary in carrying out title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The head of each department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government administering programs and services substantially related to the objectives of this chapter shall collaborate with the Assistant Secretary in carrying out this chapter, and shall develop a written analysis, for review and comment by the Assistant Secretary, of the impact of such programs and services on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> older individuals (with particular attention to low-income older individuals, including low-income minority older individuals, older individuals with limited English proficiency, and older individuals residing in rural areas) and eligible individuals (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3056p">section 3056p of this title</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the functions and responsibilities of State agencies and area agencies on aging.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc4284c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal programs related to chapter objectives</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of subsection (a), programs related to the objectives of this chapter shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> title II of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5000">42 U.S.C. 5000</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> titles XVI, XVIII, XIX, and XX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1381">42 U.S.C. 1381</ref> et seq., 1395 et seq., 1396 et seq., 1397 et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> sections 1715v and 1715w of title 12,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">42 U.S.C. 1437</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">section 1701q of title 12</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301">42 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> title I of Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.] and the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3271">29 U.S.C. 3271</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> sections 5309 and 5310 of title 49,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], including block grants under title XIX of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300w">42 U.S.C. 300w</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">42 U.S.C. 8621</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> part A of the Energy Conservation in Existing Buildings Act of 1976 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6861">42 U.S.C. 6861</ref> et seq.], relating to weatherization assistance for low income persons,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> the Community Services Block Grant Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">42 U.S.C. 9901</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> demographic statistics and analysis programs conducted by the Bureau of the Census under title 13,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> parts II and III of title 38,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">29 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15001">42 U.S.C. 15001</ref> et seq.],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, established under part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3750–376">42 U.S.C. 3750–376</ref>6b)),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003298">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003298"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below. So in original. The second closing parenthesis before the comma probably should not appear.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> sections 3003 and 3004 of title 29, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/b/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content> section 393D of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280b–1f">42 U.S.C. 280b–1f</ref>), relating to safety of seniors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc4284da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency Coordinating Committee on Aging</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, in collaboration with other Federal officials specified in paragraph (2), shall establish an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Healthy Aging and Age-Friendly Communities (referred to in this subsection as the “Committee”) focusing on the coordination of agencies with respect to aging issues and the development of a national set of recommendations, in accordance with paragraph (6), to support the ability of older individuals to age in place and access homelessness prevention services, preventive health care, promote age-friendly communities, and address the ability of older individuals to access long-term care supports, including access to caregivers and home- and community-based health services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The officials referred to in paragraph (1) shall include the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and may include, at the direction of the President, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Commissioner of Social Security, and such other Federal officials as the President may direct. An official described in this paragraph may appoint a designee to carry out the official’s duties under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall serve as the first chairperson of the Committee, for 1 term, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall serve as the chairperson for the following term. After that following term, the Committee shall select a chairperson from among the members of the Committee, and any member may serve as the chairperson. No member may serve as the chairperson for more than 1 consecutive term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, a term shall be a period of 2 calendar years. The first term, after <date date="2020-03-25">March 25, 2020</date>, shall start not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-03-25">March 25, 2020</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Committee shall meet not less often than once each year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The recommendations described in paragraph (1) may include recommendations for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> ways to improve coordination among Federal agencies with responsibility for programs and services that impact older individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> best practices and evidence-based program and service models to assist older individuals in meeting their housing, health care, and other supportive service needs, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> consumer-directed care models for home and community-based care and supportive services that link housing, health care, and other supportive services and that facilitate aging in place, enabling older individuals to remain in their homes and communities as the individuals age;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> innovations in technology applications (including assistive technology devices and assistive technology services) that give older individuals access to information on available services or that help in providing services to older individuals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> best practices identified in coordination with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Institute on Aging, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and other Federal agencies, as appropriate, to reduce and prevent falls among older individuals, that incorporate evidence-based falls prevention programs and home modifications, which recommendations shall supplement and not unnecessarily duplicate activities authorized under section 393D of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280b–1f">42 U.S.C. 280b–1f</ref>), relating to safety of seniors;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> ways to collect and disseminate information about the programs and services available to older individuals to ensure that such information is accessible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> ways to ensure the continued collection of data relating to the housing, health care, and other supportive service needs of older individuals and to support efforts to identify and address unmet data needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> actively seeking input from and consulting with nonprofit organizations, academic or research institutions, community-based organizations, philanthropic organizations, or other entities supporting age-friendly communities about the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (F);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> identifying any barriers and impediments, including barriers and impediments in statutory and regulatory law, to the access and use by older individuals of federally funded programs and services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/6/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> ways to improve coordination to provide housing, health care, and other supportive services to older individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> Not later than 90 days following the end of each term, the Committee shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate, a report that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> describes the activities and accomplishments of the Committee in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> enhancing the overall coordination of federally funded programs and services that impact older individuals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> meeting the requirements of paragraph (6);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> incorporates an analysis from the head of each agency that is a member of the interagency coordinating committee established under paragraph (1) that describes the barriers and impediments, including barriers and impediments in statutory and regulatory law (as the chairperson of the Committee determines to be appropriate), to the access and use by older individuals of programs and services administered by such agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> makes such recommendations as the chairman determines to be appropriate for actions to meet the needs described in paragraph (6) and for coordinating programs and services designed to meet those needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> On the request of the Committee, any Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Committee without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc4284f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> In this subsection, the term “age-friendly community” means a community that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> is taking measurable steps to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/9/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> include adequate and accessible housing, public spaces and buildings, safe and secure paths, variable route transportation services, and programs and services designed to support health and well-being;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/9/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> respect and include older individuals in social opportunities, civic participation, volunteerism, and employment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc4284f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/9/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> facilitate access to supportive services for older individuals;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is not an assisted living facility or long-term care facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc4284f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3013/c/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has a plan in place to meet local needs for housing, transportation, civic participation, social connectedness, and accessible public spaces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc4284f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/73/tII/s203">Pub. L. 89–73, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/29/tII/s201/c">Pub. L. 93–29, title II, § 201(c)</ref>, <date date="1973-05-03">May 3, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/32">87 Stat. 32</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/tI/s102/b">Pub. L. 95–478, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1513">92 Stat. 1513</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/115/s2/d">Pub. L. 97–115, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1595">95 Stat. 1595</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/459/tII/s203">Pub. L. 98–459, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1768">98 Stat. 1768</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/175/tI">Pub. L. 100–175, title I</ref>, §§ 104(a), 105(b), 106(b), <date date="1987-11-29">Nov. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/929">101 Stat. 929</ref>, 930; <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tIII/s3003/b">Pub. L. 102–240, title III, § 3003(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2088">105 Stat. 2088</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/375/tII/s203">Pub. L. 102–375, title II, § 203</ref>, title IX, § 904(a)(5), <date date="1992-09-30">Sept. 30, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1210">106 Stat. 1210</ref>, 1306; <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tIV/s405/g/2">Pub. L. 103–82, title IV, § 405(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/921">107 Stat. 921</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/171">Pub. L. 103–171</ref>, §§ 2(4), 3(a)(13), <date date="1993-12-02">Dec. 2, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1988">107 Stat. 1988</ref>, 1990; <ref href="/us/pl/105/220/tII/s251/b/3">Pub. L. 105–220, title II, § 251(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1080">112 Stat. 1080</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/33/A">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(33)(A), (f)(25)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–425, 2681–433; <ref href="/us/pl/106/402/tIV/s401/b/9/A">Pub. L. 106–402, title IV, § 401(b)(9)(A)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1739">114 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/501/tII/s202/1">Pub. L. 106–501, title II, § 202(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2230">114 Stat. 2230</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/365/tII/s203">Pub. L. 109–365, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2532">120 Stat. 2532</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tV/s512/w/1">Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(w)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1713">128 Stat. 1713</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/tI/s124/a">Pub. L. 116–131, title I, § 124(a)</ref>, (b), title VII, § 701(4), <date date="2020-03-25">Mar. 25, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/249">134 Stat. 249</ref>, 271.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc4284fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc4284fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc4284fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (b)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1425">128 Stat. 1425</ref>. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 3111 et seq.) of chapter 32 of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/113">Pub. L. 93–113</ref>, <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/394">87 Stat. 394</ref>. Title II of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 5000 et seq.) of chapter 66 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Titles XVI, XVIII, XIX, and XX of the Social Security Act are classified generally to subchapters XVI (§ 1381 et seq.), XVIII (§ 1395 et seq.), XIX (§ 1396 et seq.), and XX (§ 1397 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in subsec. (b)(5), is <ref href="/us/act/1937-09-01/ch896">act Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896</ref>, as revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 93–383, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/653">88 Stat. 653</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 1437 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Housing and Community Development Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (b)(7), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/383">Pub. L. 93–383</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/633">88 Stat. 633</ref>. Title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 is classified principally to chapter 69 (§ 5301 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Higher Education Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (b)(8), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/329">Pub. L. 89–329</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1219">79 Stat. 1219</ref>. Title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1001 et seq.) of chapter 28 of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Adult Education and Family Literacy Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(8), was title II of <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1059">112 Stat. 1059</ref>, which was classified principally to subchapter I (§ 9201 et seq.) of chapter 73 of Title 20, Education, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tV">Pub. L. 113–128, title V</ref>, §§ 506, 511(a), <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1703">128 Stat. 1703</ref>, 1705, effective <date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>. <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> also included a title II, entitled the “Adult Education and Family Literacy Act”, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 3271 et seq.) of chapter 32 of Title 29, Labor. Pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3361/a">section 3361(a) of Title 29</ref>, references to a provision of <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref> are deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1425">128 Stat. 1425</ref>, effective <date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>. For complete classification of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref> to the Code, see Tables. For complete classification of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(10), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 6A (§ 201 et seq.) of this title. Title XIX of the Public Health Service Act is classified to subchapter XVII (§ 300w et seq.) of chapter 6A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981, referred to in subsec. (b)(11), is title XXVI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/893">95 Stat. 893</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 8621 et seq.) of chapter 94 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Conservation in Existing Buildings Act of 1976, referred to in subsec. (b)(12), is title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/94/385">Pub. L. 94–385</ref>, <date date="1976-08-14">Aug. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1150">90 Stat. 1150</ref>. Part A of the Energy Conservation in Existing Buildings Act of 1976 is classified generally to part A (§ 6861 et seq.) of subchapter III of chapter 81 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6801">section 6801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Community Services Block Grant Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(13), is subtitle B (§ 671 et seq.) of title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/511">95 Stat. 511</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 106 (§ 9901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">section 9901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (b)(16), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/112">Pub. L. 93–112</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/355">87 Stat. 355</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 701 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">section 701 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000, referred to in subsec. (b)(17), is <ref href="/us/pl/106/402">Pub. L. 106–402</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1677">114 Stat. 1677</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 144 (§ 15001 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15001">section 15001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, referred to in subsec. (b)(18), deemed to be a reference to the grant program referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10151/a">section 10151(a) of Title 34</ref>, Crime Control and Law Enforcement. See <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10151/b/1">section 10151(b)(1) of Title 34</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, referred to in subsec. (b)(18), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/351">Pub. L. 90–351</ref>, <date date="1968-06-19">June 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/197">82 Stat. 197</ref>. Part E of title I of the Act was classified generally to subchapter V (§ 3750 et seq.) of chapter 46 of this title, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as subchapter V (§ 10151 et seq.) of chapter 101 of Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1968 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of Title 34</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc4284fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b)(9), “sections 5309 and 5310 of title 49” substituted for “sections 3, 9, and 16 of the Federal Transit Act” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s6/b">Pub. L. 103–272, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1378">108 Stat. 1378</ref>, the first section of which enacted subtitles II, III, and V to X of Title 49, Transportation. Previously, section 9 of the Federal Transit Act, classified to section 1607a of former Title 49, Transportation, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tIII/s305/a">Pub. L. 95–599, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2473">92 Stat. 2473</ref>, and a new section 9 of the Act, classified to section 1607a of former Title 49, was enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/97/424/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 97–424, title III, § 303</ref>, formerly § 303(a), <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2141">96 Stat. 2141</ref>. The new section 9 of the Act was repealed and reenacted as sections 5307 and 5336 of Title 49, Transportation, by <ref href="/us/pl/103/272">Pub. L. 103–272</ref>, §§ 1(b), 7(b), <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/795">108 Stat. 795</ref>, 840, 1379.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc4284fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b)(20). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/a">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(a)</ref>, added par. (20).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/1">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “other Federal officials” for “the Federal officials” and “Committee on Healthy Aging and Age-Friendly Communities” for “Committee on Aging” and inserted before period at end “and the development of a national set of recommendations, in accordance with paragraph (6), to support the ability of older individuals to age in place and access homelessness prevention services, preventive health care, promote age-friendly communities, and address the ability of older individuals to access long-term care supports, including access to caregivers and home- and community-based health services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/2">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “The first term, after <date date="2020-03-25">March 25, 2020</date>, shall start not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-03-25">March 25, 2020</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/A">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “The recommendations described in paragraph (1) may include recommendations for” for “The Committee shall” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/B">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “ways to” for “share information with and establish an ongoing system to” and “that impact older individuals” for “for older individuals and recommend improvements to such system with an emphasis on—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) improving access to programs and services for older individuals;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) maximizing the impact of federally funded programs and services for older individuals by increasing the efficiency, effectiveness, and delivery of such programs and services;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) planning and preparing for the impact of demographic changes on programs and services for older individuals; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iv) reducing or eliminating areas of overlap and duplication by Federal agencies in the provision and accessibility of such programs and services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/C/i">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(C)(i)</ref>, struck out “identify, promote, and implement (as appropriate),” before “best practices” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/C/ii">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(C)(ii)</ref>–(iv), added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/D">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(D)</ref>, inserted “ways to” before “collect”, struck out “older individuals and” before “the programs”, and substituted “older individuals to ensure that such information is accessible” for “the individuals to ensure that the individuals can access comprehensive information”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/E">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(E)</ref>, substituted “ways to ensure” for “work with the Federal Interagency Forum on Aging-Related Statistics, the Bureau of the Census, and member agencies to ensure”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/F">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(F)</ref>, substituted “seeking input from and consulting with nonprofit organizations, academic or research institutions, community-based organizations, philanthropic organizations, or other entities supporting age-friendly communities” for “seek input from and consult with nongovernmental experts and organizations, including public health interest and research groups and foundations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/G">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(G)</ref>, substituted “identifying” for “identify”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/3/H">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(3)(H)</ref>, amended subpar. (G) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (G) read as follows: “work with States to better provide housing, health care, and other supportive services to older individuals by—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) holding meetings with State agencies;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) providing ongoing technical assistance to States about better meeting the needs of older individuals; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) working with States to designate liaisons, from the State agencies, to the Committee.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s701/4">Pub. L. 116–131, § 701(4)</ref>, substituted “Committee on Education and Labor” for “Committee on Education and the Workforce” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/4">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “services that impact older individuals” for “services for older individuals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/116/131/s124/b/5">Pub. L. 116–131, § 124(b)(5)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s512/w/1/A">Pub. L. 113–128, § 512(w)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “In particular, the Secretary of Labor shall consult and cooperate with the Assistant Secretary in carrying out title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act” for “In particular, the Secretary of Labor shall consult and cooperate with the Assistant Secretary in carrying out title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s512/w/1/B">Pub. L. 113–128, § 512(w)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act” for “title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/365/s203/1">Pub. L. 109–365, § 203(1)</ref>, substituted “(with particular attention to low-income older individuals, including low-income minority older individuals, older individuals with limited English proficiency, and older individuals residing in rural areas)” for “(with particular attention to low-income minority older individuals and older individuals residing in rural areas)” and “section 3056p” for “section 3056e”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(19). <ref href="/us/pl/109/365/s203/2">Pub. L. 109–365, § 203(2)</ref>, added par. (19).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/365/s203/3">Pub. L. 109–365, § 203(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/501">Pub. L. 106–501</ref> inserted “and older individuals residing in rural areas” after “low-income minority older individuals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(17). <ref href="/us/pl/106/402">Pub. L. 106–402</ref> substituted “Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000” for “Developmental Disabilities and Bill of Rights Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/f/25/A/i">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(25)(A)(i)]</ref>, struck out “the Job Training Partnership Act and” after “in carrying out”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/33/A/i">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(33)(A)(i)]</ref>, substituted last sentence for former last sentence which read as follows: “In particular, the Secretary of Labor shall consult and cooperate with the Assistant Secretary in carrying out the Job Training Partnership Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1501">29 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/f/25/A/ii">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(25)(A)(ii)]</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “the Job Training Partnership Act or title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/33/A/ii">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(33)(A)(ii)]</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “the Job Training Partnership Act,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref> substituted “Adult Education and Family Literacy Act” for “Adult Education Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/171/s3/a/13">Pub. L. 103–171, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, substituted “Assistant Secretary” for “Commissioner” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> substituted “the Corporation for National and Community Service” for “the ACTION Agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/171/s2/4">Pub. L. 103–171, § 2(4)</ref>, struck out “Federal” before “department” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/375/s203/a">Pub. L. 102–375, § 203(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The Commissioner, in carrying out the purposes and provisions of this chapter, shall advise, consult, and cooperate with the head of each Federal agency or department proposing or administering programs or services substantially related to the purposes of this chapter, with respect to such programs or services. The head of each Federal agency or department proposing to establish programs and services substantially related to the purposes of this chapter shall consult with the Commissioner prior to the establishment of such programs and services. The head of each Federal agency administering any program substantially related to the purposes of this chapter, particularly administering any program set forth in subsection (b) of this section, shall, to achieve appropriate coordination, consult and cooperate with the Commissioner in carrying out such program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/375/s904/a/5">Pub. L. 102–375, § 904(a)(5)</ref>, substituted “objectives of this chapter” for “purposes of this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(18). <ref href="/us/pl/102/375/s203/b">Pub. L. 102–375, § 203(b)</ref>, added par. (18).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> substituted references to sections of the Federal Transit Act for sections of the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964, which for purposes of codification were translated as sections of title 49, Appendix, thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/100/175/s105/b">Pub. L. 100–175, § 105(b)</ref>, inserted reference to block grants under title XIX of the Public Health Service Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/100/175/s104/a">Pub. L. 100–175, § 104(a)</ref>, added par. (15).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16), (17). <ref href="/us/pl/100/175/s106/b">Pub. L. 100–175, § 106(b)</ref>, added pars. (16) and (17).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/459/s203/a">Pub. L. 98–459, § 203(a)</ref>, substituted “Job Training Partnership Act” for “Comprehensive Employment and Training Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/459/s203/b">Pub. L. 98–459, § 203(b)</ref>, inserted reference to title XVI of the Social Security Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/98/459/s203/c">Pub. L. 98–459, § 203(c)</ref>, struck out “the community schools program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965,” before “title I” and the comma after “Higher Education Act of 1965”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/98/459/s203/d">Pub. L. 98–459, § 203(d)</ref>, struck out reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1604">section 1604 of title 49</ref>, Appendix.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10) to (14). <ref href="/us/pl/98/459/s203/e">Pub. L. 98–459, § 203(e)</ref>, added pars. (10) to (14).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/115/s2/d/1">Pub. L. 97–115, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “purposes” for “purpose”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/115/s2/d/2">Pub. L. 97–115, § 2(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “purposes of this chapter” for “purpose of this chapter” in provisions preceding par. (1), substituted “Comprehensive Employment and Training Act” for “Comprehensive Employment and Training Act of 1973” in par. (1), struck out par. (8) which referred to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2809/a/8">section 2809(a)(8) of this title</ref>, redesignated par. (9) as (8) and inserted references to title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 and to the Adult Education Act, and redesignated par. (10) as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478">Pub. L. 95–478</ref> added subsec. (a) and struck out similar prior provisions stating that “Federal agencies proposing to establish programs substantially related to the purposes of this chapter shall consult with the Administration on Aging prior to the establishment of such services, and Federal agencies administering such programs shall cooperate with the Administration on Aging in carrying out such services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478">Pub. L. 95–478</ref> added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc4284ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbc428500-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Education and Labor of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Education and the Workforce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc428501-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> effective on the first day of the first full program year after <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date> (<date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s506">section 506 of Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc428502-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(33)(A)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, and amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(25)(A)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>, see section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(g)(1), (2)(B)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3502">section 3502 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc428503-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> effective <date date="1994-04-04">Apr. 4, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc428504-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/175">Pub. L. 100–175</ref> effective <date date="1987-10-01">Oct. 1, 1987</date>, except not applicable with respect to any area plan submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3026/a">section 3026(a) of this title</ref> or any State plan submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3027/a">section 3027(a) of this title</ref> and approved for any fiscal year beginning before <date date="1987-11-29">Nov. 29, 1987</date>, see section 701(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/175">Pub. L. 100–175</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc428505-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/459">Pub. L. 98–459</ref> effective <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/459/s803/a">section 803(a) of Pub. L. 98–459</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc428506-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/478">Pub. L. 95–478</ref> effective at close of <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s504">section 504 of Pub. L. 95–478</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
