<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc44f6a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c"><num value="3020c">§ 3020c.</num><heading> Contracting and grant authority; private pay relationships; appropriate use of funds</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc44f6a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), this chapter shall not be construed to prevent a recipient of a grant or a contract under this chapter (other than subchapter IX) from entering into an agreement with a profitmaking organization for the recipient to provide services to individuals or entities not otherwise receiving services under this chapter, provided that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc44f6a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if funds provided under this chapter to such recipient are initially used by the recipient to pay part or all of a cost incurred by the recipient in developing and carrying out such agreement, such agreement guarantees that the cost is reimbursed to the recipient;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc44f6a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> if such agreement provides for the provision of 1 or more services, of the type provided under this chapter by or on behalf of such recipient, to an individual or entity seeking to receive such services—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc44f6a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the individuals and entities may only purchase such services at their fair market rate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc44f6a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all costs incurred by the recipient in providing such services (and not otherwise reimbursed under paragraph (1)), are reimbursed to such recipient; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc44f6a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the recipient reports the rates for providing such services under such agreement in accordance with subsection (c) and the rates are consistent with the prevailing market rate for provision of such services in the relevant geographic area as determined by the State agency or area agency on aging (as applicable); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc44f6a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any amount of payment to the recipient under the agreement that exceeds reimbursement under this subsection of the recipient’s costs is used to provide, or support the provision of, services under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc44f6a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Ensuring appropriate use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An agreement described in subsection (a) may not—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc44f6a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be made without the prior approval of the State agency (or, in the case of a grantee under subchapter X, without the prior recommendation of the Director of the Office for American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian Aging and the prior approval of the Assistant Secretary), after timely submission of all relevant documents related to the agreement including information on all costs incurred;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc44f6aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> directly or indirectly provide for, or have the effect of, paying, reimbursing, subsidizing, or otherwise compensating an individual or entity in an amount that exceeds the fair market value of the services subject to such agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc44f6ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> result in the displacement of services otherwise available to an older individual with greatest social need, an older individual with greatest economic need, or an older individual who is at risk for institutional placement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc44f6ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in any other way compromise, undermine, or be inconsistent with the objective of serving the needs of older individuals, as determined by the Assistant Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc44f6ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring and reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To ensure that any agreement described in subsection (a) complies with the requirements of this section and other applicable provisions of this chapter, the Assistant Secretary shall develop and implement uniform monitoring procedures and reporting requirements consistent with the provisions of subparagraphs (A) through (E) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3026/a/13">section 3026(a)(13) of this title</ref> in consultation with the State agencies and area agencies on aging. The Assistant Secretary shall annually prepare and submit to the chairpersons and ranking members of the appropriate committees of Congress a report analyzing all such agreements, and the costs incurred and services provided under the agreements. This report shall contain information on the number of the agreements per State, summaries of all the agreements, and information on the type of organizations participating in the agreements, types of services provided under the agreements, and the net proceeds from, and documentation of funds spent and reimbursed, under the agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc4766ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Timely reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All reimbursements made under this section shall be made in a timely manner, according to standards specified by the Assistant Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc4766af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3020c/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “cost” means an expense, including an administrative expense, incurred by a recipient in developing or carrying out an agreement described in subsection (a), whether the recipient contributed funds, staff time, or other plant, equipment, or services to meet the expense.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc4766b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/73/tII/s212">Pub. L. 89–73, title II, § 212</ref>, formerly § 213, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/tI/s102/i">Pub. L. 95–478, title I, § 102(i)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1516">92 Stat. 1516</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s606/c">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 606(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/486">95 Stat. 486</ref>; renumbered § 212, <ref href="/us/pl/97/115/s2/e/2">Pub. L. 97–115, § 2(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1596">95 Stat. 1596</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/175/tI/s107/c">Pub. L. 100–175, title I, § 107(c)</ref>, <date date="1987-11-29">Nov. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/931">101 Stat. 931</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/171/s3/a/4">Pub. L. 103–171, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-02">Dec. 2, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1990">107 Stat. 1990</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/365/tII/s207">Pub. L. 109–365, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2536">120 Stat. 2536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc4766b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc4766b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbc4766b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/89/73/s212">section 212 of Pub. L. 89–73</ref> was renumbered section 211 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3020b">section 3020b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc4766b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/365">Pub. L. 109–365</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “None of the provisions of this chapter shall be construed to prevent a recipient of a grant or a contract from entering into an agreement, subject to the approval of the State agency (or in the case of a grantee under subchapter X of this chapter, subject to the recommendation of the Director of the Office for American Indian, Alaskan Native, and Native Hawaiian Aging and the approval of the Assistant Secretary), with a profitmaking organization to carry out the provisions of this chapter and of the appropriate State plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/171">Pub. L. 103–171</ref> substituted “Director of the Office for” for “Associate Commissioner on” and “Assistant Secretary” for “Commissioner”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/175">Pub. L. 100–175</ref> inserted “(or in the case of a grantee under subchapter X of this chapter, subject to the recommendation of the Associate Commissioner on American Indian, Alaskan Native, and Native Hawaiian Aging and the approval of the Commissioner)” after “State agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> struck out provisions respecting demonstration of superiority by the organization.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc4766b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc4766b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/175">Pub. L. 100–175</ref> effective <date date="1987-10-01">Oct. 1, 1987</date>, except not applicable with respect to any area plan submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3026/a">section 3026(a) of this title</ref> or any State plan submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3027/a">section 3027(a) of this title</ref> and approved for any fiscal year beginning before <date date="1987-11-29">Nov. 29, 1987</date>, see section 701(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/175">Pub. L. 100–175</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbc4766b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective at close of <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s504">section 504 of Pub. L. 95–478</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
