<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc580901-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3030f"><num value="3030f">§ 3030f.</num><heading> Program authorized</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary shall establish and carry out a program to make grants to States under State plans approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3027">section 3027 of this title</ref> for the establishment and operation of nutrition projects for older individuals that provide—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc580902-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3030f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> on 5 or more days a week (except in a rural area where such frequency is not feasible (as defined by the Assistant Secretary by rule) and a lesser frequency is approved by the State agency) at least 1 home delivered meal per day, which may consist of hot, cold, frozen, dried, canned, or fresh foods and, as appropriate, supplemental foods, and any additional meals that the recipient of a grant or contract under this subpart elects to provide; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc580903-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3030f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> nutrition education, nutrition counseling, and other nutrition services, as appropriate, based on the needs of meal recipients.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbc580904-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/73/tIII/s336">Pub. L. 89–73, title III, § 336</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/tI/s103/b">Pub. L. 95–478, title I, § 103(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1536">92 Stat. 1536</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/375/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 102–375, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1992-09-30">Sept. 30, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1238">106 Stat. 1238</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/171/s3/a/13">Pub. L. 103–171, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-02">Dec. 2, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1990">107 Stat. 1990</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/365/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 109–365, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2548">120 Stat. 2548</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/144/s4/h">Pub. L. 114–144, § 4(h)</ref>, <date date="2016-04-19">Apr. 19, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/339">130 Stat. 339</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc580905-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc580906-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc580907-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/144">Pub. L. 114–144</ref> substituted “canned, or fresh foods and, as appropriate, supplemental foods, and any additional meals” for “canned, fresh, or supplemental foods and any additional meals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/365">Pub. L. 109–365</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Assistant Secretary shall carry out a program for making grants to States under State plans approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3027">section 3027 of this title</ref> for the establishment and operation of nutrition projects for older individuals which, 5 or more days a week (except in a rural area where such frequency is not feasible (as defined by the Assistant Secretary by regulation) and a lesser frequency is approved by the State agency), provide at least one home delivered hot, cold, frozen, dried, canned, or supplemental foods (with a satisfactory storage life) meal per day and any additional meals which the recipient of a grant or contract under this subpart may elect to provide.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/171">Pub. L. 103–171</ref> substituted “Assistant Secretary” for “Commissioner” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/375">Pub. L. 102–375</ref> inserted “(except in a rural area where such frequency is not feasible (as defined by the Commissioner by regulation) and a lesser frequency is approved by the State agency)” after “week” and struck out before period at end “, each of which assures a minimum of one-third of the daily recommended dietary allowances as established by the Food and Nutrition Board of the National Academy of Sciences-National Research Council”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc580908-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbc580909-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective at close of <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s504">section 504 of Pub. L. 95–478</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
