<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc5cc3f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b"><num value="3032b">§ 3032b.</num><heading> Older individuals’ protection from violence projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc5cc3f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Program authorized</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary shall make grants to States, area agencies on aging, nonprofit organizations, or tribal organizations to carry out the activities described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc5cc3f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A State, an area agency on aging, a nonprofit organization, or a tribal organization that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall use such grant to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc5cc3f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> support projects in local communities, involving diverse sectors of each community, to coordinate activities concerning intervention in and prevention of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, including family violence and sexual assault, against older individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc5cc3f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> develop and implement outreach programs directed toward assisting older individuals who are victims of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation (including family violence and sexual assault, against older individuals), including programs directed toward assisting the individuals in senior housing complexes, nursing homes, board and care facilities, and senior centers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc5cc3fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> expand access to family violence and sexual assault programs (including shelters, rape crisis centers, and support groups), including mental health services, safety planning and legal advocacy for older individuals and encourage the use of senior housing, hotels, or other suitable facilities or services when appropriate as emergency short-term shelters for older individuals who are the victims of elder abuse, including family violence and sexual assault; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc5cc3fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> promote research on legal, organizational, or training impediments to providing services to older individuals through shelters and other programs, such as impediments to provision of services in coordination with delivery of health care or services delivered under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc5cc3fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Preference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall give preference to a State, an area agency on aging, a nonprofit organization, or a tribal organization that has the ability to carry out the activities described in this section and subchapter XI of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc5cc3fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3032b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Assistant Secretary shall encourage each State, area agency on aging, nonprofit organization, and tribal organization that receives a grant under subsection (a) to coordinate activities provided under this section with activities provided by other area agencies on aging, tribal organizations, State adult protective service programs, private nonprofit organizations, and by other entities receiving funds under subchapter XI of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc5cc3fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/73/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 89–73, title IV, § 413</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/501/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 106–501, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2259">114 Stat. 2259</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
