<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc6d8ccd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3104"><num value="3104">§ 3104.</num><heading> Advance acquisition of land for public purposes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc6d8cce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to make grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to encourage and assist the timely acquisition of land planned to be utilized in the future for public purposes, the Secretary is authorized to make grants to States and local public bodies and agencies to assist in financing the acquisition of a fee simple estate or other interest in such land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc6d8ccf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum amount of grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amount of any grant made under this section shall not exceed the aggregate amount of reasonable interest charges on the loans or other financial obligations incurred to finance the acquisition of such land for a period not in excess of the lesser of (1) five years from the date of acquisition of such land or (2) the period of time between the date on which the land was acquired and the date its use began for the purpose for which it was acquired: <i>Provided</i>, That where all or any portion of the cost of such land is not financed through borrowings, the amount of the grant shall be computed on the basis of the aggregate amount of reasonable interest charges that the Secretary determines would have been required.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc6d8cd0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3104/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of land for public purpose within reasonable period of time</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No grant shall be made under this section unless the Secretary determines that the land will be utilized for a public purpose within a reasonable period of time and that such utilization will contribute to economy, efficiency, and the comprehensively planned development of the area. The Secretary shall in all cases require that land acquired with the assistance of a grant under this section be utilized for a public purpose within five years after the date on which a contract to make such grant is entered into, unless the Secretary determines that due to unusual circumstances a longer period of time is necessary and in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc6d8cd1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3104/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Diversion of land; repayment; interim use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No land acquired with assistance under this section shall, without approval of the Secretary, be diverted from the purpose originally approved. The Secretary shall approve no such diversion unless he finds that the diversion is in accord with the then applicable comprehensive plan for the area. In cases of a diversion of land to other than a public purpose, the Secretary may require repayment of the grant, or substitution of land of approximately equal fair market value, whichever he deems appropriate. An interim use of the land for a public or private purpose in accordance with standards prescribed by the Secretary, or approved by him, shall not constitute a diversion within the meaning of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc6d8cd2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3104/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility for other Federal loans or grant programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no project for which land is acquired with assistance under this section shall, solely as a result of such advance acquisition, be considered ineligible for the purpose of any other Federal loan or grant program, and the amount of the purchase price paid for the land by the recipient of a grant under this section may be considered an eligible cost for the purpose of such other Federal loan or grant program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc6d8cd3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/117/tVII/s704">Pub. L. 89–117, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1965-08-10">Aug. 10, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/491">79 Stat. 491</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s22/b">Pub. L. 90–19, § 22(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/26">81 Stat. 26</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/448/tVI/s603/b">Pub. L. 90–448, title VI, § 603(b)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/533">82 Stat. 533</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/470/tI/s107/c">Pub. L. 96–470, title I, § 107(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2238">94 Stat. 2238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc6d8cd4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc6d8cd5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc6d8cd6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/470">Pub. L. 96–470</ref> substituted “unless the Secretary determines that due to unusual circumstances a longer period of time is necessary and in the public interest” for “unless the Secretary (1) determines that due to unusual circumstances a longer period of time is necessary and in the public interest, and (2) reports such determination promptly to the Committees on Banking and Currency of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref> substituted “to be utilized in the future for public purposes” for “to be utilized in connection with the future construction of public works or facilities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref> changed the period from not more than the lesser of (1) five years from the date such loan was made or such financial obligation was incurred, or (2) the period of time between the date such loan was made or such financial obligation was incurred and the date construction is begun on the public work or facility, to not more than the lesser of (1) five years from the date of acquisition of such land, or (2) the period of time between the date on which the land was acquired and the date its use began for the purpose for which it was acquired, and inserted proviso requiring the amount of the grant, where all or any portion of the cost of land is not financed through borrowings, to be computed on the basis of the aggregate amount of reasonable interest charges that the Secretary determines would have been required.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref> substituted provisions requiring the Secretary to determine that the land will be utilized for a public purpose within a reasonable period of time, for provisions which required a determination that the public work or facility for which the land is to be utilized is planned to be constructed or initiated within a reasonable period of time, empowered the Secretary to extend the time if he determines that due to unusual circumstances a longer period of time is necessary and in the public interest, and required a prompt report of such determination to Congressional Committees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref> inserted provisions prohibiting diversion of land without approval of the Secretary, directing the Secretary to disapprove any diversion unless he finds that the diversion is in accord with the then applicable comprehensive plan for the area, authorizing the Secretary to accept, in cases of repayment, substitution of land of approximately equal fair market value, and stating that an interim use of land for a public or private purpose in accordance with prescribed standards shall not constitute a diversion, and eliminated provisions which required repayment if the land purchased with assistance is not utilized within five years after the agreement is entered into in connection with the construction of the public work or facility for which the land was acquired.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsecs. (a), (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
