<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc7bbd50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3272"><num value="3272">§ 3272.</num><heading> Cooperative assistance to State and other public agencies; types of assistance; private engineering services</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to provide soil surveys to assist States, their political subdivisions, soil and water conservation districts, towns, cities, planning boards and commissions, community development districts, and other public agencies in community planning and resource development for the protection and improvement of the quality of the environment, recreational development, the conservation of land and water resources, the development of multiple uses of such resources, and the control and prevention of pollution from sediment and other pollutants in areas of rapidly changing uses, including farm and nonfarm areas, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, upon the request of a State or other public agency, provide by means of such cooperative arrangements with the State or other public agency as he may deem advisable, the following assistance with respect to such areas and purposes:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc7bbd51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3272/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the making of studies and reports necessary for the classification and interpretation of kinds of soil;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc7bbd52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3272/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an intensification of the use and benefits of the National Cooperative Soil Survey;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc7bbd53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3272/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the furnishing of technical and other assistance needed for use of soil surveys; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc7bbd54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3272/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> consultation with other Federal agencies participating or assisting in the planning and development of such areas in order to assure the coordination of the work under this chapter with the related work of such other agencies.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provision by the Secretary of such assistance shall not interfere with the furnishing of engineering services by private engineering firms or consultants for on-site sampling and testing of sites or for design and construction of specific engineering works.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="idbc7bbd55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/560/s2">Pub. L. 89–560, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-09-07">Sept. 7, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/706">80 Stat. 706</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
