<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc855a95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532"><num value="3532">§ 3532.</num><heading> Establishment of Department</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc855a96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation; appointment and supervision of Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established at the seat of government an executive department to be known as the Department of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Department”). There shall be at the head of the Department a Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”), who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Department shall be administered under the supervision and direction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc855a97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> General duties of Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, among his responsibilities, advise the President with respect to Federal programs and activities relating to housing and urban development; develop and recommend to the President policies for fostering the orderly growth and development of the Nation’s urban areas; exercise leadership at the direction of the President in coordinating Federal activities affecting housing and urban development; provide technical assistance and information, including a clearinghouse service to aid State, county, town, village, or other local governments in developing solutions to community and metropolitan development problems; consult and cooperate with State Governors and State agencies, including, when appropriate, holding informal public hearings, with respect to Federal and State programs for assisting communities in developing solutions to community and metropolitan development problems and for encouraging effective regional cooperation in the planning and conduct of community and metropolitan development programs and projects; encourage comprehensive planning by the State aud <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003322">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003322"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “and”.</note> local governments with a view to coordinating Federal, State, and local urban and community development activities; encourage private enterprise to serve as large a part of the Nation’s total housing and urban development needs as it can and develop the fullest cooperation with private enterprise in achieving the objectives of the Department; and conduct continuing comprehensive studies, and make available findings, with respect to the problems of housing and urban development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc855a98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Denial or limitation of benefits of departmental programs, functions, or activities on basis of population or corporate status of community</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to deny or limit the benefits of any program, function, or activity assigned to the Department by this chapter or any other Act to any community on the basis of its population or corporate status, except as may be expressly provided by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc855a99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of housing and urban development programs in enterprise zones</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc855a9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> promote the coordination of all programs under the jurisdiction of the Secretary that are carried on within an enterprise zone designated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11501">section 11501 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc855a9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> expedite, to the greatest extent possible, the consideration of applications for programs referred to in paragraph (1) through the consolidation of forms or otherwise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc855a9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3532/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide, whenever possible, for the consolidation of periodic reports required under programs referred to in paragraph (1) into one summary report submitted at such intervals as may be designated by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc855a9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s3">Pub. L. 89–174, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/667">79 Stat. 667</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/83/s10/b">Pub. L. 90–83, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/223">81 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tVII/s705">Pub. L. 100–242, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1963">101 Stat. 1963</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc855a9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc855a9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc855aa0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/89/174">Pub. L. 89–174</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/667">79 Stat. 667</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3531">section 3531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc855aa1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 624a of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees, prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employee by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-01">Sept. 1, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc855aa2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/83">Pub. L. 90–83</ref> struck out provision for compensation of Secretary.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc855aa3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbc855aa4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Interim Appointments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nomination and appointment of Secretary of Housing and Urban Development any time after <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, and interim designation and compensation of officer of Housing and Home Finance Agency for that office upon nonentry upon the office upon expiration of first period of sixty calendar days following <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, or on earlier date specified by Executive order, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 89–174</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3531">section 3531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc855aa5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Office of Lead Based Paint Abatement and Poisoning Prevention</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/389/tII">Pub. L. 102–389, title II</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1593">106 Stat. 1593</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/389/tII">“Notwithstanding any other provision of this or any other Act with respect to any fiscal year, the Office of Lead-Based Paint Abatement and Poisoning Prevention shall be contained within the Office of the Secretary, and said Office shall have ultimate responsibility within the Department of Housing and Urban Development, except for the Secretary, for all matters related to the abatement of lead in housing, and research related to lead abatement, consistent with the responsibilities outlined for the Office in Senate Report 102–107.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/102/139/tII">Pub. L. 102–139, title II</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/753">105 Stat. 753</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/139/tII">“That there shall be established, in the Office of the Secretary, an Office of Lead Based Paint Abatement and Poisoning Prevention to be headed by a career Senior Executive Service employee who shall be responsible for all lead-based paint abatement and poisoning prevention activities (including, but not limited to, research, abatement, training regulations and policy development): <i>Provided further</i>, That such office shall be allocated a staffing level of twenty staff years.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc855aa6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Condominium and Cooperative Study and Report; Submission to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tVII/s821">Pub. L. 93–383, title VII, § 821</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/740">88 Stat. 740</ref>, authorized the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to conduct a full and complete investigation and study, and report to Congress not later than one year after <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, with respect to condominiums and cooperatives, and the problems, difficulties, and abuses or potential abuses applicable to condominium and cooperative housing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbc855aa7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc855aa8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Order of Succession</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For order of succession during any period when both Secretary and Deputy Secretary of Housing and Urban Development are unable to perform functions and duties of office of Secretary, see Ex. Ord. No. 13243, <date date="2001-12-18">Dec. 18, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 66262, listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3345">section 3345 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbc855aa9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11297. Coordination of Federal Urban Program</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11297, <date date="1966-08-11">Aug. 11, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 10765, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS our Nation has become predominantly urban in character and is confronted by serious problems arising from inherited urban decay and rapid urban growth; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS the living standards and general welfare of its people depend upon the solution of the problems of urban life; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS the Congress has provided in the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act [see Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3531">section 3531 of this title</ref>] that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the Secretary) shall “advise the President with respect to Federal programs and activities relating to housing and urban development; develop and recommend to the President policies for fostering the orderly growth and development of the Nation’s urban areas; and exercise leadership at the direction of the President in coordinating Federal activities affecting housing and urban development”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS such activities are closely interrelated with other important Federal activities affecting urban areas so that there is a need for maximum consultation and cooperation among Federal departments and agencies in their administration of programs having impact on urban areas; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS such consultation and cooperation are also essential to enable the Secretary to carry out his responsibilities under that Act to “provide technical assistance and information, including a clearinghouse service to aid State, county, town, village, or other local governments in developing solutions to community and metropolitan development problems; consult and cooperate with State Governors and State agencies . . . with respect to Federal and State programs for assisting communities in developing solutions to community and metropolitan development problems and for encouraging effective regional cooperation in the planning and conduct of community and metropolitan development programs and projects”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">NOW, THEREFORE, by virtue of the authority vested in me as President of the United States by the Constitution and laws of the United States, it is ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Functions of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</i>. (a) To assist the Secretary in carrying out his responsibilities pursuant to the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act, he shall convene, or authorize his representatives to convene, meetings at appropriate times and places of the heads, or representatives designated by them, of such Federal departments and agencies with programs affecting urban areas as he deems necessary or desirable for the following purposes:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) To provide a forum for consideration of mutual problems concerning Federal programs and activities affecting the development of urban areas and for the exchange of current information needed to achieve coordination of, and to avoid duplication in, such programs and activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) To promote cooperations among Federal departments and agencies in achieving consistent policies, practices, and procedures for administration of their programs affecting urban areas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) To consult with and obtain the advice of the Federal departments and agencies with respect to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(A) consultation and cooperation with State Governors and State and local agencies concerning Federal and State programs for assisting communities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(B) provision of technical information, a clearinghouse service, and other assistance to State and local governments in solving community and metropolitan development problems; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(C) encouragement of comprehensive planning of, and effective regional cooperation in, local urban, community, and metropolitan development activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) To identify urban development problems of particular States, metropolitan areas, or communities which require interagency or intergovernmental coordination.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary shall make arrangements with such Federal departments and agencies for working groups to consider special problems arising with respect to matters described in subsection (a) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 2. <i>Agency responsibilities</i>. The heads of Federal departments and agencies have programs which have an impact on urban areas, or representatives designated by them, shall participate in meetings convened pursuant to this Order and, to the extent permitted by law and funds available, shall furnish information, at the request of the Secretary, pertaining to programs within the responsibilities of such departments or agencies, and such additional information as will assist the Secretary in providing a clearinghouse service to aid State and local governments in developing solutions to community and metropolitan development problems.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 3. <i>Construction</i>. Nothing in this Order shall be construed as subjecting any function vested by law in, or assigned pursuant to law to, any Federal department or agency or head thereof to the authority of any other agency or officer or as abrogating or restricting any such function in any manner.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 4. <i>Administrative arrangements</i>. (a) Each executive department and agency participating under section 1 or section 2 shall furnish necessary assistance for effectuating the provisions of this Order as authorized by <ref href="/us/act/1945-05-03/s214">section 214 of the Act of May 3, 1945</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/134">59 Stat. 134</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s691">31 U.S.C. 691</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1346/b">31 U.S.C. 1346(b)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Department of Housing and Urban Development shall provide necessary administrative services pursuant to this Order.</p>
<signature>
<name>Lyndon B. Johnson.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbc87caaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13602</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13602, <date date="2012-03-15">Mar. 15, 2012</date>, 77 F.R. 16131, which established a White House Council on Strong Cities, Strong Communities, was superseded and revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13748, § 5, <date date="2016-11-16">Nov. 16, 2016</date>, 81 F.R. 83621, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s601">section 601 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
