<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc8a1565-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3537"><num value="3537">§ 3537.</num><heading> Separability</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other evidence of the intent of Congress, it is hereby declared to be the intent of Congress that if any provision of this chapter, or the application thereof to any persons or circumstances, shall be adjudged by any court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, such judgment shall not affect, impair, or invalidate the remainder of this chapter or its application to other persons and circumstances, but shall be confined in its operation to the provision of this chapter, or the application thereof to the persons and circumstances, directly involved in the controversy in which such judgment shall have been rendered.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbc8a1566-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s10">Pub. L. 89–174, § 10</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/671">79 Stat. 671</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc8a1567-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc8a1568-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc8a1569-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/89/174">Pub. L. 89–174</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/667">79 Stat. 667</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3531">section 3531 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc8a156a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 624f of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees, prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-01">Sept. 1, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
