<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc8c85df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544"><num value="3544">§ 3544.</num><heading> Preventing fraud and abuse in housing and urban development programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicant; participant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The terms “applicant” and “participant” shall have such meanings as the Secretary by regulation shall prescribe, except that such terms shall include members of an applicant’s or participant’s household, and such terms shall not include persons whose involvement is only in their official capacity, such as State or local government officials and officers of lending institutions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Public housing agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “public housing agency” means any agency described in section 3(b)(6) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/b/6">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(6)</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development” includes Indian housing programs assisted under title II <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003326">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003326"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicant and participant consent</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As a condition of initial or continuing eligibility for participation in any program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development involving initial and periodic review of an applicant’s or participant’s income, and to assure that the level of benefits provided under the program is correct, the Secretary may require that an applicant or participant—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> sign a consent form approved by the Secretary authorizing the Secretary, the public housing agency, or the owner responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits to request current or previous employers to verify salary and wage information pertinent to the applicant’s or participant’s eligibility or level of benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> sign a consent form approved by the Secretary authorizing the Secretary or the public housing agency responsible for determining eligibility or level of benefits to request a State agency charged with the administration of the State unemployment law to release wage information with respect to such applicant or participant or information regarding whether such applicant or participant is receiving, has received, or has made application for, unemployment compensation, and the amount of any such compensation being received (or to be received) by such applicant or participant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> sign a consent form approved by the Secretary authorizing the Secretary to request the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary of the Treasury to release information pursuant to section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 with respect to such applicant or participant for the sole purpose of the Secretary verifying income information pertinent to the applicant’s or participant’s eligibility or level of benefits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> only in the case of an applicant or participant that is a member of a family described in section 3(f)(2) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/f/2">42 U.S.C. 1437a(f)(2)</ref>), sign an agreement under which the applicant or participant agrees to provide to the appropriate public housing agency, or the owner responsible for determining the participant’s eligibility or level of benefits, the information required under section 3(f)(1) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/f/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(f)(1)</ref>] for the sole purpose of verifying income information pertinent to the applicant’s or participant’s eligibility or level of benefits, and comply with such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Except as provided in this subsection, this consent form shall not be used to request taxpayer return information protected by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6103">section 6103 of title 26</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to records</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicant and participant protections</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> In order to protect applicants for, and recipients of, benefits under the programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development from the improper use of information obtained pursuant to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s503/i">section 503(i) of this title</ref> from the State agency charged with the administration of the State unemployment compensation law, pursuant to section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>] from the applicant or participant, or pursuant to section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 from the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary of the Treasury, officers and employees of the Department of Housing and Urban Development and (in the case of information obtained pursuant to such section 503(i) or 3(d)(1) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>]) representatives of public housing agencies may only use such information—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc8c85ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to verify an applicant’s or participant’s eligibility for or level of benefits; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc8c85ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of an owner or public housing agency responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits, to inform such owner or public housing agency that an applicant’s or participant’s eligibility for or level of benefits is uncertain and to request such owner or public housing agency to verify such applicant’s or participant’s income information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> No Federal, State, or local agency, or public housing agency, or owner responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits receiving such information may terminate, deny, suspend, or reduce any benefits of an applicant or participant until such agency or owner has taken appropriate steps to independently verify information relating to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc8c85f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of the wages, other earnings or income, or unemployment compensation involved,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc8c85f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> whether such applicant or participant actually has (or had) access to such wages, other earnings or income, or benefits for his or her own use, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc8c85f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the period or periods when, or with respect to which, the applicant or participant actually received such wages, other earnings or income, or benefits.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Such applicant or participant shall be informed by the agency or owner of the findings made by the agency or owner on the basis of such verified information, and shall be given an opportunity to contest such findings, in the same manner as applies to other information and findings relating to eligibility factors under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any person who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains any information concerning an applicant or participant pursuant to the authority contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s503/i">section 503(i) of this title</ref>, section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], or section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 without consent or agreement, as applicable, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section or under false pretenses, or any person who knowingly and willfully discloses any such information in any manner to any individual not entitled under any law to receive it, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and fined not more than $5,000. The term “person” as used in this paragraph shall include an officer or employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, an officer or employee of any public housing agency, and any owner responsible for determining eligibility for or level of benefits (or employee thereof).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any applicant or participant affected by (i) a negligent or knowing disclosure of information referred to in this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s503/i">section 503(i) of this title</ref>, section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], or section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 about such person by an officer or employee of any public housing agency or owner (or employee thereof), which disclosure is not authorized by this section, such section 503(i), such section 3(d)(1) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], such section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix), or any regulation implementing this section, such section 503(i), such section 3(d)(1) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], or such section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix), or for which consent, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, has not been granted, or (ii) any other negligent or knowing action that is inconsistent with this section, such section 503(i), such section 3(d)(1) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 1437a(d)(1)</ref>], such section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix), or any such implementing regulation may bring a civil action for damages and such other relief as may be appropriate against any officer or employee of any public housing agency or owner (or employee thereof) responsible for any such unauthorized action. The district court of the United States in the district in which the affected applicant or participant resides, in which such unauthorized action occurred, or in which the applicant or participant alleged to be responsible for any such unauthorized action resides, shall have jurisdiction in such matters. Appropriate relief that may be ordered by such district courts shall include reasonable attorney’s fees and other litigation costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the provisions of this section shall take effect on <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Optional early implementation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At the initiative of a State or an agency of the State, and with the approval of the Secretary of Labor, the amendments made by subsection (c)(1) may be made effective in such State on any date before <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, which is more than 90 days after <date date="1988-11-07">November 7, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for State agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any State the legislature of which has not been in session for at least 30 calendar days (whether or not consecutive) between <date date="1988-11-07">November 7, 1988</date>, and <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, the amendments made by subsection (c)(1) shall take effect 30 calendar days after the first day on which such legislature is in session on or after <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc8c85fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions of release of information by third parties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An applicant or participant under any program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development may not be required or requested to consent to the release of information by third parties as a condition of initial or continuing eligibility for participation in the program unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the request for consent is made, and the information secured is maintained, in accordance with this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003327">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003327"><num>2</num> So in original. The comma probably should be “and”.</note> <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc8c85fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3544/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the consent that is requested is appropriately limited, with respect to time and information relevant and necessary to meet the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc8c85ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/628/tIX/s904">Pub. L. 100–628, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3259">102 Stat. 3259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIX/s903/a">Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 903(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3867">106 Stat. 3867</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/tIII/s3003">Pub. L. 103–66, title III, § 3003</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/338">107 Stat. 338</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s508/d/2">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 508(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2529">112 Stat. 2529</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/74/tII/s214/b">Pub. L. 106–74, title II, § 214(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-20">Oct. 20, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1074">113 Stat. 1074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc8c8600-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc8c8601-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc8c8602-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is <ref href="/us/act/1937-09-01/ch896">act Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896</ref>, as revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 93–383, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/653">88 Stat. 653</ref>. Title II of the Act, which was classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1437aa et seq.) of chapter 8 of this title, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 104–330, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4041">110 Stat. 4041</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The amendments made by subsection (c)(1), referred to in subsec. (d)(2), (3), mean the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/100/628/s904/c/1">section 904(c)(1) of Pub. L. 100–628</ref>, which enacted section 503(i) and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s504/a/2">section 504(a)(2) of this title</ref>. See Codification note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc8c8603-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/100/628/s904">section 904 of Pub. L. 100–628</ref>. Subsec. (c)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/628/s904">section 904 of Pub. L. 100–628</ref> amended sections 503 and 504 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988, and not as part of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc8c8604-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/74">Pub. L. 106–74</ref> inserted “, or the owner responsible for determining the participant’s eligibility or level of benefits,” after “appropriate public housing agency” and substituted “verifying income” for “the public housing agency verifying income”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s508/d/2/A">Pub. L. 105–276, § 508(d)(2)(A)</ref>, which directed the amendment of subsec. (b) by adding par. (4) at end, was executed by adding par. (4) after par. (3), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s508/d/2/B/i">Pub. L. 105–276, § 508(d)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted “, pursuant to section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 from the applicant or participant,” after “unemployment compensation law” and “or 3(d)(1)” after “such section 503(i)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s508/d/2/B/ii/I">Pub. L. 105–276, § 508(d)(2)(B)(ii)(I)</ref>, (II), in first sentence, inserted “, section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937,” after “503(i) of this title” and “or agreement, as applicable,” after “consent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s508/d/2/B/ii/III">Pub. L. 105–276, § 508(d)(2)(B)(ii)(III)</ref>, (IV), in first sentence, inserted “section 3(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937,” after “503(i) of this title,” and “such section 3(d)(1),” after “such section 503(i),” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/1">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(1)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/2/D">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(2)(D)</ref>, in concluding provisions, substituted “Except as provided in this subsection, this” for “This”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/2/A">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(2)(A)</ref>–(C), added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/5">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(5)</ref>, struck out “State employment” after “Access to” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/3/A/i">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(3)(A)(i)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted “or pursuant to section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 from the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary of the Treasury” after “compensation law” and “(in the case of information obtained pursuant to such section 503(i))” before “representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “owner or public housing agency” for “owner” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B)(i) to (iii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/3/B">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “wages, other earnings or income,” for “wages” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/4/A">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(4)(A)</ref>, inserted “or section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix) of title 26 without consent pursuant to subsection (b) of this section or” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s503/i">section 503(i) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/4/B/i">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(4)(B)(i)</ref>, added cl. (i) and struck out former cl. (i) which read as follows: “a negligent or knowing disclosure of information referred to in this section or in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s503/i">section 503(i) of this title</ref> about such person by an officer or employee of any public housing agency or owner (or employee thereof), which disclosure is not authorized by this section, such section 503(i), or any regulation implementing this section or such section 503(i), or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s3003/4/B/ii">Pub. L. 103–66, § 3003(4)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “such section 6103(<i>l</i>)(7)(D)(ix),” after “503(i)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc8c8605-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbc8c8606-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by title V of <ref href="/us/pl/105/276">Pub. L. 105–276</ref> effective and applicable beginning upon <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>, except as otherwise provided, with provision that Secretary may implement amendment before such date, except to extent that such amendment provides otherwise, and with savings provision, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s503">section 503 of Pub. L. 105–276</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc8c8607-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inclusion of Disaster Housing Assistance Program in Certain Fraud and Abuse Prevention Measures</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/201/tV/s501">Pub. L. 114–201, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2016-07-29">July 29, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/811">130 Stat. 811</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/201/tV/s501">“The Disaster Housing Assistance Program administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall be considered a ‘program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development’ under section 904 of the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3544">42 U.S.C. 3544</ref>) for the purpose of income verifications.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc8c8608-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Release Forms</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIX/s903/b">Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 903(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3868">106 Stat. 3868</ref>, directed Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, not later than the expiration of the 180-day period beginning <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, to develop a release form that fulfilled the requirements of this section and provided that during the period beginning <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, and ending upon implementation of the use of the new form, the benefits provided to an applicant or participant under any program of Department of Housing and Urban Development, or eligibility for such benefits, could not be terminated, denied, suspended, or reduced because of any failure to sign any form authorizing the release of information from any third party, if the applicant or participant otherwise disclosed all financial information relating to the application or recertification.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
