<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc8ed06b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3549"><num value="3549">§ 3549.</num><heading> Investigation of violations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on and after <date date="2003-02-20">February 20, 2003</date>, the Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall, in consultation with the Budget Officer, have sole authority to investigate potential or actual violations under the Anti-Deficiency Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1341">31 U.S.C. 1341</ref> et seq.) and all other statutes and regulations related to the obligation and expenditure of funds made available in this, or any other Act; shall determine whether violations exist; and shall submit final reports on violations to the Secretary, the President, the Office of Management and Budget and the Congress in accordance with applicable statutes and Office of Management and Budget circulars.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbc8ed06c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dK/tII">Pub. L. 108–7, div. K, title II</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/499">117 Stat. 499</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc8ed06d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc8ed06e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc8ed06f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2003, and also as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Resolution, 2003, and not as part of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc8ed070-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc8ed071-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Duties of Chief Financial Officer</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/115/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 109–115, div. A, title III</ref>, <date date="2005-11-30">Nov. 30, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2457">119 Stat. 2457</ref>, which provided that the Chief Financial Officer establish control of and maintain adequate systems of accounting for appropriations and other available funds as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1514">31 U.S.C. 1514</ref>, and further provided that, for purposes of funds control and Anti-Deficiency Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1341">31 U.S.C. 1341</ref> et seq.) violation determinations, the point of obligation was to be the executed agreement or contract, with certain exceptions, and that the Chief Financial Officer was to appoint and train qualified personnel to conduct investigations, establish guidelines and timeframes for such investigations, prescribe requirements for final reports on violations, and prescribe procedures for conducting investigations of, and reporting on, Anti-Deficiency Act violations, was not repeated in subsequent appropriation acts. Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dI/tII">Pub. L. 108–447, div. I, title II</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3312">118 Stat. 3312</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dG/tII">Pub. L. 108–199, div. G, title II</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/389">118 Stat. 389</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dK/tII">Pub. L. 108–7, div. K, title II</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/499">117 Stat. 499</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dG/tII">Pub. L. 108–199, div. G, title II</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/389">118 Stat. 389</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
