<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc95fc32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a"><num value="3616a">§ 3616a.</num><heading> Fair housing initiatives program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) may make grants to, or (to the extent of amounts provided in appropriation Acts) enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, State or local governments or their agencies, public or private nonprofit organizations or institutions, or other public or private entities that are formulating or carrying out programs to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices, to develop, implement, carry out, or coordinate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> programs or activities designed to obtain enforcement of the rights granted by title VIII of the Act of <date date="1968-04-11">April 11, 1968</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.] (commonly referred to as the Civil Rights Act of 1968), or by State or local laws that provide rights and remedies for alleged discriminatory housing practices that are substantially equivalent to the rights and remedies provided in such title VIII, through such appropriate judicial or administrative proceedings (including informal methods of conference, conciliation, and persuasion) as are available therefor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> education and outreach programs designed to inform the public concerning rights and obligations under the laws referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Private enforcement initiatives</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall use funds made available under this subsection to conduct, through contracts with private nonprofit fair housing enforcement organizations, investigations of violations of the rights granted under title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.], and such enforcement activities as appropriate to remedy such violations. The Secretary may enter into multiyear contracts and take such other action as is appropriate to enhance the effectiveness of such investigations and enforcement activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall use funds made available under this subsection to conduct, through contracts with private nonprofit fair housing enforcement organizations, a range of investigative and enforcement activities designed to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> carry out testing and other investigative activities in accordance with subsection (b)(1), including building the capacity for housing investigative activities in unserved or underserved areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> discover and remedy discrimination in the public and private real estate markets and real estate-related transactions, including, but not limited to, the making or purchasing of loans or the provision of other financial assistance sales and rentals of housing and housing advertising;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> carry out special projects, including the development of prototypes to respond to new or sophisticated forms of discrimination against persons protected under title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> provide technical assistance to local fair housing organizations, and assist in the formation and development of new fair housing organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> provide funds for the costs and expenses of litigation, including expert witness fees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding of fair housing organizations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall use funds made available under this section to enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with qualified fair housing enforcement organizations, other private nonprofit fair housing enforcement organizations, and nonprofit groups organizing to build their capacity to provide fair housing enforcement, for the purpose of supporting the continued development or implementation of initiatives which enforce the rights granted under title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.], as amended. Contracts or cooperative agreements may not provide more than 50 percent of the operating budget of the recipient organization for any one year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Capacity enhancement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall use funds made available under this section to help establish, organize, and build the capacity of fair housing enforcement organizations, particularly in those areas of the country which are currently underserved by fair housing enforcement organizations as well as those areas where large concentrations of protected classes exist. For purposes of meeting the objectives of this paragraph, the Secretary may enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with qualified fair housing enforcement organizations. The Secretary shall establish annual goals which reflect the national need for private fair housing enforcement organizations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Education and outreach</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, through contracts with one or more qualified fair housing enforcement organizations, other fair housing enforcement organizations, and other nonprofit organizations representing groups of persons protected under title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.], shall establish a national education and outreach program. The national program shall be designed to provide a centralized, coordinated effort for the development and dissemination of fair housing media products, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> public service announcements, both audio and video;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> television, radio and print advertisements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> posters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbc95fc46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> pamphlets and brochures.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall designate a portion of the amounts provided in subsection (g)(4) for a national program specifically for activities related to the annual national fair housing month. The Secretary shall encourage cooperation with real estate industry organizations in the national education and outreach program. The Secretary shall also encourage the dissemination of educational information and technical assistance to support compliance with the housing adaptability and accessibility guidelines contained in the Fair Housing Act Amendments of 1988.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional and local programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, through contracts with fair housing enforcement organizations, other nonprofit organizations representing groups of persons protected under title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.], State and local agencies certified by the Secretary under section 810(f) of the Fair Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3610/f">42 U.S.C. 3610(f)</ref>], or other public or private entities that are formulating or carrying out programs to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices, shall establish or support education and outreach programs at the regional and local levels.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Community-based programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide funding to fair housing organizations and other nonprofit organizations representing groups of persons protected under title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968, or other public or private entities that are formulating or carrying out programs to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices, to support community-based education and outreach activities, including school, church, and community presentations, conferences, and other educational activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Program administration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not less than 30 days before providing a grant or entering into any contract or cooperative agreement to carry out activities authorized by this section, the Secretary shall submit notification of such proposed grant, contract, or cooperative agreement (including a description of the geographical distribution of such contracts) to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1071/d">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1071(d)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/720">109 Stat. 720</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall, for use during the demonstration authorized in this section, establish guidelines for testing activities funded under the private enforcement initiative of the fair housing initiatives program. The purpose of such guidelines shall be to ensure that investigations in support of fair housing enforcement efforts described in subsection (a)(1) shall develop credible and objective evidence of discriminatory housing practices. Such guidelines shall apply only to activities funded under this section, shall not be construed to limit or otherwise restrict the use of facts secured through testing not funded under this section in any legal proceeding under Federal fair housing laws, and shall not be used to restrict individuals or entities, including those participating in the fair housing initiatives program, from pursuing any right or remedy guaranteed by Federal law. Not later than 6 months after the end of the demonstration period authorized in this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003332">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003332"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the Secretary shall submit to Congress the evaluation of the Secretary of the effectiveness of such guidelines in achieving the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Such regulations shall include provisions governing applications for assistance under this section, and shall require each such application to contain—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a description of the assisted activities proposed to be undertaken by the applicant, together with the estimated costs and schedule for completion of such activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of the experience of the applicant in formulating or carrying out programs to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> available information, including studies made by or available to the applicant, indicating the nature and extent of discriminatory housing practices occurring in the general location where the applicant proposes to conduct its assisted activities, and the relationship of such activities to such practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an estimate of such other public or private resources as may be available to assist the proposed activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a description of proposed procedures to be used by the applicant for monitoring conduct and evaluating results of the proposed activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any additional information required by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Regulations issued under this subsection shall not become effective prior to the expiration of 90 days after the Secretary transmits such regulations, in the form such regulations are intended to be published, to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary shall not obligate or expend any amount under this section before the effective date of the regulations required under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003333">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003333"><num>2</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> $21,000,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $26,000,000 for fiscal year 1994, of which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> not less than $3,820,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $8,500,000 for fiscal year 1994 shall be for private enforcement initiatives authorized under subsection (b), divided equally between activities specified under subsection (b)(1) and those specified under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not less than $2,230,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $8,500,000 for fiscal year 1994 shall be for qualified fair housing enforcement organizations authorized under subsection (c)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> not less than $2,010,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $4,000,000 for fiscal year 1994 shall be for the creation of new fair housing enforcement organizations authorized under subsection (c)(2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> not less than $2,540,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $5,000,000 for fiscal year 1994 shall be for education and outreach programs authorized under subsection (d), to be divided equally between activities specified under subsection (d)(1) and those specified under subsections (d)(2) and (d)(3).</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any amount appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified fair housing enforcement organization</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “qualified fair housing enforcement organization” means any organization that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is organized as a private, tax-exempt, nonprofit, charitable organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has at least 2 years experience in complaint intake, complaint investigation, testing for fair housing violations and enforcement of meritorious claims; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is engaged in all the activities listed in paragraph (1)(B) at the time of application for assistance under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">An organization which is not solely engaged in fair housing enforcement activities may qualify as a qualified fair housing enforcement organization, provided that the organization is actively engaged in each of the activities listed in subparagraph (B).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc95fc62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The term “fair housing enforcement organization” means any organization that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> meets the requirements specified in paragraph (1)(A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is currently engaged in the activities specified in paragraph (1)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> upon the receipt of funds under this section will become engaged in all of the activities specified in paragraph (1)(B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> for purposes of funding under subsection (b), has at least 1 year of experience in the activities specified in paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">None of the funds authorized under this section may be used by the Secretary for purposes of settling claims, satisfying judgments or fulfilling court orders in any litigation action involving either the Department or housing providers funded by the Department. None of the funds authorized under this section may be used by the Department for administrative costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc95fc68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the close of each fiscal year in which assistance under this section is furnished, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Congress a comprehensive report which shall contain—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a description of the progress made in accomplishing the objectives of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a summary of all the private enforcement activities carried out under this section and the use of such funds during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a list of all fair housing enforcement organizations funded under this section during the preceding fiscal year, identified on a State-by-State basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a summary of all education and outreach activities funded under this section and the use of such funds during the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc95fc6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s3616a/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> any findings, conclusions, or recommendations of the Secretary as a result of the funded activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc95fc6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/242/tV/s561">Pub. L. 100–242, title V, § 561</ref>, <date date="1988-02-05">Feb. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1942">101 Stat. 1942</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tIX/s953">Pub. L. 101–625, title IX, § 953</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4419">104 Stat. 4419</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIX/s905/b">Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 905(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3869">106 Stat. 3869</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1071/d">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1071(d)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/720">109 Stat. 720</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc95fc6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc95fc70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc95fc71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Civil Rights Act of 1968, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (b)(1), (2)(C), (c)(1), and (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/284">Pub. L. 90–284</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/73">82 Stat. 73</ref>. Title VIII of the Act, known as the Fair Housing Act, is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 3601 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of these Acts to the Code, see Short Title notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">section 3601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fair Housing Act Amendments of 1988, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), probably means the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/430">Pub. L. 100–430</ref>, <date date="1988-09-13">Sept. 13, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1619">102 Stat. 1619</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">section 3601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The phrase “Not later than 6 months after the end of the demonstration period authorized in this section”, referred to in subsec. (f)(2), probably means the end of the demonstration period pursuant to former subsec. (e) of this section, which provided that such period was to end <date date="1992-09-30">Sept. 30, 1992</date>. However, subsec. (e) was redesignated (h) and struck out by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref>. See 1992 Amendment notes below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc95fc72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987, and not as part of title VIII of <ref href="/us/pl/90/284">Pub. L. 90–284</ref>, known as the Fair Housing Act, which comprises this subchapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3616">section 3616 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc95fc73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “The Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives a quarterly report that summarizes the activities funded under this section and describes the geographical distribution of grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements funded under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsecs. (b) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s905/b/1">Pub. L. 102–550, § 905(b)(1)</ref>, (2), added subsecs. (b) to (d) and redesignated former subsecs. (b) and (c) as (e) and (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s905/b/1">Pub. L. 102–550, § 905(b)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (d) as (g) and, in first sentence, substituted “$21,000,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $26,000,000 for fiscal year 1994, of which—” and pars. (1) to (4) for “including any program evaluations, $6,000,000 for fiscal year 1991 and $6,300,000 for fiscal year 1992, of which not more than $3,000,000 in each year shall be for the private enforcement initiative demonstration.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s905/b/4">Pub. L. 102–550, § 905(b)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (h) and struck out former subsec. (h) which provided that the demonstration period authorized by this section would end <date date="1992-09-30">Sept. 30, 1992</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s905/b/1">Pub. L. 102–550, § 905(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s905/b/4">Pub. L. 102–550, § 905(b)(4)</ref>, added subsecs. (i) and (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/s953/a">Pub. L. 101–625, § 953(a)</ref>, amended first sentence generally. Prior to amendment, first sentence read as follows: “There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section, including any program evaluations, $5,000,000 for fiscal year 1988, and $5,000,000 for fiscal year 1989, of which not more than $3,000,000 in each year shall be for the private enforcement initiative demonstration.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/s953/b">Pub. L. 101–625, § 953(b)</ref>, substituted “1992” for “1989”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc95fc74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbc95fc75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives abolished and replaced by Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred from Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc95fc76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIX/s905/a">Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 905(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3868">106 Stat. 3868</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/550/tIX/s905/a">
<inline>“The Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in the past half decade, there have been major legislative and administrative changes in Federal fair housing and fair lending laws and substantial improvements in the Nation’s understanding of discrimination in the housing markets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in response to evidence of continuing housing discrimination, the Congress passed the Fair Housing Act Amendments of 1988 [probably should be the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/430">Pub. L. 100–430</ref>, see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">section 3601 of this title</ref>], to provide for more effective enforcement of fair housing rights through judicial and administrative avenues and to expand the number of protected classes covered under Federal fair housing laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> in the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery and Enforcement Act of 1989 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/73">Pub. L. 101–73</ref>, see Short Title of 1989 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</ref>], the Congress expanded the disclosure provisions under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act [probably should be the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975; <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2801">12 U.S.C. 2801</ref> et seq.] to provide increased information on the mortgage lending patterns of financial institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> in the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.], the Congress provided a clear and comprehensive national mandate for the elimination of discrimination against individuals with disabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> in 1991, data collected under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act disclosed evidence of pervasive discrimination in the Nation’s mortgage lending markets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the Housing Discrimination Survey, released by the Department of Housing and Urban Development in 1991, found that Hispanic and African-American homeseekers experience some form of discrimination in at least half of their encounters with sales and rental agents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the Fair Housing Initiatives Program should be revised and expanded to reflect the significant changes in the fair housing and fair lending area that have taken place since the Program’s initial authorization in the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 [<ref href="/us/pl/100/242">Pub. L. 100–242</ref>, see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> continuing educational efforts by the real estate industry are a useful way to increase understanding by the public of their fair housing rights and responsibilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> the proven efficacy of private nonprofit fair housing enforcement organizations and community-based efforts makes support for these organizations a necessary component of the fair housing enforcement system.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
