<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc9f98af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002"><num value="4002">§ 4002.</num><heading> Additional Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc9f98b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> annual losses throughout the Nation from floods and mudslides are increasing at an alarming rate, largely as a result of the accelerating development of, and concentration of population in, areas of flood and mudslide hazards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the availability of Federal loans, grants, guaranties, insurance, and other forms of financial assistance are often determining factors in the utilization of land and the location and construction of public and of private industrial, commercial, and residential facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> property acquired or constructed with grants or other Federal assistance may be exposed to risk of loss through floods, thus frustrating the purpose for which such assistance was extended;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Federal instrumentalities insure or otherwise provide financial protection to banking and credit institutions whose assets include a substantial number of mortgage loans and other indebtedness secured by property exposed to loss and damage from floods and mudslides;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the Nation cannot afford the tragic losses of life caused annually by flood occurrences, nor the increasing losses of property suffered by flood victims, most of whom are still inadequately compensated despite the provision of costly disaster relief benefits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> it is in the public interest for persons already living in flood-prone areas to have both an opportunity to purchase flood insurance and access to more adequate limits of coverage, so that they will be indemnified, for their losses in the event of future flood disasters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc9f98b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The purpose of this Act, therefore, is to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> substantially increase the limits of coverage authorized under the national flood insurance program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provide for the expeditious identification of, and the dissemination of information concerning, flood-prone areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> require States or local communities, as a condition of future Federal financial assistance, to participate in the flood insurance program and to adopt adequate flood plan ordinances with effective enforcement provisions consistent with Federal standards to reduce or avoid future flood losses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc9f98bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4002/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> require the purchase of flood insurance by property owners who are being assisted by Federal programs or by federally supervised, regulated, or insured agencies or institutions in the acquisition or improvement of land or facilities located or to be located in identified areas having special flood hazards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc9f98bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/234/s2">Pub. L. 93–234, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/975">87 Stat. 975</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc9f98bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc9f98be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc9f98bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (b), means <ref href="/us/pl/93/234">Pub. L. 93–234</ref>, <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/975">87 Stat. 975</ref>, known as the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1973 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc9f98c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, and not as part of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
