<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbca1e312-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a"><num value="4012a">§ 4012a.</num><heading> Flood insurance purchase and compliance requirements and escrow accounts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e313-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount and term of coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After the expiration of sixty days following <date date="1973-12-31">December 31, 1973</date>, no Federal officer or agency shall approve any financial assistance for acquisition or construction purposes for use in any area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which the sale of flood insurance has been made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.], unless the building or mobile home and any personal property to which such financial assistance relates is covered by flood insurance in an amount at least equal to its development or project cost (less estimated land cost) or to the maximum limit of coverage made available with respect to the particular type of property under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, whichever is less: <i>Provided</i>, That if the financial assistance provided is in the form of a loan or an insurance or guaranty of a loan, the amount of flood insurance required need not exceed the outstanding principal balance of the loan and need not be required beyond the term of the loan. The requirement of maintaining flood insurance shall apply during the life of the property, regardless of transfer of ownership of such property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e314-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement for mortgage loans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e315-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulated lending institutions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each Federal entity for lending regulation (after consultation and coordination with the Financial Institutions Examination Council established under the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3301">12 U.S.C. 3301</ref> et seq.]) shall by regulation direct regulated lending institutions—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e316-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not to make, increase, extend, or renew any loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located or to be located in an area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance has been made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.], unless the building or mobile home and any personal property securing such loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance in an amount at least equal to the outstanding principal balance of the loan or the maximum limit of coverage made available under the Act with respect to the particular type of property, whichever is less; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e317-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to accept private flood insurance as satisfaction of the flood insurance coverage requirement under subparagraph (A) if the coverage provided by such private flood insurance meets the requirements for coverage under such subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e318-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal agency lenders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A Federal agency lender may not make, increase, extend, or renew any loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located or to be located in an area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance has been made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, unless the building or mobile home and any personal property securing such loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance in the amount provided in paragraph (1)(A). Each Federal agency lender shall accept private flood insurance as satisfaction of the flood insurance coverage requirement under the preceding sentence if the flood insurance coverage provided by such private flood insurance meets the requirements for coverage under such sentence. Each Federal agency lender shall issue any regulations necessary to carry out this paragraph. Such regulations shall be consistent with and substantially identical to the regulations issued under paragraph (1)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e319-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Government-sponsored enterprises for housing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall implement procedures reasonably designed to ensure that, for any loan that is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e31a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located in an area that has been identified, at the time of the origination of the loan or at any time during the term of the loan, by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance is available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e31b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> purchased by such entity,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the building or mobile home and any personal property securing the loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance in the amount provided in paragraph (1)(A). The Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall accept private flood insurance as satisfaction of the flood insurance coverage requirement under paragraph (1)(A) if the flood insurance coverage provided by such private flood insurance meets the requirements for coverage under such paragraph and any requirements established by the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, respectively, relating to the financial solvency, strength, or claims-paying ability of private insurance companies from which the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation will accept private flood insurance.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e31c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e31d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall apply on <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e31e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> New coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Paragraphs (2) and (3) shall apply only with respect to any loan made, increased, extended, or renewed after the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>. Paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to any loan made, increased, extended, or renewed by any lender supervised by the Farm Credit Administration only after the expiration of the period under this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e31f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Continued effect of regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the regulations to carry out paragraph (1), as in effect immediately before <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>, shall continue to apply until the regulations issued to carry out paragraph (1) as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s522/a">section 522(a) of Public Law 103–325</ref> take effect.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e320-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to supersede or limit the authority of a Federal entity for lending regulation, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, a Federal agency lender, the Federal National Mortgage Association, or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation to establish requirements relating to the financial solvency, strength, or claims-paying ability of private insurance companies from which the entity or agency will accept private flood insurance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e321-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e322-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each lender shall disclose to a borrower that is subject to this subsection that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e323-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> flood insurance is available from private insurance companies that issue standard flood insurance policies on behalf of the national flood insurance program or directly from the national flood insurance program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e324-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> flood insurance that provides the same level of coverage as a standard flood insurance policy under the national flood insurance program may be available from a private insurance company that issues policies on behalf of the company; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e325-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/6/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the borrower is encouraged to compare the flood insurance coverage, deductibles, exclusions, conditions and premiums associated with flood insurance policies issued on behalf of the national flood insurance program and policies issued on behalf of private insurance companies and to direct inquiries regarding the availability, cost, and comparisons of flood insurance coverage to an insurance agent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e326-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as affecting or otherwise limiting the authority of a Federal entity for lending regulation to approve any disclosure made by a regulated lending institution for purposes of complying with subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e327-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Private flood insurance defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “private flood insurance” means an insurance policy that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e328-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> is issued by an insurance company that is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e329-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> licensed, admitted, or otherwise approved to engage in the business of insurance in the State or jurisdiction in which the insured building is located, by the insurance regulator of that State or jurisdiction; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e32a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of a policy of difference in conditions, multiple peril, all risk, or other blanket coverage insuring nonresidential commercial property, is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003335">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003335"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “is” probably should not appear.</note> recognized, or not disapproved, as a surplus lines insurer by the insurance regulator of the State or jurisdiction where the property to be insured is located;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e32b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provides flood insurance coverage which is at least as broad as the coverage provided under a standard flood insurance policy under the national flood insurance program, including when considering deductibles, exclusions, and conditions offered by the insurer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e32c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e32d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> a requirement for the insurer to give 45 days’ written notice of cancellation or non-renewal of flood insurance coverage to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e32e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the insured; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e32f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the regulated lending institution or Federal agency lender;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e330-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> information about the availability of flood insurance coverage under the national flood insurance program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e331-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a mortgage interest clause similar to the clause contained in a standard flood insurance policy under the national flood insurance program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e332-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> a provision requiring an insured to file suit not later than 1 year after date of a written denial of all or part of a claim under the policy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e333-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/b/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> contains cancellation provisions that are as restrictive as the provisions contained in a standard flood insurance policy under the national flood insurance program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e334-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions to purchase requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e335-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> State-owned property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, flood insurance shall not be required on any State-owned property that is covered under an adequate State policy of self-insurance satisfactory to the Administrator. The Administrator shall publish and periodically revise the list of States to which this subsection applies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e336-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Small loans</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to any loan having—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e337-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an original outstanding principal balance of $5,000 or less; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e338-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a repayment term of 1 year or less.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e339-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Detached structures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, flood insurance shall not be required, in the case of any residential property, for any structure that is a part of such property but is detached from the primary residential structure of such property and does not serve as a residence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e33a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Escrow of flood insurance payments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e33b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulated lending institutions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e33c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal entities responsible for lending regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each Federal entity for lending regulation (after consultation and coordination with the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council) shall, by regulation, direct that all premiums and fees for flood insurance under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, for residential improved real estate or a mobile home, shall be paid to the regulated lending institution or servicer for any loan secured by the residential improved real estate or mobile home, with the same frequency as payments on the loan are made, for the duration of the loan. Except as provided in subparagraph (B), upon receipt of any premiums or fees, the regulated lending institution or servicer shall deposit such premiums and fees in an escrow account on behalf of the borrower. Upon receipt of a notice from the Administrator or the provider of the flood insurance that insurance premiums are due, the premiums deposited in the escrow account shall be paid to the provider of the flood insurance.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e33d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as may be required under applicable State law, a Federal entity for lending regulation may not direct or require a regulated lending institution to deposit premiums or fees for flood insurance under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 in an escrow account on behalf of a borrower under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e33e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e33f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the regulated lending institution has total assets of less than $1,000,000,000; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e340-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> on or before <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, the regulated lending institution—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbca1e341-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/i/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> in the case of a loan secured by residential improved real estate or a mobile home, was not required under Federal or State law to deposit taxes, insurance premiums, fees, or any other charges in an escrow account for the entire term of the loan; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbca1e342-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/i/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> did not have a policy of consistently and uniformly requiring the deposit of taxes, insurance premiums, fees, or any other charges in an escrow account for loans secured by residential improved real estate or a mobile home; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e343-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> in the case of a loan that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e344-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is in a junior or subordinate position to a senior lien secured by the same residential improved real estate or mobile home for which flood insurance is being provided at the time of the origination of the loan;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e345-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> is secured by residential improved real estate or a mobile home that is part of a condominium, cooperative, or other project development, if the residential improved real estate or mobile home is covered by a flood insurance policy that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbca1e346-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> meets the requirements that the regulated lending institution is required to enforce under subsection (b)(1);</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbca1e347-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> is provided by the condominium association, cooperative, homeowners association, or other applicable group; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbca1e348-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> the premium for which is paid by the condominium association, cooperative, homeowners association, or other applicable group as a common expense;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e349-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> is secured by residential improved real estate or a mobile home that is used as collateral for a business purpose;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e34a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> is a home equity line of credit;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e34b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> is a nonperforming loan; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbca1e34c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/B/ii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> has a term of not longer than 12 months.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e34d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal agency lenders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each Federal agency lender shall by regulation require and provide for escrow and payment of any flood insurance premiums and fees relating to residential improved real estate and mobile homes securing loans made by the Federal agency lender under the circumstances and in the manner provided under paragraph (1). Any regulations issued under this paragraph shall be consistent with and substantially identical to the regulations issued under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e34e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of RESPA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Escrow accounts established pursuant to this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of section 10 of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2609">12 U.S.C. 2609</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e34f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> “Residential improved real estate” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “residential improved real estate” means improved real estate for which the improvement is a residential building.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e350-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection shall apply only with respect to any loan made, increased, extended, or renewed after the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e351-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Placement of flood insurance by lender</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e352-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification to borrower of lack of coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, at the time of origination or at any time during the term of a loan secured by improved real estate or by a mobile home located in an area that has been identified by the Administrator (at the time of the origination of the loan or at any time during the term of the loan) as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance is available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.], the lender or servicer for the loan determines that the building or mobile home and any personal property securing the loan is not covered by flood insurance or is covered by such insurance in an amount less than the amount required for the property pursuant to paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (b), the lender or servicer shall notify the borrower under the loan that the borrower should obtain, at the borrower’s expense, an amount of flood insurance for the building or mobile home and such personal property that is not less than the amount under subsection (b)(1), for the term of the loan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e353-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchase of coverage on behalf of borrower</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the borrower fails to purchase such flood insurance within 45 days after notification under paragraph (1), the lender or servicer for the loan shall purchase the insurance on behalf of the borrower and may charge the borrower for the cost of premiums and fees incurred by the lender or servicer for the loan in purchasing the insurance, including premiums or fees incurred for coverage beginning on the date on which flood insurance coverage lapsed or did not provide a sufficient coverage amount.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e354-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of force-placed insurance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 30 days of receipt by the lender or servicer of a confirmation of a borrower’s existing flood insurance coverage, the lender or servicer shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e355-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> terminate any insurance purchased by the lender or servicer under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e356-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> refund to the borrower all premiums paid by the borrower for any insurance purchased by the lender or servicer under paragraph (2) during any period during which the borrower’s flood insurance coverage and the insurance coverage purchased by the lender or servicer were each in effect, and any related fees charged to the borrower with respect to the insurance purchased by the lender or servicer during such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e357-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Sufficiency of demonstration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of confirming a borrower’s existing flood insurance coverage, a lender or servicer for a loan shall accept from the borrower an insurance policy declarations page that includes the existing flood insurance policy number and the identity of, and contact information for, the insurance company or agent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e358-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of determination regarding required purchase</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e359-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The borrower and lender for a loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home may jointly request the Administrator to review a determination of whether the building or mobile home is located in an area having special flood hazards. Such request shall be supported by technical information relating to the improved real estate or mobile home. Not later than 45 days after the Administrator receives the request, the Administrator shall review the determination and provide to the borrower and the lender with a letter stating whether or not the building or mobile home is in an area having special flood hazards. The determination of the Administrator shall be final.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e35a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any person to whom a borrower provides a letter issued by the Administrator pursuant to subparagraph (A), stating that the building or mobile home securing the loan of the borrower is not in an area having special flood hazards, shall have no obligation under this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003336">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003336"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> to require the purchase of flood insurance for such building or mobile home during the period determined by the Administrator, which shall be specified in the letter and shall begin on the date on which such letter is provided.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e35b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of failure to respond</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a request under subparagraph (A) is made in connection with the origination of a loan and the Administrator fails to provide a letter under subparagraph (A) before the later of (i) the expiration of the 45-day period under such subparagraph, or (ii) the closing of the loan, no person shall have an obligation under this title <sup>2</sup> to require the purchase of flood insurance for the building or mobile home securing the loan until such letter is provided.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e35c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection shall apply to all loans outstanding on or after <date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e35d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil monetary penalties for failure to require flood insurance or notify</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e35e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil monetary penalties against regulated lenders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any regulated lending institution that is found to have a pattern or practice of committing violations under paragraph (2) shall be assessed a civil penalty by the appropriate Federal entity for lending regulation in the amount provided under paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e35f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Lender violations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The violations referred to in paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e360-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> making, increasing, extending, or renewing loans in violation of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e361-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (b) of this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e362-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the escrow requirements under subsection (d) of this section; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbca1e363-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the notice requirements under section 1364 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104a">42 U.S.C. 4104a</ref>]; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca1e364-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> failure to provide notice or purchase flood insurance coverage in violation of subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e365-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil monetary penalties against GSE’s</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e366-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation is found by the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to have a pattern or practice of purchasing loans in violation of the procedures established pursuant to subsection (b)(3), the Director of such Office <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003337">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003337"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “Agency”.</note> shall assess a civil penalty against such enterprise in the amount provided under paragraph (5) of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e367-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> “Enterprise” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, the term “enterprise” means the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e368-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice and hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A penalty under this subsection may be issued only after notice and an opportunity for a hearing on the record.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e369-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A civil monetary penalty under this subsection may not exceed $2,000 for each violation under paragraph (2) or paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca1e36a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Lender compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any State or local law, for purposes of this subsection, any regulated lending institution that purchases flood insurance or renews a contract for flood insurance on behalf of or as an agent of a borrower of a loan for which flood insurance is required shall be considered to have complied with the regulations issued under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca4536b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of transfer on liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any sale or other transfer of a loan by a regulated lending institution that has committed a violation under paragraph (1), that occurs subsequent to the violation, shall not affect the liability of the transferring lender with respect to any penalty under this subsection. A lender shall not be liable for any violations relating to a loan committed by another regulated lending institution that previously held the loan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca4536c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposit of penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any penalties collected under this subsection shall be paid into the National Flood Mitigation Fund under section 1367 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104d">42 U.S.C. 4104d</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca4536d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any penalty under this subsection shall be in addition to any civil remedy or criminal penalty otherwise available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca4536e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/f/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Statute of limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No penalty may be imposed under this subsection after the expiration of the 4-year period beginning on the date of the occurrence of the violation for which the penalty is authorized under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca4536f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Other actions to remedy pattern of noncompliance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca45370-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Federal entities for lending regulation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A Federal entity for lending regulation may require a regulated lending institution to take such remedial actions as are necessary to ensure that the regulated lending institution complies with the requirements of the national flood insurance program if the Federal agency for lending regulation makes a determination under paragraph (2) regarding the regulated lending institution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca45371-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of violations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A determination under this paragraph shall be a finding that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca45372-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the regulated lending institution has engaged in a pattern and practice of noncompliance in violation of the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (b), (d), or (e) or the notice requirements under section 1364 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104a">42 U.S.C. 4104a</ref>]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca45373-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the regulated lending institution has not demonstrated measurable improvement in compliance despite the assessment of civil monetary penalties under subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbca45374-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Fee for determining location</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other Federal or State law, any person who makes a loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home or any servicer for such a loan may charge a reasonable fee for the costs of determining whether the building or mobile home securing the loan is located in an area having special flood hazards, but only in accordance with the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca45375-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Borrower fee</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The borrower under such a loan may be charged the fee, but only if the determination—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca45376-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is made pursuant to the making, increasing, extending, or renewing of the loan that is initiated by the borrower;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca45377-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is made pursuant to a revision or updating under section 1360(f) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003338">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003338"><num>4</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968”.</note> [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4101/f">42 U.S.C. 4101(f)</ref>] of the floodplain areas and flood-risk zones or publication of a notice or compendia under subsection (h) or (i) of section 1360 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003338">4</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4101/h">42 U.S.C. 4101(h)</ref>, (i)] that affects the area in which the improved real estate or mobile home securing the loan is located or that, in the determination of the Administrator, may reasonably be considered to require a determination under this subsection; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbca45378-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> results in the purchase of flood insurance coverage pursuant to the requirement under subsection (e)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbca45379-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchaser or transferee fee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The purchaser or transferee of such a loan may be charged the fee in the case of sale or transfer of the loan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbca4537a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/234/tI/s102">Pub. L. 93–234, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/978">87 Stat. 978</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 451(e)(1)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1229">97 Stat. 1229</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tV">Pub. L. 103–325, title V</ref>, §§ 522–526, 531, 582(c), <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2257-2262">108 Stat. 2257–2262</ref>, 2267, 2287; <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/dA/tI/s1161/e">Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I, § 1161(e)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2780">122 Stat. 2780</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II</ref>, §§ 100208, 100209(a), 100238(a)(1), 100239(a), 100244(a), <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/919">126 Stat. 919</ref>, 920, 958, 966; <ref href="/us/pl/112/281/s1">Pub. L. 112–281, § 1</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2485">126 Stat. 2485</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/89">Pub. L. 113–89</ref>, §§ 13(a), 25(a), <date date="2014-03-21">Mar. 21, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1026">128 Stat. 1026</ref>, 1030.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbca4537b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbca4537c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbca4537d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), (d)(1), and (e)(1), and the Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is title XIII of <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/572">82 Stat. 572</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter (§ 4001 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), probably means the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/630/tX">Pub. L. 95–630, title X</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3694">92 Stat. 3694</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 34 (§ 3301 et seq.) of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3301">section 3301 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s522/a">Section 522(a) of Public Law 103–325</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(4)(C), was in original “section 522(a) of such Act”, which generally amended subsec. (b) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in subsec. (e)(5)(B), (C), means title I of <ref href="/us/pl/93/234">Pub. L. 93–234</ref>, <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/977">87 Stat. 977</ref>, which enacted this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104">section 4104 of this title</ref> and amended sections 4001, 4013 to 4016, 4026, 4054, 4056, and 4121 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbca4537e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, and not as part of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbca4537f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s13/a">Pub. L. 113–89, § 13(a)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s25/a/1">Pub. L. 113–89, § 25(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “subparagraph (B)” for “subparagraph (C)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s25/a/2">Pub. L. 113–89, § 25(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “under subparagraph (A)—” for “under subparagraph (A) or (B), if—” in introductory provisions, designated existing provisions as cl. (i) and inserted “if—” after cl. (i) designation, redesignated former cls. (i) and (ii) as subcls. (I) and (II), respectively, of cl. (i), redesignated former subcls. (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively, of subcl. (II), and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (d)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/281">Pub. L. 112–281</ref> inserted “residential” before “improved real estate” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100239/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100239(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “; and” for period at end, substituted “institutions—” for “institutions”, inserted subpar. (A) designation before “not to make”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100239/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100239(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(A)” for “paragraph (1)” in two places and inserted “Each Federal agency lender shall accept private flood insurance as satisfaction of the flood insurance coverage requirement under the preceding sentence if the flood insurance coverage provided by such private flood insurance meets the requirements for coverage under such sentence.” after first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100239/a/3">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100239(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(A). The Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall accept private flood insurance as satisfaction of the flood insurance coverage requirement under paragraph (1)(A) if the flood insurance coverage provided by such private flood insurance meets the requirements for coverage under such paragraph and any requirements established by the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, respectively, relating to the financial solvency, strength, or claims-paying ability of private insurance companies from which the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation will accept private flood insurance.” for “paragraph (1).” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100239/a/4">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100239(a)(4)</ref>, added pars. (5) to (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100209/a">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100209(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Each Federal entity for lending regulation (after consultation and coordination with the Financial Institutions Examination Council) shall by regulation require that, if a regulated lending institution requires the escrowing of taxes, insurance premiums, fees, or any other charges for a loan secured by residential improved real estate or a mobile home, then all premiums and fees for flood insurance under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 for the real estate or mobile home shall be paid to the regulated lending institution or other servicer for the loan in a manner sufficient to make payments as due for the duration of the loan. Upon receipt of the premiums, the regulated lending institution or servicer of the loan shall deposit the premiums in an escrow account on behalf of the borrower. Upon receipt of a notice from the Administrator or the provider of the insurance that insurance premiums are due, the regulated lending institution or servicer shall pay from the escrow account to the provider of the insurance the amount of insurance premiums owed.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100244/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100244(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “purchasing the insurance, including premiums or fees incurred for coverage beginning on the date on which flood insurance coverage lapsed or did not provide a sufficient coverage amount” for “purchasing the insurance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100244/a/3">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100244(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100244/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100244(a)(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (4) and redesignated former pars. (3) and (4) as (5) and (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100208">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100208</ref>, substituted “$2,000” for “$350” and struck out at end “The total amount of penalties assessed under this subsection against any single regulated lending institution or enterprise during any calendar year may not exceed $100,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (f)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289">Pub. L. 110–289</ref> substituted “Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency” for “Director of the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight of the Department of Housing and Urban Development”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s531">Pub. L. 103–325, § 531</ref>, substituted section catchline for former section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s582/c">Pub. L. 103–325, § 582(c)</ref>, struck out “, during the anticipated economic or useful life of the project,” before “covered by flood insurance” and inserted at end “The requirement of maintaining flood insurance shall apply during the life of the property, regardless of transfer of ownership of such property.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s522/a">Pub. L. 103–325, § 522(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “Each Federal instrumentality responsible for the supervision, approval, regulation, or insuring of banks, savings and loan associations, or similar institutions shall by regulation direct such institutions not to make, increase, extend, or renew after the expiration of sixty days following <date date="1973-12-31">December 31, 1973</date>, any loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located or to be located in an area that has been identified by the Director as an area having special flood hazards and in which flood insurance has been made available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, unless the building or mobile home and any personal property securing such loan is covered for the term of the loan by flood insurance in an amount at least equal to the outstanding principal balance of the loan or to the maximum limit of coverage made available with respect to the particular type of property under the Act, whichever is less.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s522/b">Pub. L. 103–325, § 522(b)</ref>, inserted heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. (1) heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref>, §§ 523–526, added subsecs. (d) to (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> substituted “Director” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbca45380-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbca45381-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s25/b/1">Pub. L. 113–89, § 25(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-03-21">Mar. 21, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1031">128 Stat. 1031</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/89/s25/b/1">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required application</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments to section 102(d)(1) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 4012a(d)(1)</ref>) made by section 100209(a) of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Public Law 112–141</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/126/920">126 Stat. 920</ref>) and by subsection (a) of this section shall apply to any loan that is originated, refinanced, increased, extended, or renewed on or after <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Optional application.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subparagraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the terms ‘Federal entity for lending regulation’, ‘improved real estate’, ‘regulated lending institution’, and ‘servicer’ have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4003">42 U.S.C. 4003</ref>);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><chapeau> the term ‘outstanding loan’ means a loan that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="aa">     “(aa)</num><content> is outstanding as of <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="bb">     “(bb)</num><content> is not subject to the requirement to escrow premiums and fees for flood insurance under section 102(d)(1) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 4012a(d)(1)</ref>) as in effect on <date date="2012-07-05">July 5, 2012</date>; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="cc">     “(cc)</num><content> would, if the loan had been originated, refinanced, increased, extended, or renewed on or after <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>, be subject to the requirements under section 102(d)(1)(A) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, as amended; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="III">“(III)</num><chapeau> the term ‘section 102(d)(1)(A) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, as amended’ means section 102(d)(1)(A) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1/A">42 U.S.C. 4012a(d)(1)(A)</ref>), as amended by—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="aa">     “(aa)</num><content> section 100209(a) of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Public Law 112–141</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/126/920">126 Stat. 920</ref>); and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="bb">     “(bb)</num><content> subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Option to escrow flood insurance payments</inline>.—</heading><content>Each Federal entity for lending regulation (after consultation and coordination with the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council) shall, by regulation, direct that each regulated lending institution or servicer of an outstanding loan shall offer and make available to a borrower the option to have the borrower’s payment of premiums and fees for flood insurance under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.), including the escrow of such payments, be treated in the same manner provided under section 102(d)(1)(A) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, as amended.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbca45382-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII/s100209/b">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, § 100209(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/920">126 Stat. 920</ref>, which provided that the amendment made to this section by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100209/a">section 100209(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref> would apply to any mortgage outstanding or entered into on or after the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s25/b/2">Pub. L. 113–89, § 25(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-03-21">Mar. 21, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1032">128 Stat. 1032</ref>. For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100209/a">section 100209(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, see Effective Date of 2014 Amendment note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbca45383-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/s582/c">section 582(c) of Pub. L. 103–325</ref> applicable to disasters declared after <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5154a/e">section 5154a(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbca45384-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s25/b/3">Pub. L. 113–89, § 25(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-03-21">Mar. 21, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1032">128 Stat. 1032</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/89/s25/b/3">“Nothing in this section [amending this section and enacting and repealing provisions set out as notes under this section] or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to supersede, during the period beginning on <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date> and ending on <date date="2015-12-31">December 31, 2015</date>, the requirements under section 102(d)(1) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4012a/d/1">42 U.S.C. 4012a(d)(1)</ref>), as in effect on <date date="2012-07-05">July 5, 2012</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbca45385-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbca45386-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Treatment of Floodproofed Residential Basements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s21">Pub. L. 113–89, § 21</ref>, <date date="2014-03-21">Mar. 21, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1028">128 Stat. 1028</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/89/s21">“The Administrator [of the Federal Emergency Management Agency] shall continue to extend exceptions and variances for flood-proofed basements consistent with section 60.6 of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, which are effective <date date="2009-04-03">April 3, 2009</date>; and section 60.3 of such title, which are effective <date date="2009-04-03">April 3, 2009</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
