<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcb2ab59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4081"><num value="4081">§ 4081.</num><heading> Services by insurance industry</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb2ab5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4081/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracting for services and facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In administering the flood insurance program under this subchapter, the Administrator is authorized to enter into any contracts, agreements, or other appropriate arrangements which may, from time to time, be necessary for the purpose of utilizing, on such terms and conditions as may be agreed upon, the facilities and services of any insurance companies or other insurers, insurance agents and brokers, or insurance adjustment organizations; and such contracts, agreements, or arrangements may include provision for payment of applicable operating costs and allowances for such facilities and services as set forth in the schedules prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4018">section 4018 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb2ab5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4081/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain laws inapplicable to contracting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any such contracts, agreements, or other arrangements may be entered into without regard to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref> or any other provision of law requiring competitive bidding and without regard to the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb2ab5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4081/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Hold harmless</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall hold any agent or broker selling or undertaking to sell flood insurance under this chapter harmless from any judgment for damages against such agent or broker as a result of any court action by a policyholder or applicant arising out of an error or omission on the part of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and shall provide any such agent or broker with indemnification, including court costs and reasonable attorney fees, arising out of and caused by an error or omission on the part of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and its contractors. The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may not hold harmless or indemnify an agent or broker for his or her error or omission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb2ab5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4081/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> FEMA authority on transfer of policies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Administrator may, at the discretion of the Administrator, refuse to accept the transfer of the administration of policies for coverage under the flood insurance program under this chapter that are written and administered by any insurance company or other insurer, or any insurance agent or broker.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb2ab5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4081/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Risk transfer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may secure reinsurance of coverage provided by the flood insurance program from the private reinsurance and capital markets at rates and on terms determined by the Administrator to be reasonable and appropriate, in an amount sufficient to maintain the ability of the program to pay claims.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcb2ab5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/448/tXIII/s1345">Pub. L. 90–448, title XIII, § 1345</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/585">82 Stat. 585</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s341/e">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 341(e)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/419">95 Stat. 419</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 451(d)(1)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1229">97 Stat. 1229</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tV/s574">Pub. L. 103–325, title V, § 574</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2278">108 Stat. 2278</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II</ref>, §§ 100238(b)(1), 100245, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/958">126 Stat. 958</ref>, 966; <ref href="/us/pl/113/89/s10">Pub. L. 113–89, § 10</ref>, <date date="2014-03-21">Mar. 21, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1025">128 Stat. 1025</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/263">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(263)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4334">136 Stat. 4334</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcb2ab60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcb2ab61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcb2ab62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (d), was in the original a reference to “this title” meaning title XIII of <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/572">82 Stat. 572</ref>, known as the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbcb2ab63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcb2ab64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/89">Pub. L. 113–89</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100245">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100245</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/325">Pub. L. 103–325</ref> inserted before period at end “and without regard to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> substituted “Director” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcb2ab65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcb2ab66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s371">section 371 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3701">section 3701 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbcb2ab67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 120 days following <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, or such later date prescribed by the Secretary but in no event more than 180 days following <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/448/s1377">section 1377 of Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbcb2ab68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbcb2ab69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Oversight and Expense Reimbursements of Insurance Companies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII/s100224">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, § 100224</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/936">126 Stat. 936</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII/s100224">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of Biennial Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">To the administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 20 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>], each property and casualty insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program shall submit to the Administrator any biennial report required by the Federal Emergency Management Agency to be prepared in the prior 5 years by such company.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">To gao</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 10 days after the submission of the biennial reports under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall submit all such reports to the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice to congress of failure to comply</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall notify and report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on any property and casualty insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program that failed to submit its biennial reports as required under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to comply</inline>.—</heading><content>A property and casualty insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program which fails to comply with the reporting requirement under this subsection or the requirement under section 62.23(j)(1) of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to biennial audit of the flood insurance financial statements) shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount of not more than $1,000 per day for each day that the company remains in noncompliance with either such requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Methodology To Determine Reimbursed Expenses</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>], the Administrator shall develop a methodology for determining the appropriate amounts that property and casualty insurance companies participating in the Write Your Own program should be reimbursed for selling, writing, and servicing flood insurance policies and adjusting flood insurance claims on behalf of the National Flood Insurance Program. The methodology shall be developed using actual expense data for the flood insurance line and can be derived from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> flood insurance expense data produced by the property and casualty insurance companies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> flood insurance expense data collected by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a combination of the methodologies described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of Expense Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>To develop the methodology established under subsection (b), the Administrator may require each property and casualty insurance company participating in the Write Your Own program to submit a report to the Administrator, in a format determined by the Administrator and within 60 days of the request, that details the expense levels of each such company for selling, writing, and servicing standard flood insurance policies and adjusting and servicing claims.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FEMA Rulemaking on Reimbursement of Expenses Under the Write Your Own Program</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>], the Administrator shall issue a rule to formulate revised expense reimbursements to property and casualty insurance companies participating in the Write Your Own program for their expenses (including their operating and administrative expenses for adjustment of claims) in selling, writing, and servicing standard flood insurance policies, including how such companies shall be reimbursed in both catastrophic and noncatastrophic years. Such reimbursements shall be structured to ensure reimbursements track the actual expenses, including standard business costs and operating expenses, of such companies as closely as practicably possible.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report of the Administrator</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 60 days after the effective date of the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (d), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report containing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the specific rationale and purposes of such rule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the reasons for the adoption of the policies contained in such rule; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the degree to which such rule accurately represents the true operating costs and expenses of property and casualty insurance companies participating in the Write Your Own program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">GAO Study and Report on Expenses of Write Your Own Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the effective date of the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (d), the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> conduct a study on the efficacy, adequacy, and sufficiency of the final rules issued pursuant to subsection (d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on the findings of the study conducted under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">GAO authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the study and report required under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> may use any previous findings, studies, or reports that the Comptroller General previously completed on the Write Your Own program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> shall determine if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (d) allows the Federal Emergency Management Agency to access adequate information regarding the actual expenses of property and casualty insurance companies participating in the Write Your Own program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the actual reimbursements paid out under the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (d) accurately reflect the expenses reported by property and casualty insurance companies participating in the Write Your Own program, including the standard business costs and operating expenses of such companies; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> shall analyze the effect of the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (d) on the level of participation of property and casualty insurers in the Write Your Own program.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100224">section 100224 of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4004">section 4004 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
