<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcb4f62e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c"><num value="4101c">§ 4101c.</num><heading> Coordination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb4f62f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency budget crosscut and coordination report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb4f630-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the heads of each Federal department or agency carrying out activities under sections 4101a and 4101b of this title shall work together to ensure that flood risk determination data and geospatial data are shared among Federal agencies in order to coordinate the efforts of the Nation to reduce its vulnerability to flooding hazards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb4f631-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the submission of the budget of the United States Government by the President to Congress, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in coordination with the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the United States Geological Survey, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Corps of Engineers, and other Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate authorizing and appropriating committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives an interagency budget crosscut and coordination report, certified by the Secretary or head of each such agency, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb4f632-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> contains an interagency budget crosscut report that displays relevant sections of the budget proposed for each of the Federal agencies working on flood risk determination data and digital elevation models, including any planned interagency or intra-agency transfers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb4f633-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> describes how the efforts aligned with such sections complement one another.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb4f634-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of the Administrator</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out sections 4101a and 4101b of this title, the Administrator shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb4f635-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> participate, pursuant to section 216 of the E–Government Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</ref> note), in the establishment of such standards and common protocols as are necessary to assure the interoperability of geospatial data for all users of such information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb4f636-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> coordinate with, seek assistance and cooperation of, and provide a liaison to the Federal Geographic Data Committee pursuant to the Office of Management and Budget Circular A–16 and Executive Order 12906 (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1457">43 U.S.C. 1457</ref> note; relating to the National Spatial Data Infrastructure) for the implementation of and compliance with such standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb4f637-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> integrate with, leverage, and coordinate funding of, to the maximum extent practicable, the current flood mapping activities of each unit of State and local government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb4f638-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> integrate with, leverage, and coordinate, to the maximum extent practicable, the current geospatial activities of other Federal agencies and units of State and local government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb4f639-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4101c/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> develop a funding strategy to leverage and coordinate budgets and expenditures, and to maintain or establish joint funding and other agreement mechanisms with other Federal agencies and units of State and local government to share in the collection and utilization of geospatial data among all governmental users.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcb4f63a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII/s100220">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, § 100220</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/932">126 Stat. 932</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcb4f63b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcb4f63c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcb4f63d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 216 of the E–Government Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/107/347/s216">section 216 of Pub. L. 107–347</ref>, which is set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3501">section 3501 of Title 44</ref>, Public Printing and Documents.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12906, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is Ex. Ord. No. 12906, <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, 59 F.R. 17671, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1457">section 1457 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbcb4f63e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012, and also as part of the Moving Ahead for Progress in the 21st Century Act, also known as the MAP–21, and not as part of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcb4f63f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbcb4f640-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of terms used in this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4004">section 4004 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
