<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcb766c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c"><num value="4104c">§ 4104c.</num><heading> Mitigation assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall carry out a program to provide financial assistance to States and communities, using amounts made available from the National Flood Mitigation Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104d">section 4104d of this title</ref>, for planning and carrying out activities designed to reduce the risk of flood damage to structures covered under contracts for flood insurance under this chapter. Such financial assistance shall be made available—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb766c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to States and communities in the form of grants under this section for carrying out mitigation activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb766c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to States and communities in the form of grants under this section for carrying out mitigation activities that reduce flood damage to severe repetitive loss structures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcb766c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to property owners in the form of direct grants under this section for carrying out mitigation activities that reduce flood damage to individual structures for which 2 or more claim payments for losses have been made under flood insurance coverage under this chapter if the Administrator, after consultation with the State and community, determines that neither the State nor community in which such a structure is located has the capacity to manage such grants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility for mitigation assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to receive financial assistance under this section for mitigation activities, a State or community shall develop, and have approved by the Administrator, a flood risk mitigation plan (in this section referred to as a “mitigation plan”), that describes the mitigation activities to be carried out with assistance provided under this section, is consistent with the criteria established by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4102">section 4102 of this title</ref>, provides for reduction of flood losses to structures for which contracts for flood insurance are available under this chapter, and may be included in a multihazard mitigation plan. The mitigation plan shall be consistent with a comprehensive strategy for mitigation activities for the area affected by the mitigation plan, that has been adopted by the State or community following a public hearing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible mitigation activities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement of consistency with approved mitigation plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts provided under this section may be used only for mitigation activities that are consistent with mitigation plans that are approved by the Administrator and identified under paragraph (4). The Administrator shall provide assistance under this section to the extent amounts are available in the National Flood Mitigation Fund pursuant to appropriation Acts, subject only to the absence of approvable mitigation plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements of technical feasibility, cost effectiveness, and interest of National Flood Insurance Fund</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator may approve only mitigation activities that the Administrator determines—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcb766cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are technically feasible and cost-effective; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcb766d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> will eliminate future payments from the National Flood Insurance Fund for severe repetitive loss structures through an acquisition or relocation activity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall take into consideration recognized ancillary benefits.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Eligible activities under a mitigation plan may include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> demolition or relocation of any structure located on land that is along the shore of a lake or other body of water and is certified by an appropriate State or local land use authority to be subject to imminent collapse or subsidence as a result of erosion or flooding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> elevation, relocation, demolition, or floodproofing of structures (including public structures) located in areas having special flood hazards or other areas of flood risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> acquisition by States and communities of properties (including public properties) located in areas having special flood hazards or other areas of flood risk and properties substantially damaged by flood, for public use, as the Administrator determines is consistent with sound land management and use in such area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> elevation, relocation, or floodproofing of utilities (including equipment that serves structures);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> minor physical mitigation efforts that do not duplicate the flood prevention activities of other Federal agencies and that lessen the frequency or severity of flooding and decrease predicted flood damages, which shall not include major flood control projects such as dikes, levees, seawalls, groins, and jetties unless the Administrator specifically determines in approving a mitigation plan that such activities are the most cost-effective mitigation activities for the National Flood Mitigation Fund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the development or update of mitigation plans by a State or community which meet the planning criteria established by the Administrator, except that the amount from grants under this section that may be used under this subparagraph may not exceed $50,000 for any mitigation plan of a State or $25,000 for any mitigation plan of a community;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the provision of technical assistance by States to communities and individuals to conduct eligible mitigation activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> other activities that the Administrator considers appropriate and specifies in regulation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> other mitigation activities not described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) or the regulations issued under subparagraph (H), that are described in the mitigation plan of a State or community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/3/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> without regard to the requirements under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d), and if the State applied for and was awarded at least $1,000,000 in grants available under this section in the prior fiscal year, technical assistance to communities to identify eligible activities, to develop grant applications, and to implement grants awarded under this section, not to exceed $50,000 to any 1 State in any fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility of demolition and rebuilding of properties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall consider as an eligible activity the demolition and rebuilding of properties to at least base flood elevation or greater, if required by the Administrator or if required by any State regulation or local ordinance, and in accordance with criteria established by the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may provide grants for eligible mitigation activities as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Severe repetitive loss structures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of mitigation activities to severe repetitive loss structures, in an amount up to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 100 percent of all eligible costs, if the activities are approved under subsection (c)(2)(A)(i); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the expected savings to the National Flood Insurance Fund from expected avoided damages through acquisition or relocation activities, if the activities are approved under subsection (c)(2)(A)(ii).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Repetitive loss structures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of mitigation activities to repetitive loss structures, in an amount up to 90 percent of all eligible costs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Other mitigation activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of all other mitigation activities, in an amount up to 75 percent of all eligible costs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Recapture</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Noncompliance with plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Administrator determines that a State or community that has received mitigation assistance under this section has not carried out the mitigation activities as set forth in the mitigation plan, the Administrator shall recapture any unexpended amounts and deposit the amounts in the National Flood Mitigation Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104d">section 4104d of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to provide matching funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Administrator determines that a State or community that has received mitigation assistance under this section has not provided matching funds in the amount required under subsection (d), the Administrator shall recapture any unexpended amounts of mitigation assistance exceeding the amount of such matching funds actually provided and deposit the amounts in the National Flood Mitigation Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104d">section 4104d of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Congress describing the status of mitigation activities carried out with assistance provided under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to make grant award within 5 years</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For any application for a grant under this section for which the Administrator fails to make a grant award within 5 years of the date of the application, the grant application shall be considered to be denied and any funding amounts allocated for such grant applications shall remain in the National Flood Mitigation Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4104d">section 4104d of this title</ref> and shall be made available for grants under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Community</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “community” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> a political subdivision that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcb766ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has zoning and building code jurisdiction over a particular area having special flood hazards; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcb766ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is participating in the national flood insurance program; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a political subdivision of a State, or other authority, that is designated by political subdivisions, all of which meet the requirements of subparagraph (A), to administer grants for mitigation activities for such political subdivisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Repetitive loss structure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “repetitive loss structure” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4121">section 4121 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbcb766f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Severe repetitive loss structure</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “severe repetitive loss structure” means a structure that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is covered under a contract for flood insurance made available under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcb766f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> has incurred flood-related damage—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcb766f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for which 4 or more separate claims payments have been made under flood insurance coverage under this chapter, with the amount of each such claim exceeding $5,000, and with the cumulative amount of such claims payments exceeding $20,000; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcb766f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4104c/h/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for which at least 2 separate claims payments have been made under such coverage, with the cumulative amount of such claims exceeding the value of the insured structure.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcb766f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/448/tXIII/s1366">Pub. L. 90–448, title XIII, § 1366</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tV/s553/a">Pub. L. 103–325, title V, § 553(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2270">108 Stat. 2270</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/264/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 108–264, title I, § 103(a)</ref>–(c), (e), (f), <date date="2004-06-30">June 30, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/721">118 Stat. 721</ref>, 722; <ref href="/us/pl/112/95/tVIII/s815/b">Pub. L. 112–95, title VIII, § 815(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/125">126 Stat. 125</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II</ref>, §§ 100225(a), 100238(b)(1), <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/938">126 Stat. 938</ref>, 958.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcb766f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcb766f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcb766f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), and (h)(3)(A), (B)(i), was in the original a reference to “this title” meaning title XIII of <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/572">82 Stat. 572</ref>, known as the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcb766f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/3">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Such financial assistance shall be made available—” for “Such financial assistance shall be made available to States and communities in the form of grants under subsection (b) of this section for planning assistance and in the form of grants under this section for carrying out mitigation activities.” and added pars. (1) to (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/4">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “provides for reduction of” for “and provides protection against” and inserted “, and may be included in a multihazard mitigation plan” after “under this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which related to mitigation planning assistance grants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator shall” for “Director shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/A">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “Requirement of consistency with approved mitigation plan” for “Use of amounts” in heading and “Amounts provided under this section may be used only for mitigation activities that are consistent with mitigation plans that are approved by the Administrator and identified under paragraph (4).” for “Amounts provided under this section (other than under subsection (b) of this section) may be used only for mitigation activities specified in a mitigation plan approved by the Director under subsection (d) of this section.” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/B">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(B)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Director may approve only mitigation plans that specify mitigation activities that the Director determines are technically feasible and cost-effective and only such plans that propose activities that are cost-beneficial to the National Flood Mitigation Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/D/i">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(D)(i)</ref>, substituted “Eligible activities under a mitigation plan may” for “The Director shall determine whether mitigation activities described in a mitigation plan submitted under subsection (d) of this section comply with the requirements under paragraph (1). Such activities may” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/B">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (5) as (3) and struck out former par. (3). Prior to amendment, text of par. (3) read as follows: “The Director shall approve mitigation plans meeting the requirements for approval under paragraph (1) that will be most cost-beneficial to the National Flood Mitigation Fund. The Director may approve only mitigation plans that give priority for funding to such properties, or to such subsets of properties, as are in the best interest of the National Flood Insurance Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/D/iv">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(D)(iv)</ref>, added subpar. (D). Former subpar. (D) redesignated (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/D/ii">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(D)(ii)</ref>, (iii), redesignated subpar. (D) as (E) and struck out former subpar. (E) which read as follows: “beach nourishment activities;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/D/iii">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(D)(iii)</ref>, (v), added subpar. (F) and redesignated former subpar. (F) as (G). Former subpar. (G) redesignated (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/D/ii">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(D)(ii)</ref>, (iii), redesignated subpar. (G) as (H) and struck out former subpar. (H) which read as follows: “other mitigation activities not described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) or the regulations issued under subparagraph (G), that are described in the mitigation plan of a State or community.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(I), (J). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/D/vi">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(D)(vi)</ref>, (vii), added subpars. (I) and (J).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/B">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(B)</ref>, (E), added par. (4) and struck out former par. (4). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In providing grants under this subsection for mitigation activities, the Director shall give first priority for funding to such properties, or to such subsets of such properties as the Director may establish, that the Director determines are in the best interests of the National Flood Insurance Fund and for which matching amounts under subsection (f) of this section are available.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/C">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(C)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/5/E">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(5)(E)</ref>, struck out par. (6). Text read as follows: “The Director shall consider as an eligible activity the demolition and rebuilding of properties to at least base flood levels or higher, if required by the Director or if required by any State or local ordinance, and in accordance with project implementation criteria established by the Director.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(1)</ref>, (6), added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which related to notification of mitigation plan approval and grant award.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/7">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(7)</ref>, substituted “required under subsection (d)” for “certified under subsection (g)” and “the amount” for “3 times the amount”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/112/95">Pub. L. 112–95</ref> added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/8">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(8)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>” for “<date date="1994-09-23">September 23, 1994</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (j) as (f) and struck out former subsec. (f) which related to limitations on amount of mitigation assistance during any 5-year period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(1)</ref>, (9), added subsecs. (g) and (h) and struck out former subsecs. (g) and (h) which related to the matching requirement for mitigation assistance and oversight of recipients of mitigation assistance, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (i) and (j) as (e) and (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (m). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s100225/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 100225(a)(1)</ref>, struck out subsecs. (k) and (m) which defined “community” for purposes of this section and which related to encouraging and improving participation in the national flood insurance program, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/264/s103/f">Pub. L. 108–264, § 103(f)</ref>, substituted “7.5 percent of the available funds under this section” for “$1,500,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/264/s103/a">Pub. L. 108–264, § 103(a)</ref>, inserted at end “The Director may approve only mitigation plans that give priority for funding to such properties, or to such subsets of properties, as are in the best interest of the National Flood Insurance Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/264/s103/b">Pub. L. 108–264, § 103(b)</ref>, added par. (4) and struck out heading and text of former par. (4). Text read as follows: “The Director shall make every effort to provide mitigation assistance under this section for mitigation plans proposing activities for repetitive loss structures and structures that have incurred substantial damage.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/264/s103/e">Pub. L. 108–264, § 103(e)</ref>, added par. (2) and redesignated former par. (2) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/108/264/s103/c">Pub. L. 108–264, § 103(c)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcb766fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbcb766fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/325/tV/s553/b">Pub. L. 103–325, title V, § 553(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2273">108 Stat. 2273</ref>, required the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to issue regulations no later than 6 months after <date date="1994-09-23">Sept. 23, 1994</date>, to carry out this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbcb766fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
