<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcb9d72d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4107"><num value="4107">§ 4107.</num><heading> Consultation with local officials; scope</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out his responsibilities under the provisions of this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003350">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003350"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</ref> et seq.] which relate to notification to and identification of flood-prone areas and the application of criteria for land management and use, including criteria derived from data reflecting new developments that may indicate the desirability of modifying elevations based on previous flood studies, the Administrator shall establish procedures assuring adequate consultation with the appropriate elected officials of general purpose local governments, including but not limited to those local governments whose prior eligibility under the program has been suspended. Such consultation shall include, but not be limited to, fully informing local officials at the commencement of any flood elevation study or investigation undertaken by any agency on behalf of the Administrator concerning the nature and purpose of the study, the areas involved, the manner in which the study is to be undertaken, the general principles to be applied, and the use to be made of the data obtained. The Administrator shall encourage local officials to disseminate information concerning such study widely within the community, so that interested persons will have an opportunity to bring all relevant facts and technical data concerning the local flood hazard to the attention of the agency during the course of the study.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbcb9d72e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/234/tII/s206">Pub. L. 93–234, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/983">87 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 451(e)(1)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1229">97 Stat. 1229</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII/s100238/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, § 100238(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/958">126 Stat. 958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcb9d72f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcb9d730-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcb9d731-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in text, means title II of <ref href="/us/pl/93/234">Pub. L. 93–234</ref>, <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/975">87 Stat. 975</ref>, which enacted sections 4105 to 4107 and 4128 of this title and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4101">section 4101 of this title</ref> and sections 24 and 1709–1 of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1973 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, referred to in text, is title XIII of <ref href="/us/pl/90/448">Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/572">82 Stat. 572</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter (§ 4001 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbcb9d732-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, and not as part of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcb9d733-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> substituted “Administrator” for “Director” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> substituted “Director” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcb9d734-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbcb9d735-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
