<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcb9d758-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4122"><num value="4122">§ 4122.</num><heading> Studies of other natural disasters; cooperation and consultation with other departments and agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcb9d759-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4122/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Administrator is authorized to undertake such studies as may be necessary for the purpose of determining the extent to which insurance protection against earthquakes or any other natural disaster perils, other than flood, is not available from public or private sources, and the feasibility of such insurance protection being made available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcb9d75a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4122/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Studies under this section shall be carried out, to the maximum extent practicable, with the cooperation of other Federal departments and agencies and State and local agencies, and the Administrator is authorized to consult with, receive information from, and enter into any necessary agreements or other arrangements with such other Federal departments and agencies (on a reimbursement basis) and such State and local agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcb9d75b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/448/tXIII/s1371">Pub. L. 90–448, title XIII, § 1371</ref>, <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/588">82 Stat. 588</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 451(d)(1)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1229">97 Stat. 1229</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dF/tII/s100238/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, § 100238(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/958">126 Stat. 958</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcb9d75c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcb9d75d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcb9d75e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> substituted “Administrator” for “Director” in subsecs. (a) and (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> substituted “Director” for “Secretary” in subsecs. (a) and (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcb9d75f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbcb9d760-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 120 days following <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, or such later date prescribed by the Secretary but in no event more than 180 days following <date date="1968-08-01">Aug. 1, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/448/s1377">section 1377 of Pub. L. 90–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbcb9d761-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbcb9d762-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Sinkhole Insurance</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title IV, § 453], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1230">97 Stat. 1230</ref>, permitted the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to make a grant to a nonprofit organization, educational institution, or State or local agency to study the feasibility of expanding the national flood insurance program to cover damage or loss arising from sinkholes and authorized appropriations.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
