<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb75ed6b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421"><num value="421">§ 421.</num><heading> Disability determinations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb75ed6b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> State agencies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of any individual, the determination of whether or not he is under a disability (as defined in section 416(i) or 423(d) of this title) and of the day such disability began, and the determination of the day on which such disability ceases, shall be made by a State agency, notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any State that notifies the Commissioner of Social Security in writing that it wishes to make such disability determinations commencing with such month as the Commissioner of Social Security and the State agree upon, but only if (A) the Commissioner of Social Security has not found, under subsection (b)(1), that the State agency has substantially failed to make disability determinations in accordance with the applicable provisions of this section or rules issued thereunder, and (B) the State has not notified the Commissioner of Social Security, under subsection (b)(2), that it does not wish to make such determinations. If the Commissioner of Social Security once makes the finding described in clause (A) of the preceding sentence, or the State gives the notice referred to in clause (B) of such sentence, the Commissioner of Social Security may thereafter determine whether (and, if so, beginning with which month and under what conditions) the State may again make disability determinations under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The disability determinations described in paragraph (1) made by a State agency shall be made in accordance with the pertinent provisions of this subchapter and the standards and criteria contained in regulations or other written guidelines of the Commissioner of Social Security pertaining to matters such as disability determinations, the class or classes of individuals with respect to which a State may make disability determinations (if it does not wish to do so with respect to all individuals in the State), and the conditions under which it may choose not to make all such determinations. In addition, the Commissioner of Social Security shall promulgate regulations specifying, in such detail as the Commissioner deems appropriate, performance standards and administrative requirements and procedures to be followed in performing the disability determination function in order to assure effective and uniform administration of the disability insurance program throughout the United States. The regulations may, for example, specify matters such as—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb75ed6bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the administrative structure and the relationship between various units of the State agency responsible for disability determinations,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb75ed6bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the physical location of and relationship among agency staff units, and other individuals or organizations performing tasks for the State agency, and standards for the availability to applicants and beneficiaries of facilities for making disability determinations,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb75ed6be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> State agency performance criteria, including the rate of accuracy of decisions, the time periods within which determinations must be made, the procedures for and the scope of review by the Commissioner of Social Security, and, as the Commissioner finds appropriate, by the State, of its performance in individual cases and in classes of cases, and rules governing access of appropriate Federal officials to State offices and to State records relating to its administration of the disability determination function,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb75ed6bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> fiscal control procedures that the State agency may be required to adopt, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb75ed6c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the submission of reports and other data, in such form and at such time as the Commissioner of Social Security may require, concerning the State agency’s activities relating to the disability determination.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Commissioner of Social Security to take any action except pursuant to law or to regulations promulgated pursuant to law.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb75ed6c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations by Commissioner</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the Commissioner of Social Security finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that a State agency is substantially failing to make disability determinations in a manner consistent with the Commissioner’s regulations and other written guidelines, the Commissioner of Social Security shall, not earlier than 180 days following the Commissioner’s finding, and after the Commissioner has complied with the requirements of paragraph (3), make the disability determinations referred to in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a State, having notified the Commissioner of Social Security of its intent to make disability determinations under subsection (a)(1), no longer wishes to make such determinations, it shall notify the Commissioner of Social Security in writing of that fact, and, if an agency of the State is making disability determinations at the time such notice is given, it shall continue to do so for not less than 180 days, or (if later) until the Commissioner of Social Security has complied with the requirements of paragraph (3). Thereafter, the Commissioner of Social Security shall make the disability determinations referred to in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Commissioner of Social Security shall develop and initiate all appropriate procedures to implement a plan with respect to any partial or complete assumption by the Commissioner of Social Security of the disability determination function from a State agency, as provided in this section, under which employees of the affected State agency who are capable of performing duties in the disability determination process for the Commissioner of Social Security shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law, have a preference over any other individual in filling an appropriate employment position with the Commissioner of Social Security (subject to any system established by the Commissioner of Social Security for determining hiring priority among such employees of the State agency) unless any such employee is the administrator, the deputy administrator, or assistant administrator (or his equivalent) of the State agency, in which case the Commissioner of Social Security may accord such priority to such employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Commissioner of Social Security shall not make such assumption of the disability determination function until such time as the Secretary of Labor determines that, with respect to employees of such State agency who will be displaced from their employment on account of such assumption by the Commissioner of Social Security and who will not be hired by the Commissioner of Social Security to perform duties in the disability determination process, the State has made fair and equitable arrangements to protect the interests of employees so displaced. Such protective arrangements shall include only those provisions which are provided under all applicable Federal, State and local statutes including, but not limited to, (i) the preservation of rights, privileges, and benefits (including continuation of pension rights and benefits) under existing collective-bargaining agreements; (ii) the continuation of collective-bargaining rights; (iii) the assignment of affected employees to other jobs or to retraining programs; (iv) the protection of individual employees against a worsening of their positions with respect to their employment; (v) the protection of health benefits and other fringe benefits; and (vi) the provision of severance pay, as may be necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb75ed6c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of determination by Commissioner</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commissioner of Social Security may on the Commissioner’s own motion or as required under paragraphs (2) and (3) review a determination, made by a State agency under this section, that an individual is or is not under a disability (as defined in section 416(i) or 423(d) of this title) and, as a result of such review, may modify such agency’s determination and determine that such individual either is or is not under a disability (as so defined) or that such individual’s disability began on a day earlier or later than that determined by such agency, or that such disability ceased on a day earlier or later than that determined by such agency. A review by the Commissioner of Social Security on the Commissioner’s own motion of a State agency determination under this paragraph may be made before or after any action is taken to implement such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commissioner of Social Security (in accordance with paragraph (3)) shall review determinations, made by State agencies pursuant to this section, that individuals are under disabilities (as defined in section 416(i) or 423(d) of this title). Any review by the Commissioner of Social Security of a State agency determination under this paragraph shall be made before any action is taken to implement such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> In carrying out the provisions of paragraph (2) with respect to the review of determinations made by State agencies pursuant to this section that individuals are under disabilities (as defined in section 416(i) or 423(d) of this title), the Commissioner of Social Security shall review—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb75ed6cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> at least 50 percent of all such determinations made by State agencies on applications for benefits under this subchapter, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb75ed6cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> other determinations made by State agencies pursuant to this section to the extent necessary to assure a high level of accuracy in such other determinations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In conducting reviews pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Commissioner of Social Security shall, to the extent feasible, select for review those determinations which the Commissioner of Social Security identifies as being the most likely to be incorrect.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb75ed6cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1992-04-01">April 1, 1992</date>, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of Social Security shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a written report setting forth the number of reviews conducted under subparagraph (A)(ii) during the preceding fiscal year and the findings of the Commissioner of Social Security based on such reviews of the accuracy of the determinations made by State agencies pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb75ed6d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings and judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any individual dissatisfied with any determination under subsection (a), (b), (c), or (g) shall be entitled to a hearing thereon by the Commissioner of Social Security to the same extent as is provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s405/b">section 405(b) of this title</ref> with respect to decisions of the Commissioner of Social Security, and to judicial review of the Commissioner’s final decision after such hearing as is provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s405/g">section 405(g) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> State’s right to cost from Trust Funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State which is making disability determinations under subsection (a)(1) shall be entitled to receive from the Trust Funds, in advance or by way of reimbursement, as determined by the Commissioner of Social Security, the cost to the State of making disability determinations under subsection (a)(1). The Commissioner of Social Security shall from time to time certify such amount as is necessary for this purpose to the Managing Trustee, reduced or increased, as the case may be, by any sum (for which adjustment hereunder has not previously been made) by which the amount certified for any prior period was greater or less than the amount which should have been paid to the State under this subsection for such period; and the Managing Trustee, prior to audit or settlement by the Government Accountability Office, shall make payment from the Trust Funds at the time or times fixed by the Commissioner of Social Security, in accordance with such certification. Appropriate adjustments between the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund with respect to the payments made under this subsection shall be made in accordance with paragraph (1) of subsection (g) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref> (but taking into account any refunds under subsection (f) of this section) to insure that the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund is charged with all expenses incurred which are attributable to the administration of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s423">section 423 of this title</ref> and the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund is charged with all other expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All money paid to a State under this section shall be used solely for the purposes for which it is paid; and any money so paid which is not used for such purposes shall be returned to the Treasury of the United States for deposit in the Trust Funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations governing determinations in certain cases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of individuals in a State which does not undertake to perform disability determinations under subsection (a)(1), or which has been found by the Commissioner of Social Security to have substantially failed to make disability determinations in a manner consistent with the Commissioner’s regulations and guidelines, in the case of individuals outside the United States, and in the case of any class or classes of individuals for whom no State undertakes to make disability determinations, the determinations referred to in subsection (a) shall be made by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Commissioner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation of impairments by qualified medical professionals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An initial determination under subsection (a), (c), (g), or (i) shall not be made until the Commissioner of Social Security has made every reasonable effort to ensure—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in any case where there is evidence which indicates the existence of a mental impairment, that a qualified psychiatrist or psychologist has completed the medical portion of the case review and any applicable residual functional capacity assessment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in any case where there is evidence which indicates the existence of a physical impairment, that a qualified physician has completed the medical portion of the case review and any applicable residual functional capacity assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of disability cases to determine continuing eligibility; permanent disability cases; appropriate number of cases reviewed; reporting requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In any case where an individual is or has been determined to be under a disability, the case shall be reviewed by the applicable State agency or the Commissioner of Social Security (as may be appropriate), for purposes of continuing eligibility, at least once every 3 years, subject to paragraph (2); except that where a finding has been made that such disability is permanent, such reviews shall be made at such times as the Commissioner of Social Security determines to be appropriate. Reviews of cases under the preceding sentence shall be in addition to, and shall not be considered as a substitute for, any other reviews which are required or provided for under or in the administration of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The requirement of paragraph (1) that cases be reviewed at least every 3 years shall not apply to the extent that the Commissioner of Social Security determines, on a State-by-State basis, that such requirement should be waived to insure that only the appropriate number of such cases are reviewed. The Commissioner of Social Security shall determine the appropriate number of cases to be reviewed in each State after consultation with the State agency performing such reviews, based upon the backlog of pending reviews, the projected number of new applications for disability insurance benefits, and the current and projected staffing levels of the State agency, but the Commissioner of Social Security shall provide for a waiver of such requirement only in the case of a State which makes a good faith effort to meet proper staffing requirements for the State agency and to process case reviews in a timely fashion. The Commissioner of Social Security shall report annually to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives with respect to the determinations made by the Commissioner of Social Security under the preceding sentence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Commissioner of Social Security shall report annually to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives with respect to the number of reviews of continuing disability carried out under paragraph (1), the number of such reviews which result in an initial termination of benefits, the number of requests for reconsideration of such initial termination or for a hearing with respect to such termination under subsection (d), or both, and the number of such initial terminations which are overturned as the result of a reconsideration or hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In any case in which the Commissioner of Social Security initiates a review under this subsection of the case of an individual who has been determined to be under a disability, the Commissioner of Social Security shall notify such individual of the nature of the review to be carried out, the possibility that such review could result in the termination of benefits, and the right of the individual to provide medical evidence with respect to such review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For suspension of reviews under this subsection in the case of an individual using a ticket to work and self-sufficiency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–19/i">section 1320b–19(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations; consultative examinations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of Social Security shall prescribe regulations which set forth, in detail—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the standards to be utilized by State disability determination services and Federal personnel in determining when a consultative examination should be obtained in connection with disability determinations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> standards for the type of referral to be made; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> procedures by which the Commissioner of Social Security will monitor both the referral processes used and the product of professionals to whom cases are referred.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude the issuance, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553/b/A">section 553(b)(A) of title 5</ref>, of interpretive rules, general statements of policy, and rules of agency organization relating to consultative examinations if such rules and statements are consistent with such regulations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of uniform standards for determination of disability</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish by regulation uniform standards which shall be applied at all levels of determination, review, and adjudication in determining whether individuals are under disabilities as defined in section 416(i) or 423(d) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the rulemaking procedures established under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Special notice to blind individuals with respect to hearings and other official actions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In any case where an individual who is applying for or receiving benefits under this subchapter on the basis of disability by reason of blindness is entitled to receive notice from the Commissioner of Social Security of any decision or determination made or other action taken or proposed to be taken with respect to his or her rights under this subchapter, such individual shall at his or her election be entitled either (A) to receive a supplementary notice of such decision, determination, or action, by telephone, within 5 working days after the initial notice is mailed, (B) to receive the initial notice in the form of a certified letter, or (C) to receive notification by some alternative procedure established by the Commissioner of Social Security and agreed to by the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The election under paragraph (1) may be made at any time, but an opportunity to make such an election shall in any event be given, to every individual who is an applicant for benefits under this subchapter on the basis of disability by reason of blindness, at the time of his or her application. Such an election, once made by an individual, shall apply with respect to all notices of decisions, determinations, and actions which such individual may thereafter be entitled to receive under this subchapter until such time as it is revoked or changed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb76147e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Work activity as basis for review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In any case where an individual entitled to disability insurance benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s423">section 423 of this title</ref> or to monthly insurance benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">section 402 of this title</ref> based on such individual’s disability (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s423/d">section 423(d) of this title</ref>) has received such benefits for at least 24 months—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> no continuing disability review conducted by the Commissioner may be scheduled for the individual solely as a result of the individual’s work activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> no work activity engaged in by the individual may be used as evidence that the individual is no longer disabled; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> no cessation of work activity by the individual may give rise to a presumption that the individual is unable to engage in work.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb76147ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> An individual to which paragraph (1) applies shall continue to be subject to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> continuing disability reviews on a regularly scheduled basis that is not triggered by work; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb76147ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s421/m/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> termination of benefits under this subchapter in the event that the individual has earnings that exceed the level of earnings established by the Commissioner to represent substantial gainful activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb76147ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title II, § 221, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-09-01/ch1206">Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1206</ref>, title I, § 106(g), <ref href="/us/stat/68/1081">68 Stat. 1081</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch836">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 836</ref>, title I, § 103(c)(7), (8), (h), <ref href="/us/stat/70/818">70 Stat. 818</ref>, 823; <ref href="/us/pl/90/248/tI/s158/c/3">Pub. L. 90–248, title I, § 158(c)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/869">81 Stat. 869</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/tIII">Pub. L. 96–265, title III</ref>, §§ 304(a)–(f), 311(a), <date date="1980-06-09">June 9, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/453-456">94 Stat. 453–456</ref>, 460; <ref href="/us/pl/97/455">Pub. L. 97–455</ref>, §§ 3(a), 6, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2499">96 Stat. 2499</ref>, 2500; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/a/14">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1164">98 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/460">Pub. L. 98–460</ref>, §§ 6(a), 8(a), 9(a)(1), 10(a), 17(a), <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1802">98 Stat. 1802</ref>, 1804, 1805, 1811; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1883/a/9">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1883(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2916">100 Stat. 2916</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tVIII/s8012/a">Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8012(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3789">102 Stat. 3789</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tX/s10306/a/1">Pub. L. 101–239, title X, § 10306(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2484">103 Stat. 2484</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5128/a">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5128(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-286">104 Stat. 1388–286</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s107/a/4">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 107(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1478">108 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/tI">Pub. L. 106–170, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b)(1)(A), 111(a), <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1873">113 Stat. 1873</ref>, 1881; <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s832/a">Pub. L. 114–74, title VIII, § 832(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/613">129 Stat. 613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb76147f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb76147f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb76147f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 421, <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531/tII/s221">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title II, § 221</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-18/ch945/s3/e">July 18, 1952, ch. 945, § 3(e)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/772">66 Stat. 772</ref>; amended by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, § 5, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref href="/us/stat/67/631">67 Stat. 631</ref>, relating to disability determinations, ceased to be in effect at the close of <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>. See section 3(g) of act <date date="1952-07-18">July 18, 1952</date>, set out as an Effective and Termination Date of 1952 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s413">section 413 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb76147f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/114/74">Pub. L. 114–74</ref> amended subsec. (h) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “An initial determination under subsection (a), (c), (g), or (i) that an individual is not under a disability, in any case where there is evidence which indicates the existence of a mental impairment, shall be made only if the Commissioner of Social Security has made every reasonable effort to ensure that a qualified psychiatrist or psychologist has completed the medical portion of the case review and any applicable residual functional capacity assessment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/271">Pub. L. 108–271</ref> substituted “Government Accountability Office” for “General Accounting Office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (i)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/b/1/A">Pub. L. 106–170, § 101(b)(1)(A)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s111/a">Pub. L. 106–170, § 111(a)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” wherever appearing except where appearing before “of Labor” in subsec. (b)(3)(B) and substituted “the Commissioner deems” for “he deems” and “the Commissioner finds” for “he finds” in subsec. (a)(2), “the Commissioner’s” for “his” wherever appearing in subsecs. (b)(1), (c)(1), and (g), “the Commissioner has complied” for “he has complied” in subsec. (b)(1), “Commissioner’s” for “Secretary’s” in subsec. (d), and “prescribed by the Commissioner” for “prescribed by him” in subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “In carrying out the provisions of paragraph (2) with respect to the review of determinations, made by State agencies pursuant to this section, that individuals are under disabilities (as defined in section 416(i) or 423(d) of this title), the Secretary shall review—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) at least 15 percent of all such determinations made by State agencies in the fiscal year 1981,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) at least 35 percent of all such determinations made by State agencies in the fiscal year 1982, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) at least 65 percent of all such determinations made by State agencies in any fiscal year after the fiscal year 1982.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (i)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> substituted “semiannually” for “annually”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> struck out “under this section” before “shall be entitled”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s17/a/2">Pub. L. 98–460, § 17(a)(2)</ref>, (b), temporarily substituted “subsection (b)(1)(C)” for “subsection (b)(1)”. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1984 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s17/a/1">Pub. L. 98–460, § 17(a)(1)</ref>, (b), temporarily amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “If the Secretary finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that a State agency is substantially failing to make disability determinations in a manner consistent with his regulations and other written guidelines, the Secretary shall, not earlier than 180 days following his finding, and after he has complied with the requirements of paragraph (3), make the disability determinations referred to in subsection (a)(1).” See Effective and Termination Dates of 1984 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s17/a/3">Pub. L. 98–460, § 17(a)(3)</ref>, (b), temporarily substituted “Except as provided in subparagraph (D)(i) of paragraph (1), the Secretary” for “The Secretary” in subpars. (A) and (B). See Effective and Termination Dates of 1984 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s17/a/4">Pub. L. 98–460, § 17(a)(4)</ref>, (b), temporarily substituted “Except as provided in subsection (b)(1)(D), any individual” for “Any individual”. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1984 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> substituted “Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund is charged” for “Federal Disability Trust Fund is charged”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s8/a">Pub. L. 98–460, § 8(a)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s6/a">Pub. L. 98–460, § 6(a)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s9/a/1">Pub. L. 98–460, § 9(a)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s10/a">Pub. L. 98–460, § 10(a)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/97/455">Pub. L. 97–455</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted “, subject to paragraph (2)” after “at least once every 3 years”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s304/a">Pub. L. 96–265, § 304(a)</ref>, completely revised provisions under which determinations are to be made by State agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s304/b">Pub. L. 96–265, § 304(b)</ref>, substituted provisions covering the making of disability determinations by the Secretary rather than by the State for provisions relating to agreements between the Secretary and the State under which the State would make disability determinations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s304/c">Pub. L. 96–265, § 304(c)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted provision that a review by the Secretary on his own motion of a State agency determination may be made before or after any action is taken to implement that determination, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s304/d">Pub. L. 96–265, § 304(d)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a), (b), (c), or (g)” for “subsection (a), (c), or (g)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s304/e">Pub. L. 96–265, § 304(e)</ref>, substituted “which is making disability determinations under subsection (a)(1)” for “which has an agreement with the Secretary”, substituted “as determined by the Secretary” for “as may be mutually agreed upon”, and substituted “making disability determinations under subsection (a)(1)” for “carrying out the agreement under this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s304/f">Pub. L. 96–265, § 304(f)</ref>, substituted “does not undertake to perform disability determinations under subsection (a)(1), or which has been found by the Secretary to have substantially failed to make disability determinations in a manner consistent with his regulations and guidelines” for “has no agreement under subsection (b)” and “for whom no State undertakes to make disability determinations” for “not included in an agreement under subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s311/a">Pub. L. 96–265, § 311(a)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/248/s158/c/3">Pub. L. 90–248, § 158(c)(3)</ref>, substituted in first sentence reference to “423(d)” for “423(c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/248/s158/c/4">Pub. L. 90–248, § 158(c)(4)</ref>, substituted reference to “423(d)” for “423(c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1956-08-01">Aug. 1, 1956</date>, § 103(c)(7), inserted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s423/c">section 423(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1956-08-01">Aug. 1, 1956</date>, § 103(c)(8), restricted disability to definition of such term contained in section 416(i) or 423(c) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1956-08-01">Aug. 1, 1956</date>, § 103(h), substituted “Trust Funds” for “Trust Fund”, and provided for adjustments between the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund with respect to payments made under this subsection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). Act <date date="1956-08-01">Aug. 1, 1956</date>, § 103(h), substituted “Trust Funds” for “Trust Fund”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb76147f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s832/b">Pub. L. 114–74, title VIII, § 832(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/613">129 Stat. 613</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s832/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to determinations of disability made on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/b/1/A">section 101(b)(1)(A) of Pub. L. 106–170</ref> effective with the first month following one year after <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, subject to <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/d">section 101(d) of Pub. L. 106–170</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/c">section 101(c) of Pub. L. 106–170</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–19">section 1320b–19 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/170/tI/s111/b">Pub. L. 106–170, title I, § 111(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1881">113 Stat. 1881</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/170/tI/s111/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5128/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5128(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-287">104 Stat. 1388–287</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5128/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to determinations made by State agencies in fiscal years after fiscal year 1990.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tX/s10306/a/3">Pub. L. 101–239, title X, § 10306(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2484">103 Stat. 2484</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tX/s10306/a/3">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to notices issued on or after <date date="1990-07-01">July 1, 1990</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tVIII/s8012/b">Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8012(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3789">102 Stat. 3789</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/647/tVIII/s8012/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to reports required to be submitted after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s8/c">Pub. L. 98–460, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1804">98 Stat. 1804</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/460/s8/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382c">section 1382c of this title</ref>] shall apply to determinations made after 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s17/b">Pub. L. 98–460, § 17(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1812">98 Stat. 1812</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/460/s17/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) of this section [amending this section] shall become effective on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>] and shall expire on <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>. The provisions of the Social Security Act amended by subsection (a) of this section (as such provisions were in effect immediately before the date of the enactment of this Act) shall be effective after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/455/s3/b">Pub. L. 97–455, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2499">96 Stat. 2499</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/455/s3/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall become effective on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/265/tIII/s304/h">Pub. L. 96–265, title III, § 304(h)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-09">June 9, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/456">94 Stat. 456</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/265/tIII/s304/h">“The amendments made by subsections (a), (b), (d), (e), and (f) [amending this section] shall be effective beginning with the twelfth month following the month in which this Act is enacted [June 1980]. Any State that, on the effective date of the amendments made by this section, has in effect an agreement with the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 221(a) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/a">42 U.S.C. 421(a)</ref>] (as in effect prior to such amendments) will be deemed to have given to the Secretary the notice specified in section 221(a)(1) of such Act as amended by this section, in lieu of continuing such agreement in effect after the effective date of such amendments. Thereafter, a State may notify the Secretary in writing that it no longer wishes to make disability determinations, effective not less than 180 days after the notification is given.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/96/265/tIII/s311/b">Pub. L. 96–265, title III, § 311(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-09">June 9, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/460">94 Stat. 460</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/265/tIII/s311/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall become effective on <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb76147fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/248">Pub. L. 90–248</ref> applicable with respect to application for disability insurance benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s423">section 423 of this title</ref> and to disability determinations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s416/i">section 416(i) of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/248/s158/e">section 158(e) of Pub. L. 90–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s423">section 423 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb76147ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expansion of Cooperative Disability Investigations Units</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s811">Pub. L. 114–74, title VIII, § 811</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/601">129 Stat. 601</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s811">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2022-10-01">October 1, 2022</date>, the Commissioner of Social Security shall take any necessary actions, subject to the availability of appropriations, to ensure that cooperative disability investigations units have been established, in areas where there is cooperation with local law enforcement agencies, that would cover each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and American Samoa.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>] and annually thereafter until the earlier of 2022 or the date on which nationwide coverage is achieved, the Commissioner of Social Security shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report describing a plan to implement the nationwide coverage described in subsection (a) and outlining areas where the Social Security Administration did not receive the cooperation of local law enforcement agencies.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614800-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Work-Related Continuing Disability Reviews</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s845/b">Pub. L. 114–74, title VIII, § 845(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/618">129 Stat. 618</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s845/b">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Commissioner of Social Security shall annually submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the number of work-related continuing disability reviews conducted each year to determine whether earnings derived from services demonstrate an individual’s ability to engage in substantial gainful activity. Such report shall include—</p>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the number of individuals receiving benefits based on disability under title II of such Act [probably means title II of <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.] for whom reports of earnings were received from any source by the Commissioner in the previous calendar year, reported as a total number and separately by the source of the report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the number of individuals for whom such reports resulted in a determination to conduct a work-related continuing disability review, and the basis on which such determinations were made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> in the case of a beneficiary selected for a work-related continuing disability review on the basis of a report of earnings from any source—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> the average number of days—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> between the receipt of the report and the initiation of the review;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> between the initiation and the completion of the review; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the average amount of overpayment, if any;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the number of such reviews completed during such calendar year, and the number of such reviews that resulted in a suspension or termination of benefits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the number of such reviews initiated in the current year that had not been completed as of the end of such calendar year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the number of such reviews initiated in a prior year that had not been completed as of the end of such calendar year;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the total savings to the Trust Funds and the Treasury generated from benefits suspended or terminated as a result of such reviews; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><chapeau> with respect to individuals for whom a work-related continuing disability review was completed during such calendar year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the number who participated in the Ticket to Work program under section 1148 [probably means section 1148 of <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1319b–19">42 U.S.C. 1319b–19</ref>] during such calendar year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the number who used any program work incentives during such calendar year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the number who received vocational rehabilitation services during such calendar year with respect to which the Commissioner of Social Security reimbursed a State agency under section 222(d) [probably means section 222(d) of <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s422/d">42 U.S.C. 422(d)</ref>].”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614801-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Election Under Subsection (<i>l</i>)(1) by Current Recipients</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tX/s10306/a/2">Pub. L. 101–239, title X, § 10306(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2484">103 Stat. 2484</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tX/s10306/a/2">“Not later than <date date="1990-07-01">July 1, 1990</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide every individual receiving benefits under title II of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.] on the basis of disability by reason of blindness an opportunity to make an election under section 221(<i>l</i>)(1) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421">42 U.S.C. 421</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1)] (as added by paragraph (1)).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614802-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Moratorium on Mental Impairment Reviews</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s5">Pub. L. 98–460, § 5</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1801">98 Stat. 1801</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/460/s5">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services (hereafter in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’) shall revise the criteria embodied under the category ‘Mental Disorders’ in the ‘Listing of Impairments’ in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>] under appendix 1 to subpart P of part 404 of title 20 of the Code of Federal Regulations. The revised criteria and listings, alone and in combination with assessments of the residual functional capacity of the individuals involved, shall be designed to realistically evaluate the ability of a mentally impaired individual to engage in substantial gainful activity in a competitive workplace environment. Regulations establishing such revised criteria and listings shall be published no later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Until such time as revised criteria have been established by regulation in accordance with subsection (a), no continuing eligibility review shall be carried out under section 221(i) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/i">42 U.S.C. 421(i)</ref>], or under the corresponding requirements established for disability determinations and reviews under title XVI of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1381">42 U.S.C. 1381</ref> et seq.], with respect to any individual previously determined to be under a disability by reason of a mental impairment, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> no initial decision on such review has been rendered with respect to such individual prior to the date of the enactment of this Act, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an initial decision on such review was rendered with respect to such individual prior to the date of the enactment of this Act but a timely appeal from such decision was filed or was pending on or after <date date="1983-06-07">June 7, 1983</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph and subsection (c)(1) the term ‘continuing eligibility review’, when used to refer to a review of a previous determination of disability, includes any reconsideration of or hearing on the initial decision rendered in such review as well as such initial decision itself, and any review by the Appeals Council of the hearing decision.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) shall not apply in any case where the Secretary determines that fraud was involved in the prior determination, or where an individual (other than an individual eligible to receive benefits under section 1619 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382h">42 U.S.C. 1382h</ref>]) is determined by the Secretary to be engaged in substantial gainful activity (or gainful activity, in the case of a widow, surviving divorced wife, widower, or surviving divorced husband for purposes of section 202(e) and (f) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402/e">42 U.S.C. 402(e)</ref>, (f)]).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any initial determination that an individual is not under a disability by reason of a mental impairment and any determination that an individual is not under a disability by reason of a mental impairment in a reconsideration of or hearing on an initial disability determination, made or held under title II or XVI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq., 1381 et seq.] after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>] and prior to the date on which revised criteria are established by regulation in accordance with subsection (a), and any determination that an individual is not under a disability by reason of a mental impairment made under or in accordance with title II or XVI of such Act in a reconsideration of, hearing on, review by the Appeals Council of, or judicial review of a decision rendered in any continuing eligibility review to which subsection (b)(1) applies, shall be redetermined by the Secretary as soon as feasible after the date on which such criteria are so established, applying such revised criteria.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In the case of a redetermination under paragraph (1) of a prior action which found that an individual was not under a disability, if such individual is found on redetermination to be under a disability, such redetermination shall be applied as though it had been made at the time of such prior action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any individual with a mental impairment who was found to be not disabled pursuant to an initial disability determination or a continuing eligibility review between <date date="1981-03-01">March 1, 1981</date>, and the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>], and who reapplies for benefits under title II or XVI of the Social Security Act, may be determined to be under a disability during the period considered in the most recent prior determination. Any reapplication under this paragraph must be filed within one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and benefits payable as a result of the preceding sentence shall be paid only on the basis of the reapplication.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614803-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Institution of Notification System</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s6/c">Pub. L. 98–460, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1802">98 Stat. 1802</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/460/s6/c">“The Secretary shall institute a system of notification required by the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1383b">section 1383b of this title</ref>] as soon as is practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614804-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Demonstration Projects; Opportunity for Personal Appearance Prior to Disability Determinations; Report to Congressional Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s6/d">Pub. L. 98–460, § 6(d)</ref>, (e), <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1802">98 Stat. 1802</ref>, 1803, required the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as soon as practicable after <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, to implement demonstration projects in at least five States in which the opportunity for a personal appearance prior to a determination of ineligibility for disability benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/i">42 U.S.C. 421(i)</ref> or prior to initial disability determinations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/a">42 U.S.C. 421(a)</ref>, (c), (g) and title XVI of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1381">42 U.S.C. 1381</ref> et seq.) was substituted for the face to face evidentiary hearing required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s405/b/2">42 U.S.C. 405(b)(2)</ref>, and to report to the appropriate committees of Congress by <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614805-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Promulgation of Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s9/a/2">Pub. L. 98–460, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1805">98 Stat. 1805</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/460/s9/a/2">“The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall prescribe regulations required under section 221(j) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/j">42 U.S.C. 421(j)</ref>] not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614806-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Frequency of Continuing Eligibility Reviews</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s15">Pub. L. 98–460, § 15</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1808">98 Stat. 1808</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/460/s15">“The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promulgate final regulations, within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>], which establish the standards to be used by the Secretary in determining the frequency of reviews under section 221(i) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/j">42 U.S.C. 421(j)</ref>]. Until such regulations have been issued as final regulations, no individual may be reviewed more than once under section 221(i) of the Social Security Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614807-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Travel Expenses for Medical Examinations, Reconsideration Interviews, and Proceedings Before Administrative Law Judges</heading><p>Provisions authorizing payment of travel expenses either on an actual cost or commuted basis, to an individual for travel incident to medical examinations, and to parties, their representatives and all reasonably necessary witnesses for travel within the United States, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands, to reconsider interviews and to proceedings before administrative law judges under subchapters II, XVI, and XVIII of this chapter were contained in the following appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/95/480/tII">Pub. L. 95–480, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1582">92 Stat. 1582</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/94/439/tII">Pub. L. 94–439, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1432">90 Stat. 1432</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1976-01-28">Jan. 28, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/94/206/tII">Pub. L. 94–206, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/17">90 Stat. 17</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1974-12-07">Dec. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/93/517/tII">Pub. L. 93–517, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1645">88 Stat. 1645</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1973-12-18">Dec. 18, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/93/192/tII">Pub. L. 93–192, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/759">87 Stat. 759</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1971-08-10">Aug. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/92/80/tII">Pub. L. 92–80, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/296">85 Stat. 296</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/91/667/tII">Pub. L. 91–667, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2013">84 Stat. 2013</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1970-03-05">Mar. 5, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/91/204/tII">Pub. L. 91–204, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/41">84 Stat. 41</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1968-10-11">Oct. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/90/557/tII">Pub. L. 90–557, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/988">82 Stat. 988</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1967-11-08">Nov. 8, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/90/132/tII">Pub. L. 90–132, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/402">81 Stat. 402</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1966-11-07">Nov. 7, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/89/787/tII">Pub. L. 89–787, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1395">80 Stat. 1395</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1965-08-31">Aug. 31, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/89/156/tII">Pub. L. 89–156, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/604">79 Stat. 604</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1964-09-19">Sept. 19, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/88/605/tII">Pub. L. 88–605, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/974">78 Stat. 974</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1963-10-11">Oct. 11, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/88/136/tII">Pub. L. 88–136, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/239">77 Stat. 239</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1962-08-14">Aug. 14, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/87/582/tII">Pub. L. 87–582, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/375">76 Stat. 375</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/87/290/tII">Pub. L. 87–290, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/604">75 Stat. 604</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/703/tII">Pub. L. 86–703, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/769">74 Stat. 769</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1959-08-14">Aug. 14, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/158/tII">Pub. L. 86–158, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/352">73 Stat. 352</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1958-08-01">Aug. 1, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/85/580/tII">Pub. L. 85–580, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/471">72 Stat. 471</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1957-06-29">June 29, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/85/67/tII">Pub. L. 85–67, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/221">71 Stat. 221</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-06-29/ch477">June 29, 1956, ch. 477</ref>, title II, <ref href="/us/stat/70/434">70 Stat. 434</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1955-08-01/ch437">Aug. 1, 1955, ch. 437</ref>, title II, <ref href="/us/stat/69/408">69 Stat. 408</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614808-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Decisions Rendered by Administrative Law Judges as Result of Disability Hearings; Report to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/265/tIII/s304/g">Pub. L. 96–265, title III, § 304(g)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-09">June 9, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/456">94 Stat. 456</ref>, required the Secretary of Health and Human Services to implement a program of reviewing decisions rendered by administrative law judges based on hearings under subsec. (d) of this section and to report to Congress by <date date="1982-01-01">Jan. 1, 1982</date>, on its progress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb7614809-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assumption by Secretary of Functions and Operations of State Disability Determination Units</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/265/tIII/s304/i">Pub. L. 96–265, title III, § 304(i)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-09">June 9, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/457">94 Stat. 457</ref>, directed Secretary of Health and Human Services to submit to Congress by <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, a detailed plan on how he intended to assume functions and operations of a State disability determination unit when this became necessary under amendments made by this section [amending this section], and how he intended to meet requirements of section 221(b)(3) of Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/b/3">42 U.S.C. 421(b)(3)</ref>]. Such plan was to assume the uninterrupted operation of disability determination function and utilization of best qualified personnel to carry out such function, and was to include recommendations for any amendment of Federal law or regulation required to carry out such plan.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
