<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb7745af8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431"><num value="431">§ 431.</num><heading> Benefits for certain individuals interned by United States during World War II</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb7745af9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> “Internee” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section the term “internee” means an individual who was interned during any period of time from <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, through <date date="1946-12-31">December 31, 1946</date>, at a place within the United States operated by the Government of the United States for the internment of United States citizens of Japanese ancestry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb7745afa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability in determining entitlement to and amount of monthly benefits and lump-sum death payments, and period of disability; effect of payment of benefits by other agency or instrumentality of United States</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7745afb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> For purposes of determining entitlement to and the amount of any monthly benefit for any month after December 1972, or entitlement to and the amount of any lump-sum death payment in the case of a death after such month, payable under this subchapter on the basis of the wages and self-employment income of any individual, and for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s416/i/3">section 416(i)(3) of this title</ref>, such individual shall be deemed to have been paid during any period after he attained age 18 and for which he was an internee, wages (in addition to any wages actually paid to him) at a weekly rate of basic pay during such period as follows—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7745afc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case such individual was not employed prior to the beginning of such period, 40 multiplied by the minimum hourly rate or rates in effect at any such time under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s206/a/1">section 206(a)(1) of title 29</ref>, for each full week during such period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7745afd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case such individual who was employed prior to the beginning of such period, 40 multiplied by the greater of (i) the highest hourly rate received during any such employment, or (ii) the minimum hourly rate or rates in effect at any such time under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s206/a/1">section 206(a)(1) of title 29</ref>, for each full week during such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7745afe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> This subsection shall not be applicable in the case of any monthly benefit or lump-sum death payment if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7745aff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a larger such benefit or payment, as the case may be, would be payable without its application; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7745b00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a benefit (other than a benefit payable in a lump-sum unless it is a commutation of, or a substitute for, periodic payments) which is based, in whole or in part, upon internment during any period from <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, through <date date="1946-12-31">December 31, 1946</date>, at a place within the United States operated by the Government of the United States for the internment of United States citizens of Japanese ancestry, is determined by any agency or wholly owned instrumentality of the United States to be payable by it under any other law of the United States or under a system established by such agency or instrumentality.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The provisions of clause (B) shall not apply in the case of any monthly benefit or lump-sum death payment under this subchapter if its application would reduce by $0.50 or less the primary insurance amount (as computed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s415">section 415 of this title</ref> prior to any recomputation thereof pursuant to subsection (f) of such section) of the individual on whose wages and self-employment income such benefit or payment is based. The provisions of clause (B) shall also not apply for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s416/i/3">section 416(i)(3) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb776a4f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon application for benefits, a recalculation of benefits (by reason of this section), or a lump-sum death payment on the basis of the wages and self-employment income of any individual who was an internee, the Commissioner of Social Security shall accept the certification of the Secretary of Defense or his designee concerning any period of time for which an internee is to receive credit under paragraph (1) and shall make a decision without regard to clause (B) of paragraph (2) of this subsection unless the Commissioner has been notified by some other agency or instrumentality of the United States that, on the basis of the period for which such individual was an internee, a benefit described in clause (B) of paragraph (2) has been determined by such agency or instrumentality to be payable by it. If the Commissioner of Social Security has not been so notified, the Commissioner shall then ascertain whether some other agency or wholly owned instrumentality of the United States has decided that a benefit described in clause (B) of paragraph (2) is payable by it. If any such agency or instrumentality has decided, or thereafter decides, that such a benefit is payable by it, it shall so notify the Commissioner of Social Security, and the Commissioner of Social Security shall certify no further benefits for payment or shall recompute the amount of any further benefits payable, as may be required by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb776a4f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any agency or wholly owned instrumentality of the United States which is authorized by any law of the United States to pay benefits, or has a system of benefits which are based, in whole or in part, on any period for which any individual was an internee shall, at the request of the Commissioner of Social Security, certify to the Commissioner, with respect to any individual who was an internee, such information as the Commissioner of Social Security deems necessary to carry out the Commissioner’s functions under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb776a4f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s431/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Trust Funds and the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for the fiscal year ending <date date="1978-06-30">June 30, 1978</date>, such sums as the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary jointly determine would place the Trust Funds and the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund in the position in which they would have been if the preceding provisions of this section had not been enacted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb776a4f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title II, § 231, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tI/s142/a">Pub. L. 92–603, title I, § 142(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1367">86 Stat. 1367</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/j/2/A/iii">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(j)(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1170">98 Stat. 1170</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s107/a/1">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 107(a)(1)</ref>, (4), (c), <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1477">108 Stat. 1477</ref>, 1478, 1481.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb776a4f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb776a4f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb776a4f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s107/a/1">Pub. L. 103–296, § 107(a)(1)</ref>, (4), substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary of Health and Human Services” after “an internee, the”, after “If the”, and after “so notify the”, substituted “the Commissioner” for “he” before “has been notified” and before “shall then ascertain”, and substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” before “shall certify no”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s107/a/1">Pub. L. 103–296, § 107(a)(1)</ref>, (4), substituted “Commissioner of Social Security, certify to the Commissioner, with respect to any individual who was an internee, such information as the Commissioner of Social Security deems necessary to carry out the Commissioner’s functions under paragraph (3) of this subsection” for “Secretary of Health and Human Services, certify to him, with respect to any individual who was an internee, such information as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out his functions under paragraph (3) of this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s107/c">Pub. L. 103–296, § 107(c)</ref>, substituted “Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary jointly determine” for “Secretary determines”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> substituted “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb776a4f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb776a4f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb776a4fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb776a4fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special $50 Payment Under Tax Reduction Act of 1975</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Special payment of $50 as soon as practicable after <date date="1975-03-29">Mar. 29, 1975</date>, by the Secretary of the Treasury to each individual who, for the month of March 1975, was entitled to a monthly insurance benefit payable under this subchapter, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/12/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 94–12</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">section 402 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
