<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcd41673-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4501"><num value="4501">§ 4501.</num><heading> Congressional statement of purpose</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the policy of the Congress and the purpose of this chapter to provide for the development of a national urban policy and to encourage the rational, orderly, efficient, and economic growth, development, and redevelopment of our States, metropolitan areas, cities, counties, towns, and communities in predominantly rural areas which demonstrate a special potential for accelerated growth; to encourage the prudent use and conservation of energy and our natural resources; and to encourage and support development which will assure our communities and their residents of adequate tax bases, community services, job opportunities, and good housing in well-balanced neighborhoods in socially, economically, and physically attractive living environments.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbcd41674-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/609/tVII/s701/b">Pub. L. 91–609, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1791">84 Stat. 1791</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/128/tVI/s601/a/2">Pub. L. 95–128, title VI, § 601(a)(2)</ref>–(5), <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1143">91 Stat. 1143</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcd41675-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcd41676-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcd41677-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/91/609">Pub. L. 91–609</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1791">84 Stat. 1791</ref>, known as the Urban Growth and New Community Development Act of 1970, which enacted this chapter, amended sections 1453, 1460, and 1492 of this title, sections 371 and 1464 of Title 12, Banks and Banking, and section 461 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1453 and 4501 of this title. For complete classification of title VII to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcd41678-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/128">Pub. L. 95–128</ref> substituted “national urban policy” for “national urban growth policy”, encouraged prudent use and conservation of energy, and provided for the assurance of the residents of the communities, and of good housing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcd41679-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idbcd4167a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/609/tVII/s701/a">Section 701(a) of title VII of Pub. L. 91–609</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/128/tVI/s601/a/1">Pub. L. 95–128, title VI, § 601(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1142">91 Stat. 1142</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/128/tVI/s601/a/1">“This title [enacting this chapter, amending sections 1453, 1460, and 1492, of this title, sections 371 and 1464 of Title 12, Banks and Banking, and section 461 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1453">section 1453 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘National Urban Policy and New Community Development Act of 1970’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
