<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcd416d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541"><num value="4541">§ 4541.</num><heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd416d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> alcohol is one of the most dangerous drugs and the drug most frequently abused in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> approximately ten million, or 7 percent, of the adults in the United States are alcoholics or problem drinkers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> it is estimated that alcoholism and other alcohol related problems cost the United States over $43,000,000,000 annually in lost production, medical and public assistance expenditures, police and court costs, and motor vehicle and other accidents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> alcohol abuse is found with increasing frequency among persons who are multiple-drug abusers and among former heroin users who are being treated in methadone maintenance programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> alcohol abuse is being discovered among growning numbers of youth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> alcohol abuse and alcoholism have a substantial impact on the families of alcohol abusers and alcoholics and contributes to domestic violence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> alcohol abuse and alcoholism, together with abuse of other legal and illegal drugs, present a need for prevention and intervention programs designed to reach the general population and members of high risk populations such as youth, women, the elderly, and families of alcohol abusers and alcoholics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> alcoholism is an illness requiring treatment and rehabilitation through the assistance of a broad range of community health and social services and with the cooperation of law enforcement agencies, employers, employee associations, and associations of concerned individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd416e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> It is the policy of the United States and the purpose of this chapter to approach alcohol abuse and alcoholism from a comprehensive community care standpoint, and to meet the problems of alcohol abuse and alcoholism through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> comprehensive Federal, State, and local planning for, and effective use of, Federal assistance to States, and direct Federal assistance to community-based programs to meet the urgent needs of special populations, in coordination with all other governmental and nongovernmental sources of assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the development of methods for diverting problem drinkers from criminal justice systems into prevention and treatment programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the development and encouragement of prevention programs designed to combat the spread of alcoholism, alcohol abuse, and abuse of other legal and illegal drugs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the development and encouragement of effective occupational prevention and treatment programs within government and in cooperation with the private sector; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd416e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4541/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> increased Federal commitment to research into the behavioral and biomedical etiology of, the treatment of, and the mental and physical health and social and economic consequences of, alcohol abuse and alcoholism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcd416e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/616/s2">Pub. L. 91–616, § 2</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/282/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 93–282, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/126">88 Stat. 126</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/371/s2">Pub. L. 94–371, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-07-26">July 26, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1035">90 Stat. 1035</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/622/tII/s268/a">Pub. L. 95–622, title II, § 268(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3437">92 Stat. 3437</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1301">93 Stat. 1301</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcd416e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcd416e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcd416e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/91/616">Pub. L. 91–616</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1848">84 Stat. 1848</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism Prevention, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Act of 1970. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcd416ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2/a">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted current findings of number of alcoholics or problem drinkers in the country (approximately ten million or 7 percent of the adults) for 1974 findings of number of alcohol abusers and alcoholics of estimated number of ninety-five million drinkers in the Nation (minimum of nine million or 7 per centum of the adults).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2/a">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted current findings respecting annual cost of over $43,000,000,000 to the United States for alcoholism and other related problems in lost production, motor vehicle and other accidents, and other items, for 1974 findings respecting minimum annual problem drinking costs of $15,000,000 to the national economy in lost working time and identical other items.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, inserted congressional finding respecting contribution of alcohol abuse and alcoholism to domestic violence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2/b/3">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, added par. (7). Former par. (7) redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated former par. (7) as (8) and enlisted cooperation of employers, employee associations, and associations of concerned individuals in treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2/c/1">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s2/c/3">Pub. L. 96–180, § 2(c)(3)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4) and redesignated former par. (3) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/95/622">Pub. L. 95–622</ref> added par. (6) and redesignated former par. (6) as (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/371">Pub. L. 94–371</ref> restructured provisions and inserted authorization for increased Federal commitment to research into the behavioral and biomedical etiology of alcohol abuse and alcoholism and the treatment and consequences of alcohol abuse and alcoholism.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcd416eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idbcd416ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s1/a">Pub. L. 96–180, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1301">93 Stat. 1301</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/180/s1/a">“This Act [enacting section 4594, amending this section and sections 4551 to 4553, 4561, 4571 to 4573, 4576 to 4578, 4585, 4587, and 4588 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4552">section 4552 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism Prevention, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1979’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idbcd416ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/371/s1">Pub. L. 94–371, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-07-26">July 26, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1035">90 Stat. 1035</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/371/s1">“That this Act [enacting sections 4578 and 4585 to 4588 of this title, amending this section, sections 218, 3511, 4571 to 4573, 4576, 4577, and 4581 of this title, and sections 1176 and 1177 of Title 21, Food and Drugs, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 4573 and 4577 of this title, and sections 1176 and 1177 of Title 21] may be cited as the ‘Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism Prevention, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1976’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idbcd416ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1974 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/282/tI/s101">Pub. L. 93–282, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/126">88 Stat. 126</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/282/tI/s101">“This title [enacting this section and sections 4542, 4553, 4576, and 4577 of this title, amending sections 242a, 4571, 4572, 4573, 4581, and 4582 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 4581 and 4582 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism Prevention, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1974’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idbcd416ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/616/s1">Pub. L. 91–616, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1848">84 Stat. 1848</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/616/s1">“This Act [enacting this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2688j–2">section 2688j–2 of this title</ref> and amending sections 218, 246, 2688h and 2688t of this title] may be cited as the ‘Comprehensive Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism Prevention, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Act of 1970’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbcd416f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Commission on Alcoholism and Other Alcohol-Related Problems; Establishment; Executive Secretary; Interim and Final Reports of Study; Termination; Authorization of Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/180/s18">Pub. L. 96–180, § 18</ref>, <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1306">93 Stat. 1306</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/24/s5/a/2">Pub. L. 98–24, § 5(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-26">Apr. 26, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/183">97 Stat. 183</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/stat/93/695">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> There is established a Commission to be known as the National Commission on Alcoholism and Other Alcohol-Related Problems (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Commission’). The Commission shall be composed of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> four Members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate upon the recommendation of the majority and minority leaders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> four Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives upon the recommendation of the majority and minority leaders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> nine public members appointed by the President; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> not more than four nonvoting members appointed by the President from individuals employed in the administration of programs of the Federal Government which affect the prevention and treatment of alcoholism and the rehabilitation of alcoholics and alcohol abusers.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">At no time shall more than two members appointed under subparagraph (A), more that two of the members appointed under subparagraph (B), or more than five of the members appointed under subparagraph (C) be members of the same political party.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The President shall designate one of the members of the Commission as Chairman, and one as Vice Chairman. Nine members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may conduct hearings. Members appointed under paragraph (1)(D) shall not be considered in determining a quorum of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of the duties vested in the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairman or at the call of the majority of the members thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Commission may appoint, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, an executive secretary to assist the Commission in carrying out its functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide the Commission with such additional professional and clerical staff, such information, and the services of such consultants as the Secretary determines necessary for the Commission to carry out effectively its functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Commission may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable it to carry out its duties under this section. Upon request of the Chairman of the Commission, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission consistent with applicable laws and regulations with respect to the privacy of medical records.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The Commission shall conduct a study of alcoholism and alcohol-related problems and shall include in the study—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an assessment of unmet treatment and rehabilitation needs of alcoholics and their families;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> an assessment of personnel needs in the fields of research, treatment, rehabilitation, and prevention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an assessment of the integration and financing of alcoholism treatment and rehabilitation into health and social health care services within communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> a study of the relationship of alcohol use to aggressive behavior and crime;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> a study of the relationship of alcohol use to family violence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> a study of the relationship of alcoholism to illnesses, particularly those illnesses with a high stress component, among family members of alcoholics;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> an evaluation of the effectiveness of prevention programs, including the relevance of alcohol control laws and regulations to alcoholism and alcohol-related problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> a survey of the unmet research needs in the area of alcoholism and alcohol-related problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> a survey of the prevalence of occupational alcoholism and alcohol abuse programs offered by Federal contractors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> an evaluation of the needs of special and underserved population groups, including American Indians, Alaskan Natives, Native Hawaiians, Native American Pacific Islanders, youth, the elderly, women, and the handicapped and assess the adequacy of existing services to fulfill such needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The Commission shall submit to the President and the Congress such interim reports as it deems advisable and shall within two years after the date on which funds first become available to carry out this section submit to the President and the Congress a final report which shall contain a detailed statement of its findings and conclusions and also such recommendations for legislation and administrative actions as it deems appropriate. The Commission shall cease to exist sixty days after the final report is submitted under this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall be responsible for the coordination of the activities of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of this section $1,000,000 to remain available until the expiration of the Commission.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
