<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcd8d0d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622"><num value="4622">§ 4622.</num><heading> Moving and related expenses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcd8d0d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General provision</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a program or project to be undertaken by a displacing agency will result in the displacement of any person, the head of the displacing agency shall provide for the payment to the displaced person of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> actual reasonable expenses in moving himself, his family, business, farm operation, or other personal property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> actual direct losses of tangible personal property as a result of moving or discontinuing a business or farm operation, but not to exceed an amount equal to the reasonable expenses that would have been required to relocate such property, as determined by the head of the agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> actual reasonable expenses in searching for a replacement business or farm; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> actual reasonable expenses necessary to reestablish a displaced farm, nonprofit organization, or small business at its new site, but not to exceed $25,000, as adjusted by regulation, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4633/d">section 4633(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcd8d0d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Displacement from dwelling; election of payments: expense and dislocation allowance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any displaced person eligible for payments under subsection (a) of this section who is displaced from a dwelling and who elects to accept the payments authorized by this subsection in lieu of the payments authorized by subsection (a) of this section may receive an expense and dislocation allowance, which shall be determined according to a schedule established by the head of the lead agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcd8d0d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Displacement from business or farm operation; election of payments; minimum and maximum amounts; eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any displaced person eligible for payments under subsection (a) of this section who is displaced from the person’s place of business or farm operation and who is eligible under criteria established by the head of the lead agency may elect to accept the payment authorized by this subsection in lieu of the payment authorized by subsection (a) of this section. Such payment shall consist of a fixed payment in an amount to be determined according to criteria established by the head of the lead agency, except that such payment shall not be less than $1,000 nor more than $40,000, as adjusted by regulation, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4633/d">section 4633(d) of this title</ref>. A person whose sole business at the displacement dwelling is the rental of such property to others shall not qualify for a payment under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcd8d0d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain utility relocation expenses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd8d0da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as otherwise provided by Federal law—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if a program or project (i) which is undertaken by a displacing agency, and (ii) the purpose of which is not to relocate or reconstruct any utility facility, results in the relocation of a utility facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the owner of the utility facility which is being relocated under such program or project has entered into, with the State or local government on whose property, easement, or right-of-way such facility is located, a franchise or similar agreement with respect to the use of such property, easement, or right-of-way; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if the relocation of such facility results in such owner incurring an extraordinary cost in connection with such relocation;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the displacing agency may, in accordance with such regulations as the head of the lead agency may issue, provide to such owner a relocation payment which may not exceed the amount of such extraordinary cost (less any increase in the value of the new utility facility above the value of the old utility facility and less any salvage value derived from the old utility facility).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd8d0de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> “extraordinary cost in connection with a relocation” means any cost incurred by the owner of a utility facility in connection with relocation of such facility which is determined by the head of the displacing agency, under such regulations as the head of the lead agency shall issue—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd8d0e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to be a non-routine relocation expense;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd8d0e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to be a cost such owner ordinarily does not include in its annual budget as an expense of operation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd8d0e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to meet such other requirements as the lead agency may prescribe in such regulations; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd8d0e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> “utility facility” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd8d0e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any electric, gas, water, steam power, or materials transmission or distribution system;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd8d0e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any transportation system;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd8d0e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any communications system (including cable television); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd8d0e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4622/d/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any fixtures, equipment, or other property associated with the operation, maintenance, or repair of any such system;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">located on property which is owned by a State or local government or over which a State or local government has an easement or right-of-way. A utility facility may be publicly, privately, or cooperatively owned.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcd8d0e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/646/tII/s202">Pub. L. 91–646, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1895">84 Stat. 1895</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/tIV/s405">Pub. L. 100–17, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/249">101 Stat. 249</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1521/a">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1521(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/577">126 Stat. 577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcd8d0e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcd8d0ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcd8d0eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1521/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1521(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “$25,000, as adjusted by regulation, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4633/d">section 4633(d) of this title</ref>” for “$10,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1521/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1521(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “$40,000, as adjusted by regulation, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4633/d">section 4633(d) of this title</ref>” for “$20,000” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s405/a/1">Pub. L. 100–17, § 405(a)(1)</ref>, inserted introductory provisions and struck out former introductory provisions which read as follows: “Whenever the acquisition of real property for a program or project undertaken by a Federal agency in any State will result in the displacement of any person on or after <date date="1971-01-02">January 2, 1971</date>, the head of such agency shall make a payment to any displaced person, upon proper application as approved by such agency head, for—”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s405/a/2">Pub. L. 100–17, § 405(a)(2)</ref>–(4), added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s405/b">Pub. L. 100–17, § 405(b)</ref>, substituted “an expense and dislocation allowance, which shall be determined according to a schedule established by the head of the lead agency” for “a moving expense allowance, determined according to a schedule established by the head of the Federal agency, not to exceed $300; and a dislocation allowance of $200”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s405/c">Pub. L. 100–17, § 405(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “Any displaced person eligible for payments under subsection (a) of this section who is displaced from his place of business or from his farm operation and who elects to accept the payment authorized by this subsection in lieu of the payment authorized by subsection (a) of this section, may receive a fixed payment in an amount equal to the average annual net earnings of the business or farm operation, except that such payment shall be not less than $2,500 nor more than $10,000. In the case of a business no payment shall be made under this subsection unless the head of the Federal agency is satisfied that the business (1) cannot be relocated without a substantial loss of its existing patronage, and (2) is not a part of a commercial enterprise having at least one other establishment not being acquired by the United States, which is engaged in the same or similar business. For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘average annual net earnings’ means one-half of any net earnings of the business or farm operation, before Federal, State, and local income taxes, during the two taxable years immediately preceding the taxable year in which such business or farm operation moves from the real property acquired for such project, or during such other period as the head of such agency determines to be more equitable for establishing such earnings, and includes any compensation paid by the business or farm operation to the owner, his spouse, or his dependents during such period.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s405/d">Pub. L. 100–17, § 405(d)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcd8d0ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcd8d0ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective 2 years after the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1521/g">section 1521(g) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s308">section 308 of Title 23</ref>, Highways.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcd8d0ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/17">Pub. L. 100–17</ref> effective on effective date provided in regulations promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4633">section 4633 of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s412">section 412 of Pub. L. 100–17</ref>), but not later than 2 years after <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 100–17</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4601">section 4601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
