<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcdb1b31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4631"><num value="4631">§ 4631.</num><heading> Federal share of costs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcdb1b32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4631/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost to displacing agency; eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The cost to a displacing agency of providing payments and assistance under this subchapter and subchapter III of this chapter shall be included as part of the cost of a program or project undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance. A displacing agency, other than a Federal agency, shall be eligible for Federal financial assistance with respect to such payments and assistance in the same manner and to the same extent as other program or project costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcdb1b33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4631/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Comparable payments under other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No payment or assistance under this subchapter or subchapter III of this chapter shall be required to be made to any person or included as a program or project cost under this section, if such person receives a payment required by Federal, State, or local law which is determined by the head of the Federal agency to have substantially the same purpose and effect as such payment under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcdb1b34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4631/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements prior to <date date="1971-01-02">January 2, 1971</date>; advancements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any grant to, or contract or agreement with, a State agency executed before <date date="1971-01-02">January 2, 1971</date>, under which Federal financial assistance is available to pay all or part of the cost of any program or project which will result in the displacement of any person on or after <date date="1971-01-02">January 2, 1971</date>, shall be amended to include the cost of providing payments and services under sections 4630 and 4655 of this title. If the head of a Federal agency determines that it is necessary for the expeditious completion of a program or project he may advance to the State agency the Federal share of the cost of any payments or assistance by such State agency pursuant to sections 4626, 4630, 4635, and 4655 of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcdb1b35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/646/tII/s211">Pub. L. 91–646, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1900">84 Stat. 1900</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 100–17, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/254">101 Stat. 254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcdb1b36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcdb1b37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcdb1b38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter III of this chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “title III of this Act”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/646">Pub. L. 91–646</ref>, <date date="1971-01-02">Jan. 2, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1904">84 Stat. 1904</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter III of this chapter. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcdb1b39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s411/a">Pub. L. 100–17, § 411(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The cost to a State agency of providing payments and assistance pursuant to sections 4626, 4630, 4635, and 4655 of this title, shall be included as part of the cost of a program or project for which Federal financial assistance is available to such State agency, and such State agency shall be eligible for Federal financial assistance with respect to such payments and assistance in the same manner and to the same extent as other program or project costs, except that, notwithstanding any other law in the case where the Federal financial assistance is by grant or contribution the Federal agency shall pay the full amount of the first $25,000 of the cost to a State agency of providing payments and assistance for a displaced person under sections 4626, 4630, 4635, and 4655 of this title, on account of any acquisition or displacement occurring prior to <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, and in any case where such Federal financial assistance is by loan, the Federal agency shall loan such State agency the full amount of the first $25,000 of such cost.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s411/b">Pub. L. 100–17, § 411(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “No payment or assistance under section 4630 or 4655 of this title shall be required or included as a program or project cost under this section, if the displaced person receives a payment required by the State law of eminent domain which is determined by such Federal agency head to have substantially the same purpose and effect as such payment under this section, and to be part of the cost of the program or project for which Federal financial assistance is available.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcdb1b3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcdb1b3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/17">Pub. L. 100–17</ref> effective on effective date provided in regulations promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4633">section 4633 of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s412">section 412 of Pub. L. 100–17</ref>), but not later than 2 years after <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 100–17</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4601">section 4601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
