<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbce4b7ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a"><num value="4852a">§ 4852a.</num><heading> Task force on lead-based paint hazard reduction and financing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce4b7ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall establish a task force to make recommendations on expanding resources and efforts to evaluate and reduce lead-based paint hazards in private housing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce4b7ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The task force shall include individuals representing the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Farmers Home Administration, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Environmental Protection Agency, employee organizations in the building and construction trades industry, landlords, tenants, primary lending institutions, private mortgage insurers, single-family and multifamily real estate interests, nonprofit housing developers, property liability insurers, public housing agencies, low-income housing advocacy organizations, national, State and local lead-poisoning prevention advocates and experts, and community-based organizations located in areas with substantial rental housing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce4b7ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The task force shall make recommendations to the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency concerning—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> incorporating the need to finance lead-based paint hazard reduction into underwriting standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> developing new loan products and procedures for financing lead-based paint hazard evaluation and reduction activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> adjusting appraisal guidelines to address lead safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> incorporating risk assessments or inspections for lead-based paint as a routine procedure in the origination of new residential mortgages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> revising guidelines, regulations, and educational pamphlets issued by the Department of Housing and Urban Development and other Federal agencies relating to lead-based paint poisoning prevention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> reducing the current uncertainties of liability related to lead-based paint in rental housing by clarifying standards of care for landlords and lenders, and by exploring the “safe harbor” concept;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> increasing the availability of liability insurance for owners of rental housing and certified contractors and establishing alternative systems to compensate victims of lead-based paint poisoning; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce4b7f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> evaluating the utility and appropriateness of requiring risk assessments or inspections and notification to prospective lessees of rental housing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce4b7f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4852a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The members of the task force shall not receive Federal compensation for their participation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbce4b7f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tX/s1015">Pub. L. 102–550, title X, § 1015</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3908">106 Stat. 3908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
