<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbce728d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909"><num value="4909">§ 4909.</num><heading> Prohibited acts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce728d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b), the following acts or the causing thereof are prohibited:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce728d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of a manufacturer, to distribute in commerce any new product manufactured after the effective date of a regulation prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4905">section 4905 of this title</ref> which is applicable to such product, except in conformity with such regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce728d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce728d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The removal or rendering inoperative by any person, other than for purposes of maintenance, repair, or replacement, of any device or element of design incorporated into any product in compliance with regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4905">section 4905 of this title</ref>, prior to its sale or delivery to the ultimate purchaser or while it is in use, or (B) the use of a product after such device or element of design has been removed or rendered inoperative by any person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce728d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the case of a manufacturer, to distribute in commerce any new product manufactured after the effective date of a regulation prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4907/b">section 4907(b) of this title</ref> (requiring information respecting noise) which is applicable to such product, except in conformity with such regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce728d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The removal by any person of any notice affixed to a product or container pursuant to regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4907/b">section 4907(b) of this title</ref>, prior to sale of the product to the ultimate purchaser.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce728d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The importation into the United States by any person of any new product in violation of a regulation prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4908">section 4908 of this title</ref> which is applicable to such product.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce728da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The failure or refusal by any person to comply with any requirement of section 4910(d) or 4912(a) of this title or regulations prescribed under section 4912(a), 4916, or 4917 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce728db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce728dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the purpose of research, investigations, studies, demonstrations, or training, or for reasons of national security, the Administrator may exempt for a specified period of time any product, or class thereof, from paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (5) of subsection (a), upon such terms and conditions as he may find necessary to protect the public health or welfare.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce728dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4909/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any product which is manufactured solely for use outside any State and which (and the container of which) is labeled or otherwise marked to show that it is manufactured solely for use outside any State; except that such paragraphs shall apply to such product if it is in fact distributed in commerce for use in any State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbce728de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/574/s10">Pub. L. 92–574, § 10</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1242">86 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
