<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbce97398-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953"><num value="4953">§ 4953.</num><heading> Selection and assignment of volunteers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce97399-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered projects and programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director, on the receipt of applications by public or nonprofit private organizations to receive volunteers under this part, may assign volunteers selected under subsection (b) to work in appropriate projects and programs sponsored by such organizations, including work—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce9739a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in meeting the health, education, welfare, or related needs of Indians living on reservations or Federal trust lands, of migratory and seasonal farmworkers and their families, and of residents of the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce9739b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the care and rehabilitation of mentally ill, developmentally disabled, and other individuals with disabilities, especially individuals with severe disabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce9739c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in addressing the problems of the homeless, unemployed individuals, and low-income youths;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce9739d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in addressing the special needs connected with alcohol and drug abuse through prevention, education, rehabilitation, treatment, and related activities, consistent with the purpose of this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce9739e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> in addressing significant health care problems, including mental illness, chronic and life-threatening illnesses, and health care for homeless individuals (especially homeless children) through prevention, treatment, and community-based care activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce9739f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> in connection with programs or activities authorized, supported, or of a character eligible for assistance under this chapter or the Community Service Block Grant Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">42 U.S.C. 9901</ref> et seq.], titles VIII and X of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2991">42 U.S.C. 2991</ref> et seq., 2996 et seq.], the Head Start Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9831">42 U.S.C. 9831</ref> et seq.], the Community Economic Development Act of 1981 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9801">42 U.S.C. 9801</ref> et seq.], or other similar Acts, in furtherance of the purpose of this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> in strengthening, supplementing, and expanding efforts to address the problem of illiteracy throughout the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> in assisting with the reentry and reintegration of formerly incarcerated youth and adults into society, including providing training and counseling in education, employment, and life skills;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> in developing and carrying out financial literacy, financial planning, budgeting, saving, and reputable credit accessibility programs in low-income communities, including those programs that educate individuals about financing home ownership and higher education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> in initiating and supporting before-school and after-school programs, serving children in low-income communities, that may engage participants in mentoring, tutoring, life skills and study skills programs, service-learning, physical, nutrition, and health education programs, and other activities addressing the needs of the children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> in establishing and supporting community economic development initiatives, with a priority on work on such initiatives in rural areas and the other areas where such initiatives are needed most;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> in assisting veterans and their family members through establishing or augmenting programs that assist such persons with access to legal assistance, health care (including mental health care), employment counseling or training, education counseling or training, affordable housing, and other support services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> in addressing the health and wellness of individuals in low-income communities and individuals in underserved communities, including programs to increase access to preventive services, insurance, and health services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recruitment and placement procedures for local and national placement of volunteers; establishment, requirements, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director shall establish placement procedures that involve sponsoring organizations and that offer opportunities for both local and national placement of volunteers for service under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director shall establish and maintain within the national headquarters of the Corporation (or any successor entity of such agency) a volunteer placement office which shall be responsible for all functions related to the recruitment and placement of volunteers under this part. Such functions and activities shall be carried out in coordination or in conjunction with recruitment and placement activities carried out under the National and Community Service Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12501">42 U.S.C. 12501</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Such volunteer placement office shall develop, operate, and maintain a current and comprehensive database that provides information—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to individuals, with respect to specific opportunities for service as a volunteer with approved projects or programs to which no volunteer has been assigned; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to approved projects or programs, with respect to the availability of individuals whose applications for service as a volunteer have been approved and who are awaiting an assignment with a specific project or program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Director shall assign or hire as necessary, such additional national, regional, and State personnel to carry out the functions described in this subsection and subsection (c) as may be necessary to ensure that such functions are carried out in a timely and effective manner. The Director shall give priority in the hiring of such additional personnel to individuals who have formerly served as volunteers under this part and to individuals who have specialized experience in the recruitment and management of volunteers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Volunteers shall be selected from among qualified individuals submitting an application for such service at such time, in such form, and containing such information as may be necessary to evaluate the suitability of each individual for such service and to determine, in accordance with paragraph (7),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003379">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003379"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be paragraph “(5)”.</note> the most appropriate assignment for each such volunteer. The Director shall approve the application of each individual who applies in conformance with this subsection and who, on the basis of the information provided in the application, is determined by the Director to be qualified to serve as a volunteer under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director shall ensure that applications for service as a volunteer under this part are available to the public on request to the Corporation (including any State or regional offices of the Agency) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003380">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003380"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “the Corporation)”.</note> and that an individual making such request is informed of the manner in which such application is required to be submitted. A completed application may be submitted by any interested individual to, and shall be accepted by, any office of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director shall provide for the assignment of each applicant approved as a volunteer under this part to a project or program that is, to the maximum extent practicable, consistent with the abilities, experiences, and preferences of such applicant that are set forth in the application described in paragraph (4) and the needs and preferences of projects or programs approved for the assignment of such volunteers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Director shall utilize the database established under paragraph (2)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A sponsoring organization of VISTA may recruit volunteers for service under this part. The Director shall give a locally recruited volunteer priority for placement in the sponsoring organization of VISTA that recruited such volunteer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A volunteer under this part shall not be assigned to any project or program without the express approval and consent of such project or program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> If an applicant under this part who is recruited locally becomes unavailable for service prior to the commencement of service, the recipient of the project grant or contract that was designated to receive the services of such applicant may replace such applicant with another qualified applicant approved by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/b/5/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> If feasible and appropriate, low-income community volunteers shall be given the option of serving in the home communities of such volunteers in teams with nationally recruited specialist volunteers. The Director shall attempt to assign such volunteers to serve in the home or nearby communities of such volunteers and shall make national efforts to attract other individuals to serve in the VISTA program. The Director shall also, in the assignment of volunteers under this subparagraph, recognize that community-identified needs that cannot be met in the local area and the individual desires of VISTA volunteers in regard to the service in various geographical areas of the United States should be taken into consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Public awareness and recruit activities; dissemination of information; reimbursement of costs; coordination; obligation of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Director, in conjunction with the personnel described in subsection (b)(2)(C), shall engage in public awareness and recruitment activities. Such activities may include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> public service announcements through the Internet and related technologies, radio, television, and the print media;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> advertising through the Internet and related technologies, print media, direct mail, and other means;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> disseminating information about opportunities for service as a volunteer under this part to relevant entities including institutions of higher education and other educational institutions (including libraries), professional associations, community-based agencies, youth service and volunteer organizations, business organizations, labor unions, senior citizens organizations, State or local offices of economic development, State employment security agencies, employment offices, and other institutions and organizations from or through which potential volunteers may be recruited;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> disseminating such information through presentations made personally by employees of the Corporation or other designees of the Director, to students and faculty at institutions of higher education and to other entities described in subparagraph (C), including presentations made at the facilities, conventions, or other meetings of such entities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> publicizing the student loan deferment and forgiveness opportunities available to VISTA volunteers under parts B and E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1071">20 U.S.C. 1071</ref> et seq., 1087aa et seq.] and including such information in all applications and recruitment materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> publicizing national service educational awards available under the National and Community Service Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12501">42 U.S.C. 12501</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> providing, on request, technical assistance with the recruitment of volunteers under this part to programs and projects receiving assistance under this part; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbce973c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> maintaining and publicizing a national toll-free telephone number through which individuals may obtain information about opportunities for service as a volunteer under this part and request and receive an application for such service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In designing and implementing the activities authorized under this section, the Director shall seek to involve individuals who have formerly served as volunteers under this part to assist in the dissemination of information concerning the program established under this part. The Director may reimburse the costs incurred by such former volunteers for such participation, including expenses incurred for travel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbce973c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Director shall consult with the Director of the Peace Corps to coordinate the recruitment and public awareness activities carried out under this subsection with those of the Peace Corps and to develop joint procedures and activities for the recruitment of volunteers to serve under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of plans to volunteers for job advancement; coordination with private industry councils or local workforce investment boards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall provide each low-income community volunteer with an individual plan for job advancement or for transition to a situation leading to gainful employment. Whenever feasible, such efforts shall be coordinated with an appropriate local workforce development board established under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3122">section 3122 of title 29</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Educational and vocational counseling for volunteers; Director to provide</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director may provide or arrange for educational and vocational counseling of volunteers and recent former volunteers under this part to (1) encourage them to use, in the national interest, the skills and experience which they have derived from their training and service, particularly working in combating poverty as members of the helping professions, and (2) promote the development of appropriate opportunities for the use of such skills and experience, and the placement therein of such volunteers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions; restrictions on political activities; place of service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (e), the assignment of volunteers under this section shall be on such terms and conditions (including restrictions on political activities that appropriately recognize the special status of volunteers living among the persons or groups served by programs to which they have been assigned) as the Director may determine, including work assignments in their own or nearby communities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Program or project submittal to Governor; commencement and termination of service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Volunteers under this part shall not be assigned to work in a program or project in any community unless the application for such program or project contains evidence of local support and has been submitted to the Governor or other chief executive officer of the State concerned. In the event of a timely request in writing, supported by a statement of reasons, by the Governor or other chief executive officer of the State concerned, the Director shall terminate a program or proj­ect or the assignment of a volunteer to a program or project not later than 30 days after the date such request is received by the Director, or at such later date as is agreed upon by the Director and such Governor or other chief executive officer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director is encouraged to enter into agreements with other Federal agencies to use VISTA volunteers in furtherance of program objectives that are consistent with the purposes described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4951">section 4951 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbce973c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s4953/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements with nonprofit organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director may enter into agreements under which public and private nonprofit organizations, with sufficient financial capacity and size, pay for all or a portion of the costs of supporting the service of volunteers under this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbce973ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/113/tI/s103">Pub. L. 93–113, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/396">87 Stat. 396</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/143/s2">Pub. L. 96–143, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-12-13">Dec. 13, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1074">93 Stat. 1074</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/a">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(a)</ref>–(c)(1), (d), <date date="1984-05-21">May 21, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/189">98 Stat. 189</ref>, 190; <ref href="/us/pl/99/551/s3/a">Pub. L. 99–551, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3071">100 Stat. 3071</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 101–204, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, (b), (d)(2), title VII, § 701, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1807">103 Stat. 1807</ref>, 1809, 1811, 1820; <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tIII/s323">Pub. L. 103–82, title III, § 323</ref>, title IV, § 405(a)(2)–(4), <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/899">107 Stat. 899</ref>, 920; <ref href="/us/pl/103/304/s3/b/7">Pub. L. 103–304, § 3(b)(7)</ref>, (8), <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1568">108 Stat. 1568</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/36/A">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(36)(A), (f)(28)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–427, 2681–434; <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/tII/s2102">Pub. L. 111–13, title II, § 2102</ref>, <date date="2009-04-21">Apr. 21, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1582">123 Stat. 1582</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tV/s512/h">Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(h)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1708">128 Stat. 1708</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbce973cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbce973cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbce973cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/113">Pub. L. 93–113</ref>, <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/394">87 Stat. 394</ref>, known as the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Community Service Block Grant Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), probably means the Community Services Block Grant Act, which is subtitle B (§ 671 et seq.) of title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/511">95 Stat. 511</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 106 (§ 9901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">section 9901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/452">Pub. L. 88–452</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/508">78 Stat. 508</ref>. Titles VIII and X of the Act are classified generally to subchapters VIII (§ 2991 et seq.) and X (§ 2996 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 34 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Head Start Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), is subchapter B (§§ 635–657) of chapter 8 of subtitle A of title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/499">95 Stat. 499</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 9831 et seq.) of chapter 105 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9801">section 9801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Community Economic Development Act of 1981, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), is subchapter A (§§ 611–633) of chapter 8 of subtitle A of title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/489">95 Stat. 489</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 9801 et seq.) of chapter 105 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9801">section 9801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National and Community Service Act of 1990, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2)(A) and (c)(1)(F), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/610">Pub. L. 101–610</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3127">104 Stat. 3127</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 129 (§ 12501 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12501">section 12501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Higher Education Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(E), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/329">Pub. L. 89–329</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1219">79 Stat. 1219</ref>. Parts B and E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 are classified to parts B (§ 1071 et seq.) and E (§ 1087aa et seq.), respectively, of subchapter IV of chapter 28 of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbce973ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> substituted “employment. Whenever feasible, such efforts shall be coordinated with an appropriate local workforce development board established under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3122">section 3122 of title 29</ref>.” for “employment. Whenever feasible, such efforts shall be coordinated with an appropriate local workforce investment board established under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2832">section 2832 of title 29</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/1/A">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,” after “American Samoa,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/1/B">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “individuals with disabilities, especially individuals with severe disabilities;” for “handicapped individuals, especially those with severe handicaps;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/1/C">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “unemployed individuals,” for “the jobless, the hungry,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/1/D">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “through prevention, education, rehabilitation, treatment,” for “prevention, education,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/1/E">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(1)(E)</ref>, substituted “mental illness, chronic and life-threatening illnesses,” for “chronic and life-threatening illnesses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/1/F/i">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(1)(F)(i)</ref>, which directed substitution of “Head Start Act” for “Headstart act”, was executed by making the substitution for “Headstart Act” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8) to (13). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/1/F/ii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(1)(F)(ii)</ref>–(H), added pars. (8) to (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/2/A">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “placement procedures that involve sponsoring organizations and” for “recruitment and placement procedures”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/2/B/i">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(2)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “Community Service Act of 1990.” for “Community Service Trust Act of 1993. Upon the transfer of the functions of the ACTION Agency to the Corporation for National and Community Service, the office established under this subparagraph shall be merged with the recruitment office of such Corporation. At no time after such transfer of functions shall more than one office responsible primarily for recruitment exist within the Corporation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “database that provides” for “central information system that shall, on request, promptly provide” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/2/B/iii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(2)(B)(iii)</ref>, inserted “and management” after “the recruitment” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/2/C">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “database” for “information system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/3/A/i">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(3)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “the Internet and related technologies,” before “radio,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “Internet and related technologies,” before “print media,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/3/A/iii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(3)(A)(iii)</ref>, inserted “State or local offices of economic development, State employment security agencies, employment offices,” before “and other institutions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/3/A/iv">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(3)(A)(iv)</ref>, substituted “Community Service Act of 1990” for “Community Service Trust Act of 1993”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/3/B">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(3)(B)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which read as follows: “Beginning in fiscal year 1991 and for each fiscal year thereafter, for the purpose of carrying out this subsection, the Director shall obligate not less than 1.5 percent of the amounts appropriated for each fiscal year under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5081/a">section 5081(a) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/4">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(4)</ref>, struck out “private industry council established under the Job Training Partnership Act or” after “coordinated with an appropriate”. See 1998 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/5">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(5)</ref>, struck out “, and such Governor or other chief executive officer has not, within 45 days of the date of such submission, notified the Director in writing, supported by a statement of reasons, that such Governor or other chief executive officer disapproves such program or project” before period at end of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/6">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(6)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/f/28/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(28)(A)]</ref>, which directed amendment of the second sentence to read “private industry council established under the Job Training Partnership Act or”, was not executed, to reflect the probable intent of Congress and subsequent amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2102/4">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2102(4)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/36/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(36)(A)]</ref>, substituted “Whenever feasible, such efforts shall be coordinated with an appropriate private industry council established under the Job Training Partnership Act or local workforce investment board established under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2832">section 2832 of title 29</ref>.” for “Whenever feasible, such efforts shall be coordinated with an appropriate private industry council under the Job Training Partnership Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/304/s3/b/7">Pub. L. 103–304, § 3(b)(7)</ref>, redesignated par. (6) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/103/304/s3/b/8">Pub. L. 103–304, § 3(b)(8)</ref>, realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/a/1">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “public” for “a public” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/a/2">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(a)(2)</ref>, directed amendment of par. (2) by striking “and” at end. See 1984 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/a/3">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(a)(3)</ref>, struck out “illiterate or functionally illiterate youth and other individuals,” after “the hungry,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/a/4">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(a)(4)</ref>, struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/a/5">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(a)(5)</ref>, struck out “or” before “the Community Economic”, inserted “or other similar Acts,” before “in furtherance of”, and substituted “; and” for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/a/6">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(a)(6)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s405/a/2">Pub. L. 103–82, § 405(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “the Corporation (or any” for “the ACTION Agency (or any”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/b/1/A">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(b)(1)(A)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “The Director shall establish and maintain within the national headquarters of the ACTION Agency a volunteer placement office. The office shall be headed by an individual designated by the Director to be the national Administrator of Recruitment and Placement, who shall be responsible for carrying out the functions described in this subsection and subsection (c) and all other functions delegated by the Director relating to the recruitment and placement of volunteers under this part.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/b/1/B">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated subpar. (D) as (C) and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “The Director shall, at a minimum, designate one employee of the ACTION Agency in each region of the United States whose primary duties and responsibilities shall be to assist the Administrator in carrying out the functions described in this subsection and subsection (c).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s405/a/3">Pub. L. 103–82, § 405(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “the Corporation” for “the ACTION Agency” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/b/2">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(b)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated par. (5) as (4) and struck out former par. (4) which read as follows: “Each application for service as a volunteer under this part shall—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) indicate the period of time during which the applicant is available to serve as a volunteer under this part;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) describe the previous education, training, military and work experience, and any other relevant skills or interests of the applicant;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) specify the State or geographic region in which the applicant prefers to be assigned; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(D) specify—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(i) the type of project or program to which the applicant prefers to be assigned; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(ii) the particular project or program to which the applicant prefers to be assigned.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/b/2">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(b)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated pars. (5) and (7) as (4) and (6), respectively, and struck out former par. (6) which read as follows: “Completed applications received by the ACTION Agency shall be forwarded to the regional ACTION office representing the State in which such applicant resides. The regional or State employees designated in subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (2) shall assist in evaluating such applications and, to the extent feasible and appropriate, interviewing applicants.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/c/1/A">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(c)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), in introductory provisions, substituted “personnel described in subsection (b)(2)(C)” for “regional or State employees designated in subparagraphs (C) and (D) of subsection (b)(2)” and “Such activities may include” for “Such activities shall include”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s405/a/4">Pub. L. 103–82, § 405(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “the Corporation” for “the ACTION Agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F) to (H). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/c/1/C">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(c)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), added subpar. (F) and redesignated former subpars. (F) and (G) as (G) and (H), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/c/2">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(c)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated par. (6) as (4) and struck out former par. (4) which required Director to develop annual plan for recruitment of volunteers under this part and former par. (5) which required that at least 20 percent of volunteers under this part be between ages 18 and 27 and that at least 20 percent be 55 or older.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323/d">Pub. L. 103–82, § 323(d)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s101/d/2/A">Pub. L. 101–204, § 101(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Selection and assignment” for “Assignment” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s101/d/2/B">Pub. L. 101–204, § 101(d)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted introductory provisions and struck out former introductory provisions which read as follows: “The Director, upon request of Federal, State, or local agencies, or private nonprofit organizations, may assign such volunteers to work in the several States in the local communities in which the volunteers were recruited in appropriate projects and programs, including work—”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s701">Pub. L. 101–204, § 701</ref>, added par. (5) and redesignated former par. (5) as (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s101/a">Pub. L. 101–204, § 101(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment subsec. (b) read as follows: “The Director shall establish, at a cost not to exceed $250,000, procedures to recruit and place individuals from all walks of life, age groups, economic levels, and geographic areas to serve as VISTA volunteers. The procedures shall include an information system to ensure that potential applicants are made aware of the broad range of VISTA volunteer opportunities and a system to identify and place qualified volunteers where their skills are most needed. The Director shall also establish procedures for national and local recruitment, media and public awareness efforts, and specialized campaigns designed to recruit recent college graduates, special skilled volunteers, and individuals 55 years of age and older. The Director, wherever feasible and appropriate, shall assign low-income community volunteers to serve in their home communities in teams with nationally recruited specialist volunteers. The Director shall make efforts to assign volunteers to serve in their home or nearby communities and shall make national efforts to attract other volunteers to serve in the VISTA program. The Director shall also, in the assignment of volunteers, recognize that the community identified needs which cannot be met in the local area, and the individual desires of VISTA volunteers in regard to placement in various geographic areas of the Nation, should be taken into consideration.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s101/b">Pub. L. 101–204, § 101(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsecs. (c) and (d) as (d) and (e), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s101/b/1">Pub. L. 101–204, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(2)(C), redesignated subsec. (e) as (f) and substituted reference to subsec. (e) of this section for reference to subsec. (d) of this section. Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s101/b/1">Pub. L. 101–204, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (f) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/551">Pub. L. 99–551</ref> amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “The Director, wherever feasible and appropriate, shall assign low-income community volunteers to serve in their home communities in teams with nationally recruited specialist volunteers. The Director shall make efforts to assign volunteers to serve in their home communities or in nearby communities and shall make national efforts to attract other volunteers to serve in the VISTA program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “in the local communities in which the volunteers were recruited” and inserted “, including work” in provisions before par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/a/2">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, which directed substitution of a semicolon for “, under the supervision of nonprofit institutions or facilities, and”, was executed by making the substitution for “, under the supervision of nonprofit institutions or facilities; and” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/a/4">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(a)(4)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4). Former par. (3) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated par. (3) as (5), and substituted “the Community Service Block Grant Act, titles VIII and X of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, the Headstart Act, or the Community Economic Development Act of 1981,” for “the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, as amended”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/b">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(b)</ref>, substituted “The Director shall make efforts to assign volunteers to serve in their home communities or in nearby communities and shall make national efforts to attract other volunteers to serve in the VISTA program” for “Not later than 30 days after the assignment of any such community volunteer, the Director shall insure that each such volunteer is provided an individual plan designed to provide an opportunity for job advancement or for transition to a situation leading to gainful employment. One hundred and twenty days prior to the completion of such community volunteer’s term of service, the Director shall insure that such plan is updated and reviewed with the volunteer. The Director shall offer to provide each volunteer enrolled for a period of full-time service of not less than one year under this subchapter, and, upon the request of such volunteer, provide such volunteer with an individual and updated plan as described in the preceding two sentences”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/c/1/B">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(c)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) and (d). Former subsecs. (c) and (d) redesignated subsecs. (e) and (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/c/1/A">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(c)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s4/c/1/A">Pub. L. 98–288, § 4(c)(1)(A)</ref>, (d), redesignated subsec. (d) as (f), and substituted “work in a program or project in any community unless the application for such program or project contains evidence of local support and” for “duties or work in a program or project in any State unless such program or project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/143/s2/a">Pub. L. 96–143, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted “Not later than 30 days after” for “Prior to” and inserted provisions that the Director offer to provide each volunteer enrolled for a period of full-time service of not less than one year under this subchapter, and, upon the request of such volunteer, provide such volunteer with an individual and updated plan as described in the preceding two sentences.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/143/s2/b">Pub. L. 96–143, § 2(b)</ref>, inserted “in a program or project” after “work” and “or project” after “program” and inserted provisions requiring notification by a Governor or other chief executive officer to the Director that such Governor or other chief executive officer has disapproved a program or project under this section and requiring the Director to terminate a program or project under this section in the event of a timely request by the Governor or other chief executive officer not later than 30 days after the date such request is received or at such date agreed upon by the Director and such Governor or other chief executive officer.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcebe3cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcebe3d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> effective on the first day of the first full program year after <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date> (<date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s506">section 506 of Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcebe3d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/13">Pub. L. 111–13</ref> effective <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s6101/a">section 6101(a) of Pub. L. 111–13</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcebe3d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(36)(A)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, and amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(28)(A)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>, see section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(g)(1), (2)(B)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3502">section 3502 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcebe3d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/304/s3/b/10">Pub. L. 103–304, § 3(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1568">108 Stat. 1568</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/304/s3/b/10">
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the amendments made by this subsection [amending this section and sections 5024, 12591, 12602, 12615, 12619, 12622, 12651d, 12653, and 12655n of this title] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retroactive effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by paragraphs (1) and (2) [amending sections 12651d and 12655n of this title] shall take effect as of <date date="1993-10-01">October 1, 1993</date>.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcebe3d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s323">section 323 of Pub. L. 103–82</ref> effective <date date="1993-10-01">Oct. 1, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s392">section 392 of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4951">section 4951 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 405(a)(2) to (4) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> effective <date date="1994-04-04">Apr. 4, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcebe3d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/551">Pub. L. 99–551</ref> effective <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/551/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 99–551</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
