<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcee5572-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001"><num value="5001">§ 5001.</num><heading> Grants and contracts for volunteer service projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee5573-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval of projects; rules and regulations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to help retired individuals and working older individuals to share their experiences, abilities, and skills to improve their communities and themselves through service in their communities, the Director is authorized to make grants to State agencies (established or designated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3025/a/1">section 3025(a)(1) of this title</ref>) or grants to or contracts with other public and nonprofit private agencies and organizations to pay part or all of the costs for the development or operation, or both, of volunteer service projects under this section, if the Director determines, in accordance with regulations the Director shall prescribe, that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5574-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> volunteers will not be reimbursed for other than transportation, meals, and other out-of-pocket expenses incident to the provision of services under this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5575-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> only individuals 55 years of age or older will be enrolled as volunteers to provide services under this part (except for administrative purposes), and such services will be performed in the community where such individuals reside or in nearby communities either (A) on publicly owned and operated facilities or projects, or (B) on local projects sponsored by private nonprofit organizations (other than political parties), other than projects involving the construction, operation, or maintenance of so much of any facility used or to be used for sectarian instruction or as a place for religious worship;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5576-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the project includes such short-term training as may be necessary to make the most effective use of the skills and talents of participating volunteers and individuals, and provide for the payment of the reasonable expenses of such volunteers while undergoing such training; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5577-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the project is being designed and implemented with the advice of persons competent in the field of service to be provided, as well as persons who have expertise in the management of volunteers and the needs of older individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee5578-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Proportion of required local contribution; exceptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In no event shall the required proportion of the local contribution (including in-kind contributions) for a grant or contract made under this section be more than 10 per centum in the first year of assistance under this section, 20 per centum in the second such year, and 30 per centum in any subsequent such years: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the Director may make exceptions in cases of demonstrated need, determined (in accordance with regulations which the Director shall prescribe) on the basis of the financial capability of a particular recipient of assistance under this section, to permit a lesser local contribution proportion than any required contribution proportion established by the Director in generally applicable regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee5579-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions upon award of grant or contract</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall not award any grant or contract under this part for a project in any State to any agency or organization unless, if such State has a State agency established or designated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3025/a/1">section 3025(a)(1) of this title</ref>, such agency itself is the recipient of the award or such agency has been afforded at least forty-five days in which to review the proj­ect application and make recommendations thereon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee557a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Volunteer service as employment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, volunteer service under this part shall not be deemed employment for any purpose which the Director finds is not fully consistent with the provisions and in furtherance of the purpose of this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee557b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration of grant or contract; competitive process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee557c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Beginning with fiscal year 2013 and for each fiscal year thereafter, each grant or contract awarded under this section, for such a year, shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee557d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> awarded for a period of 3 years, with an option for a grant renewal of 3 years if the grantee meets the performances <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003382">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003382"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “performance”.</note> measures established under subsection (g); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee557e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> awarded through a competitive process described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee557f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee5580-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Corporation shall promulgate regulations establishing the competitive process required under paragraph (1)(B), and make such regulations available to the public, not later than 18 months after <date date="2009-04-21">April 21, 2009</date>. The Corporation shall consult with the directors of programs receiving grants under this section during the development and implementation of the competitive process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee5581-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The competitive process required by subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5582-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> include the use of a peer review panel, including members with expertise in senior service and aging, to review applications;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5583-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> include site inspections of programs assisted under this section, as appropriate;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5584-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in the case of an applicant who has previously received a grant or contract for a program under this section, include an evaluation of the program conducted by a review team, as described in subsection (f);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5585-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> ensure that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcee5586-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the grants or contracts awarded under this section through the competitive process for a grant or contract cycle support an aggregate number of volunteer service years for a given geographic service area that is not less than the aggregate number of volunteer service years supported under this section for such service area for the previous grant or contract cycle;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcee5587-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the grants or contracts awarded under this section through the competitive process for a grant or contract cycle maintain a similar program distribution, as compared to the program distribution for the previous grant or contract cycle; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcee5588-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> every effort is made to minimize the disruption to volunteers; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5589-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/e/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> include the use of performance measures, outcomes, and other criteria established under subsection (g).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee558a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee558b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5052">section 5052 of this title</ref>, and effective beginning 180 days after <date date="2009-04-21">April 21, 2009</date>, each grant or contract under this section that expires in fiscal year 2011, 2012, or 2013 shall be subject to an evaluation process conducted by a review team described in paragraph (4). The evaluation process shall be carried out, to the maximum extent practicable, in fiscal year 2010, 2011, and 2012, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee558c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Corporation shall promulgate regulations establishing the evaluation process required under paragraph (1), and make such regulations available to the public, not later than 18 months after <date date="2009-04-21">April 21, 2009</date>. The Corporation shall consult with the directors of programs receiving grants under this section during the development and implementation of the evaluation process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee558d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The evaluation process required under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee558e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> include performance measures, outcomes, and other criteria established under subsection (g); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee558f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> evaluate the extent to which the recipient of the grant or contract meets or exceeds such performance measures, outcomes, and other criteria through a review of the recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee5590-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> To the maximum extent practicable, the Corporation shall provide that each evaluation required by this subsection is conducted by a review team that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5591-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> includes individuals who are knowledgeable about programs assisted under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5592-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes current or former employees of the Corporation who are knowledgeable about programs assisted under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5593-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> includes representatives of communities served by volunteers of programs assisted under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5594-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> shall receive periodic training to ensure quality and consistency across evaluations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee5595-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The findings of an evaluation described in this subsection of a program described in paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5596-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be presented to the recipient of the grant or contract for such program in a timely, transparent, and uniform manner that conveys information of program strengths and weaknesses and assists with program improvement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee5597-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/f/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be used as the basis for program improvement, and for the provision of training and technical assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee5598-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance measures, outcomes, and other criteria</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee5599-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Corporation shall, with particular attention to the different needs of rural and urban programs assisted under this section, develop performance measures, outcomes, and other criteria for programs assisted under this section that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee559a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> include an assessment of the strengths and areas in need of improvement of a program assisted under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee559b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> include an assessment of whether such program has adequately addressed population and community-wide needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee559c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> include an assessment of the efforts of such program to collaborate with other community-based organizations, units of government, and entities providing services to seniors, taking into account barriers to such collaboration that such program may encounter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee559d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> include a protocol for fiscal management that shall be used to assess such program’s compliance with the program requirements for the appropriate use of Federal funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee559e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> include an assessment of whether the program is in conformity with the eligibility, outreach, enrollment, and other requirements for programs assisted under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee559f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> contain other measures of performance developed by the Corporation, in consultation with the review teams described in subsection (f)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee55a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee55a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The performance measures, outcomes, and other criteria established under this subsection may be updated or modified as necessary, in consultation with directors of programs under this section, but not earlier than fiscal year 2014.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee55a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For each fiscal year preceding fiscal year 2014, the Corporation may, after consulting with directors of the programs under this section, determine that a performance measure, outcome, or criterion established under this subsection is operationally problematic, and may, in consultation with such directors and after notifying the authorizing committees—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee55a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> eliminate the use of that performance measure, outcome or criterion; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee55a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> modify that performance measure, outcome, or criterion as necessary to render it no longer operationally problematic.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee55a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the event that a program does not meet one or more of the performance measures, outcome, or criteria established under this subsection, the Corporation shall initiate procedures to terminate the program in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5052">section 5052 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee55a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Training and technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall develop procedures by which programs assisted under this section may receive training and technical assistance, which may include regular monitoring visits to assist programs in meeting the performance measures, outcomes, and criteria.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee55a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Temporary continuation of programs that fail to meet performance measures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee55a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (g)(3) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5052">section 5052 of this title</ref>, the Corporation shall continue to fund a program assisted under this section that has failed to meet or exceed the performance measures, outcomes, and other criteria established under this subsection for not more than 12 months if the competitive process established under subsection (e) does not result in a successor grant or contract for such program, in order to minimize the disruption to volunteers and the disruption of services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee55a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case where a program is continued under paragraph (1), the Corporation shall conduct outreach regarding the availability of a grant under this section for the area served by such program and establish a new competition for awarding the successor program to the continued program. The recipient operating the continued program shall remain eligible for the new competition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcee55aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Corporation may monitor the recipient of a grant or contract supporting a program continued under paragraph (1) during this period and may provide training and technical assistance to assist such recipient in meeting the performance measures for such program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbcee55ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Online resource guide</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation shall develop and disseminate an online resource guide for programs under this section not later than 180 days after <date date="2009-04-21">April 21, 2009</date>, which shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee55ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> examples of high-performing programs assisted under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee55ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> corrective actions for underperforming programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcee55ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5001/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> examples of meaningful outcome-based performance measures, outcomes, and criteria that capture a program’s mission and priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcee55af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/113/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–113, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/401">87 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/351/s4">Pub. L. 93–351, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/357">88 Stat. 357</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 95–478, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1556">92 Stat. 1556</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s14/a">Pub. L. 98–288, § 14(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1984-05-21">May 21, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/192">98 Stat. 192</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/tIX/s902/2">Pub. L. 101–204, title IX, § 902(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-07">Dec. 7, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1826">103 Stat. 1826</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tIII/s343">Pub. L. 103–82, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/904">107 Stat. 904</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/tII/s2143">Pub. L. 111–13, title II, § 2143</ref>, <date date="2009-04-21">Apr. 21, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1584">123 Stat. 1584</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcee55b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcee55b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcee55b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2143/1/A">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2143(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “share their experiences, abilities, and skills to improve their communities and themselves through service in their communities,” for “avail themselves of opportunities for volunteer service in their community,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2143/1/B">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2143(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “, and individuals 60 years of age or older will be given priority for enrollment,” before “as volunteers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2143/1/C">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2143(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “designed and implemented” for “established and will be carried out” and “field of service to be provided, as well as persons who have expertise in the management of volunteers and the needs of older individuals.” for “field of service involved, and of persons with interest in and knowledge of the needs of older persons.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s2143/2">Pub. L. 111–13, § 2143(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) to (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s343/1">Pub. L. 103–82, § 343(1)</ref>, substituted “retired individuals and working older individuals” for “retired persons” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s343/2">Pub. L. 103–82, § 343(2)</ref>, substituted “55 years of age or older” for “aged sixty or over” and inserted “, and individuals 60 years of age or older will be given priority for enrollment,” after “will be enrolled”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s902/2/A">Pub. L. 101–204, § 902(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “projects” for “programs” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/204/s902/2/B">Pub. L. 101–204, § 902(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “project” for “program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s14/a">Pub. L. 98–288, § 14(a)</ref>, substituted “the Director” for “he” in two places in provisions before par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s14/b">Pub. L. 98–288, § 14(b)</ref>, substituted “and 30 per centum in any subsequent such years” for “30 per centum in the third such year, 40 per centum in the fourth such year, and 50 per centum in any subsequent such years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s402/a/1">Pub. L. 95–478, § 402(a)(1)</ref>, substituted reference to section “3025(a)(1)” for “3024(a)(1)” of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s402/a/1">Pub. L. 95–478, § 402(a)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted reference to section “3025(a)(1)” for “3024(a)(1)” of this title and decreased period for review to “forty-five” from “sixty” days.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s402/a/3">Pub. L. 95–478, § 402(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/351">Pub. L. 93–351</ref> added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcee55b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcee55b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/13">Pub. L. 111–13</ref> effective <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s6101/a">section 6101(a) of Pub. L. 111–13</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcee55b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> effective <date date="1993-10-01">Oct. 1, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s392">section 392 of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4951">section 4951 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcee55b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/478">Pub. L. 95–478</ref> effective at close of <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s504">section 504 of Pub. L. 95–478</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbcee55b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Aging Resource Specialists for Coordination of National Older American Volunteer Programs With State and Community Programs on Aging and Nutrition Programs for Elderly; Designation; Duties; Definitions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/135/tII/s205/c">Pub. L. 94–135, title II, § 205(c)</ref>, <date date="1975-11-28">Nov. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/727">89 Stat. 727</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tIII/s341/b/4">Pub. L. 103–82, title III, § 341(b)(4)</ref>, title IV, § 405(i), <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/904">107 Stat. 904</ref>, 921, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/82/tIII/s341/b/4">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> In order to provide maximum coordination between programs carried out under title III and title VII of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3021">42 U.S.C. 3021</ref> et seq.; <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3045">42 U.S.C. 3045</ref> et seq.) and National Senior Volunteer Corps [now National Senior Service Corps] programs carried out under title II of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5001">42 U.S.C. 5001</ref> et seq.) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5000">42 U.S.C. 5000</ref> et seq.], in order to enhance the effectiveness of the support provided to such National Senior Volunteer Corps programs by the Corporation for National and Community Service, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation shall designate an aging resource specialist with respect to programs carried out in each State under title II of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 [this subchapter].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Each aging resource specialist designated under paragraph (1) shall be qualified to serve in such capacity by appropriate experience and training, and shall be stationed in a State office of the Corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> The primary responsibility of each aging resource specialist shall be—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to support programs carried out under title II of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 [this subchapter] in any State or other jurisdiction served by the State office involved; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to seek to coordinate such programs with programs carried out under title III and title VII of the Older Americans Act of 1965 [sections 3021 et seq. and 3045 et seq. of this title] in any such State or other jurisdiction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the term ‘Corporation’ means the Corporation for National and Community Service established by section 191 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12651">42 U.S.C. 12651</ref>].[;]</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the term ‘primary responsibility’ means the devotion of more than one-half of regular working hours to the performance of duties described in paragraph (2)(B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the term ‘State’ means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
