<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb776a550-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s502"><num value="502">§ 502.</num><heading> Payments to States; computation of amounts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb776a551-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s502/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification of amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Labor shall from time to time certify to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment to each State which has an unemployment compensation law approved by the Secretary of Labor under the Federal Unemployment Tax Act, such amounts as the Secretary of Labor determines to be necessary for the proper and efficient administration of such law during the fiscal year for which such payment is to be made, including 100 percent of so much of the reasonable expenditures of the State as are attributable to the costs of the implementation and operation of the immigration status verification system described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–7/d">section 1320b–7(d) of this title</ref>. The Secretary of Labor’s determination shall be based on (1) the population of the State; (2) an estimate of the number of persons covered by the State law and of the cost of proper and efficient administration of such law; and (3) such other factors as the Secretary of Labor finds relevant. The Secretary of Labor shall not certify for payment under this section in any fiscal year a total amount in excess of the amount appropriated therefor for such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb776a552-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s502/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Out of the sums appropriated therefor, the Secretary of the Treasury shall, upon receiving a certification under subsection (a), pay, through the Fiscal Service of the Department of the Treasury and prior to audit or settlement by the Government Accountability Office, to the State agency charged with the administration of such law the amount so certified.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb776a553-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s502/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Mailing costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No portion of the cost of mailing a statement under section 6050B(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to unemployment compensation) shall be treated as not being a cost for the proper and efficient administration of the State unemployment compensation law by reason of including with such statement information about the earned income credit provided by section 32 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. The preceding sentence shall not apply if the inclusion of such information increases the postage required to mail such statement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb776a554-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title III, § 302, <ref href="/us/stat/49/626">49 Stat. 626</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1939-08-10/ch666">Aug. 10, 1939, ch. 666</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1378">53 Stat. 1378</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 4, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7873, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1095">60 Stat. 1095</ref>; 1949 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1949-08-20">Aug. 20, 1949</date>, 14 F.R. 5225, <ref href="/us/stat/63/1065">63 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1165">98 Stat. 1165</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/603/tI/s121/b/3">Pub. L. 99–603, title I, § 121(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3390">100 Stat. 3390</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 102–318, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-03">July 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/297">106 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb776a555-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb776a556-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb776a557-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Unemployment Tax Act, referred to in subsec. (a), comprised subchapter C (§§ 1600 to 1611) of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939. Chapter 9 of the 1939 Code was repealed (subject to certain exceptions) by section 7851(a)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, Title 26. The Internal Revenue Code of 1954 was redesignated the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>. The Federal Unemployment Tax Act also comprises chapter 23 (§ 3301 et seq.) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. For table of comparisons of the 1939 Code to the 1986 Code, see Table I preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code. See also <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7852/b">section 7852(b) of Title 26</ref> for provision that references in any other law to a provision of the 1939 Code, unless expressly incompatible with the intent thereof, shall be deemed a reference to the corresponding provision of the 1986 Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb776a558-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/271">Pub. L. 108–271</ref> substituted “Government Accountability Office” for “General Accounting Office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/318">Pub. L. 102–318</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/603">Pub. L. 99–603</ref> inserted at end of first sentence “, including 100 percent of so much of the reasonable expenditures of the State as are attributable to the costs of the implementation and operation of the immigration status verification system described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–7/d">section 1320b–7(d) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> substituted “the Fiscal Service of the Department of the Treasury” for “the Division of Disbursement of the Treasury Department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1939—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1939-08-10">Aug. 10, 1939</date>, substituted “Federal Unemployment Tax Act” for “sections 1101–1110 of this title,” and inserted “efficient” before “administration”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb7791559-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb779155a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/318/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 102–318, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-03">July 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/297">106 Stat. 297</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/318/tIII/s302/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-07-03">July 3, 1992</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb779155b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/603/tI/s121/c/2">Pub. L. 99–603, title I, § 121(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3391">100 Stat. 3391</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/603/tI/s121/c/2">“The amendments made by subsection (b) [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437r">section 1437r of this title</ref>, amending this section and sections 303, 603, 1203, 1353, and 1396b of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025">section 2025 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture, and <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1096">section 1096 of Title 20</ref>, Education, and amending provisions set out as a Puerto Rico, Guam, and Virgin Islands note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1383">section 1383 of this title</ref>] take effect on <date date="1987-10-01">October 1, 1987</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb779155c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb779155d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Method of Allocating Administrative Funds Among States</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/164/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 102–164, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1991-11-15">Nov. 15, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1061">105 Stat. 1061</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/tV/s533">Pub. L. 102–318, title V, § 533</ref>, <date date="1992-07-03">July 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/317">106 Stat. 317</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/318/tV/s533">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Labor shall submit to the Congress, before <date date="1994-12-31">December 31, 1994</date>, a comprehensive report setting forth a proposal for revising the method of allocating grants among the States under section 302 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s502">42 U.S.C. 502</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specific Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required by subsection (a) shall include an analysis of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the use of unemployment insurance workload levels as the primary factor in allocating grants among the States under section 302 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s502">42 U.S.C. 502</ref>],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> ways to ensure that each State receive not less than a minimum grant amount for each fiscal year,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the use of nationally available objective data to determine the unemployment compensation administrative costs of each State, with consideration of legitimate cost differences among the States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> ways to simplify the method of allocating such grants among the States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> ways to eliminate the disincentives to productivity and efficiency which exist in the current method of allocating such grants among the States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> ways to promote innovation and cost-effective practices in the method of allocating such grants among the States, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the effect of the proposal set forth in such report on the grant amounts allocated to each State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Review Period</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Labor may not revise the method in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1991-11-15">Nov. 15, 1991</date>] for allocating grants among the States under section 302 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s502">42 U.S.C. 502</ref>], until after the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the report required by subsection (a) is submitted to the Congress.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb779155e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb779155f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of Labor, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Labor, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 6 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1263">64 Stat. 1263</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Federal Security Administrator with respect to unemployment compensation transferred to Secretary of Labor by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1949, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1 of Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1949, also provided that functions transferred by this section shall be performed by Secretary of Labor, or subject to his direction and control, by such officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Labor as he shall designate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Administrator” substituted for “Board” by section 4 of Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1946, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
