<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcf30fc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5052"><num value="5052">§ 5052.</num><heading> Suspension and termination of financial assistance; procedures; notice and hearing; emergency situations; refunding applications</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcf30fca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5052/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Director is authorized, in accordance with the provisions of this section, to suspend further payments or to terminate payments under any contract or grant providing assistance under this chapter, whenever the Director determines there is a material failure to comply with the applicable terms and conditions of any such grant or contract. The Director shall prescribe procedures to insure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcf30fcb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5052/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assistance under this chapter shall not be suspended for failure to comply with applicable terms and conditions, except in emergency situations for thirty days;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcf30fcc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5052/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an application for refunding under this chapter may not be denied unless the recipient has been given (A) notice at least 75 days before the denial of such application of the possibility of such denial and the grounds for any such denial, and (B) opportunity to show cause why such action should not be taken;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcf30fcd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5052/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in any case where an application for refunding is denied for failure to comply with the terms and conditions of the grant or contract award, the recipient shall be afforded an opportunity for an informal hearing before an impartial hearing officer, who has been agreed to by the recipient and the Agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcf30fce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5052/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> assistance under this chapter shall not be terminated for failure to comply with applicable terms and conditions unless the recipient has been afforded reasonable notice and opportunity for a full and fair hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcf30fcf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5052/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In order to assure equal access to all recipients, such hearings or other meetings as may be necessary to fulfill the requirements of this section shall be held at locations convenient to the recipient agency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcf30fd0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/113/tIV/s412">Pub. L. 93–113, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/411">87 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/288/s22">Pub. L. 98–288, § 22</ref>, <date date="1984-05-21">May 21, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/195">98 Stat. 195</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/551/s10/i/8">Pub. L. 99–551, § 10(i)(8)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3078">100 Stat. 3078</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcf30fd1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcf30fd2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcf30fd3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/113">Pub. L. 93–113</ref>, <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/394">87 Stat. 394</ref>, known as the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcf30fd4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/551">Pub. L. 99–551</ref> substituted “the Director” for “he” before “determines” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/288">Pub. L. 98–288</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), substituted a semicolon for “nor shall an application for refunding under this chapter be denied, unless the recipient has been given reasonable notice and opportunity to show why such action should not be taken; and” in par. (1), added pars. (2) and (3), redesignated former par. (2) as (4), and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcf30fd5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcf30fd6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/551">Pub. L. 99–551</ref> effective <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/551/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 99–551</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
