<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd06232f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d"><num value="5116d">§ 5116d.</num><heading> Application</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A grant may not be made to a State under this subchapter unless an application therefor is submitted by the State to the Secretary and such application contains the types of information specified by the Secretary as essential to carrying out the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5116a">section 5116a of this title</ref>, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd062330-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a description of the lead entity that will be responsible for the administration of funds provided under this subchapter and the oversight of programs funded through the community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect which meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5116a">section 5116a of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description of how the community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect will operate, including how community-based child abuse and neglect prevention programs provided by public and private, nonprofit organizations will be integrated into a developing continuum of family centered, holistic, preventive services for children and families;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a description of the inventory of current unmet needs and current community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities to prevent child abuse and neglect, and other family resource services operating in the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d23-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a budget for the development, operation, and expansion of the community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect that verifies that the State will expend in non-Federal funds an amount equal to not less than 20 percent of the amount received under this subchapter (in cash, not in-kind) for activities under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d24-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> an assurance that funds received under this subchapter will supplement, not supplant, other State and local public funds designated for the start up, maintenance, expansion, and redesign of community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d25-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a description of the State’s capacity to ensure the meaningful involvement of parents who are consumers, of family advocates, and of adult former victims of child abuse or neglect, who can provide leadership in the planning, implementation, and evaluation of the programs and policy decisions of the applicant agency in accomplishing the desired outcomes for such efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> a description of the criteria that the entity will use to develop, or select and fund, community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect as part of network development, expansion, or enhancement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d27-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> a description of outreach activities that the entity and the community-based and prevention-focused programs designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect will undertake to maximize the participation of racial and ethnic minorities, children and adults with disabilities, homeless families and those at risk of homelessness, unaccompanied homeless youth, and members of other underserved or underrepresented groups;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d28-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> a plan for providing operational support, training, and technical assistance to community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect for development, operation, expansion and enhancement activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> a description of how the applicant entity’s activities and those of the network and its members (where appropriate) will be evaluated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> a description of the actions that the applicant entity will take to advocate systemic changes in State policies, practices, procedures, and regulations to improve the delivery of community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect services to children and families; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd086d2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> an assurance that the applicant entity will provide the Secretary with reports at such time and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbd086d2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/247/tII/s204">Pub. L. 93–247, title II, § 204</ref>, formerly § 205, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/235/tI/s121">Pub. L. 104–235, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1996-10-03">Oct. 3, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3083">110 Stat. 3083</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/tI/s125">Pub. L. 108–36, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="2003-06-25">June 25, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/815">117 Stat. 815</ref>; renumbered § 204 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/tI">Pub. L. 111–320, title I</ref>, §§ 135, 141, <date date="2010-12-20">Dec. 20, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3479">124 Stat. 3479</ref>, 3482.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd086d2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd086d2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbd086d2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 5116d, <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/tII/s205">Pub. L. 93–247, title II, § 205</ref>, formerly <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tIV/s406">Pub. L. 98–473, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2198">98 Stat. 2198</ref>; renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/s205">§ 205 of Pub. L. 93–247</ref>, and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/126">Pub. L. 101–126</ref>, §§ 2(a), 3(a)(3), (c)(1), (2), 4(e), <date date="1989-10-25">Oct. 25, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/764">103 Stat. 764</ref>, 766, 767; <ref href="/us/pl/102/295/tI/s124">Pub. L. 102–295, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="1992-05-28">May 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/198">106 Stat. 198</ref>, related to grant allotments, required use of grants, and grant application requirements, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s401/a">Pub. L. 103–252, § 401(a)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/s204">section 204 of Pub. L. 93–247</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5116c">section 5116c of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/tI/s124">Pub. L. 108–36, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="2003-06-25">June 25, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/815">117 Stat. 815</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/s204">section 204 of Pub. L. 93–247</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5116c">section 5116c of this title</ref> prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s401/a">Pub. L. 103–252, § 401(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd086d30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/1">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(1)</ref>, struck out “(through networks where appropriate)” after “child abuse and neglect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/1">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(1)</ref>, (2), struck out “(through networks where appropriate)” after “child abuse and neglect”, and substituted “, including how community-based child abuse and neglect prevention” for “and how family resource and support” and “programs provided” for “services provided”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/3">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(3)</ref>, inserted a comma after “operation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/4">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(4)</ref>, substituted “a description of the State’s” for “an assurance that the State has the” and “consumers, of family advocates, and of adult former victims of child abuse or neglect,” for “consumers and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/5">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(5)</ref>, inserted a comma after “expansion”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/6">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(6)</ref>, struck out “and activities” after “prevention-focused programs” and inserted “unaccompanied homeless youth,” after “homelessness,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (9). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/7">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(7)</ref>, inserted a comma after “training”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (11). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s135/8">Pub. L. 111–320, § 135(8)</ref>, inserted a comma after “procedures”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/1">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(1)</ref>, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect (through networks where appropriate)” for “Statewide network of community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/2">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(2)</ref>, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect (through networks where appropriate)” for “network of community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs” and struck out “, including those funded by programs consolidated under this subchapter and subchapter I of this chapter,” before “will be integrated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/3">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(3)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “an assurance that an inventory of current family resource programs, respite care, child abuse and neglect prevention activities, and other family resource services operating in the State, and a description of current unmet needs, will be provided;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/4">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(4)</ref>, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect” for “State’s network of community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/5">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(5)</ref>, substituted “start up, maintenance, expansion, and redesign of community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect” for “Statewide network of community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/6">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(6)</ref>, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect” for “individual community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (8). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/7">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(7)</ref>, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect” for “community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (9). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/8">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(8)</ref>, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect” for “community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (10). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/9">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(9)</ref>, inserted “(where appropriate)” after “members”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (11). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/10">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(10)</ref>, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect” for “prevention-focused, family resource and support program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (12), (13). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s125/11">Pub. L. 108–36, § 125(11)</ref>, redesignated par. (13) as (12).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
