<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd0622ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116"><num value="5116">§ 5116.</num><heading> Purpose and authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd0622f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0622f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to support community-based efforts to develop, operate, expand, enhance, and coordinate initiatives, programs, and activities to prevent child abuse and neglect and to support the coordination of resources and activities, to better strengthen and support families to reduce the likelihood of child abuse and neglect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0622f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to foster an understanding, appreciation, and knowledge of diverse populations in order to be effective in preventing and treating child abuse and neglect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd0622f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall make grants under this subchapter on a formula basis to the entity designated by the State as the lead entity (referred to in this subchapter as the “lead entity”) under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5116a/1">section 5116a(1) of this title</ref> for the purpose of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0622f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> developing, operating, expanding, and enhancing community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect that are accessible, effective, culturally appropriate, and build upon existing strengths that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> offer assistance to families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide early, comprehensive support for parents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> promote the development of parenting skills, especially in young parents and parents with very young children;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> increase family stability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> improve family access to other formal and informal resources and opportunities for assistance available within communities, including access to such resources and opportunities for unaccompanied homeless youth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> support the additional needs of families with children with disabilities through respite care and other services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> demonstrate a commitment to involving parents in the planning and program implementation of the lead agency and entities carrying out local programs funded under this title, including involvement of parents of children with disabilities, parents who are individuals with disabilities, racial and ethnic minorities, and members of other underrepresented or underserved groups; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd0622fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> provide referrals to early health and developmental services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0622fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> fostering the development of a continuum of preventive services for children and families, including unaccompanied homeless youth, through State and community-based collaborations and partnerships both public and private;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0622fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> financing the start-up, maintenance, expansion, or redesign of specific community-based child abuse and neglect prevention program services (such as respite care services, child abuse and neglect prevention activities, disability services, mental health services, substance abuse treatment services, domestic violence services, housing services, transportation, adult education, home visiting and other similar services) identified by the inventory and description of current services required under section 5116d(3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003397">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003397"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title as an unmet need, and integrated with the network of community-based child abuse and neglect prevention programs to the extent practicable given funding levels and community priorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0622ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> maximizing funding through leveraging of funds for the financing, planning, community mobilization, collaboration, assessment, information and referral, startup, training and technical assistance, information management and reporting, reporting and evaluation costs for establishing, operating, or expanding community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd062300-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5116/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> financing public information activities that focus on the healthy and positive development of parents and children and the promotion of child abuse and neglect prevention activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd062301-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/247/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–247, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/235/tI/s121">Pub. L. 104–235, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1996-10-03">Oct. 3, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3080">110 Stat. 3080</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/tI/s121/a">Pub. L. 108–36, title I, § 121(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2003-06-25">June 25, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/813">117 Stat. 813</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/tI/s132">Pub. L. 111–320, title I, § 132</ref>, <date date="2010-12-20">Dec. 20, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3478">124 Stat. 3478</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd062302-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd062303-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd062304-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5116d/3">Section 5116d(3) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), was in the original “section 205(a)(3)” and was translated as meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/s204/3">section 204(3) of Pub. L. 93–247</ref> to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the redesignation of section 205 as 204 by <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/tI/s141">Pub. L. 111–320, title I, § 141</ref>, <date date="2010-12-20">Dec. 20, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3482">124 Stat. 3482</ref>, and because section 204 does not contain subsections.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbd062305-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 5116, <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–247, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/tIV/s401/a">Pub. L. 103–252, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/666">108 Stat. 666</ref>, related to community-based family resource programs, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/104/235/s121">Pub. L. 104–235, § 121</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 5116, <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–247, title II, § 201</ref>, formerly <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 98–473, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2197">98 Stat. 2197</ref>; renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/93/247/s201">§ 201 of Pub. L. 93–247</ref>, and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/126">Pub. L. 101–126</ref>, §§ 2(a), 3(a)(3), (c)(1), 4(a), <date date="1989-10-25">Oct. 25, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/764">103 Stat. 764</ref>, 766; <ref href="/us/pl/102/295/tI/s121/b">Pub. L. 102–295, title I, § 121(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-28">May 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/198">106 Stat. 198</ref>, set forth purpose of subchapter to assist States in supporting child abuse and neglect prevention activities through community based grants, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s401/a">Pub. L. 103–252, § 401(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd062306-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/1">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(1)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “to support community-based efforts to develop, operate, expand, enhance, and, where appropriate to network, initiatives aimed at the prevention of child abuse and neglect, and to support networks of coordinated resources and activities to better strengthen and support families to reduce the likelihood of child abuse and neglect; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/2/A">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “hereafter” before “referred” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/2/B/i">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(2)(B)(i)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted a comma after “expanding” and struck out “(through networks where appropriate)” after “child abuse and neglect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “, including access to such resources and opportunities for unaccompanied homeless youth” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/2/B/iii">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(2)(B)(iii)</ref>, added subpar. (G) and struck out former subpar. (G) which read as follows: “demonstrate a commitment to meaningful parent leadership, including among parents of children with disabilities, parents with disabilities, racial and ethnic minorities, and members of other underrepresented or underserved groups; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/2/C">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(2)(C)</ref>, inserted “, including unaccompanied homeless youth,” after “children and families”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/2/D">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(2)(D)</ref>, substituted “specific community-based child abuse and neglect prevention program services” for “specific family resource and support program services”, inserted “substance abuse treatment services, domestic violence services,” after “mental health services,”, and substituted “the network of community-based child abuse and neglect prevention programs” for “the network of community-based family resource and support program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/320/s132/2/E">Pub. L. 111–320, § 132(2)(E)</ref>, inserted “and reporting” after “information management” and struck out comma after “prevention-focused” and “(through networks where appropriate)” after “child abuse and neglect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s121/a">Pub. L. 108–36, § 121(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “to support State efforts to develop, operate, expand and enhance a network of community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs that coordinate resources among existing education, vocational rehabilitation, disability, respite care, health, mental health, job readiness, self-sufficiency, child and family development, community action, Head Start, child care, child abuse and neglect prevention, juvenile justice, domestic violence prevention and intervention, housing, and other human service organizations within the State; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s121/b/1/A">Pub. L. 108–36, § 121(b)(1)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “community-based and prevention-focused programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect (through networks where appropriate) that are accessible, effective, culturally appropriate, and build upon existing strengths that” for “Statewide networks of community-based, prevention-focused, family resource and support programs that”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(G), (H). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s121/b/1/B">Pub. L. 108–36, § 121(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), added subpars. (G) and (H) and struck out former subpar. (G) which read as follows: “decrease the risk of homelessness;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/36/s121/b/2">Pub. L. 108–36, § 121(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “through leveraging of funds” after “maximizing funding” and substituted “community-based and prevention-focused” for “a Statewide network of community-based, prevention-focused” and “programs and activities designed to strengthen and support families to prevent child abuse and neglect (through networks where appropriate)” for “family resource and support program”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
