<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd0adde3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122"><num value="5122">§ 5122.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0adde4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency</inline>.—</heading><content>“Emergency” means any occasion or instance for which, in the determination of the President, Federal assistance is needed to supplement State and local efforts and capabilities to save lives and to protect property and public health and safety, or to lessen or avert the threat of a catastrophe in any part of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0adde5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Major disaster</inline>.—</heading><content>“Major disaster” means any natural catastrophe (including any hurricane, tornado, storm, high water, winddriven water, tidal wave, tsunami, earthquake, volcanic eruption, landslide, mudslide, snowstorm, or drought), or, regardless of cause, any fire, flood, or explosion, in any part of the United States, which in the determination of the President causes damage of sufficient severity and magnitude to warrant major disaster assistance under this chapter to supplement the efforts and available resources of States, local governments, and disaster relief organizations in alleviating the damage, loss, hardship, or suffering caused thereby.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0adde6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “United States” means the fifty States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0adde7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0adde8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “Governor” means the chief executive of any State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0adde9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Indian tribal government</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Indian tribal government” means the governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or community that the Secretary of the Interior acknowledges to exist as an Indian tribe under the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s479a">25 U.S.C. 479a</ref> et seq.).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003401">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003401"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0addea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Individual with a disability</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “individual with a disability” means an individual with a disability as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12102/2">section 12102(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0addeb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Local government</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “local government” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a county, municipality, city, town, township, local public authority, school district, special district, intrastate district, council of governments (regardless of whether the council of governments is incorporated as a nonprofit corporation under State law), regional or interstate government entity, or agency or instrumentality of a local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0added-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an Indian tribe or authorized tribal organization, or Alaska Native village or organization, that is not an Indian tribal government as defined in paragraph (6); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a rural community, unincorporated town or village, or other public entity, for which an application for assistance is made by a State or political subdivision of a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0addef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> “Federal agency” means any department, independent establishment, Government corporation, or other agency of the executive branch of the Federal Government, including the United States Postal Service, but shall not include the American National Red Cross.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0addf0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public facility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>“Public facility” means the following facilities owned by a State or local government:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addf1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any flood control, navigation, irrigation, reclamation, public power, sewage treatment and collection, water supply and distribution, watershed development, or airport facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addf2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any non-Federal-aid street, road, or highway.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addf3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any other public building, structure, or system, including those used for educational, recreational, or cultural purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addf4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/10/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any park.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0addf5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Private nonprofit facility.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addf6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “private nonprofit facility” means private nonprofit educational (without regard to the religious character of the facility), center-based childcare, utility, irrigation, emergency, medical, rehabilitational, and temporary or permanent custodial care facilities (including those for the aged and disabled) and facilities on Indian reservations, as defined by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd0addf7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional facilities</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition to the facilities described in subparagraph (A), the term “private nonprofit facility” includes any private nonprofit facility that provides essential social services to the general public (including museums, zoos, performing arts facilities, community arts centers, community centers, libraries, homeless shelters, senior citizen centers, rehabilitation facilities, shelter workshops, food banks, broadcasting facilities, houses of worship, and facilities that provide health and safety services of a governmental nature), as defined by the President. No house of worship may be excluded from this definition because leadership or membership in the organization operating the house of worship is limited to persons who share a religious faith or practice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0addf8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5122/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Chief executive</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Chief Executive” means the person who is the Chief, Chairman, Governor, President, or similar executive official of an Indian tribal government.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbd0addf9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/288/tI/s102">Pub. L. 93–288, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1974-05-22">May 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/144">88 Stat. 144</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/tI/s103/b">Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 103(b)</ref>–(d), (f), <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4689">102 Stat. 4689</ref>, 4690; <ref href="/us/pl/102/247/tII/s205">Pub. L. 102–247, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1992-02-24">Feb. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/38">106 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/390/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 106–390, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1572">114 Stat. 1572</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/tVI/s688">Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 688</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1448">120 Stat. 1448</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/2/dB/s1110/c">Pub. L. 113–2, div. B, § 1110(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-29">Jan. 29, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/49">127 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/111/s2/a">Pub. L. 114–111, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2240">129 Stat. 2240</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/dB/tVI/s20604/a">Pub. L. 115–123, div. B, title VI, § 20604(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/85">132 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dD">Pub. L. 115–254, div. D</ref>, §§ 1214, 1238(b), <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3449">132 Stat. 3449</ref>, 3466.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd0addfa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd0addfb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd0addfc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in introductory provisions and par. (2), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/288">Pub. L. 93–288</ref>, <date date="1974-05-22">May 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/143">88 Stat. 143</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994, referred to in par. (6), is title I of <ref href="/us/pl/103/454">Pub. L. 103–454</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4791">108 Stat. 4791</ref>, which was classified principally to section 479a et seq. of Title 25, Indians, prior to editorial reclassification as section 5130 et seq. of Title 25. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5101">section 5101 of Title 25</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd0addfd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Par. (11). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Pub. L. 115–123</ref> amended subpar. (B) generally by substituting a second subpar. (A) and a subpar. (B) for former subpar. (B). Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “In addition to the facilities described in subparagraph (A), the term ‘private nonprofit facility’ includes any private nonprofit facility that provides essential services of a governmental nature to the general public (including museums, zoos, performing arts facilities, community arts centers, libraries, homeless shelters, senior citizen centers, rehabilitation facilities, shelter workshops, broadcasting facilities, and facilities that provide health and safety services of a governmental nature), as defined by the President.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (11)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1238/b/2">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1238(b)(2)</ref>, struck out first subpar. (A) which read as follows: “The term ‘private nonprofit facility’ means private nonprofit educational, utility, irrigation, emergency, medical, rehabilitational, and temporary or permanent custodial care facilities (including those for the aged and disabled) and facilities on Indian reservations, as defined by the President.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1238/b/1">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1238(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “center-based childcare,” after “facility),” in second subpar. (A) as added by <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Pub. L. 115–123</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (11)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1214">Pub. L. 115–254, § 1214</ref>, inserted “food banks,” after “shelter workshops,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Par. (11)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/111">Pub. L. 114–111</ref> inserted “broadcasting facilities,” after “workshops,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/113/2/s1110/c/3">Pub. L. 113–2, § 1110(c)(3)</ref>, added par. (6). Former par. (6) redesignated (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/113/2/s1110/c/2">Pub. L. 113–2, § 1110(c)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (6) as (7). Former par. (7) redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/2/s1110/c/1">Pub. L. 113–2, § 1110(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “, that is not an Indian tribal government as defined in paragraph (6); and” for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (8) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/113/2/s1110/c/2">Pub. L. 113–2, § 1110(c)(2)</ref>, redesignated pars. (7) to (10) as (8) to (11), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (12). <ref href="/us/pl/113/2/s1110/c/4">Pub. L. 113–2, § 1110(c)(4)</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Pars. (6) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s688/2">Pub. L. 109–295, § 688(2)</ref>, added par. (6) and redesignated former pars. (6) and (7) as (7) and (8), respectively. Former par. (8) redesignated (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (9). <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s688/2">Pub. L. 109–295, § 688(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (8) as (9). Former par. (9) redesignated (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s688/1">Pub. L. 109–295, § 688(1)</ref>, amended par. (9) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “ ‘Private nonprofit facility’ means private nonprofit educational, utility, irrigation, emergency, medical, rehabilitational, and temporary or permanent custodial care facilities (including those for the aged and disabled), other private nonprofit facilities which provide essential services of a governmental nature to the general public, and facilities on Indian reservations as defined by the President.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (10). <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s688/2">Pub. L. 109–295, § 688(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (9) as (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/390/s302/1">Pub. L. 106–390, § 302(1)</ref>, substituted “and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands” for “the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/390/s302/1">Pub. L. 106–390, § 302(1)</ref>, substituted “and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands” for “the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/106/390/s302/2">Pub. L. 106–390, § 302(2)</ref>, added par. (6) and struck out former par. (6) which read as follows: “ ‘Local government’ means (A) any county, city, village, town, district, or other political subdivision of any State, any Indian tribe or authorized tribal organization, or Alaska Native village or organization, and (B) includes any rural community or unincorporated town or village or any other public entity for which an application for assistance is made by a State or political subdivision thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (9). <ref href="/us/pl/106/390/s302/3">Pub. L. 106–390, § 302(3)</ref>, inserted “irrigation,” after “utility,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Pars. (3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/247">Pub. L. 102–247</ref> inserted “the Northern Mariana Islands,” after “American Samoa,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s103/b">Pub. L. 100–707, § 103(b)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “ ‘Emergency’ means any hurricane, tornado, storm, flood, high water, wind-driven water, tidal wave, tsunami, earthquake, volcanic eruption, landslide, mudslide, snowstorm, drought, fire, explosion, or other catastrophe in any part of the United States which requires Federal emergency assistance to supplement State and local efforts to save lives and protect property, public health and safety or to avert or lessen the threat of a disaster.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s103/c">Pub. L. 100–707, § 103(c)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “ ‘Major disaster’ means any hurricane, tornado, storm, flood, high water, wind-driven water, tidal wave, tsunami, earthquake, volcanic eruption, landslide, mudslide, snowstorm, drought, fire, explosion, or other catastrophe in any part of the United States which, in the determination of the President, causes damage of sufficient severity and magnitude to warrant major disaster assistance under this chapter, above and beyond emergency services by the Federal Government, to supplement the efforts and available resources of States, local governments, and disaster relief organizations in alleviating the damage, loss, hardship, or suffering caused thereby.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s103/d">Pub. L. 100–707, § 103(d)</ref>, struck out “the Canal Zone,” after “American Samoa,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s103/f">Pub. L. 100–707, § 103(f)</ref>, added pars. (8) and (9).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd0addfe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd0addff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dD/s1238/c">Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1238(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3466">132 Stat. 3466</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/254/dD/s1238/c">“The amendment made by subsection (b)(1) [amending this section] shall apply to any major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 401 or 501, respectively, of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref>, 5191) on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref> applicable to each major disaster and emergency declared by the President on or after <date date="2017-08-01">Aug. 1, 2017</date>, and authorities provided under div. D of <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref> applicable to each major disaster and emergency declared by the President on or after <date date="2016-01-01">Jan. 1, 2016</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1202">section 1202 of Pub. L. 115–254</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/115/123/dB/tVI/s20604/c">Pub. L. 115–123, div. B, title VI, § 20604(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/86">132 Stat. 86</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/123/dB/tVI/s20604/c">
<inline>“This section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172">section 5172 of this title</ref>] and the amendments made by this section shall apply—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to the provision of assistance in response to a major disaster or emergency declared on or after <date date="2017-08-23">August 23, 2017</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> any application for assistance that, as of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>], is pending before Federal Emergency Management Agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any application for assistance that has been denied, where a challenge to that denial is not yet finally resolved as of the date of enactment of this Act.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd0ade00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/2/dB/s1110/e">Pub. L. 113–2, div. B, § 1110(e)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-29">Jan. 29, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/49">127 Stat. 49</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/2/dB/s1110/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuance</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall issue regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5123">section 5123 of this title</ref> and amending this section and sections 5170 and 5191 of this title].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Factors</inline>.—</heading><content>In issuing the regulations, the President shall consider the unique conditions that affect the general welfare of Indian tribal governments.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd0ade01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Local Government</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/707/tI/s103/e">Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 103(e)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4690">102 Stat. 4690</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/707/tI/s103/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘local government’ is deemed to have the same meaning in the Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/pl/93/288">Pub. L. 93–288</ref>, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of this title</ref>], as amended by this Act [see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of this title</ref>], as that term had on <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>, under section 102(6) of the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 [par. (6) of this section] and regulations implementing the Disaster Relief Act of 1974.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of effectiveness</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (1) shall not be effective on and after the 90th day after the President transmits to the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report which includes an interpretation of the term ‘local government’ for purposes of the Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, as amended by this Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Functions of President under <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s103/e/2">section 103(e)(2) of Pub. L. 100–707</ref> delegated to Administrator of Federal Emergency Management Agency by section 3 of Ex. Ord. No. 12673, <date date="1989-03-23">Mar. 23, 1989</date>, 54 F.R. 12571, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5195">section 5195 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="definitions" id="idbd0ade02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dD/s1203">Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1203</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3438">132 Stat. 3438</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/254/dD/s1203">
<inline>“In this division [see Short Title of 2018 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of this title</ref>]:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Administrator’ means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agency</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Agency’ means the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
