<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd2e926a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5196e"><num value="5196e">§ 5196e.</num><heading> Radiological Emergency Preparedness Fund</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury a Radiological Emergency Preparedness Fund, which shall be available under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.], as amended, and Executive Order 12657, for offsite radiological emergency planning, preparedness, and response. Beginning in fiscal year 1999 and thereafter, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall promulgate through rulemaking fees to be assessed and collected, applicable to persons subject to FEMA’s radiological emergency preparedness regulations. The aggregate charges assessed pursuant to this section during fiscal year 1999 shall not be less than 100 percent of the amounts anticipated by FEMA necessary for its radiological emergency preparedness program for such fiscal year. The methodology for assessment and collection of fees shall be fair and equitable; and shall reflect costs of providing such services, including administrative costs of collecting such fees. Fees received pursuant to this section shall be deposited in the Fund as offsetting collections and will become available for authorized purposes on <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, and remain available until expended.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd2e926b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tIII">Pub. L. 105–276, title III</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2502">112 Stat. 2502</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/tVI/s612/c">Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 612(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1410">120 Stat. 1410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd2e926c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd2e926d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd2e926e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12657, referred to in text, is Ex. Ord. No. 12657, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 47513, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5195">section 5195 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd2e926f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999, and not as part of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd2e9270-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbd2e9271-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency” substituted for “Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s612/c">section 612(c) of Pub. L. 109–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s313">section 313 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security. Any reference to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/109/295">Pub. L. 109–295</ref> or an amendment by title VI to be considered to refer and apply to the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency until <date date="2007-03-31">Mar. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s612/f/2">section 612(f)(2) of Pub. L. 109–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s313">section 313 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd2e9272-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
