<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd2e928c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197"><num value="5197">§ 5197.</num><heading> Administrative authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e928d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the powers and duties assigned to the Administrator under this subchapter, the Administrator may exercise the administrative authorities provided under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e928e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory personnel</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e928f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administrator may employ not more than 100 part-time or temporary advisory personnel (including not to exceed 25 subjects of the United Kingdom or citizens of Canada) as the Administrator considers to be necessary in carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e9290-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Persons holding other offices or positions under the United States for which they receive compensation, while serving as advisory personnel, shall receive no additional compensation for such service. Other part-time or temporary advisory personnel so employed may serve without compensation or may receive compensation at a rate not to exceed $180 for each day of service, plus authorized subsistence and travel, as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e9291-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Services of other agency personnel and volunteers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e9292-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> use the services of Federal agencies and, with the consent of any State or local government, accept and use the services of State and local agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e9293-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> establish and use such regional and other offices as may be necessary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e9294-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> use such voluntary and uncompensated services by individuals or organizations as may from time to time be needed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e9295-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Gifts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may accept gifts of supplies, equipment, and facilities and may use or distribute such gifts for emergency preparedness purposes in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e9296-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may reimburse any Federal agency for any of its expenditures or for compensation of its personnel and use or consumption of its materials and facilities under this subchapter to the extent funds are available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e9297-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Printing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may purchase such printing, binding, and blank-book work from public, commercial, or private printing establishments or binderies as the Administrator considers necessary upon orders placed by the Director of the Government Publishing Office or upon waivers issued in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s504">section 504 of title 44</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e9298-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary and proper to carry out any of the provisions of this subchapter and perform any of the powers and duties provided by this subchapter. The Administrator may perform any of the powers and duties provided by this subchapter through or with the aid of such officials of the Federal Emergency Management Agency as the Administrator may designate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd2e9299-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to expend contributions correctly</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e929a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> When, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the State or other person involved, the Administrator finds that there is a failure to expend funds in accordance with the regulations, terms, and conditions established under this subchapter for approved emergency preparedness plans, programs, or projects, the Administrator may notify such State or person that further payments will not be made to the State or person from appropriations under this subchapter (or from funds otherwise available for the purposes of this subchapter for any approved plan, program, or project with respect to which there is such failure to comply) until the Administrator is satisfied that there will no longer be any such failure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e929b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Until so satisfied, the Administrator shall either withhold the payment of any financial contribution to such State or person or limit payments to those programs or projects with respect to which there is substantial compliance with the regulations, terms, and conditions governing plans, programs, or projects hereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e929c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> As used in this subsection, the term “person” means the political subdivision of any State or combination or group thereof or any person, corporation, association, or other entity of any nature whatsoever, including instrumentalities of States and political subdivisions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd2e929d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/288/tVI/s621">Pub. L. 93–288, title VI, § 621</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dC/tXXXIV/s3411/a/3">Pub. L. 103–337, div. C, title XXXIV, § 3411(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3107">108 Stat. 3107</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/351/s3/c/2">Pub. L. 111–351, § 3(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3864">124 Stat. 3864</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dH/tI/s1301/d">Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2537">128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd2e929e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd2e929f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbd2e92a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in section 2253 of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s3412/a">Pub. L. 103–337, § 3412(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd2e92a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/111/351">Pub. L. 111–351</ref> substituted “Administrator” for “Director” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd2e92a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbd2e92a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Director of the Government Publishing Office” substituted for “Public Printer” in subsec. (f) on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s1301/d">section 1301(d) of Pub. L. 113–235</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s301">section 301 of Title 44</ref>, Public Printing and Documents.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd2e92a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
