<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd3102db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h"><num value="5197h">§ 5197h.</num><heading> Minority emergency preparedness demonstration program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd3102dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish a minority emergency preparedness demonstration program to research and promote the capacity of minority communities to provide data, information, and awareness education by providing grants to or executing contracts or cooperative agreements with eligible nonprofit organizations to establish and conduct such programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd3102dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities supported</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An eligible nonprofit organization may use a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3102de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to conduct research into the status of emergency preparedness and disaster response awareness in African American and Hispanic households located in urban, suburban, and rural communities, particularly in those States and regions most impacted by natural and manmade disasters and emergencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3102df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to develop and promote awareness of emergency preparedness education programs within minority communities, including development and preparation of culturally competent educational and awareness materials that can be used to disseminate information to minority organizations and institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd3102e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A nonprofit organization is eligible to be awarded a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section with respect to a program if the organization is a nonprofit organization that is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/3">section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such title, whose primary mission is to provide services to communities predominately populated by minority citizens, and that can demonstrate a partnership with a minority-owned business enterprise or minority business located in a HUBZone (as defined in section 632(p) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003417">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003417"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 15) with respect to the program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd3102e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A recipient of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded under this section may only use the proceeds of the grant, contract, or agreement to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3102e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> acquire expert professional services necessary to conduct research in communities predominately populated by minority citizens, with a primary emphasis on African American and Hispanic communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3102e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> develop and prepare informational materials to promote awareness among minority communities about emergency preparedness and how to protect their households and communities in advance of disasters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3102e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> establish consortia with minority national organizations, minority institutions of higher education, and faith-based institutions to disseminate information about emergency preparedness to minority communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3102e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> implement a joint project with a minority serving institution, including a part B institution (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1061/2">section 1061(2) of title 20</ref>), an institution described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 1063b(e)(1) <sup>1</sup> of title 20, and a Hispanic-serving institution (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1101a/a/5">section 1101a(a)(5) of title 20</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd3102e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Application and review procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, an organization must submit an application to the Administrator at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Administrator may reasonably require. The Administrator shall establish a procedure by which to accept such applications.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd3102e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5197h/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,500,000 for fiscal year 2002 and such funds as may be necessary for fiscal years 2003 through 2007. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd3102e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/288/tVI/s629">Pub. L. 93–288, title VI, § 629</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/73/tIV/s431">Pub. L. 107–73, title IV, § 431</ref>, <date date="2001-11-26">Nov. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/697">115 Stat. 697</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/351/s3/c/2">Pub. L. 111–351, § 3(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3864">124 Stat. 3864</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd3102e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd3102ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd3102eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/p">Section 632(p) of title 15</ref>, referred to in subsec. (c), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657a/b">section 657a(b) of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, by <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXVII/s1701/a/2">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1795">131 Stat. 1795</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1063b/e/1">section 1063b(e)(1) of title 20</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(4), was in the original “subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 326 of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1063b/e/1/A">20 U.S.C. 1063b(e)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), or (C))”, which was translated as reading “subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 326(e)(1) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1063b/e/1/A">20 U.S.C. 1063b(e)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), or (C))” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd3102ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/111/351">Pub. L. 111–351</ref> substituted “Administrator” for “Director” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd3102ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd3102ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
