<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd310317-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5204b"><num value="5204b">§ 5204b.</num><heading> Technical assistance for insular areas</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd310318-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5204b/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Upon the declaration by the President of a disaster in an insular area, the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall assess, in cooperation with the Secretary and chief executive of such insular area, the capability of the insular government to respond to the disaster, including the capability to assess damage; coordinate activities with Federal agencies, particularly the Federal Emergency Management Agency; develop recovery plans, including recommendations for enhancing the survivability of essential infrastructure; negotiate and manage reconstruction contracts; and prevent the misuse of funds. If the President finds that the insular government lacks any of these or other capabilities essential to the recovery effort, then the President shall provide technical assistance to the insular area which the President deems necessary for the recovery effort.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd310319-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5204b/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> One year following the declaration by the President of a disaster in an insular area, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall submit to the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the House Committee on Natural Resources a report on the status of the recovery effort, including an audit of Federal funds expended in the recovery effort and recommendations on how to improve public health and safety, survivability of infrastructure, recovery efforts, and effective use of funds in the event of future disasters.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd31031a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/247/tII/s203">Pub. L. 102–247, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1992-02-24">Feb. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/37">106 Stat. 37</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s15/p">Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(p)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4594">108 Stat. 4594</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/tVI/s612/c">Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 612(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1410">120 Stat. 1410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd31031b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd31031c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd31031d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Omnibus Insular Areas Act of 1992, and not as part of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd31031e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “House Committee on Natural Resources” for “House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd31031f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbd310320-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency” substituted for “Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency” in subsecs. (a) and (b) on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s612/c">section 612(c) of Pub. L. 109–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s313">section 313 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security. Any reference to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/109/295">Pub. L. 109–295</ref> or an amendment by title VI to be considered to refer and apply to the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency until <date date="2007-03-31">Mar. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s612/f/2">section 612(f)(2) of Pub. L. 109–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s313">section 313 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd310321-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
