<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd526db8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409"><num value="5409">§ 5409.</num><heading> Prohibited acts; exemptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526db9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> No person shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526dba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> make use of any means of transportation or communication affecting interstate or foreign commerce or the mails to manufacture for sale, lease, sell, offer for sale or lease, or introduce or deliver, or import into the United States, any manufactured home which is manufactured on or after the effective date of any applicable Federal manufactured home construction and safety standard under this chapter and which does not comply with such standard, except as provided in subsection (b), where such manufacture, lease, sale, offer for sale or lease, introduction, delivery, or importation affects commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526dbb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> fail or refuse to permit access to or copying of records, or fail to make reports or provide information, or fail or refuse to permit entry or inspection, as required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5413">section 5413 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526dbc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> fail to furnish notification of any defect as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5414">section 5414 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526dbd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> fail to issue a certification required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5415">section 5415 of this title</ref>, or issue a certification to the effect that a manufactured home conforms to all applicable Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards, if such person in the exercise of due care has reason to know that such certification is false or misleading in a material respect;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526dbe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> fail to comply with a final order issued by the Secretary under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526dbf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> issue a certification pursuant to subsection (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5403">section 5403 of this title</ref>, if such person in the exercise of due care has reason to know that such certification is false or misleading in a material respect; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526dc0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> after the expiration of the period specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5404/c/2/B">section 5404(c)(2)(B) of this title</ref>, fail to comply with the requirements for the installation program required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5404">section 5404 of this title</ref> in any State that has not adopted and implemented a State installation program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526dc1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526dc2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall not apply to the sale, the offer for sale, or the introduction or delivery for introduction in interstate commerce of any manufactured home after the first purchase of it in good faith for purposes other than resale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526dc3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5410">section 5410 of this title</ref>, paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall not apply to any person who establishes that he did not have reason to know in the exercise of due care that such manufactured home is not in conformity with applicable Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards, or to any person who, prior to such first purchase, holds a certificate issued by the manufacturer or importer of such manufactured home to the effect that such manufactured home conforms to all applicable Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards, unless such person knows that such manufactured home does not so conform.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526dc4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A manufactured home offered for importation in violation of paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall be refused admission into the United States under joint regulations issued by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary, except that the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary may, by such regulations, provide for authorizing the importation of such manufactured home into the United States upon such terms and conditions (including the furnishing of a bond) as may appear to them appropriate to insure that any such manufactured home will be brought into conformity with any applicable Federal manufactured home construction or safety standard prescribed under this chapter, or will be exported from, or forfeited to, the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526dc5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary may, by joint regulations, permit the importation of any manufactured home after the first purchase of it in good faith for purposes other than resale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526dc6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall not apply in the case of a manufactured home intended solely for export, and so labeled or tagged on the manufactured home itself and on the outside of the container, if any, in which it is to be exported.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526dc7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5409/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Compliance with any Federal manufactured home construction or safety standard issued under this chapter does not exempt any person from any liability under common law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd526dc8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tVI/s610">Pub. L. 93–383, title VI, § 610</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/704">88 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/128/tIX/s902/b">Pub. L. 95–128, title IX, § 902(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-12">Oct. 12, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1149">91 Stat. 1149</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/399/tIII/s308/c/4">Pub. L. 96–399, title III, § 308(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-08">Oct. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1641">94 Stat. 1641</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/tVI/s608">Pub. L. 106–569, title VI, § 608</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3009">114 Stat. 3009</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd526dc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd526dca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd526dcb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/106/569">Pub. L. 106–569</ref> added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsecs. (a)(1), (4), (b)(1) to (5), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/399">Pub. L. 96–399</ref> substituted “manufactured home” for “mobile home” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/95/128">Pub. L. 95–128</ref> added par. (6).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd526dcc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd526dcd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/569">Pub. L. 106–569</ref> effective <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, except that amendment has no effect on any order or interpretative bulletin issued under this chapter and published as a proposed rule pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">5 U.S.C. 553</ref> on or before <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/s612">section 612 of Pub. L. 106–569</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5401">section 5401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbd526dce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon the expiration of 180 days following <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/s627">section 627 of Pub. L. 93–383</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5401">section 5401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
