<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd526de5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5412"><num value="5412">§ 5412.</num><heading> Noncompliance with standards or defective nature of manufactured home; administrative or judicial determination; repurchase by manufacturer or repair by distributor or retailer; reimbursement of expenses, etc., by manufacturer; injunctive relief against manufacturer for failure to comply; jurisdiction and venue; damages; period of limitation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526de6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5412/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary or a court of appropriate jurisdiction determines that any manufactured home does not conform to applicable Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards, or that it contains a defect which constitutes an imminent safety hazard, after the sale of such manufactured home by a manufacturer to a distributor or a retailer and prior to the sale of such manufactured home by such distributor or retailer to a purchaser—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526de7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5412/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the manufacturer shall immediately repurchase such manufactured home from such distributor or retailer at the price paid by such distributor or retailer, plus all transportation charges involved and a reasonable reimbursement of not less than 1 per centum per month of such price paid prorated from the date of receipt by certified mail of notice of such nonconformance to the date of repurchase by the manufacturer; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd526de8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5412/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the manufacturer, at his own expense, shall immediately furnish the purchasing distributor or retailer the required conforming part or parts or equipment for installation by the distributor or retailer on or in such manufactured home, and for the installation involved the manufacturer shall reimburse such distributor or retailer for the reasonable value of such installation plus a reasonable reimbursement of not less than 1 per centum per month of the manufacturer’s or distributor’s selling price prorated from the date of receipt by certified mail of notice of such nonconformance to the date such vehicle is brought into conformance with applicable Federal standards, so long as the distributor or retailer proceeds with reasonable diligence with the installation after the required part or equipment is received.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The value of such reasonable reimbursements as specified in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall be fixed by mutual agreement of the parties, or, failing such agreement, by the court pursuant to the provisions of subsection (b).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd526de9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5412/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> If any manufacturer fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (a), then the distributor or retailer, as the case may be, to whom such manufactured home has been sold may bring an action seeking a court injunction compelling compliance with such requirements on the part of such manufacturer. Such action may be brought in any district court in the United States in the district in which such manufacturer resides, or is found, or has an agent, without regard to the amount in controversy, and the person bringing the action shall also be entitled to recover any damage sustained by him, as well as all court costs plus reasonable attorneys’ fees. Any action brought pursuant to this section shall be forever barred unless commenced within three years after the cause of action shall have accrued.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd526dea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tVI/s613">Pub. L. 93–383, title VI, § 613</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/706">88 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/399/tIII/s308/c/4">Pub. L. 96–399, title III, § 308(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-08">Oct. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1641">94 Stat. 1641</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/tVI/s603/b/1">Pub. L. 106–569, title VI, § 603(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2999">114 Stat. 2999</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd526deb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd526dec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd526ded-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/569">Pub. L. 106–569</ref> substituted “retailer” for “dealer” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/399">Pub. L. 96–399</ref> substituted “manufactured home” for “mobile home” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd526dee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd526def-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/569">Pub. L. 106–569</ref> effective <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, except that amendment has no effect on any order or interpretative bulletin issued under this chapter and published as a proposed rule pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">5 U.S.C. 553</ref> on or before <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/s612">section 612 of Pub. L. 106–569</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5401">section 5401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbd526df0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon the expiration of 180 days following <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/s627">section 627 of Pub. L. 93–383</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5401">section 5401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
