<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd54b8b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5502"><num value="5502">§ 5502.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd54b8b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5502/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “solar heating”, with respect to any building, means the use of solar energy to meet such portion of the total heating needs of such building (including hot water), or such portion of the needs of such building for hot water (where its remaining heating needs are met by other methods), as may be required under performance criteria prescribed by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development utilizing the services of the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd54b8b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5502/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the terms “solar heating and cooling” and “combined solar heating and cooling”, with respect to any building, mean the use of solar energy to provide both such portion of the total heating needs of such building (including hot water) and such portion of the total cooling needs of such building, or such portion of the needs of such building for hot water (where its remaining heating needs are met by other methods) and such portion of the total cooling needs of a building, as may be required under performance criteria prescribed by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development utilizing the services of the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and such term includes cooling by means of nocturnal heat radiation, by evaporation, or by other methods of meeting peakload energy requirements at nonpeakload times;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd54b8b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5502/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “residential dwellings” includes previously occupied and new single family and multifamily dwellings, mobile homes, and publicly assisted housing owned by a private sponsor or a State or local housing authority not covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5515">section 5515 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd54b8b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5502/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd54b8b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5502/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd54b8b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5502/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Omitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbd54b8b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/409/s3">Pub. L. 93–409, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1070">88 Stat. 1070</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/438/tI/s104/f">Pub. L. 93–438, title I, § 104(f)</ref>, title III, § 301(h), <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1238">88 Stat. 1238</ref>, 1250; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/577">91 Stat. 577</ref>, 606, 607; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd54b8ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd54b8bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd54b8bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6) of this section, which defined the term “Director” as meaning the Director of the National Science Foundation, was omitted because of the transfer of functions from the National Science Foundation to the Secretary of Energy and the substitution of “Secretary of Energy” for “Director” wherever appearing in this subchapter. See Transfer of Functions note set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd54b8bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Pars. (1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd54b8be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd54b8bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Energy” substituted for “Director of the National Science Foundation” in pars. (1) and (2) pursuant to sections 104(f) and 301(h) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/438">Pub. L. 93–438</ref>, which are classified to sections 5814(f) and 5871(h) of this title and which transferred functions of National Science Foundation relating to or utilized in connection with solar heating and cooling development to Administrator of Energy Research and Development Administration, and pursuant to sections 301(a), 703, and 707 of <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, which are classified to sections 7151(a), 7293, and 7297 of this title and which terminated Energy Research and Development Administration and transferred its functions and functions of Administrator thereof (with certain exceptions) to Secretary of Energy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
