<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd5728f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5506"><num value="5506">§ 5506.</num><heading> Test procedures and definitive performance criteria for solar heating and combined solar heating and cooling components and systems and suitable dwellings; determination, consultation and publication in Federal Register</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as feasible, and utilizing data available from the demonstration programs under sections 5503 and 5504 of this title, the Secretary, utilizing the services of the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and in consultation with the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy shall determine, prescribe, and publish in the Federal Register in accordance with the applicable provisions regarding rulemaking prescribed by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>,</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd5728f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5506/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> definitive performance criteria for solar heating and combined solar heating and cooling components and systems to be used in residential dwellings, taking into account climatic variations existing between different geographic areas;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd5728f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5506/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> definitive performance criteria (relating to suitability for solar heating and for combined solar heating and cooling) for such dwellings, taking into account climatic variations existing between different geographic areas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd5728f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5506/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> procedures whereby manufacturers of solar heating and combined solar heating and cooling components and systems shall have their products tested in order to provide certification that such products conform to the performance criteria established under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbd5728f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/409/s8">Pub. L. 93–409, § 8</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1073">88 Stat. 1073</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/438/tI/s104/f">Pub. L. 93–438, title I, § 104(f)</ref>, title III, § 301(h), <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1238">88 Stat. 1238</ref>, 1250; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/577">91 Stat. 577</ref>, 606, 607; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd5728f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd5728f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd5728f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd5728f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd5728f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Energy” substituted in text for “Director”, meaning Director of National Science Foundation, pursuant to sections 104(f) and 301(h) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/438">Pub. L. 93–438</ref>, which are classified to sections 5814(f) and 5871(h) of this title and which transferred functions of National Science Foundation relating to or utilized in connection with solar heating and cooling development to Administrator of Energy Research and Development Administration, and pursuant to sections 301(a), 703, and 707 of <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, which are classified to sections 7151(a), 7293, and 7297 of this title and which terminated Energy Research and Development Administration and transferred its functions and functions of Administrator thereof (with certain exceptions) to Secretary of Energy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
