<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd5728fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5507"><num value="5507">§ 5507.</num><heading> Arrangements with Federal agencies for development and demonstration of solar heating and combined heating and cooling systems for commercial buildings</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of General Services, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and concurrently with the conduct of the programs under sections 5503 and 5504 of this title, shall enter into arrangements with appropriate Federal agencies to carry out such projects and activities (including demonstration projects) with respect to apartment buildings, office buildings, factories, crop-drying facilities and other agricultural structures, public buildings (including schools and colleges), and other non-residential, commercial, or industrial buildings, taking into account the special needs of and individual differences in such buildings based upon size, function, and other relevant factors, as may be appropriate for the early development and demonstration of solar heating and combined solar heating and cooling systems suitable and effective for use in such buildings.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd5728fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/409/s9">Pub. L. 93–409, § 9</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1074">88 Stat. 1074</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/438/tI/s104/f">Pub. L. 93–438, title I, § 104(f)</ref>, title III, § 301(h), <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1238">88 Stat. 1238</ref>, 1250; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/577">91 Stat. 577</ref>, 606, 607; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd5728fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd5728fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd5728fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd5728ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd572900-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Energy” substituted in text for “Director”, meaning Director of National Science Foundation, pursuant to sections 104(f) and 301(h) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/438">Pub. L. 93–438</ref>, which are classified to sections 5814(f) and 5871(h) of this title and which transferred functions of National Science Foundation relating to or utilized in connection with solar heating and cooling development to Administrator of Energy Research and Development Administration, and pursuant to sections 301(a), 703, and 707 of <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, which are classified to sections 7151(a), 7293, and 7297 of this title and which terminated Energy Research and Development Administration and transferred its functions and functions of Administrator thereof (with certain exceptions) to Secretary of Energy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
