<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd572908-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5509"><num value="5509">§ 5509.</num><heading> Supervision of systems and programs by Secretary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd572909-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5509/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring of performance; collection and evaluation of data; studies and investigation; reports to Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, utilizing the services of the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and in coordination with such other Government agencies as may be appropriate, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd57290a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5509/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> monitor the performance and operation of solar heating and combined solar heating and cooling systems installed in residential dwellings under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd57290b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5509/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> collect and evaluate data and information on the performance and operation of solar heating and combined solar heating and cooling systems installed in residential dwellings under this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd57290c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5509/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> from time to time, carrying out such studies and investigations and take such other actions, including the submission of special reports to the Congress when appropriate, as may be necessary to assure that the programs for which the Secretary is responsible under this subchapter effectively carry out the policy of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd57290d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5509/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation with scientific, technical, and professional societies and industry representatives in development of performance criteria and test procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the development of the performance criteria and test procedures required under sections 5503, 5504, and 5506 of this title, the Secretary shall work closely with the appropriate scientific, technical, and professional societies and industry representatives to insure the best possible use of available expertise in this area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd57290e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5509/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Continued liaison with building and related industries and scientific and technical communities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall also maintain continuing liaison with the building industry and related industries and interests, and with the scientific and technical community during and after the period of the programs carried out under this subchapter, in order to assure that the projected benefits of such programs are and will continue to be realized.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd57290f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/409/s11">Pub. L. 93–409, § 11</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1074">88 Stat. 1074</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd572910-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd572911-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd572912-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
