<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd572913-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510"><num value="5510">§ 5510.</num><heading> Dissemination of information to promote practical use of solar heating and cooling technologies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd572914-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination by Secretary with other Federal agencies in dissemination to Federal, State, and local authorities, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall take all possible steps to assure that full and complete information with respect to the demonstrations and other activities conducted under this subchapter is made available to Federal, State, and local authorities, the building industry and related segments of the economy, the scientific and technical community, and the public at large, both during and after the close of the programs under this subchapter, with the objective of promoting and facilitating to the maximum extent feasible the early and widespread practical use of solar energy for the heating and cooling of buildings throughout the United States. In accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5514">section 5514 of this title</ref> such information shall be disseminated on a coordinated basis by the Secretary, the Administrator, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Secretary of Energy, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office, and other appropriate Federal offices and agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd572915-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Studies, investigations and modifications of building codes, zoning ordinances, etc., to promote use of solar energy in buildings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd572916-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> study and investigate the effect of building codes, zoning ordinances, tax regulations, and other laws, codes, ordinances, and practices upon the practical use of solar energy for the heating and cooling of buildings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd572917-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> determine the extent to which such laws, codes, ordinances, and practices should be changed to permit or facilitate such use, and the methods by which any such changes may best be brought about; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd572918-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> study the necessity of a program of incentives to accelerate the commercial application of solar heating and cooling technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd572919-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment and operation of Solar Heating and Cooling Information Data Bank; retrieval and dissemination services; compilation of information for use by governmental agencies, nonprofit organizations and private persons; utilization of existing information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd57291a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In carrying out his functions under subsections (a) and (b) the Secretary, utilizing the capabilities of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Department of Commerce, and the Secretary of Energy to the maximum extent possible, shall establish and operate a Solar Heating and Cooling Information Data Bank (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “bank”) for the purpose of collecting, reviewing, processing, and disseminating solar heating and cooling information and data in a timely and accurate manner in support of the objectives of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd57291b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Information and data compiled in the bank shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd57291c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> technical information (including reports, journal articles, dissertions,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003433">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003433"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “dissertations,”.</note> monographs, and project descriptions) on solar energy research, development, and applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd57291d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> technical information on the design, construction, and maintenance of buildings compatible with solar heating and cooling concepts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd57291e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> physical and chemical properties of the materials required for solar heating and cooling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd57291f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> climatic conditions in appropriate areas of the United States, including those areas where the demonstrations are to be located; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd572920-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> engineering performance of devices utilized in solar heating and cooling or to be employed in the demonstrations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd572921-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5514">section 5514 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall provide retrieval and dissemination services to cover the solar heating and cooling information described under paragraph (2) for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd572922-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Federal, State, and local government organizations that are active in the area of energy resources (and their contractors);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd572923-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> universities, colleges, and other nonprofit organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd572924-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> private persons, upon request, in appropriate cases.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd572925-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In carrying out his functions under this subsection, the Secretary shall utilize, when feasible, the existing data base of scientific and technical information in Federal agencies, adding to such data base any information described in paragraph (2) which does not already reside in such base.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd572926-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5510/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual reports to President and Congress by officers and agencies; contents; special annual report by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Federal officer and agency having functions under this subchapter shall include in his or its annual report to the President and the Congress a full and complete description of his or its activities (current and projected) under this subchapter, along with his or its recommendations for legislative, administrative, or other action to improve the programs under this subchapter or to achieve the objectives of this subchapter more promptly and effectively. In addition, the Secretary shall submit annually to the President and the Congress a special report summarizing in appropriate detail all of the activities (current and projected) of the various Federal officers and agencies having functions under this subchapter, with the objective of presenting a comprehensive overall view of such programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd572927-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/409/s12">Pub. L. 93–409, § 12</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1075">88 Stat. 1075</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/438/tI/s104/f">Pub. L. 93–438, title I, § 104(f)</ref>, title III, § 301(h), <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1238">88 Stat. 1238</ref>, 1250; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/577">91 Stat. 577</ref>, 606, 607; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4732/b/21">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(b)(21)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–585.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd572928-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd572929-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd57292a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> substituted “Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office” for “Commissioner of the Patent Office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd57292b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd57292c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> effective 4 months after <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, see section 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4731] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s1">section 1 of Title 35</ref>, Patents.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd57292d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which a report required under subsec. (d) of this section is listed in item 12 on page 102), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd57292e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Energy” substituted for “Director”, meaning Director of National Science Foundation, in subsec. (a) and for “National Science Foundation” in subsec. (c) pursuant to sections 104(f) and 301(h) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/438">Pub. L. 93–438</ref>, which are classified to sections 5814(f) and 5871(h) of this title and which transferred functions of National Science Foundation relating to or utilized in connection with solar heating and cooling development to Administrator of Energy Research and Development Administration, and pursuant to sections 301(a), 703, and 707 of <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, which are classified to sections 7151(a), 7293, and 7297 of this title and which terminated Energy Research and Development Administration and transferred its functions and functions of Administrator thereof (with certain exceptions) to Secretary of Energy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
