<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd572962-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5516"><num value="5516">§ 5516.</num><heading> Transfer of functions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within sixty days after the effective date of the law creating the Energy Research and Development Administration or any other law creating a permanent Federal organization or agency having jurisdiction over the energy research and development functions of the United States (or within sixty days after <date date="1974-09-03">September 3, 1974</date>, if the effective date of such law occurs prior to the enactment of this subchapter), the energy research and development functions vested in the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the National Science Foundation under this subchapter and any funds which may have been appropriated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5517">section 5517 of this title</ref>, to the extent necessary or appropriate, may, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Office of Management and Budget, be transferred to and vested in the Energy Research and Development Administration or such other organization or agency.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd572963-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/409/s18">Pub. L. 93–409, § 18</ref>, <date date="1974-09-03">Sept. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1078">88 Stat. 1078</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd572964-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd572965-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd572966-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Energy Research and Development Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of National Science Foundation relating to or utilized in connection with solar heating and cooling development transferred to Administrator of Energy Research and Development Administration by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5814/f">section 5814(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
