<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd5be3af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816"><num value="5816">§ 5816.</num><heading> Personnel and services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of officers and employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to select, appoint, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2201/d">section 2201(d) of this title</ref> as are necessary to perform the functions now or hereafter vested in him and to prescribe their functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment of experts and consultants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to obtain services as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Participation of military personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to provide for participation of military personnel in the performance of his functions. Members of the Army, the Navy, the Air Force, or the Marine Corps may be detailed for service in the Administration by the appropriate military Secretary, pursuant to cooperative agreements with the Secretary, for service in the Administration in positions other than a position the occupant of which must be approved by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Status of military personnel unaffected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appointment, detail, or assignment to, acceptance of, and service in, any appointive or other position in the Administration under this section shall in no way affect the status, office, rank, or grade which such officers or enlisted men may occupy or hold, or any emolument, perquisite, right, privilege, or benefit incident to or arising out of any such status, office, rank, or grade. A member so appointed, detailed, or assigned shall not be subject to direction or control by his Armed Force, or any officer thereof, directly or indirectly, with respect to the responsibilities exercised in the position to which appointed, detailed, or assigned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Transportation and per diem expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to pay transportation expenses, and per diem in lieu of subsistence expenses, in accordance with chapter 57 of title 5 for travel between places of recruitment and duty, and while at places of duty, of persons appointed for emergency, temporary, or seasonal services in the field service of the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel of other agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to utilize, on a reimbursable basis, the services of any personnel made available by any department, agency, or instrumentality, including any independent agency of the Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory boards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to establish advisory boards, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5, to advise with and make recommendations to the Administrator on legislation, policies, administration, research, and other matters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd5be3b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5816/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment of noncitizens</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to employ persons who are not citizens of the United States in expert, scientific, technical, or professional capacities whenever he deems it in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd5be3b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/438/tI/s106">Pub. L. 93–438, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1239">88 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/264">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(264)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4335">136 Stat. 4335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd5be3b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd5be3ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd5be3bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5,” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act (<ref href="/us/pl/92/463">Public Law 92–463</ref>),”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd5be3bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd5be3bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Energy Research and Development Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd5be3be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Boards</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory boards established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a board established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such board is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a board established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
