<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd5be3f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5820"><num value="5820">§ 5820.</num><heading> Coordination with environmental efforts</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to establish programs to utilize research and development performed by other Federal agencies to minimize the adverse environmental effects of energy projects. The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, as well as other affected agencies and departments, shall cooperate fully with the Administrator in establishing and maintaining such programs, and in establishing appropriate interagency agreements to develop cooperative programs and to avoid unnecessary duplication.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd5e54f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/438/tI/s110">Pub. L. 93–438, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1242">88 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd5e54f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd5e54f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd5e54f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Energy Research and Development Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd5e54fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Research Applied to National Needs; Coordination of Energy Research and Development Activities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/471/s2/e/3">Pub. L. 94–471, § 2(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2053">90 Stat. 2053</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/471/s2/e/3">“In the conduct of the energy research and development activities under the ‘Research Applied to National Needs’ category, the National Science Foundation shall coordinate all new energy research project awards with the Administrator of the Energy Research and Development Administration or his designee.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/94/86/s5">Pub. L. 94–86, § 5</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/430">89 Stat. 430</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
