<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd631031-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5872"><num value="5872">§ 5872.</num><heading> Transfer of personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd631032-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5872/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Provisions of law applicable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in the next sentence, the personnel employed in connection with, and the personnel positions, assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, arising from, available to or to be made available in connection with the functions and programs transferred by this chapter, are, subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1531">section 1531 of title 31</ref>, correspondingly transferred for appropriate allocation. Personnel positions expressly created by law, personnel occupying those positions on the effective date of this chapter, and personnel authorized to receive compensation at the rate prescribed for offices and positions at levels II, III, IV, or V of the Executive Schedule (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313–531">5 U.S.C. 5313–531</ref>6) on the effective date of this chapter shall be subject to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5871">section 5871 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd631033-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5872/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition against separation or reduction in grade or compensation for one year after transfer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), transfer of nontemporary personnel pursuant to this chapter shall not cause any such employee to be separated or reduced in grade or compensation for one year after such transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd631034-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5872/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation in new position at not less than rate provided for previous position</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who, on the effective date of this chapter, held a position compensated in accordance with the Executive Schedule prescribed in chapter 53 of title 5, and who, without a break in service, is appointed in the Administration to a position having duties comparable to those performed immediately preceding his appointment shall continue to be compensated in his new position at not less than the rate provided for his previous position.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd631035-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/438/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 93–438, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1250">88 Stat. 1250</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd631036-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd631037-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd631038-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/438">Pub. L. 93–438</ref>, <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1233">88 Stat. 1233</ref>, known as the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5801">section 5801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), refers to the effective date of <ref href="/us/pl/93/438">Pub. L. 93–438</ref>. See <ref href="/us/pl/93/438/s312">section 312 of Pub. L. 93–438</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Interim Appointments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5801">section 5801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd631039-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a), “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1531">section 1531 of title 31</ref>” substituted for “section 202 of the Budget and Accounting Procedures Act of 1950 (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s581c">31 U.S.C. 581c</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd63103a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd63103b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Energy Research and Development Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
