<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd6580c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5903d"><num value="5903d">§ 5903d.</num><heading> Clean coal technology projects; proposals, implementation, funding, etc.</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 60 days following <date date="1985-12-19">December 19, 1985</date>, the Secretary of Energy shall, pursuant to the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5901">42 U.S.C. 5901</ref>, et seq.), issue a general request for proposals for clean coal technology projects for which the Secretary of Energy upon review may provide financial assistance awards. Proposals for clean coal technology projects under this section shall be submitted to the Department of Energy within 60 days after issuance of the general request for proposals. The Secretary of Energy shall make any project selections no later than <date date="1986-08-01">August 1, 1986</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary may vest fee title or other property interests acquired under cost-shared clean coal technology agreements in any entity, including the United States: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall not finance more than 50 per centum of the total costs of a project as estimated by the Secretary as of the date of award of financial assistance: <i>Provided further</i>, That cost-sharing by project sponsors is required in each of the design, construction, and operating phases proposed to be included in a project: <i>Provided further</i>, That financial assistance for costs in excess of those estimated as of the date of award of original financial assistance may not be provided in excess of the proportion of costs borne by the Government in the original agreement and only up to 25 per centum of the original financial assistance: <i>Provided further</i>, That revenues or royalties from prospective operation of projects beyond the time considered in the award of financial assistance, or proceeds from prospective sale of the assets of the project, or revenues or royalties from replication of technology in future projects or plants are not cost-sharing for the purposes of this appropriation: <i>Provided further</i>, That other appropriated Federal funds are not cost-sharing for the purposes of this appropriation: <i>Provided further</i>, That existing facilities, equipment, and supplies, or previously expended research or development funds are not cost-sharing for the purposes of this appropriation, except as amortized, depreciated, or expensed in normal business practice.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd6580c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/190/s101/d/tII/s201">Pub. L. 99–190, § 101(d) [title II, § 201]</ref>, <date date="1985-12-19">Dec. 19, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1224">99 Stat. 1224</ref>, 1251.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd6580c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd6580c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd6580c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/93/577">Pub. L. 93–577</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1878">88 Stat. 1878</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter (§ 5901 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5901">section 5901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd6580c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd6580c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd6580c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Provisions Relating to Projects Using Clean Coal Technologies</heading><p>Provisions relating to projects using clean coal technologies were contained in the following appropriations acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/154/tII">Pub. L. 102–154, title II</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1019">105 Stat. 1019</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/211/tII">Pub. L. 103–211, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-02-12">Feb. 12, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/18">108 Stat. 18</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/512/tII">Pub. L. 101–512, title II</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1944">104 Stat. 1944</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/211/tII">Pub. L. 103–211, title II</ref>, <date date="1994-02-12">Feb. 12, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/18">108 Stat. 18</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/121/tII">Pub. L. 101–121, title II</ref>, <date date="1989-10-23">Oct. 23, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/728">103 Stat. 728</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/446/tII">Pub. L. 100–446, title II</ref>, <date date="1988-09-27">Sept. 27, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1811">102 Stat. 1811</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/g/tII">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(g) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-213">101 Stat. 1329–213</ref>, 1329–240.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/h/tII">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(h) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-242">100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, 1783–272, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/h/tII">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(h) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-242">100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>, 3341–272.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
