<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd67f2b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912"><num value="5912">§ 5912.</num><heading> Water resource assessments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd67f2b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessments by Water Resources Council of water resource requirements and water supply availability for nonnuclear energy technologies; preparation requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Water Resources Council shall undertake assessments of water resource requirements and water supply availability for any nonnuclear energy technology and any probable combinations of technologies which are the subject of Federal research and development efforts authorized by this chapter, and the commercial development of which could have significant impacts on water resources. In the preparation of its assessment, the Council shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd67f2b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> utilize to the maximum extent practicable data on water supply and demand available in the files of member agencies of the Council;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd67f2b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> collect and compile any additional data it deems necessary for complete and accurate assessments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd67f2b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> give full consideration to the constraints upon availability imposed by treaty, compact, court decree, State water laws, and water rights granted pursuant to State and Federal law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd67f2b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> assess the effects of development of such technology on water quality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd67f2b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> include estimates of cost associated with production and management of the required water supply, and the cost of disposal of waste water generated by the proposed facility or process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd67f2b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> assess the environmental, social, and economic impact of any change in use of currently utilized water resource that may be required by the proposed facility or process; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd67f2ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> consult with the Council on Environmental Quality.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd67f2bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Request by Secretary that Water Resources Council prepare assessment of availability of adequate water resources for proposed demonstration projects; report; publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For any proposed demonstration project which may involve a significant impact on water resources, the Secretary shall, as a precondition of Federal assistance to that proj­ect, request the Water Resources Council to prepare an assessment of water requirements and availability for such project. A report on the assessment shall be published in the Federal Register for public review thirty days prior to the expenditure of Federal funds on the demonstration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd67f2bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessment by Water Resources Council of availability of adequate water resources as precondition for Federal assistance for commercial application of nonnuclear energy technologies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For any proposed Federal assistance for commercial application of energy technologies pursuant to this chapter, the Water Resource <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003447">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003447"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Resources”.</note> Council shall, as a precondition of such Federal assistance, provide to the Secretary an assessment of the availability of adequate water resources for such commercial application and an evaluation of the environmental, social, and economic impacts of the dedication of water to such uses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd67f2bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of reports of assessments and evaluations by Water Resources Council in Federal Register; public review and comments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Reports of assessments and evaluations prepared by the Council pursuant to subsections (a) and (c) shall be published in the Federal Register and at least ninety days shall be provided for public review and comment. Comments received shall accompany the reports when they are submitted to the Secretary and shall be available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd67f2be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion of survey and analysis of regional and national water resource availability in biennial assessment by Water Resources Council</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Council shall include a broad survey and analysis of regional and national water resource availability for energy development in the biennial assessment required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–1/a">section 1962a–1(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd67f2bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5912/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary as member of Water Resources Council</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, upon enactment of this subsection, be a member of the Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd67f2c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/577/s13">Pub. L. 93–577, § 13</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1893">88 Stat. 1893</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/39/tI/s110">Pub. L. 95–39, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1977-06-03">June 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/186">91 Stat. 186</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tX/s1009/b/9">Pub. L. 109–58, title X, § 1009(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/935">119 Stat. 935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd67f2c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd67f2c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd67f2c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsecs. (b) to (d), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/39/s110/1">Pub. L. 95–39, § 110(1)</ref>, substituted “The Water Resources Council” for “At the request of the Administrator, the Water Resources Council”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/39/s110/2">Pub. L. 95–39, § 110(2)</ref>, substituted “the Administrator shall, as a precondition of Federal assistance to that project, request the Water Resources Council to prepare an assessment of water requirements and availability for such project” for “the Administrator shall, as a precondition of Federal assistance to that project, prepare or have prepared an assessment of the availability of adequate water resources”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/39/s110/3">Pub. L. 95–39, § 110(3)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbd67f2c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbd67f2c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Council on Environmental Quality and Office of Environmental Quality relating to evaluation provided for by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5910">section 5910 of this title</ref> transferred to Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1977, § 5E, 42 F.R. 56101, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1634">91 Stat. 1634</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, effective <date date="1978-02-26">Feb. 26, 1978</date>, pursuant to Ex. Ord. No. 12040, <date date="1978-02-24">Feb. 24, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 8097, formerly set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5910">section 5910 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
