<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd67f2d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s5915"><num value="5915">§ 5915.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There may be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the purposes of this chapter such sums as may be authorized in annual authorization Acts.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd67f2d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/577/s16">Pub. L. 93–577, § 16</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1894">88 Stat. 1894</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tX/s1009/b/10">Pub. L. 109–58, title X, § 1009(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/935">119 Stat. 935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd67f2d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd67f2d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd67f2d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—<ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, in section catchline, substituted “Authorization of appropriations” for “Appropriation authorization”, and in text, substituted “There may be appropriated to the Secretary” for “(a) There may be appropriated to the Administrator” and struck out subsecs. (b) and (c), which related to amounts to be made available to the Council on Environmental Quality and the Water Resources Council and amounts which might be appropriated for demonstration projects.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd67f2d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd67f2d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Alternative Fuels Production; Energy Security Reserve Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/126/tII/s201">Pub. L. 96–126, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1979-11-27">Nov. 27, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/970">93 Stat. 970</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/190/s101/d/tII/s201">Pub. L. 99–190, § 101(d) [title II, § 201]</ref>, <date date="1985-12-19">Dec. 19, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1224">99 Stat. 1224</ref>, 1255, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/190/s101/d/tII/s201">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In order to expedite the domestic development and production of alternative fuels and to reduce dependence on foreign supplies of energy resources by establishing such domestic production at maximum levels at the earliest time practicable, there is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a special fund to be designated the ‘Energy Security Reserve’, to which is appropriated $19,000,000,000, to remain available until expended: <i>Provided</i>, That these funds shall be available for obligation only to stimulate domestic commercial production of alternative fuels and only to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts: <i>Provided further</i>, That of these funds $1,500,000,000 shall be available immediately to the Secretary of Energy to carry out the provisions of the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5901">42 U.S.C. 5901</ref>, et seq.), to remain available until expended, for the purchase or production by way of purchase commitments or price guarantees of alternative fuels: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall immediately begin the contract process for purchases of, or commitments to purchase, or to resell alternative fuels to the extent of appropriations provided herein: <i>Provided further</i>, That of these funds an additional $708,000,000 shall be available immediately to the Secretary of Energy, to remain available until expended, to support preliminary alternative fuels commercialization activities under the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974, as amended, of which (1) not to exceed $100,000,000 shall be available for project development feasibility studies, such individual awards not to exceed $4,000,000: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary may require repayment of such funds where studies determine that such project proposals have economic or technical feasibility; (2) not to exceed $100,000,000 shall be available for cooperative agreements with non-Federal entities, such individual agreements not to exceed $25,000,000 to support commercial scale development of alternative fuel facilities; (3) not to exceed $500,000,000 shall be available for a reserve to cover any defaults from loan guarantees issued to finance the construction of alternative fuels production facilities as authorized by the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974, as amended: <i>Provided</i>, That the indebtedness guaranteed or committed to be guaranteed under this appropriation shall not exceed the aggregate of $1,500,000,000; and (4) not to exceed $8,000,000 shall be available for program management.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act [<ref href="/us/pl/96/126">Pub. L. 96–126</ref>] shall be deemed to satisfy the requirements for congressional action pursuant to sections 7(c) and 19 of said Act [section 5906(c) and former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5919">section 5919 of this title</ref>] with respect to any purchase commitment, price guarantee, or loan guarantee for which funds appropriated hereby are utilized or obligated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“For the purposes of this appropriation the term ‘alternative fuels’, means gaseous, liquid, or solid fuels and chemical feedstocks derived from coal, shale, tar sands, lignite, peat, biomass, solid waste, unconventional natural gas, and other minerals or organic materials other than crude oil or any derivative thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Within ninety days following enactment of this Act [<date date="1979-11-27">Nov. 27, 1979</date>], the Secretary of Energy in his sole discretion shall issue a solicitation for applications which shall include criteria for project development feasibility studies described in this account.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Loan guarantees for oil shale facilities issued under this appropriation may be used to finance construction of full-sized commercial facilities without regard to the proviso in section 19(b)(1) of said Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5919/b/1">section 5919(b)(1) of this title</ref>] requiring the prior demonstration of a modular facility.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In any case in which the Government, under the provisions of this appropriation, accepts delivery of and does not resell any alternative fuels, such fuels shall be used by an appropriate Federal agency. Such Federal agency shall pay into the reserve the market price, as determined by the Secretary, for such fuels from sums appropriated to such Federal agency for the purchase of fuels. The Secretary shall pay the contractor, from sums appropriated herein, the contract price for such fuels.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“All amounts received by the Secretary under this appropriation, including fees, any other monies, property, or assets derived by the Secretary from operations under this appropriation shall be deposited in the reserve.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“All payments for obligations and appropriate expenses (including reimbursements to other Government accounts), pursuant to operations of the Secretary under this appropriation shall be paid from the reserve subject to appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“For the establishment in the Treasury of the United States of a special fund to be designated the ‘Solar and Conservation Reserve’, $1,000,000,000 to remain available until expended: <i>Provided</i>, That these funds shall be available for obligation only to stimulate solar energy and conservation: <i>Provided further</i>, That the withdrawal of said funds shall be subject to the passage of authorizing legislation and only to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts.”</p>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Additional provisions relating to appropriations for the Energy Security Reserve Fund, purposes for which the Fund is available, and administrative provisions for the Fund and alternative fuels production were contained in the following appropriation Acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tI/s2103">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title I, § 2103</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1058">98 Stat. 1058</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/100/tII">Pub. L. 97–100, title II</ref>, <date date="1981-12-23">Dec. 23, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1407">95 Stat. 1407</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/12/tI">Pub. L. 97–12, title I</ref>, <date date="1981-06-05">June 5, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/48">95 Stat. 48</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/369/s121">Pub. L. 96–369, § 121</ref>, <date date="1980-10-01">Oct. 1, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1357">94 Stat. 1357</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/304/tI">Pub. L. 96–304, title I</ref>, <date date="1980-07-08">July 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/880-882">94 Stat. 880–882</ref>, as amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/514/tII">Pub. L. 96–514, title II</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2974">94 Stat. 2974</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
