<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd6a3c74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104"><num value="6104">§ 6104.</num><heading> Enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd6a3c75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Methods of achieving compliance with regulations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The head of any Federal department or agency who prescribes regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6103">section 6103 of this title</ref> may seek to achieve compliance with any such regulation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd6a3c76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> by terminating, or refusing to grant or to continue, assistance under the program or activity involved to any recipient with respect to whom there has been an express finding on the record, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing, of a failure to comply with any such regulation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd6a3c77-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> by any other means authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd6a3c78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on termination of, or on refusal to grant or to continue, assistance; disbursement of withheld funds to achiever agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any termination of, or refusal to grant or to continue, assistance under subsection (a)(1) shall be limited to the particular political entity or other recipient with respect to which a finding has been made under subsection (a)(1). Any such termination or refusal shall be limited in its effect to the particular program or activity, or part of such program or activity, with respect to which such finding has been made. No such termination or refusal shall be based in whole or in part on any finding with respect to any program or activity which does not receive Federal financial assistance. Whenever the head of any Federal department or agency who prescribes regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6103">section 6103 of this title</ref> withholds funds pursuant to subsection (a), he may, in accordance with regulations he shall prescribe, disburse the funds so withheld directly to any public or nonprofit private organization or agency, or State or political subdivision thereof, which demonstrates the ability to achieve the goals of the Federal statute author­izing the program or activity while complying with regulations issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6103">section 6103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd6a3c79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Advice as to failure to comply with regulation; determination that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No action may be taken under subsection (a) until the head of the Federal department or agency involved has advised the appropriate person of the failure to comply with the regulation involved and has determined that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd6a3c7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congressional committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any action taken under subsection (a), the head of the Federal department or agency involved shall transmit a written report of the circumstances and grounds of such action to the committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate having legislative jurisdiction over the program or activity involved. No such action shall take effect until thirty days after the transmission of any such report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd6a3c7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Injunctions; notice of violations; costs; conditions for actions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd6a3c7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> When any interested person brings an action in any United States district court for the district in which the defendant is found or transacts business to enjoin a violation of this Act by any program or activity receiving Federal financial assistance, such interested person shall give notice by registered mail not less than 30 days prior to the commencement of that action to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Attorney General of the United States, and the person against whom the action is directed. Such interested person may elect, by a demand for such relief in his complaint, to recover reasonable attorney’s fees, in which case the court shall award the costs of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, to the prevailing plaintiff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd6a3c7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The notice referred to in paragraph (1) shall state the nature of the alleged violation, the relief to be requested, the court in which the action will be brought, and whether or not attorney’s fees are being demanded in the event that the plaintiff prevails. No action described in paragraph (1) shall be brought (A) if at the time the action is brought the same alleged violation by the same defendant is the subject of a pending action in any court of the United States; or (B) if administrative remedies have not been exhausted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd6a3c7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6104/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Exhaustion of administrative remedies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to actions brought for relief based on an alleged violation of the provisions of this chapter, administrative remedies shall be deemed exhausted upon the expiration of 180 days from the filing of an administrative complaint during which time the Federal department or agency makes no finding with regard to the complaint, or upon the day that the Federal department or agency issues a finding in favor of the recipient of financial assistance, whichever occurs first.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd6a3c7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/135/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 94–135, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1975-11-28">Nov. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/730">89 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/tIV/s401/c">Pub. L. 95–478, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1555">92 Stat. 1555</ref>, 1556; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd6a3c80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd6a3c81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd6a3c82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (e)(1), probably means <ref href="/us/pl/94/135">Pub. L. 94–135</ref>, <date date="1975-11-28">Nov. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/713">89 Stat. 713</ref>, known as the Older Americans Amendments of 1975. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1975 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd6a3c83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s401/d">Pub. L. 95–478, § 401(d)</ref>, authorized disbursement of withheld funds directly to organization or agency demonstrating ability to achieve the goals of the Federal statute authorizing the program or activity while complying with the regulations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s401/c">Pub. L. 95–478, § 401(c)</ref>, substituted provisions relating to injunctions, notice of violations, and costs for provision making this section the exclusive remedy for the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s401/c">Pub. L. 95–478, § 401(c)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd6a3c84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbd6a3c85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” in subsec. (e)(1) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd6a3c86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/478">Pub. L. 95–478</ref> effective at the close of <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/478/s504">section 504 of Pub. L. 95–478</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
