<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd7167fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a"><num value="6212a">§ 6212a.</num><heading> Oil exports, safety valve, and maritime security</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7167fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7167fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> National policy on oil export restriction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in subsections (c) and (d), to promote the efficient exploration, production, storage, supply, marketing, pricing, and regulation of energy resources, including fossil fuels, no official of the Federal Government shall impose or enforce any restriction on the export of crude oil.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7167fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section limits the authority of the President under the Constitution, the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.) or regulations issued under that Act (other than section 754.2 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations), the National Emergencies Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), part B of title II of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6271">42 U.S.C. 6271</ref> et seq.), the Trading With the Enemy Act (50 U.S.C. App. 1 et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003449">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003449"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or any other provision of law that imposes sanctions on a foreign person or foreign government (including any provision of law that prohibits or restricts United States persons from engaging in a transaction with a sanctioned person or government), including a foreign government that is designated as a state sponsor of terrorism, to prohibit exports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7167fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions and presidential authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7167ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may impose export licensing requirements or other restrictions on the export of crude oil from the United States for a period of not more than 1 year, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd716800-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the President declares a national emergency and formally notices the declaration of a national emergency in the Federal Register;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd716801-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the export licensing requirements or other restrictions on the export of crude oil from the United States under this subsection apply to 1 or more countries, persons, or organizations in the context of sanctions or trade restrictions imposed by the United States for reasons of national security by the Executive authority of the President or by Congress; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd716802-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, finds and reports to the President that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbd716803-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the export of crude oil pursuant to this Act has caused sustained material oil supply shortages or sustained oil prices significantly above world market levels that are directly attributable to the export of crude oil produced in the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbd716804-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> those supply shortages or price increases have caused or are likely to cause sustained material adverse employment effects in the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbd716805-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6212a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Renewal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any requirement or restriction imposed pursuant to subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) may be renewed for 1 or more additional periods of not more than 1 year each.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd716806-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dO/tI/s101">Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2987">129 Stat. 2987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd716807-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd716808-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd716809-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The International Emergency Economic Powers Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/95/223">Pub. L. 95–223</ref>, <date date="1977-12-28">Dec. 28, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1626">91 Stat. 1626</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 35 (§ 1701 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Emergencies Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/412">Pub. L. 94–412</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1255">90 Stat. 1255</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 34 (§ 1601 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">section 1601 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Policy and Conservation Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/163">Pub. L. 94–163</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/871">89 Stat. 871</ref>. Part B of title II of the Act is classified generally to part B (§ 6271 et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trading With the Enemy Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1917-10-06/ch106">act Oct. 6, 1917, ch. 106</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/411">40 Stat. 411</ref>, which was classified to sections 1 to 6, 7 to 39 and 41 to 44 of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as chapter 53 (§ 4301 et seq.) of Title 50. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(1)(C)(i), is div. O of <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2986">129 Stat. 2986</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd71680a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016, and not as part of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dO/s101">section 101 of div. O of Pub. L. 114–113</ref>. Subsec. (a) of <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dO/s101">section 101 of div. O of Pub. L. 114–113</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6212">section 6212 of this title</ref>. Subsec. (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dO/s101">section 101 of div. O of Pub. L. 114–113</ref> amended sections 53106 and 53111 of Title 46, Shipping.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
