<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd71685a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6231"><num value="6231">§ 6231.</num><heading> Congressional finding and declaration of policy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd71685b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6231/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Congress finds that the storage of substantial quantities of petroleum products will diminish the vulnerability of the United States to the effects of a severe energy supply interruption, and provide limited protection from the short-term consequences of interruptions in supplies of petroleum products.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd71685c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6231/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> It is the policy of the United States to provide for the creation of a Strategic Petroleum Reserve for the storage of up to 1 billion barrels of petroleum products to reduce the impact of disruptions in supplies of petroleum products, to carry out obligations of the United States under the international energy program, and for other purposes as provided for in this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd71685d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tI/s151">Pub. L. 94–163, title I, § 151</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/881">89 Stat. 881</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/469/tI/s103/4">Pub. L. 106–469, title I, § 103(4)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2029">114 Stat. 2029</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd71685e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd71685f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd716860-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/94/163">Pub. L. 94–163</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/871">89 Stat. 871</ref>, known as the Energy Policy and Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd716861-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/469">Pub. L. 106–469</ref> amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “It is hereby declared to be the policy of the United States to provide for the creation of a Strategic Petroleum Reserve for the storage of up to 1 billion barrels of petroleum products, but not less than 150 million barrels of petroleum products by the end of the 3-year period which begins on <date date="1975-12-22">December 22, 1975</date>, for the purpose of reducing the impact of disruptions in supplies of petroleum products or to carry out obligations of the United States under the international energy program. It is further declared to be the policy of the United States to provide for the creation of an Early Storage Reserve, as part of the Reserve, for the purpose of providing limited protection from the impact of near-term disruptions in supplies of petroleum products or to carry out obligations of the United States under the international energy program.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd716862-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd716863-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of a Strategic Ethanol Reserve</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXVII/s1778">Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1778</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1659">99 Stat. 1659</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/198/tXVII/s1778">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study of the cost effectiveness, the economic benefits, and the feasibility of establishing, maintaining, and utilizing a Strategic Ethanol Reserve relative to the existing Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The study shall be completed within one year after the enactment of this section [<date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>] and shall include, among other considerations—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the benefits and losses related to the U.S. economy, farm income, employment, government commodity programs, and the trade deficit of utilizing a Strategic Ethanol Reserve, as opposed to the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the savings from storing ethanol as opposed to storing the amount of CCC-held grain necessary to produce the ethanol.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> If the study shows that the Strategic Ethanol Reserve is cost effective, beneficial to the U.S. economy, and feasible in comparison with the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, the Secretary of Agriculture may establish, maintain, and utilize a Strategic Ethanol Reserve.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd716864-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Additional Congressional Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tX/s1032">Pub. L. 97–35, title X, § 1032</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/618">95 Stat. 618</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tX/s1032">
<inline>“The Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Strategic Petroleum Reserve should be considered a national security asset; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> enlarging the capacity and filling of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve should be accelerated (to the extent technically and economically practicable) to take advantage of any increased availability of crude oil in the world market from time to time.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
