<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd73d92c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245"><num value="6245">§ 6245.</num><heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall report annually to the President and the Congress on actions taken to implement this part. This report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d92d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the status of the physical capacity of the Reserve and the type and quantity of petroleum products in the Reserve;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d92e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an estimate of the schedule and cost to complete planned equipment upgrade or capital investment in the Reserve, including upgrades and investments carried out as part of operational maintenance or extension of life activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d92f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an identification of any life-limiting conditions or operational problems at any Reserve facility, and proposed remedial actions including an estimate of the schedule and cost of implementing those remedial actions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d930-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a description of current withdrawal and distribution rates and capabilities, and an identification of any operational or other limitations on those rates and capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d931-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a listing of petroleum product acquisitions made in the preceding year and planned in the following year, including quantity, price, and type of petroleum;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d932-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a summary of the actions taken to develop, operate, and maintain the Reserve;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d933-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> a summary of the financial status and financial transactions of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and Strategic Petroleum Reserve Petroleum Accounts for the year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d934-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> a summary of expenses for the year, and the number of Federal and contractor employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d935-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> the status of contracts for development, operation, maintenance, distribution, and other activities related to the implementation of this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d936-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> a summary of foreign oil storage agreements and their implementation status;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd73d937-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6245/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> any recommendations for supplemental legislation or policy or operational changes the Secretary considers necessary or appropriate to implement this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbd73d938-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tI/s165">Pub. L. 94–163, title I, § 165</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/889">89 Stat. 889</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tVI/s691/b/2">Pub. L. 95–619, title VI, § 691(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3288">92 Stat. 3288</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tX/s1035/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title X, § 1035(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/620">95 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tIII/s3203">Pub. L. 99–509, title III, § 3203</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1890">100 Stat. 1890</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1051/j">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1051(j)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/717">109 Stat. 717</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/469/tI/s103/17">Pub. L. 106–469, title I, § 103(17)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2032">114 Stat. 2032</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd73d939-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd73d93a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd73d93b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/469">Pub. L. 106–469</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section required the Secretary to report to the President and to Congress, not later than one year after the transmittal of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve Plan to the Congress and each year thereafter, on all actions taken to implement this part.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out subsec. (a) designation before “The Secretary shall”, and struck out subsec. (b) which directed Secretary to report to Congress on activities undertaken with respect to Strategic Petroleum Reserve under the amendments made by Strategic Petroleum Reserve Amendments Act of 1981.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/509">Pub. L. 99–509</ref> amended par. (1) generally, inserting “, including” in introductory text and adding subpars. (A) to (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”, meaning Administrator of the Federal Energy Administration, wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd76222c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd76222d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s1038">section 1038 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6240">section 6240 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd76222e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports to Congress on Petroleum Supply Interruptions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/229/s6">Pub. L. 97–229, § 6</ref>, <date date="1982-08-03">Aug. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/253">96 Stat. 253</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/229/s6">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Impact Analysis</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Energy shall analyze the impact on the domestic economy and on consumers in the United States of reliance on market allocation and pricing during any substantial reduction in the amount of petroleum products available to the United States. In making such analysis, the Secretary of Energy may consult with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies. Such analysis shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> examine the equity and efficiency of such reliance,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> distinguish between the impacts of such reliance on various categories of business (including small business and agriculture) and on households of different income levels,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> specify the nature and administration of monetary and fiscal policies that would be followed including emergency tax cuts, emergency block grants, and emergency supplements to income maintenance programs, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> describe the likely impact on the distribution of petroleum products of State and local laws and regulations (including emergency authorities) affecting the distribution of petroleum products.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such analysis shall include projections of the effect of the petroleum supply reduction on the price of motor gasoline, home heating oil, and diesel fuel, and on Federal tax revenues, Federal royalty receipts, and State and local tax revenues.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Within one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1982-08-03">Aug. 3, 1982</date>], the Secretary of Energy shall submit a report to the Congress and the President containing the analysis required by this subsection, including a detailed step-by-step description of the procedures by which the policies specified in paragraph (1)(C) would be accomplished in an emergency, along with such recommendations as the Secretary of Energy deems appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategic Petroleum Reserve Drawdown and Distribution Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President shall prepare and transmit to the Congress, at the time he transmits the drawdown plan pursuant to section 4(c) [<ref href="/us/pl/97/229/s4/c">section 4(c) of Pub. L. 97–229</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6234">42 U.S.C. 6234</ref>], a report containing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a description of the foreseeable situations (including selective and general embargoes, sabotage, war, act of God, or accident) which could result in a severe energy supply interruption or obligations of the United States arising under the international energy program necessitating distributions from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a description of the strategy or alternative strategies of distribution which could reasonably be used to respond to each situation described under paragraph (1), together with the theory and justification underlying each such strategy.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The description of each strategy under paragraph (2) shall include an explanation of the methods which would likely be used to determine the price and distribution of petroleum products from the Reserve in any such distribution, and an explanation of the disposition of revenues arising from sales of any such petroleum products under the strategy.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regional Reserve Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President or his delegate shall submit to the Congress no later than <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>, a report regarding the actions taken to comply with the provisions of section 157 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6237">42 U.S.C. 6237</ref>). Such report shall include an analysis of the economic benefits and costs of establishing Regional Petroleum Reserves, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an assessment of the ability to transport petroleum products to refiners, distributors, and end users within the regions specified in section 157(a) of such Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the comparative costs of creating and operating Regional Petroleum Reserves for such regions as compared to the costs of continuing current plans for the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a list of potential sites for Regional Petroleum Reserves.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategic Alcohol Fuel Reserve Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Energy shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, prepare and transmit to the Congress no later than <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>, a study of the potential for establishing a Strategic Alcohol Fuel Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Meaning of Terms</inline>.—</heading><content>As used in this section, the terms ‘international energy program’, ‘petroleum product’, ‘Reserve’, ‘severe energy supply interruption’, and ‘Strategic Petroleum Reserve’ have the meanings given such terms in sections 3 and 152 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6202">42 U.S.C. 6202</ref> and 6232).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
