<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd789451-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273"><num value="6273">§ 6273.</num><heading> Advisory committees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd789452-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary to establish; applicability of section 17 of Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974; chairman; inclusion of representatives of public; public meetings; notice of meeting to Attorney General and Federal Trade Commission; attendance and participation of their representatives</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To achieve the purposes of the international energy program with respect to international allocation of petroleum products and the information system provided in such program, the Secretary may provide for the establishment of such advisory committees as he determines are necessary. In addition to the requirements specified in this section, such advisory committees shall be subject to the provisions of section 17 of the Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s776">15 U.S.C. 776</ref>] (whether or not such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s761">15 U.S.C. 761</ref> et seq.] or any of its provisions expire or terminate before <date date="1985-06-30">June 30, 1985</date>); shall be chaired by a regular full-time Federal employee; and shall include representatives of the public. The meetings of such committees shall be open to the public. The Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission shall have adequate advance notice of any meeting and may have an official representative attend and participate in any such meeting.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd789453-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transcript of meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A verbatim transcript shall be kept of such advisory committee meetings, and shall be deposited with the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission. Such transcript shall be made available for public inspection and copying in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, except that matter may not be withheld from disclosure under section 552(b) of such title on grounds other than the grounds specified in section 552(b)(1), (b)(3), and so much of (b)(4) as relates to trade secrets, or pursuant to a determination under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd789454-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of application of certain requirements by President</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President, after consultation with the Secretary of State, the Federal Trade Commission, the Attorney General, and the Secretary, may suspend the application of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd789455-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> sections 1009 and 1010 of title 5,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd789456-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> subsections (b) and (c) of section 17 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003455">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003455"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd789457-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the requirement under subsection (a) of this section that meetings be open to the public, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd789458-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6273/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the second sentence of subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">if the President determines with respect to a particular meeting, (A) that such suspension is essential to the developing or carrying out of the international energy program, (B) that such suspension relates solely to the purpose of international allocation of petroleum products and the information system provided in such program, and (C) that the meeting deals with matters described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/1">section 552(b)(1) of title 5</ref>. Such determination by the President shall be in writing, shall set forth a detailed explanation of reasons justifying the granting of such suspension, and shall be published in the Federal Register at a reasonable time prior to the effective date of any such suspension.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd789459-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tII/s253">Pub. L. 94–163, title II, § 253</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/898">89 Stat. 898</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tVI/s691/b/2">Pub. L. 95–619, title VI, § 691(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3288">92 Stat. 3288</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/265">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(265)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4335">136 Stat. 4335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd78945a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd78945b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd78945c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/275">Pub. L. 93–275</ref>, <date date="1974-05-07">May 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/96">88 Stat. 96</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 16B (§ 761 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s761">section 761 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 17 of the Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s776">section 776 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/105/28/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 105–28, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-07-18">July 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/245">111 Stat. 245</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd78945d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “sections 1009 and 1010 of title 5,” for “sections 10 and 11 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”, meaning Administrator of the Federal Energy Administration.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd78945e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd78945f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment unless in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the end of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbd789460-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd789461-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Classification of Certain Information and Material</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to the classification of certain information and material obtained from advisory bodies created to implement the International Energy Program, see Ex. Ord. No. 11932, eff. <date date="1976-08-04">Aug. 4, 1976</date>, 41 F.R. 32691, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
