<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd7fbf9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294"><num value="6294">§ 6294.</num><heading> Labeling</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7fbf9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbf9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commission shall prescribe labeling rules under this section applicable to all covered products of each of the types specified in paragraphs (1), (2), (4), (6), and (8) through (12) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref>, except to the extent that, with respect to any such type (or class thereof), the Commission determines under the second sentence of subsection (b)(5) that labeling in accordance with this section is not technologically or economically feasible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbf9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbf9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Commission shall prescribe labeling rules under this section applicable to all covered products of each of the types specified in paragraphs (3), (5), and (7) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref>, except to the extent that with respect to any such type (or class thereof), the Commission determines under the second sentence of subsection (b)(5) that labeling in accordance with this section is not technologically or economically feasible or is not likely to assist consumers in making purchasing decisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfa0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Commission shall prescribe labeling rules under this section applicable to the covered product specified in paragraph (13) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref> and to which standards are applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295">section 6295 of this title</ref>. Such rules shall provide that the labeling of any fluorescent lamp ballast manufactured on or after <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, will indicate conspicuously, in a manner prescribed by the Commission under subsection (b) by <date date="1989-07-01">July 1, 1989</date>, a capital letter “E” printed within a circle on the ballast and on the packaging of the ballast or of the luminaire into which the ballast has been incorporated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfa1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Metal halide lamp fixtures.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfa2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission shall issue labeling rules under this section applicable to the covered product specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a/19">section 6292(a)(19) of this title</ref> and to which standards are applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295">section 6295 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfa3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Labeling</inline>.—</heading><content>The rules shall provide that the labeling of any metal halide lamp fixture manufactured on or after the later of <date date="2009-01-01">January 1, 2009</date>, or the date that is 270 days after <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>, shall indicate conspicuously, in a manner prescribed by the Commission under subsection (b) by <date date="2008-07-01">July 1, 2008</date>, a capital letter “E” printed within a circle on the packaging of the fixture, and on the ballast contained in the fixture.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfa4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfa5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Not later than 18 months after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Commission shall prescribe labeling rules under this section applicable to general service fluorescent lamps, medium base compact fluorescent lamps, and general service incandescent lamps. Except as provided in clause (ii), such rules shall provide that the labeling of any general service fluorescent lamp, medium base compact fluorescent lamp, and general service incandescent lamp manufactured after the 12-month period beginning on the date of the publication of such rule shall indicate conspicuously on the packaging of the lamp, in a manner prescribed by the Commission under subsection (b), such information as the Commission deems necessary to enable consumers to select the most energy efficient lamps which meet their requirements. Labeling information for incandescent lamps shall be based on performance when operated at 120 volts input, regardless of the rated lamp voltage.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfa6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If the Secretary determines that compliance with the standards specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295/i">section 6295(i) of this title</ref> for any lamp will result in the discontinuance of the manufacture of such lamp, the Commission may exempt such lamp from the labeling rules prescribed under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfa7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking to consider effectiveness of lamp labeling.—</inline></heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfa8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>, the Commission shall initiate a rulemaking to consider—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfa9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/iii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the effectiveness of current lamp labeling for power levels or watts, light output or lumens, and lamp lifetime; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/iii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> alternative labeling approaches that will help consumers to understand new high-efficiency lamp products and to base the purchase decisions of the consumers on the most appropriate source that meets the requirements of the consumers for lighting level, light quality, lamp lifetime, and total lifecycle cost.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Completion</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Commission shall—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/iii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> complete the rulemaking not later than the date that is 30 months after <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/D/iii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> consider reopening the rulemaking not later than 180 days before the effective dates of the standards for general service incandescent lamps established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295/i/1/A">section 6295(i)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, if the Commission determines that further labeling changes are needed to help consumers understand lamp alternatives.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Not later than one year after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Commission shall prescribe labeling rules under this section for showerheads and faucets to which standards are applicable under subsection (j) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295">section 6295 of this title</ref>. Such rules shall provide that the labeling of any showerhead or faucet manufactured after the 12-month period beginning on the date of the publication of such rule shall be consistent with the marking and labeling requirements of ASME A112.18.1M–1989, except that each showerhead and flow restricting or controlling spout-end device shall bear a permanent legible marking indicating the flow rate, expressed in gallons per minute (gpm) or gallons per cycle (gpc), and the flow rate value shall be the actual flow rate or the maximum flow rate specified by the standards established in subsection (j) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295">section 6295 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If the marking and labeling requirements of ASME A112.18.1M–1989 are revised at any time and approved by ANSI, the Commission shall amend the labeling rules established pursuant to clause (i) to be consistent with such revised ASME/ANSI requirements unless such requirements are inconsistent with the purposes of this chapter or the requirement specified in clause (i) requiring each showerhead and flow restricting or controlling spout-end device to bear a permanent legible marking indicating the flow rate of such product.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Not later than one year after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Commission shall prescribe labeling rules under this section for water closets and urinals to which standards are applicable under subsection (k) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295">section 6295 of this title</ref>. Such rules shall provide that the labeling of any water closet or urinal manufactured after the 12-month period beginning on the date of the publication of such rule shall be consistent with the marking and labeling requirements of ASME A112.19.2M–1990, except that each fixture (and flushometer valve associated with such fixture) shall bear a permanent legible marking indicating the water use, expressed in gallons per flush (gpf), and the water use value shall be the actual water use or the maximum water use specified by the standards established in subsection (k) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295">section 6295 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If the marking and labeling requirements of ASME A112.19.2M–1990 are revised at any time and approved by ANSI, the Commission shall amend the labeling rules established pursuant to clause (i) to be consistent with such revised ASME/ANSI requirements unless such requirements are inconsistent with the purposes of this chapter or the requirement specified in clause (i) requiring each fixture and flushometer valve to bear a permanent legible marking indicating the water use of such fixture or flushometer valve.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Any labeling rules prescribed under this subparagraph before <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, shall provide that, with respect to any gravity tank-type white 2-piece toilet which has a water use greater than 1.6 gallons per flush (gpf), any printed matter distributed or displayed in connection with such product (including packaging and point of sale material, catalog material, and print advertising) shall include, in a conspicuous manner, the words “For Commercial Use Only”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Not later than 90 days after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Commission shall initiate a rulemaking to consider—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfb7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/G/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the effectiveness of the consumer products labeling program in assisting consumers in making purchasing decisions and improving energy efficiency; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfb8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/G/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> changes to the labeling rules (including categorical labeling) that would improve the effectiveness of consumer product labels.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfb9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Not later than 2 years after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Commission shall complete the rulemaking initiated under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfbb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Not later than 18 months after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Commission shall issue by rule, in accordance with this section, labeling requirements for the electricity used by ceiling fans to circulate air in a room.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfbc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> The rule issued under clause (i) shall apply to products manufactured after the later of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfbd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/H/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> <date date="2009-01-01">January 1, 2009</date>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfbe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/H/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the date that is 60 days after the final rule is issued.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfbf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Labeling requirements.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfc0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to clauses (ii) through (iv), not later than 18 months after the date of issuance of applicable Department of Energy testing procedures, the Commission, in consultation with the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (acting through the Energy Star program), shall, by regulation, prescribe labeling or other disclosure requirements for the energy use of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfc1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> televisions;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfc2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> personal computers;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfc3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> cable or satellite set-top boxes;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfc4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> stand-alone digital video recorder boxes; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfc5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> personal computer monitors.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfc6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternate testing procedures</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the absence of applicable testing procedures described in clause (i) for products described in subclauses (I) through (V) of that clause, the Commission may, by regulation, prescribe labeling or other disclosure requirements for a consumer product category described in clause (i) if the Commission—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfc7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> identifies adequate non-Department of Energy testing procedures for those products; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfc8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> determines that labeling of, or other disclosures relating to, those products is likely to assist consumers in making purchasing decisions.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline and requirements for labeling.—</inline></heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of promulgation of any requirements under clause (i) or (ii), the Commission shall require labeling of, or other disclosure requirements for, electronic products described in clause (i).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfcb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirements prescribed under clause (i) or (ii) may include specific requirements for each electronic product to be labeled with respect to the placement, size, and content of Energy Guide labels.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfcc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of feasibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Clause (i) or (ii) shall not apply in any case in which the Commission determines that labeling in accordance with this subsection—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfcd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is not technologically or economically feasible; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/I/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> is not likely to assist consumers in making purchasing decisions.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfcf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Commission may prescribe a labeling rule under this section applicable to covered products of a type specified in paragraph (20) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref> (or a class thereof) if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfd0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Commission or the Secretary has made a determination with respect to such type (or class thereof) that labeling in accordance with this section will assist purchasers in making purchasing decisions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfd1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary has prescribed test procedures under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/b/1/B">section 6293(b)(1)(B) of this title</ref> for such type (or class thereof), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfd2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Commission determines with respect to such type (or class thereof) that application of labeling rules under this section to such type (or class thereof) is economically and technologically feasible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfd3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any determination under this subsection shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfd4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfd5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> For covered products described in subsections (u) through (ff) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295">section 6295 of this title</ref>, after a test procedure has been prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293">section 6293 of this title</ref>, the Secretary or the Commission, as appropriate, may prescribe, by rule, under this section labeling requirements for the products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfd6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of products to which TP–1 standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295/y">section 6295(y) of this title</ref> apply, labeling requirements shall be based on the “Standard for the Labeling of Distribution Transformer Efficiency” prescribed by the National Electrical Manufacturers Association (NEMA TP–3) as in effect on <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfd7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of dehumidifiers covered under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6295/dd">section 6295(dd) of this title</ref>, the Commission shall not require an “Energy Guide” label.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfd8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to include additional product categories</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may, by regulation, require labeling or other disclosures in accordance with this subsection for any consumer product not specified in this subsection or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292">section 6292 of this title</ref> if the Commission determines that labeling for the product is likely to assist consumers in making purchasing decisions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7fbfd9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules in effect; new rules</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfda-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfdb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any labeling rule in effect on <date date="1987-03-17">March 17, 1987</date>, shall remain in effect until amended, by rule, by the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfdc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> After <date date="1987-03-17">March 17, 1987</date>, and not later than 30 days after the date on which a proposed test procedure applicable to a covered product of any of the types specified in paragraphs (1) through (13), and paragraphs (15) through (20) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref> (or class thereof) is prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/b">section 6293(b) of this title</ref>, the Commission shall publish a proposed labeling rule applicable to such type (or class thereof).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfdd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commission shall afford interested persons an opportunity to present written or oral data, views, and comments with respect to the proposed labeling rules published under paragraph (1). The period for such presentations shall not be less than 45 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfde-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not earlier than 45 days nor later than 60 days after the date on which test procedures are prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/b">section 6293(b) of this title</ref> with respect to covered products of any type (or class thereof) specified in paragraphs (1) through (12) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref>, the Commission shall prescribe labeling rules with respect to covered products of such type (or class thereof). Not earlier than 45 days after the date on which test procedures are prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/b">section 6293(b) of this title</ref> with respect to covered products of a type specified in paragraph (20) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref>, the Commission may prescribe labeling rules with respect to covered products of such type (or class thereof).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfdf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A labeling rule prescribed under paragraph (3) shall take effect not later than 3 months after the date of prescription of such rule, except that such rules may take effect not later than 6 months after such date of prescription if the Commission determines that such extension is necessary to allow persons subject to such rules adequate time to come into compliance with such rules.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfe0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Commission may delay the publication of a proposed labeling rule, or the prescription of a labeling rule, beyond the dates specified in paragraph (1) or (3), if it determines that it cannot publish proposed labeling rules or prescribe labeling rules which meet the requirements of this section on or prior to the date specified in the applicable paragraph and publishes such determination in the Federal Register, together with the reasons therefor. In any such case, it shall publish proposed labeling rules or prescribe labeling rules for covered products of such type (or class thereof) as soon as practicable unless it determines (A) that labeling in accordance with this section is not economically or technically feasible, or (B) in the case of a type specified in paragraphs (3), (5), and (7) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref>, that labeling in accordance with this section is not likely to assist consumers in purchasing decisions. Any such determination shall be published in the Federal Register, together with the reasons therefor. This paragraph shall not apply to the prescription of a labeling rule with respect to covered products of a type specified in paragraph (20) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7fbfe1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Content of label</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfe2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to paragraph (6), a rule prescribed under this section shall require that each covered product in the type or class of covered products to which the rule applies bear a label which discloses—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfe3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the estimated annual operating cost of such product (determined in accordance with test procedures prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293">section 6293 of this title</ref>), except that if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfe4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Secretary determines that disclosure of estimated annual operating cost is not technologically feasible, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd7fbfe5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Commission determines that such disclosure is not likely to assist consumers in making purchasing decisions or is not economically feasible,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the Commission shall require disclosure of a different useful measure of energy consumption (determined in accordance with test procedures prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293">section 6293 of this title</ref>); and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfe6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information respecting the range of estimated annual operating costs for covered products to which the rule applies; except that if the Commission requires disclosure under subparagraph (A) of a measure of energy consumption different from estimated annual operating cost, then the label shall disclose the range of such measure of energy consumption of covered products to which such rule applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfe7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A rule under this section shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfe8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the type or class of covered products to which such rule applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfe9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (6), information respecting the range of estimated annual operating costs or other useful measure of energy consumption (determined in such manner as the rule may prescribe) for such type or class of covered products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A description of the test procedures under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293">section 6293 of this title</ref> used in determining the estimated annual operating costs or other measure of energy consumption of the type or class of covered products.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfeb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A prototype label and directions for displaying such label.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A rule under this section shall require that the label be displayed in a manner that the Commission determines is likely to assist consumers in making purchasing decisions and is appropriate to carry out this part. The Commission may permit a tag to be used in lieu of a label in any case in which the Commission finds that a tag will carry out the purposes for which the label was intended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A rule under this section applicable to a covered product may require disclosure, in any printed matter displayed or distributed at the point of sale of such product, of any information which may be required under this section to be disclosed on the label of such product. Requirements under this paragraph shall not apply to any broadcast advertisement or any advertisement in any newspaper, magazine, or other periodical.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbfee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The Commission may require that a manufacturer of a covered product to which a rule under this section applies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbfef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> include on the label,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbff0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> separately attach to the product, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbff1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> ship with the product,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">additional information relating to energy consumption, including instructions for the maintenance, use, or repair of the covered product, if the Commission determines that such additional information would assist consumers in making purchasing decisions or in using such product, and that such requirement would not be unduly burdensome to manufacturers.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbff2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Commission may delay the effective date of the requirement specified in paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection applicable to a type or class of covered product, insofar as it requires the disclosure on the label of information respecting range of a measure of energy consumption, for not more than 12 months after the date on which the rule under this section is first applicable to such type or class, if the Commission determines that such information will not be available within an adequate period of time before such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbff3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (5), and (6) of this subsection shall not apply to the covered product specified in paragraphs (13), (14), (15), (16), (17), and (18) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbff4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> If a manufacturer of a covered product specified in paragraph (15) or (17) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref> elects to provide a label for such covered product conveying the estimated annual operating cost of such product or the range of estimated annual operating costs for the type or class of such product—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbff5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such estimated cost or range of costs shall be determined in accordance with test procedures prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293">section 6293 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbff6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the format of such label shall be in accordance with a format prescribed by the Commission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd7fbff7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such label shall be displayed in a manner, prescribed by the Commission, to be likely to assist consumers in making purchasing decisions and appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd7fbff8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discretionary application</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may apply paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (5), and (6) of this subsection to the labeling of any product covered by paragraph (2)(I) or (6) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7fbff9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A rule under this section (or an amendment thereto) shall not apply to any covered product the manufacture of which was completed prior to the effective date of such rule or amendment, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7fbffa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Study of certain products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall study consumer products for which labeling rules under this section have not been proposed, in order to determine (1) the aggregate energy consumption of such products, and (2) whether the imposition of labeling requirements under this section would be feasible and useful to consumers in making purchasing decisions. The Secretary shall include the results of such study in the annual report under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6308">section 6308 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7fbffb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary and the Commission shall consult with each other on a continuing basis as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out their respective responsibilities under this part. Before the Commission makes any determination under subsection (a)(1), it shall obtain the views of the Secretary and shall take such views into account in making such determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd7fbffc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6294/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Other authority of the Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Until such time as labeling rules under this section take effect with respect to a type or class of covered product, this section shall not affect any authority of the Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] to require labeling with respect to energy consumption of such type or class of covered product.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd7fbffd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tIII/s324">Pub. L. 94–163, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/920">89 Stat. 920</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tIV/s425/b">Pub. L. 95–619, title IV, § 425(b)</ref>, (c), title VI, § 691(b)(2), <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3265">92 Stat. 3265</ref>, 3288; <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="1987-03-17">Mar. 17, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/124">101 Stat. 124</ref>, 125; <ref href="/us/pl/100/357/s2/d">Pub. L. 100–357, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-06-28">June 28, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/672">102 Stat. 672</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s123/e">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 123(e)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2822">106 Stat. 2822</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/4">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3478">112 Stat. 3478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tI/s137">Pub. L. 109–58, title I, § 137</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/645">119 Stat. 645</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tIII">Pub. L. 110–140, title III</ref>, §§ 321(b), 324(d), 325, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1584">121 Stat. 1584</ref>, 1593, 1595; <ref href="/us/pl/112/210/s10/a/12">Pub. L. 112–210, § 10(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1525">126 Stat. 1525</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/115/s2/c/2">Pub. L. 115–115, § 2(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-01-12">Jan. 12, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2281">131 Stat. 2281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd7fbffe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd7fbfff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd7fc000-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2)(E)(ii), (F)(ii) and (c)(8)(C), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/94/163">Pub. L. 94–163</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/871">89 Stat. 871</ref>, known as the Energy Policy and Conservation Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (g), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-09-26/ch311">act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/717">38 Stat. 717</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s58">section 58 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd7fc001-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/115">Pub. L. 115–115</ref> substituted “(20) of section 6292(a)” for “(19) of section 6292(a)” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (c)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/112/210/s10/a/12">Pub. L. 112–210, § 10(a)(12)</ref>, made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s325/b">Pub. L. 110–140, § 325(b)</ref>. See 2007 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s324/d/2">Pub. L. 110–140, § 324(d)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C). Former subpar. (C) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s321/b">Pub. L. 110–140, § 321(b)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D) to (H). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s324/d/1">Pub. L. 110–140, § 324(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (C) to (G) as (D) to (H), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s325/a/1">Pub. L. 110–140, § 325(a)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (I).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s325/a/2">Pub. L. 110–140, § 325(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s325/b">Pub. L. 110–140, § 325(b)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/210/s10/a/12">Pub. L. 112–210, § 10(a)(12)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(2)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s137/a">Pub. L. 109–58, § 137(a)</ref>, added subpars. (F) and (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s137/b">Pub. L. 109–58, § 137(b)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(2)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/388">Pub. L. 105–388</ref> substituted “section 6295(i)” for “section 6295(j)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(2)(C) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s123/e/1">Pub. L. 102–486, § 123(e)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (C) to (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s123/e/2">Pub. L. 102–486, § 123(e)(2)</ref>, substituted “(19)” for “(14)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s123/e/3">Pub. L. 102–486, § 123(e)(3)</ref>, substituted “(13), and paragraphs (15) through (19)” for “(14)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s123/e/4">Pub. L. 102–486, § 123(e)(4)</ref>, substituted “(19)” for “(14)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s123/e/5/A">Pub. L. 102–486, § 123(e)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (13), (14), (15), (16), (17), and (18) of section 6292(a)” for “paragraph (13) of section 6292”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s123/e/5/B">Pub. L. 102–486, § 123(e)(5)(B)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/357/s2/d/1">Pub. L. 100–357, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, designated existing provision as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a)(3), (b)(1)(B), (3), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/357/s2/d/2">Pub. L. 100–357, § 2(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “(14)” for “(13)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/100/357/s2/d/3">Pub. L. 100–357, § 2(d)(3)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/b/2/A">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/A">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (1), (2), (4), (6), and (8) through (12)” for “paragraphs (1) through (9)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/B">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (3), (5), and (7)” for “paragraphs (10) through (13)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/C/i">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (13)” for “paragraph (14)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/C/ii">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(C)(ii)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “the Commission or the Secretary has made a determination with respect to such type (or class thereof) under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/a/5/B">section 6293(a)(5)(B) of this title</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/C/iii">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(C)(iii)</ref>, substituted “section 6293(b)(1)(B)” for “section 6293(a)(5)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/D">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(D)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/D">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(D)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “Not later than 30 days after the date on which a proposed test procedure applicable to a covered product of any of the types specified in paragraphs (1) through (14) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6292/a">section 6292(a) of this title</ref> (or class thereof) is published under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/a">section 6293(a) of this title</ref>, the Commission shall publish a proposed labeling rule applicable to such type (or class thereof).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/E">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(E)</ref>, substituted “section 6293(b)” for “section 6293” in two places, “(12)” for “(13)”, and “(13)” for “(14)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/F">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(F)</ref>, substituted “(3), (5), and (7)” for “(10) through (13)” and “(13)” for “(14)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/b/2/B">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(b)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/b/2/C">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(b)(2)(C)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/b/2/D">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(b)(2)(D)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/b/2/E">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(b)(2)(E)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/a/1/G">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(a)(1)(G)</ref>, struck out “or (2)” after “subsection (a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s11/b/2/F">Pub. L. 100–12, § 11(b)(2)(F)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/s425/b">Pub. L. 95–619, § 425(b)</ref>, struck out labeling rule exception where Administrator had determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/a/6">section 6293(a)(6) of this title</ref> that test procedures could not be developed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6293/b">section 6293(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/s691/b/2">Pub. L. 95–619, § 691(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”, meaning Administrator of the Federal Energy Administration, in cls. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/s691/b/2">Pub. L. 95–619, § 691(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/s425/c">Pub. L. 95–619, § 425(c)</ref>, inserted “including instructions for the maintenance, use, or repair of the covered product,” after “energy consumption”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/s691/b/2">Pub. L. 95–619, § 691(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd7fc002-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd7fc003-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/210">Pub. L. 112–210</ref> effective as if included in the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007, <ref href="/us/pl/110/140">Pub. L. 110–140</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/210/s10/a/13">section 10(a)(13) of Pub. L. 112–210</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6291">section 6291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd7fc004-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/140">Pub. L. 110–140</ref> effective on the date that is 1 day after <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s1601">section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1824">section 1824 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd7fc005-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Market Assessments and Consumer Awareness Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tIII/s321/c">Pub. L. 110–140, title III, § 321(c)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1584">121 Stat. 1584</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/140/tIII/s321/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In cooperation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Commerce, the Federal Trade Commission, lighting and retail industry associations, energy efficiency organizations, and any other entities that the Secretary of Energy determines to be appropriate, the Secretary of Energy shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> conduct an annual assessment of the market for general service lamps and compact fluorescent lamps—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to identify trends in the market shares of lamp types, efficiencies, and light output levels purchased by residential and nonresidential consumers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to better understand the degree to which consumer decisionmaking is based on lamp power levels or watts, light output or lumens, lamp lifetime, and other factors, including information required on labels mandated by the Federal Trade Commission;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> provide the results of the market assessment to the Federal Trade Commission for consideration in the rulemaking described in section 324(a)(2)(C)(iii) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6294/a/2/C/iii">42 U.S.C. 6294(a)(2)(C)(iii)</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> in cooperation with industry trade associations, lighting industry members, utilities, and other interested parties, carry out a proactive national program of consumer awareness, information, and education that broadly uses the media and other effective communication techniques over an extended period of time to help consumers understand the lamp labels and make energy-efficient lighting choices that meet the needs of consumers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2012.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
