<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd8e17f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6308"><num value="6308">§ 6308.</num><heading> Annual report</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall report to the Congress and the President either (1) as part of his annual report, or (2) in a separate report submitted annually, on the progress of the program undertaken pursuant to this part and on the energy savings impact of this part. Each such report shall specify the actions undertaken by the Secretary in carrying out this part during the period covered by such report, and those actions which the Secretary was required to take under this part during such period but which were not taken, together with the reasons therefor. Nothing in this section provides a defense or justification for a failure by the Secretary to comply with a nondiscretionary duty as provided for in this part.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd8e17f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tIII/s338">Pub. L. 94–163, title III, § 338</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/932">89 Stat. 932</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tIV/s425/h">Pub. L. 95–619, title IV, § 425(h)</ref>, title VI, § 691(b)(2), <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3266">92 Stat. 3266</ref>, 3288; <ref href="/us/pl/100/12/s10">Pub. L. 100–12, § 10</ref>, <date date="1987-03-17">Mar. 17, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/124">101 Stat. 124</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd8e17f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd8e17f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd8e17f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/12">Pub. L. 100–12</ref> inserted at end “Nothing in this section provides a defense or justification for a failure by the Secretary to comply with a nondiscretionary duty as provided for in this part.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref> inserted requirement that each report under this section should account for actions taken by the Secretary, as well as actions not taken, during the covered period in carrying out this part and substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”, meaning Administrator of the Federal Energy Administration.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
