<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd9c48e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371"><num value="6371">§ 6371.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this part—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9c48e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “building” means any structure the construction of which was completed on or before <date date="1989-05-01">May 1, 1989</date>, which includes a heating or cooling system, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9c48e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The term “energy conservation measure” means an installation or modification of an installation in a building which is primarily intended to maintain or reduce energy consumption and reduce energy costs or allow the use of an alternative energy source, including, but not limited to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9c48e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> insulation of the building structure and systems within the building;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9c48ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> storm windows and doors, multiglazed windows and doors, heat absorbing or heat reflective glazed and coated windows and door systems, additional glazing, reductions in glass area, and other window and door system modifications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9c48eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> automatic energy control systems and load management systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9c48ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> equipment required to operate variable steam, hydraulic, and ventilating systems adjusted by automatic energy control systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9c48ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> solar space heating or cooling systems, solar electric generating systems, or any combination thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9c48ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> solar water heating systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9c48ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> furnace or utility plant and distribution system modifications including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd9c48f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> replacement burners, furnaces, boilers, or any combination thereof, which substantially increases the energy efficiency of the heating system,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd9c48f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> devices for modifying flue openings which will increase the energy efficiency of the heating system,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd9eb8f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> electrical or mechanical furnace ignition systems which replace standing gas pilot lights, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd9eb8f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/G/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> utility plant system conversion measures including conversion of existing oil- and gas-fired boiler installations to alternative energy sources, including coal;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> caulking and weatherstripping;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> replacement or modification of lighting fixtures which replacement or modification increases the energy efficiency of the lighting system without increasing the overall illumination of a facility (unless such increase in illumination is necessary to conform to any applicable State or local building code or, if no such code applies, the increase is considered appropriate by the Secretary);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> energy recovery systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> cogeneration systems which produce steam or forms of energy such as heat, as well as electricity for use primarily within a building or a complex of buildings owned by a school or hospital and which meet such fuel efficiency requirements as the Secretary may by rule prescribe;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> such other measures as the Secretary identifies by rule for purposes of this part; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> such other measures as a grant applicant shows will save a substantial amount of energy and as are identified in an energy audit prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6325/e/2">section 6325(e)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb8fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The term “hospital” means a public or nonprofit institution which is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a general hospital, tuberculosis hospital, or any other type of hospital, other than a hospital furnishing primarily domiciliary care; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> duly authorized to provide hospital services under the laws of the State in which it is situated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb8fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “hospital facilities” means buildings housing a hospital and related facilities, including laboratories, outpatient departments, nurses’ home and training facilities and central service facilities operated in connection with a hospital, and also includes buildings housing education or training facilities for health professions personnel operated as an integral part of a hospital.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb8fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The term “public or nonprofit institution” means an institution owned and operated by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb8ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a State, a political subdivision of a State or an agency or instrumentality of either, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb900-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an organization exempt from income tax under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/3">section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb901-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The term “school” means a public or nonprofit institution which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb902-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provides, and is legally authorized to provide, elementary education or secondary education, or both, on a day or residential basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb903-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb904-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> provides, and is legally authorized to provide a program of education beyond secondary education, on a day or residential basis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb905-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> admits as students only persons having a certificate of graduation from a school providing secondary education, or the recognized equivalent of such certificate;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb906-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> is accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting agency or association; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb907-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> provides an educational program for which it awards a bachelor’s degree or higher degree or provides not less than a two-year program which is acceptable for full credit toward such a degree at any institution which meets the requirements of clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) and which provides such a program;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb908-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provides not less than a one-year program of training to prepare students for gainful employment in a recognized occupation and which meets the provisions of clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of subparagraph (B); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb909-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> is a local educational agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb90a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “local education agency” means a public board of education or other public authority or a nonprofit institution legally constituted within, or otherwise recognized by, a State for either administrative control or direction of, or to perform administrative services for, a group of schools within a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb90b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “school facilities” means buildings housing classrooms, laboratories, dormitories, administrative facilities, athletic facilities, or related facilities operated in connection with a school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb90c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “State” means, in addition to the several States of the Union, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb90d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “State energy agency” means the State agency responsible for developing State energy conservation plans pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6322">section 6322 of this title</ref>, or, if no such agency exists, a State agency designated by the Governor of such State to prepare and submit a State plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6371c">section 6371c of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb90e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “State school facilities agency” means an existing agency which is broadly representative of public institutions of higher education, nonprofit institutions of higher education, public elementary and secondary schools, nonprofit elementary and secondary schools, public vocational education institutions, nonprofit vocational education institutions, and the interests of handicapped persons, in a State or, if no such agency exists, an agency which is designated by the Governor of such State which conforms to the requirements of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb90f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The term “State hospital facilities agency” means an existing agency which is broadly representative of the public hospitals and the nonprofit hospitals, or, if no such agency exists, an agency designated by the Governor of such State which conforms to the requirements of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb910-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><chapeau> The term “energy audit” means a determination of the energy consumption characteristics of a building which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb911-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/13/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identifies the type, size, and rate of energy consumption of such building and the major energy using systems of such building;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb912-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/13/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> determines appropriate energy conservation maintenance and operating procedures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb913-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/13/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> indicates the need, if any, for the acquisition and installation of energy conservation measures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb914-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The term “preliminary energy audit” means a determination of the energy consumption characteristics of a building, including the size, type, rate of energy consumption and major energy-using systems of such building.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb915-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><chapeau> The term “energy conservation project” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb916-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an undertaking to acquire and to install one or more energy conservation measures in school or hospital facilities and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb917-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> technical assistance in connection with any such undertaking and technical assistance as described in paragraph (17)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb918-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> The term “energy conservation project costs” includes only costs incurred in the design, acquisition, construction, and installation of energy conservation measures and technical assistance costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb919-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><chapeau> The term “technical assistance” means assistance, under rules promulgated by the Secretary, to States, schools, and hospitals—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb91a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/17/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to conduct specialized studies identifying and specifying energy savings or energy cost savings that are likely to be realized as a result of (i) modification of maintenance and operating procedures in a building, or (ii) the acquisition and installation of one or more specified energy conservation measures in such building, or (iii) both, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb91b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/17/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the planning or administration of specific remodeling, renovation, repair, replacement, or insulation projects related to the installation of energy conservation measures in such building.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb91c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> The term “technical assistance costs” means costs incurred for the use of existing personnel or the temporary employment of other qualified personnel (or both such types of personnel) necessary for providing technical assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb91d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> The term “energy conservation maintenance and operating procedure” means modification or modifications in the maintenance and operations of a building, and any installations therein, which are designed to reduce energy consumption in such building and which require no significant expenditure of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb91e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy or his designee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb91f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371/21"><num value="21">(21)</num><content> The term “Governor” means the chief executive officer of a State or his designee.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbd9eb920-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tIII/s391">Pub. L. 94–163, title III, § 391</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 95–619, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3239">92 Stat. 3239</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/tVI/s601/e">Pub. L. 98–454, title VI, § 601(e)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1736">98 Stat. 1736</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s6/b">Pub. L. 101–440, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-18">Oct. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1011">104 Stat. 1011</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/9">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3478">112 Stat. 3478</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd9eb921-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd9eb922-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd9eb923-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Par. (2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/388">Pub. L. 105–388</ref> substituted a semicolon for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s6/b/1">Pub. L. 101–440, § 6(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1989-05-01">May 1, 1989</date>” for “<date date="1977-04-20">April 20, 1977</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s6/b/2">Pub. L. 101–440, § 6(b)(2)</ref>, (3), in introductory provision substituted “maintain or reduce energy consumption and reduce energy costs” for “reduce energy consumption” and in subpar. (C) inserted “and load management systems” after “systems”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (8). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s6/b/4">Pub. L. 101–440, § 6(b)(4)</ref>, inserted “administrative facilities,” after “dormitories,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (17)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s6/b/5">Pub. L. 101–440, § 6(b)(5)</ref>, substituted “or energy cost savings” for “and related cost savings”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Par. (5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Par. (9). <ref href="/us/pl/98/454">Pub. L. 98–454</ref> which directed the amendment of subsec. (a) by inserting reference to the Northern Mariana Islands was executed to par. (9) of this section to reflect the probable intent of Congress, because this section does not contain a subsec. (a).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd9eb924-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idbd9eb925-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tIII/s302/c">Pub. L. 95–619, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3248">92 Stat. 3248</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/619/tIII/s302/c">“If any provision of this title [enacting sections 6371 to 6371j and section 6372 to 6372i of this title, amending sections 300k–2 and 300n–1 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6372">section 6372 of this title</ref>] or the application thereof to any person or circumstances be held invalid, the provisions of other sections of this title and their application to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd9eb926-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Statement of Findings and Purposes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 95–619, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3238">92 Stat. 3238</ref>, provided:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/619/tIII/s301">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Nation’s nonrenewable energy resources are being rapidly depleted;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> schools and hospitals are major consumers of energy, and have been especially burdened by rising energy prices and fuel shortages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> substantial energy conservation can be achieved in schools and hospitals through the implementation of energy conservation maintenance and operating procedures and the installation of energy conservation measures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> public and nonprofit schools and hospitals in many instances need financial assistance in order to make the necessary improvements to achieve energy conservation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the purpose of this part [part 1 (§§ 301–303) of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref>, enacting sections 6371 to 6371i of this title, amending sections 300k–2 and 300n–1 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] to authorize grants to States and to public and nonprofit schools and hospitals to assist them in identifying and implementing energy conservation maintenance and operating procedures and in evaluating, acquiring, and installing energy conservation measures to reduce the energy use and anticipated energy costs of schools and hospitals.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
