<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbda129fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371j"><num value="6371j">§ 6371j.</num><heading> Application of sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No grant for a project (other than so much of a grant as is used for a preliminary energy audit, energy audit, or technical assistance or a grant the total project cost of which is $5,000 or less, excluding costs for a preliminary energy audit, energy audit, or technical assistance) shall be made under this part or part 1 unless the Secretary finds that all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of work on any construction utilizing such grants will be paid at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction in the locality, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40; and the Secretary of Labor shall have with respect to the labor standards specified in this section the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (15 F.R. 3176; 5 U.S.C. Appendix) and <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3145">section 3145 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbda129fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 95–619, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3254">92 Stat. 3254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbda129fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbda129ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbda12a00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This part, referred to in text, means part 2 (§§ 310–312) of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3248">92 Stat. 3248</ref>, which enacted sections 6371j and 6372 to 6372i of this title and enacted provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6372">section 6372 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this part to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Part 1, referred to in text, means part 1 (§§ 301–304) of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3238">92 Stat. 3238</ref>, which enacted sections 6371 to 6371i of this title, amended sections 300k–2 and 300n–1 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 6371 of this title. For complete classification of this part to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950, referred to in text, is set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbda12a01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In text, “sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40” substituted for “the Act of <date date="1931-03-31">March 31, 1931</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s276a">40 U.S.C. 276a</ref>—276a–5, known as the Davis-Bacon Act)” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3145">section 3145 of title 40</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-13/s2">section 2 of the Act of June 13, 1934</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s276c">40 U.S.C. 276c</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as a part of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act, and not as a part of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act which comprises this chapter, and consequently is not a part of part E of this subchapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
