<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd9eb93b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c"><num value="6371c">§ 6371c.</num><heading> State plans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd9eb93c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Invitation to State energy agency to submit plan; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall invite the State energy agency of each State to submit, within 90 days after the effective date of the guidelines prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6371a">section 6371a of this title</ref>, or such longer period as the Secretary may, for good cause, allow, a State plan under this section for such State. Such plan shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb93d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the results of preliminary energy audits conducted in accordance with the guidelines prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6371a/a/1">section 6371a(a)(1) of this title</ref>, and an estimate of the energy savings that may result from the modification of maintenance and operating procedures and installation of energy conservation measures in the schools and hospitals in such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb93e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a recommendation as to the types of energy conservation projects considered appropriate for schools and hospitals in such State, together with an estimate of the costs of carrying out such projects in each year for which funds are appropriated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb93f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a program for identifying persons qualified to carry out energy conservation projects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb940-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> procedures to insure that funds will be allocated among eligible applicants for energy conservation projects within such State, including procedures—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd9eb941-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to insure that funds will be allocated on the basis of relative need taking into account such factors as cost, energy consumption and energy savings, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd9eb942-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to insure that equitable consideration is given to all eligible public or nonprofit institutions regardless of size and type of ownership;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb943-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a statement of the extent to which, and by which methods, such State will encourage utilization of solar space heating, cooling, and electric systems and solar water heating systems where appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb944-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> procedures to assure that all assistance under this part in such State will be expended in compliance with the requirements of an approved State plan for such State, and in compliance with the requirements of this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb945-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> procedures to insure implementation of energy conserving maintenance and operating procedures in those facilities for which proj­ects are proposed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd9eb946-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> policies and procedures designed to assure that financial assistance provided under this part in such State will be used to supplement, and not to supplant, State, local, or other funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd9eb947-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval of plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall review and approve or disapprove each State plan not later than 60 days after receipt by the Secretary. If such plan meets the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary shall approve the plan. If a State plan submitted within the 90-day period specified in subsection (a) has not been disapproved within the 60-day period following its receipt by the Secretary, such plan shall be treated as approved by the Secretary. A State energy agency may submit a new or amended plan at any time after the submission of the original plan if the agency obtains the consent of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbd9eb948-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Development and implementation of approved plans; submission of proposed State plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb949-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If a State plan has not been approved under this section within 2 years and 90 days after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, or within 90 days after the completion of the preliminary audits under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6371b/a">section 6371b(a) of this title</ref>, whichever is later, the Secretary may take such action as necessary to develop and implement such a State plan and to carry out the functions which would otherwise be carried out under this part by the State energy agency, State school facilities agency, and State hospital facilities agency, in order that the energy conservation program for schools and hospitals may be implemented in such State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd9eb94a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6371c/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision contained in this section, a State may, at any time, submit a proposed State plan for such State under this section. The Secretary shall approve or disapprove such plan not later than 60 days after receipt by the Secretary. If such plan meets the requirements of subsection (a) and is not inconsistent with any plan developed and implemented by the Secretary under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall approve the plan and withdraw any such plan developed and implemented by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd9eb94b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tIII/s394">Pub. L. 94–163, title III, § 394</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 95–619, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3243">92 Stat. 3243</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/10">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3478">112 Stat. 3478</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd9eb94c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd9eb94d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd9eb94e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/10/A">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(10)(A)</ref>, substituted semicolon for comma at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/10/B">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(10)(B)</ref>, substituted semicolon for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/10/A">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(10)(A)</ref>, substituted semicolon for comma at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/10/C">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(10)(C)</ref>, substituted semicolon for colon at end.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
