<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbda12a84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374"><num value="6374">§ 6374.</num><heading> Alternative fuel use by light duty Federal vehicles</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12a85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Department of Energy program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Beginning in the fiscal year ending <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall ensure, with the cooperation of other appropriate agencies and consistent with other Federal law, that the maximum number practicable of the vehicles acquired annually for use by the Federal Government shall be alternative fueled vehicles. In no event shall the number of such vehicles acquired be less than the number required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13212">section 13212 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In any determination of whether the acquisition of a vehicle is practicable under paragraph (1), the initial cost of such vehicle to the United States shall not be considered as a factor unless the initial cost of such vehicle exceeds the initial cost of a comparable gasoline or diesel fueled vehicle by at least 5 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall acquire both dedicated and dual fueled vehicles, and shall ensure that each type of alternative fueled vehicle is used by the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Vehicles acquired under this section shall be acquired from original equipment manufacturers. If such vehicles are not available from original equipment manufacturers, vehicles converted to use alternative fuels may be acquired if, after conversion, the original equipment manufacturer’s warranty continues to apply to such vehicles, pursuant to an agreement between the original equipment manufacturer and the person performing the conversion. This subparagraph shall not apply to vehicles acquired by the United States Postal Service pursuant to a contract entered into by the United States Postal Service before <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, and which terminates on or before <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Alternative fueled vehicles, other than those described in subparagraph (B), may be acquired solely for the purposes of studies under subsection (b), whether or not original equipment manufacturer warranties still apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> In deciding which types of alternative fueled vehicles to acquire in implementing this part, the Secretary shall consider as a factor—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12a8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> which types of vehicles yield the greatest reduction in pollutants emitted per dollar spent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12a8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the source of the fuel to supply the vehicles, giving preference to vehicles that operate on alternative fuels derived from domestic sources.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Dual fueled vehicles acquired pursuant to this section shall be operated on alternative fuels unless the Secretary determines that an agency qualifies for a waiver of such requirement for vehicles operated by the agency in a particular geographic area in which—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12a91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/E/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the alternative fuel otherwise required to be used in the vehicle is not reasonably available to retail purchasers of the fuel, as certified to the Secretary by the head of the agency; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12a92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/E/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the cost of the alternative fuel otherwise required to be used in the vehicle is unreasonably more expensive compared to gasoline, as certified to the Secretary by the head of the agency.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Secretary shall monitor compliance with this subparagraph by all such fleets and shall report annually to Congress on the extent to which the requirements of this subparagraph are being achieved. The report shall include information on annual reductions achieved from the use of petroleum-based fuels and the problems, if any, encountered in acquiring alternative fuels.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> At least 50 percent of the alternative fuels used in vehicles acquired pursuant to this section shall be derived from domestic feedstocks, except to the extent inconsistent with the multilateral trade agreements (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3501/4">section 3501(4) of title 19</ref>). The Secretary shall issue regulations to implement this requirement. For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “domestic” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13211/7">section 13211(7) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Except to the extent inconsistent with the multilateral trade agreements (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3501/4">section 3501(4) of title 19</ref>), vehicles acquired under this section shall be motor vehicles manufactured in the United States or Canada.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Acquisitions of vehicles under this section shall, to the extent practicable, be coordinated with acquisitions of alternative fueled vehicles by State and local governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12a97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Studies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Secretary, in cooperation with the Environmental Protection Agency and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, shall conduct a study of a representative sample of alternative fueled vehicles in Federal fleets, which shall at a minimum address—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12a9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the performance of such vehicles, including performance in cold weather and at high altitude;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12a9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the fuel economy, safety, and emissions of such vehicles; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12a9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a comparison of the operation and maintenance costs of such vehicles to the operation and maintenance costs of other passenger automobiles and light duty trucks.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide a report on the results of the study conducted under subparagraph (A) to the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, within one year after the first such vehicles are acquired.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12a9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary and the Administrator of the General Services Administration shall conduct a study of the advisability, feasibility, and timing of the disposal of vehicles acquired under subsection (a) and any problems of such disposal. Such study shall take into account existing laws governing the sale of Government vehicles and shall specifically focus on when to sell such vehicles and what price to charge, without compromising studies of the use of such vehicles authorized under this part.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aa0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary and the Administrator of the General Services Administration shall report the results of the study conducted under subparagraph (A) to the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, within 12 months after funds are appropriated for carrying out this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aa1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Studies undertaken under this subsection shall be coordinated with relevant testing activities of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12aa2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability to public</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent practicable, at locations where vehicles acquired under subsection (a) are supplied with alternative fuels, such fuels shall be offered for sale to the public. The head of the Federal agency responsible for such a location shall consider whether such sale is practicable, taking into account, among other factors—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12aa3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> whether alternative fuel is commercially available for vehicles in the vicinity of such location;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12aa4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> security and safety considerations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12aa5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> whether such sale is in accordance with applicable local, State, and Federal law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12aa6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the ease with which the public can access such location; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12aa7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the cost to the United States of such sale.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12aa8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal agency use of demonstration vehicles</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aa9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon the request of the head of any agency of the Federal Government, the Secretary shall ensure that such Federal agency be provided with vehicles acquired under subsection (a) to the maximum extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Funds appropriated under this section for the acquisition of vehicles under subsection (a) shall be applicable only to the portion of the cost of vehicles acquired under subsection (a) which exceeds the cost of comparable gasoline or diesel fueled vehicles.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To the extent that appropriations are available for such purposes, the Secretary shall ensure that the cost to any Federal agency receiving a vehicle under paragraph (1) shall not exceed the cost to such agency of a comparable gasoline or diesel fueled vehicle.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Only one-half of the vehicles acquired under this section by an agency of the Federal Government shall be counted against any limitation under law, Executive order, or executive or agency policy on the number of vehicles which may be acquired by such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12aae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any Federal agency receiving a vehicle under paragraph (1) shall cooperate with studies undertaken by the Secretary under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12aaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Detail of personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary, the head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of such agency to the Department of Energy to assist the Secretary in carrying out the Secretary’s duties under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12ab0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12ab1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Vehicles acquired under this section shall not be counted in any calculation of the average fuel economy of the fleet of passenger automobiles acquired in a fiscal year by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12ab2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The incremental cost of vehicles acquired under this section over the cost of comparable gasoline or diesel fueled vehicles shall not be applied to any calculation with respect to a limitation under law on the maximum cost of individual vehicles which may be acquired by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12ab3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this part—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12ab4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “acquired” means leased for a period of sixty continuous days or more, or purchased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12ab5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “alternative fuel” means methanol, denatured ethanol, and other alcohols; mixtures containing 85 percent or more (or such other percentage, but not less than 70 percent, as determined by the Secretary, by rule, to provide for requirements relating to cold start, safety, or vehicle functions) by volume of methanol, denatured ethanol, and other alcohols with gasoline or other fuels; natural gas; liquefied petroleum gas; hydrogen; coal-derived liquid fuels; fuels (other than alcohol) derived from biological materials; electricity (including electricity from solar energy); and any other fuel the Secretary determines, by rule, is substantially not petroleum and would yield substantial energy security benefits and substantial environmental benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12ab6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “alternative fueled vehicle” means a dedicated vehicle or a dual fueled vehicle;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12ab7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> the term “dedicated vehicle” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbda12ab8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a dedicated automobile, as such term is defined in section 32901(a)(7) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003480">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003480"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 49; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbda12ab9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a motor vehicle, other than an automobile, that operates solely on alternative fuel;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12aba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> the term “dual fueled vehicle” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbda12abb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> dual fueled automobile, as such term is defined in section 32901(a)(8) <sup>1</sup> of title 49; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbda12abc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a motor vehicle, other than an automobile, that is capable of operating on alternative fuel and is capable of operating on gasoline or diesel fuel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbda12abd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/g/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the term “heavy duty vehicle” means a vehicle of greater than 8,500 pounds gross vehicle weight rating.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbda12abe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12abf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the purposes of this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1993 through 1998, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbda12ac0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6374/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The authority of the Secretary to obligate amounts to be expended under this section shall be effective for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance by appropriation Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbda12ac1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/163/tIII/s400AA">Pub. L. 94–163, title III, § 400AA</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/494/s4/a">Pub. L. 100–494, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-14">Oct. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2442">102 Stat. 2442</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIII">Pub. L. 102–486, title III</ref>, §§ 302(a), 309, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2868">106 Stat. 2868</ref>, 2874; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI">Pub. L. 104–66, title I</ref>, §§ 1051(a), 1052(e), <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/716">109 Stat. 716</ref>, 718; <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/a/14">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3479">112 Stat. 3479</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/36/tI/s1002/h">Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1002(h)</ref>, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/134">113 Stat. 134</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 109–58, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/814">119 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbda12ac2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbda12ac3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbda12ac4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraphs (7) and (8) of <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s32901/a">section 32901(a) of title 49</ref>, referred to in subsec. (g)(4)(A), (5)(A), were redesignated (8) and (9), respectively, and a new par. (7) was enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tI/s103/a/2">Pub. L. 110–140, title I, § 103(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1501">121 Stat. 1501</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbda12ac5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (g)(4)(A), (5)(A), “<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s32901/a/7">section 32901(a)(7) of title 49</ref>” substituted for “section 513(h)(1)(C) of the Motor Vehicle Information Cost Savings Act” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s32901/a/8">section 32901(a)(8) of title 49</ref>” substituted for “section 513(h)(1)(D) of the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act”, respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s6/b">Pub. L. 103–272, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1378">108 Stat. 1378</ref>, the first section of which enacted subtitles II, III, and V to X of Title 49, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbda12ac6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(3)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref> amended subpar. (E) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (E) read as follows: “Dual fueled vehicles acquired pursuant to this section shall be operated on alternative fuels unless the Secretary determines that operation on such alternative fuels is not feasible.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(3)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/106/36">Pub. L. 106–36</ref> substituted “multilateral trade agreements (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3501/4">section 3501(4) of title 19</ref>)” for “General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/388">Pub. L. 105–388</ref> redesignated subsec. (i) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s1052/e">Pub. L. 104–66, § 1052(e)</ref>, struck out before period at end “, and annually thereafter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s1051/a">Pub. L. 104–66, § 1051(a)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (3) and struck out former par. (3) which directed Secretary to conduct study of heavy duty vehicles acquired under Department of Energy program and report results to Congress and par. (4) which directed Secretary to conduct study of advisability of heavy duty vehicle disposal and report results to Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/1">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “vehicles” for “passenger automobiles and light duty trucks” before “acquired annually for use” and “alternative fueled vehicles. In no event shall the number of such vehicles acquired be less than the number required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13212">section 13212 of this title</ref>.” for “alcohol powered vehicles, dual energy vehicles, natural gas powered vehicles, or natural gas dual energy vehicles.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/2">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(2)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “The Secretary shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with this part, ensure that the number of dual energy vehicles acquired under this subsection is at least as great as the number of alcohol powered vehicles acquired under this subsection, and that the number of natural gas dual energy vehicles acquired under this subsection is at least as great as the number of natural gas powered vehicles acquired under this subsection. To the extent practicable, both vehicles capable of operating on alcohol and vehicles capable of operating on natural gas shall be acquired in carrying out this subsection, and such vehicles shall be supplied by original equipment manufacturers.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/3">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s309">Pub. L. 102–486, § 309</ref>, substituted “a representative sample of alternative fueled vehicles in Federal fleets” for “the vehicles acquired under subsection (a) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/4">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(4)</ref>, added pars. (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/5">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(5)</ref>, in introductory provisions substituted “alternative fuels, such fuels” for “alcohol or natural gas, alcohol or natural gas” and in par. (1) substituted “alternative fuel” for “alcohol or natural gas”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/6">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(6)</ref>, substituted “To the extent that appropriations are available for such purposes, the Secretary” for “The Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/7">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(7)</ref>, added pars. (2) to (6) and struck out former pars. (2) to (6) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) the term ‘alcohol’ means a mixture containing 85 percent or more by volume methanol, ethanol, or other alcohols, in any combination;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) the term ‘alcohol powered vehicle’ means a vehicle designed to operate exclusively on alcohol;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) the term ‘dual energy vehicle’ means a vehicle which is capable of operating on alcohol and on gasoline or diesel fuel;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(5) the term ‘natural gas dual energy vehicle’ means a vehicle which is capable of operating on natural gas and on gasoline or diesel fuel; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(6) the term ‘natural gas powered vehicle’ means a vehicle designed to operate exclusively on natural gas.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s302/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, § 302(a)(8)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “For the purposes of this section, there are authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, $5,000,000, for the fiscal year ending <date date="1991-09-30">September 30, 1991</date>, $3,000,000, for the fiscal year ending <date date="1992-09-30">September 30, 1992</date>, $2,000,000, and for the fiscal year ending <date date="1993-09-30">September 30, 1993</date>, $2,000,000.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbda373b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbda373b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, <date date="2004-10-09">Oct. 9, 2004</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="terminationDate" id="idbda373b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/494/s4/b">Pub. L. 100–494, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-14">Oct. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2448">102 Stat. 2448</ref>, which provided that this section and the amendments made by this section (enacting this part) were to cease to be effective after <date date="1997-09-30">Sept. 30, 1997</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 102–486, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2871">106 Stat. 2871</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbda373ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/494/s2">Pub. L. 100–494, § 2</ref>, <date date="1988-10-14">Oct. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2441">102 Stat. 2441</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/494/s2">
<inline>“The Congress finds and declares that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the achievement of long-term energy security for the United States is essential to the health of the national economy, the well-being of our citizens, and the maintenance of national security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the displacement of energy derived from imported oil with alternative fuels will help to achieve energy security and improve air quality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> transportation uses account for more than 60 percent of the oil consumption of the Nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Nation’s security, economic, and environmental interests require that the Federal Government should assist clean-burning, nonpetroleum transportation fuels to reach a threshold level of commercial application and consumer acceptability at which they can successfully compete with petroleum-based fuels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> methanol, ethanol, and natural gas are proven transportation fuels that burn more cleanly and efficiently than gasoline and diesel fuel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the production and use as transportation fuels of ethanol, methanol made from natural gas or biomass, and compressed natural gas have been estimated in some studies to release less carbon dioxide than comparable quantities of petroleum-based fuel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the amount of carbon dioxide released with methanol from a coal-to-methanol industry using currently available technologies has been estimated in some studies to be significantly greater than the amount released with a comparable quantity of petroleum-based fuel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> there exists evidence that manmade pollution—the release of carbon dioxide, chlorofluorocarbons, methane, and other trace gases into the atmosphere—may be producing a long term and substantial increase in the average temperature on Earth, a phenomenon known as global warming through the greenhouse effect; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> ongoing pollution and deforestation may be contributing now to an irreversible process producing unacceptable global climate changes; necessary actions must be identified and implemented in time to protect the climate, including the development of technologies to control increased carbon dioxide emissions that result with methanol from a coal-to-methanol industry.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbda373bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Purpose</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/494/s3">Pub. L. 100–494, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-10-14">Oct. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2442">102 Stat. 2442</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/494/s3">
<inline>“The purpose of this Act [see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref>] is to encourage—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the development and widespread use of methanol, ethanol, and natural gas as transportation fuels by consumers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the production of methanol, ethanol, and natural gas powered motor vehicles.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbda373bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Nonstandard Fuels</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/494/s5">Pub. L. 100–494, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-10-14">Oct. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2448">102 Stat. 2448</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/494/s5">“No guaranty or warranty with respect to any passenger automobile or light-duty truck acquired by the United States after <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>, shall be voided or reduced in effect by reason of the operation of such vehicle with any fuel for which a currently effective waiver, which includes a limitation regarding Reid vapor pressure with respect to such fuel, has been issued by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under section 211(f) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7545/f">42 U.S.C. 7545(f)</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
