<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdaf5c39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614"><num value="6614">§ 6614.</num><heading> Policy planning; analysis; advice; establishment of advisory panel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Office shall serve as a source of scientific and technological analysis and judgment for the President with respect to major policies, plans, and programs of the Federal Government. In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Director shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> seek to define coherent approaches for applying science and technology to critical and emerging national and international problems and for promoting coordination of the scientific and technological responsibilities and programs of the Federal departments and agencies in the resolution of such problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assist and advise the President in the preparation of the Science and Technology Report, in accordance with section 6618 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003496">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003496"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> gather timely and authoritative information concerning significant developments and trends in science, technology, and in national priorities, both current and prospective, to analyze and interpret such information for the purpose of determining whether such developments and trends are likely to affect achievement of the priority goals of the Nation as set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6601/b">section 6601(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> encourage the development and maintenance of an adequate data base for human resources in science, engineering, and technology, including the development of appropriate models to forecast future manpower requirements, and assess the impact of major governmental and public programs on human resources and their utilization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> initiate studies and analyses, including systems analyses and technology assessments, of alternatives available for the resolution of critical and emerging national and international problems amendable to the contributions of science and technology and, insofar as possible, determine and compare probable costs, benefits, and impacts of such alternatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> advise the President on the extent to which the various scientific and technological programs, policies, and activities of the Federal Government are likely to affect the achievement of the priority goals of the Nation as set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6601/b">section 6601(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> provide the President with periodic reviews of Federal statutes and administrative regulations of the various departments and agencies which affect research and development activities, both internally and in relation to the private sector, or which may interfere with desirable technological innovation, together with recommendations for their elimination, reform, or updating as appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> develop, review, revise, and recommend criteria for determining scientific and technological activities warranting Federal support, and recommend Federal policies designed to advance (A) the development and maintenance of broadly based scientific and technological capabilities, including human resources, at all levels of government, academia, and industry, and (B) the effective application of such capabilities to national needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> assess and advise on policies for international cooperation in science and technology which will advance the national and international objectives of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> identify and assess emerging and future areas in which science and technology can be used effectively in addressing national and international problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> report at least once each year to the President and the Congress on the overall activities and accomplishments of the Office, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6615">section 6615 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> periodically survey the nature and needs of national science and technology policy and make recommendations to the President, for review and transmission to the Congress, for the timely and appropriate revision of such policy in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6602/a/6">section 6602(a)(6) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdaf5c47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> perform such other duties and functions and make and furnish such studies and reports thereon, and recommendations with respect to matters of policy and legislation as the President may request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director shall establish an Intergovernmental Science, Engineering, and Technology Advisory Panel (hereinafter referred to as the “Panel”), whose purpose shall be to (A) identify and define civilian problems at State, regional, and local levels which science, engineering, and technology may assist in resolving or ameliorating; (B) recommend priorities for addressing such problems; and (C) advise and assist the Director in identifying and fostering policies to facilitate the transfer and utilization of research and development results so as to maximize their application to civilian needs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Panel shall be composed of (A) the Director of the Office, or his representative; (B) at least ten members representing the interests of the States, appointed by the Director of the Office after consultation with State officials; (C) the Director of the National Science Foundation, or his representative; and (D) the Director of the Office of Pandemic Preparedness and Response Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of the Office, or his representative, shall serve as Chairman of the Panel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Panel shall perform such functions as the Chairman may prescribe, and shall meet at the call of the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdaf5c4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6614/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Each member of the Panel shall, while serving on business of the Panel, be entitled to receive compensation at a rate not to exceed the daily rate prescribed for GS–18 of the General Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, including traveltime, and, while so serving away from his home or regular place of business, he may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence in the same manner as the expenses authorized by section 5703(b) <sup>1</sup> of title 5 for persons in government service employed intermittently.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdaf5c4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/282/tII/s205">Pub. L. 94–282, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/464">90 Stat. 464</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/375/tII/s215/2">Pub. L. 97–375, title II, § 215(2)</ref>, (4), <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1826">96 Stat. 1826</ref>, 1827; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tII/s2104/k/3/A">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title II, § 2104(k)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5720">136 Stat. 5720</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdaf5c50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdaf5c51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdaf5c52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6618">Section 6618 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/375/tII/s215/1">Pub. L. 97–375, title II, § 215(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-12-21">Dec. 21, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1826">96 Stat. 1826</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6615">section 6615 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">Section 5703 of title 5</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(4), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/94/22/s4">Pub. L. 94–22, § 4</ref>, <date date="1975-05-19">May 19, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/85">89 Stat. 85</ref>, and, as so amended, does not contain a subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdaf5c53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328">Pub. L. 117–328</ref> added cl. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/97/375/s215/2">Pub. L. 97–375, § 215(2)</ref>, (4), inserted “and the Congress” after “President”, and substituted “section 6615” for “section 6618”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdaf5c54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdaf5c55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdb1cc56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comprehensive Accountability Study for Federally-Funded Research</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tIV/s430">Pub. L. 105–276, title IV, § 430</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2512">112 Stat. 2512</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/276/tIV/s430">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, may enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for the Academy to conduct a comprehensive study to develop methods for evaluating federally-funded research and development programs. This study shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> recommend processes to determine an acceptable level of success for federally-funded research and development programs by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> describing the research process in the various scientific and engineering disciplines;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> describing in the different sciences what measures and what criteria each community uses to evaluate the success or failure of a program, and on what time scales these measures are considered reliable—both for exploratory long-range work and for short-range goals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> recommending how these measures may be adapted for use by the Federal Government to evaluate federally-funded research and development programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> assess the extent to which agencies incorporate independent merit-based evaluation into the formulation of the strategic plans of funding agencies and if the quantity or quality of this type of input is unsatisfactory;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> recommend mechanisms for identifying federally-funded research and development programs which are unsuccessful or unproductive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> evaluate the extent to which independent, merit-based evaluation of federally-funded research and development programs and projects achieves the goal of eliminating unsuccessful or unproductive programs and projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><chapeau> investigate and report on the validity of using quantitative performance goals for aspects of programs which relate to administrative management of the program and for which such goals would be appropriate, including aspects related to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> administrative burden on contractors and recipients of financial assistance awards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> administrative burdens on external participants in independent, merit-based evaluations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> cost and schedule control for construction projects funded by the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the ratio of overhead costs of the program relative to the amounts expended through the program for equipment and direct funding of research; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the timeliness of program responses to requests for funding, participation, or equipment use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Independent Merit-Based Evaluation Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘independent merit-based evaluation’ means review of the scientific or technical quality of research or development, conducted by experts who are chosen for their knowledge of scientific and technical fields relevant to the evaluation and who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in the case of the review of a program activity, do not derive long-term support from the program activity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the case of the review of a project proposal, are not seeking funds in competition with the proposal.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdb1cc57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Computer Network Study</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/383/s10">Pub. L. 99–383, § 10</ref>, <date date="1986-08-21">Aug. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/816">100 Stat. 816</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/383/s10">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Office of Science and Technology Policy (hereinafter referred to as the ‘Office’) shall undertake a study of critical problems and current and future options regarding communications networks for research computers, including supercomputers, at universities and Federal research facilities in the United States. The study shall include an analysis of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the networking needs of the Nation’s academic and Federal research computer programs, including supercomputer programs, over the period which is fifteen years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-08-21">Aug. 21, 1986</date>], including requirements in terms of volume of data, reliability of transmission, software compatibility, graphics capability, and transmission security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the benefits and opportunities that an improved computer network would offer for electronic mail, file transfer, and remote access and communications for universities and Federal research facilities in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the networking options available for linking academic and other federally supported research computers, including supercomputers, with a particular emphasis on the advantages and disadvantages, if any, of fiber optic systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The Office shall submit to the Congress—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> within one year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-08-21">Aug. 21, 1986</date>], a report on findings from the study undertaken pursuant to subsection (a) with respect to needs and options regarding communications networks for university and Federal research supercomputers within the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> within two years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-08-21">Aug. 21, 1986</date>], a report on findings from the study undertaken pursuant to subsection (a) with respect to needs and options regarding communications networks for all research computers at universities and Federal research facilities in the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbdb1cc58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbdb1cc59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested in Office of Science and Technology Policy and Director thereof pursuant to subsec. (a)(2) of this section and sections 6615 and 6618 of this title transferred to Director of National Science Foundation by section 5A of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1977, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, effective <date date="1978-02-26">Feb. 26, 1978</date>, as provided by section 1(a) of Ex. Ord. No. 12039, <date date="1978-02-24">Feb. 24, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 8095, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6601">section 6601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdb1cc5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Intergovernmental Science, Engineering, and Technology Advisory Panel; Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Intergovernmental Science, Engineering, and Technology Advisory Panel, established pursuant to this section, was abolished and its functions transferred to the President by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1977, § 5A, 42 F.R. 56101, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1634">91 Stat. 1634</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, effective <date date="1978-02-26">Feb. 26, 1978</date>, as provided by section 1(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 12039, <date date="1978-02-24">Feb. 24, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 8095, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6601">section 6601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
