<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdb1cca8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617"><num value="6617">§ 6617.</num><heading> Coordination with other organizations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb1cca9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation and cooperation with Federal departments and agencies; utilization of consultants; establishment of advisory panels; consultation with State and local agencies, professional groups, and representatives of industry, etc.; hearings; utilization of services, personnel, equipment, etc., of public and private agencies and organizations, and individuals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In exercising his functions under this chapter, the Director shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1ccaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> work in close consultation and cooperation with the Domestic Council, the National Security Council, the Office of Homeland Security, the Council on Environmental Quality, the Council of Economic Advisers, the Office of Management and Budget, the National Science Board, and the Federal departments and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1ccab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> utilize the services of consultants, establish such advisory panels, and, to the extent practicable, consult with State and local governmental agencies, with appropriate professional groups, and with such representatives of industry, the universities, agriculture, labor, consumers, conservation organizations, and such other public interest groups, organizations, and individuals as he deems advisable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1ccac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> hold such hearings in various parts of the Nation as he deems necessary, to determine the views of the agencies, groups, and organizations referred to in paragraph (2) of this subsection and of the general public, concerning national needs and trends in science and technology; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1ccad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> utilize with their consent to the fullest extent possible the services, personnel, equipment, facilities, and information (including statistical information) of public and private agencies and organizations, and individuals, in order to avoid duplication of effort and expense, and may transfer funds made available pursuant to this chapter to other Federal agencies as reimbursement for the utilization of such personnel, services, facilities, equipment, and information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb1ccae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Information from Executive departments, agencies, and instrumentalities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each department, agency, and instrumentality of the Executive Branch of the Government, including any independent agency, is authorized to furnish the Director such information as the Director deems necessary to carry out his functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb1ccaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6617/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance from Administrator of National Aeronautics and Space Administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration is authorized to assist the Director with respect to carrying out his activities conducted under paragraph (5) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6614/a">section 6614(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdb1ccb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/282/tII/s208">Pub. L. 94–282, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/467">90 Stat. 467</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tXVII/s1712/2">Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1712(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2320">116 Stat. 2320</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdb1ccb1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdb1ccb2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdb1ccb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> inserted “the Office of Homeland Security,” after “the National Security Council,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdb1ccb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbdb1ccb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> effective 60 days after <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s101">section 101 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
