<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdb1ccc6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6620"><num value="6620">§ 6620.</num><heading> Release of scientific research results</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb1ccc7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6620/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Principles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2007-08-09">August 9, 2007</date>, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the heads of all Federal civilian agencies that conduct scientific research, shall develop and issue an overarching set of principles to ensure the communication and open exchange of data and results to other agencies, policymakers, and the public of research conducted by a scientist employed by a Federal civilian agency and to prevent the intentional or unintentional suppression or distortion of such research findings. The principles shall encourage the open exchange of data and results of research undertaken by a scientist employed by such an agency and shall be consistent with existing Federal laws, including chapter 18 of title 35 (commonly known as the “Bayh-Dole Act”). The principles shall also take into consideration the policies of peer-reviewed scientific journals in which Federal scientists may currently publish results.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb1ccc8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6620/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2007-08-09">August 9, 2007</date>, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall ensure that all civilian Federal agencies that conduct scientific research develop specific policies and procedures regarding the public release of data and results of research conducted by a scientist employed by such an agency consistent with the principles established under subsection (a). Such polices <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003497">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003497"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “policies”.</note> and procedures shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1ccc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6620/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> specifically address what is and what is not permitted or recommended under such policies and procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1ccca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6620/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> be specifically designed for each such agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1cccb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6620/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> be applied uniformly throughout each such agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb1cccc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6620/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> be widely communicated and readily accessible to all employees of each such agency and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdb1cccd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/69/tI/s1009">Pub. L. 110–69, title I, § 1009</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/581">121 Stat. 581</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdb1ccce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdb1cccf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbdb1ccd0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the America COMPETES Act, also known as the America Creating Opportunities to Meaningfully Promote Excellence in Technology, Education, and Science Act, and not as part of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
