<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdb43d4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625"><num value="6625">§ 6625.</num><heading> Coordination of international science and technology partnerships</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Short title</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section may be cited as the “International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2016”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall establish a body under the National Science and Technology Council with the responsibility to identify and coordinate international science and technology cooperation that can strengthen the United States science and technology enterprise, improve economic and national security, and support United States foreign policy goals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> NSTC body leadership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The body established under subsection (b) shall be co-chaired by senior level officials from the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The body established under subsection (b) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb43d53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> plan and coordinate interagency international science and technology cooperative research and training activities and partnerships supported or managed by Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb43d54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> work with other National Science and Technology Council committees to help plan and coordinate the international component of national science and technology priorities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb43d55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> establish Federal priorities and policies for aligning, as appropriate, international science and technology cooperative research and training activities and partnerships supported or managed by Federal agencies with the foreign policy goals of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb43d56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identify opportunities for new international science and technology cooperative research and training partnerships that advance both the science and technology and the foreign policy priorities of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb43d57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> in carrying out paragraph (4), solicit input and recommendations from non-Federal science and technology stakeholders, including institutions of higher education, scientific and professional societies, industry, and other relevant organizations and institutions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdb43d58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> identify broad issues that influence the ability of United States scientists and engineers to collaborate with foreign counterparts, including barriers to collaboration and access to scientific information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a biennial report on the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Website</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall make each report available to the public on the Office of Science and Technology Policy website.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The body established under subsection (b) shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after <date date="2017-01-06">January 6, 2017</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdb43d5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6625/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional reports to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit, not later than 60 days after <date date="2017-01-06">January 6, 2017</date>, and annually thereafter, to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that lists and describes the details of all foreign travel by Office of Science and Technology Policy staff and detailees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdb43d5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/329/tII/s208">Pub. L. 114–329, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2017-01-06">Jan. 6, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/3002">130 Stat. 3002</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdb43d5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdb43d5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbdb43d60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as the International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2016 and also as part of the American Innovation and Competitiveness Act, and not as part of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdb43d61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbdb43d62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definition</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of “institutions of higher education” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/329/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 114–329</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862s">section 1862s of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
