<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdb8f850-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6706"><num value="6706">§ 6706.</num><heading> Implementing rules, regulations, and procedures; criteria; employment of disabled and Vietnam-era veterans; determination of applications for grants</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, not later than thirty days after <date date="1976-07-22">July 22, 1976</date>, prescribe those rules, regulations, and procedures (including application forms) necessary to carry out this chapter. Such rules, regulations, and procedures shall assure that adequate consideration is given to the relative needs of various sections of the country. The Secretary shall consider among other factors (1) the severity and duration of unemployment in proposed project areas, (2) the income levels and extent of underemployment in proposed project area, and (3) the extent to which proposed projects will contribute to the reduction of unemployment. The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, and consistent with existing applicable collective bargaining agreements and practices, shall promulgate regulations to assure special consideration to the employment in projects under this chapter of qualified disabled veterans (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4211/1">section 4211(1) of title 38</ref>) and qualified Vietnam-era veterans (as defined in section 4211(2) of such title 38). The Secretary shall make a final determination with respect to each application for a grant submitted to him under this chapter not later than the sixtieth day after the date he receives such application. Failure to make such final determination within such period shall be deemed to be an approval by the Secretary of the grant requested. For purposes of this section, in considering the extent of unemployment or underemployment, the Secretary shall consider the amount of unemployment or underemployment in the construction and construction-related industries.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbdb8f851-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/369/tI/s107">Pub. L. 94–369, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1976-07-22">July 22, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1000">90 Stat. 1000</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/28/tI/s104">Pub. L. 95–28, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1977-05-13">May 13, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/117">91 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/2">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/406">105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/446/tXII/s1203/c/3">Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1203(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4690">108 Stat. 4690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdb8f852-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdb8f853-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdb8f854-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/446">Pub. L. 103–446</ref>, which directed substitution of “section 4211(2)” for “section 4211(2)(A)” and “section 4211(1)” for “section 2011(1)”, was executed by substituting “section 4211(2)” for “section 4211(2)(A)”. Previously, “section 4211(1)” was substituted for “section 2011(1)” by <ref href="/us/pl/103/83">Pub. L. 103–83</ref>. See 1991 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref> substituted references to <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4211">section 4211 of title 38</ref> for references to <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2011">section 2011 of title 38</ref> in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/28">Pub. L. 95–28</ref> inserted provision directing Secretary to promulgate regulations to assure special consideration to employment in projects of qualified disabled veterans and qualified Vietnam-era veterans.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
