<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdbdb342-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851"><num value="6851">§ 6851.</num><heading> Congressional findings and purpose</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdbdb343-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb344-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the fastest, most cost-effective, and most environmentally sound way to prevent future energy shortages in the United States, while reducing the Nation’s dependence on imported energy supplies, is to encourage and facilitate, through major programs, the implementation of energy conservation and renewable-resource energy measures with respect to dwelling units, nonresidential buildings, and industrial plants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb345-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> current efforts to encourage and facilitate such measures are inadequate as a consequence of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb346-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a lack of adequate and available financing for such measures, particularly with respect to individual consumers and owners of small businesses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb347-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a shortage of reliable and impartial information and advisory services pertaining to practicable energy conservation measures and renewable-resource energy measures and the cost savings that are likely if they are implemented in such units, buildings, and plants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb348-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the absence of organized programs which, if they existed, would enable consumers, especially individuals and owners of small businesses, to undertake such measures easily and with confidence in their economic value;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb349-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> major programs of financial incentives and assistance for energy conservation measures and renewable-resource energy measures in dwelling units, nonresidential buildings, and industrial plants would—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb34a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> significantly reduce the Nation’s demand for energy and the need for petroleum imports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb34b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> cushion the adverse impact of the high price of energy supplies on consumers, particularly elderly and handicapped low-income persons who cannot afford to make the modifications necessary to reduce their residential energy use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb34c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> increase, directly and indirectly, job opportunities and national economic output;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb34d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the primary responsibility for the implementation of such major programs should be lodged with the governments of the States; the diversity of conditions among the various States and regions of the Nation is sufficiently great that a wholly federally administered program would not be as effective as one which is tailored to meet local requirements and to respond to local opportunities; the State should be allowed flexibility within which to fashion such programs, subject to general Federal guidelines and monitoring sufficient to protect the financial investments of consumers and the financial interest of the United States and to insure that the measures undertaken in fact result in significant energy and cost savings which would probably not otherwise occur;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb34e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to the extent that direct Federal administration is more economical and efficient, direct Federal financial incentives and assistance should be extended through existing and proven Federal programs rather than through new programs that would necessitate new and separate administrative bureaucracies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb34f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> such programs should be designed and administered to supplement, and not to supplant or in any other way conflict with, State energy conservation programs under part C of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6321">42 U.S.C. 6321</ref> et seq.]; the emergency energy conservation program carried out by community action agencies pursuant to section 2809(a)(12) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003508">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003508"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title; and other forms of assistance and encouragement for energy conservation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdbdb350-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> It is, therefore, the purpose of this subchapter to encourage and facilitate the implementation of energy conservation measures and renewable-resource energy measures in dwelling units, nonresidential buildings, and industrial plants, through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb351-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> supplemental State energy conservation plans; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb352-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6851/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Federal financial incentives and assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdbdb353-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/385/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 94–385, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1976-08-14">Aug. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1150">90 Stat. 1150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdbdb354-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdbdb355-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdbdb356-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Policy and Conservation Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(5), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/163">Pub. L. 94–163</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/871">89 Stat. 871</ref>. Part C of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act is classified generally to part B (§ 6321 et seq.) of subchapter III of chapter 77 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2809/a/12">Section 2809(a)(12) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), which was redesignated as section 2809(a)(5) by <ref href="/us/pl/95/568/s5/a/2/E">Pub. L. 95–568, § 5(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2426">92 Stat. 2426</ref>, was subsequently repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s683/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 683(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/519">95 Stat. 519</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this title,” meaning title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/94/385">Pub. L. 94–385</ref>, known as the Energy Conservation in Existing Buildings Act of 1976, which enacted this subchapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6327">section 6327 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701z–8">section 1701z–8 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking, amended sections 6323, 6325, and 6326 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6801">section 6801 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6801">section 6801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdbdb357-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idbdbdb358-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/94/385">Pub. L. 94–385</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter, as the “Energy Conservation in Existing Buildings Act of 1976”, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/385/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 94–385</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6801">section 6801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
