<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdbdb35a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861"><num value="6861">§ 6861.</num><heading> Congressional findings and purpose</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdbdb35b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb35c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a fast, cost-effective, and environmentally sound way to prevent future energy shortages in the United States while reducing the Nation’s dependence on imported energy supplies, is to encourage and facilitate, through major programs, the implementation of energy conservation and renewable-resource energy measures with respect to dwelling units;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb35d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> existing efforts to encourage and facilitate such measures are inadequate because—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb35e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> many dwellings owned or occupied by low-income persons are energy inefficient;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdbdb35f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> low-income persons can least afford to make the modifications necessary to provide for efficient energy equipment in such dwellings and otherwise to improve the energy efficiency of such dwellings;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb360-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> weatherization of such dwellings would lower shelter costs in dwellings owned or occupied by low-income persons as well as save energy and reduce future energy capacity requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdbdb361-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> States, through Community Action Agencies established under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2701">42 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.] and units of general purpose local government, should be encouraged, with Federal financial and technical assistance, to develop and support coordinated weatherization programs designed to alleviate the adverse effects of energy costs on such low-income persons, to supplement other Federal programs serving such low-income persons, and to increase energy efficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdbdb362-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6861/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> It is, therefore, the purpose of this part to develop and implement a weatherization assistance program to increase the energy efficiency of dwellings owned or occupied by low-income persons, reduce their total residential energy expenditures, and improve their health and safety, especially low-income persons who are particularly vulnerable such as the elderly, the handicapped, and children.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdbdb363-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/385/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 94–385, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1976-08-14">Aug. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1151">90 Stat. 1151</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/j">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(j)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-18">Oct. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1015">104 Stat. 1015</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdbdb364-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdbdb365-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdbdb366-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/452">Pub. L. 88–452</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/508">78 Stat. 508</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 34 (§ 2701 et seq.) of this title prior to repeal, except for titles VIII and X, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s683/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 683(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/519">95 Stat. 519</ref>. Titles VIII and X of the Act are classified generally to subchapters VIII (§ 2991 et seq.) and X (§ 2996 et seq.) of chapter 34 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdbdb367-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/440">Pub. L. 101–440</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) The Congress finds that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) dwellings owned or occupied by low-income persons frequently are inadequately insulated;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) low-income persons, particularly elderly and handicapped low-income persons, can least afford to make the modifications necessary to provide for adequate insulation in such dwellings and to otherwise reduce residential energy use;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) weatherization of such dwellings would lower utility expenses for such low-income owners or occupants as well as save thousands of barrels per day of needed fuel; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) States, through community action agencies established under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 and units of general purpose local government, should be encouraged, with Federal financial and technical assistance, to develop and support coordinated weatherization programs designed to ameliorate the adverse effects of high energy costs on such low-income persons, to supplement other Federal programs serving such persons, and to conserve energy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) It is, therefore, the purpose of this part to develop and implement a supplementary weatherization assistance program to assist in achieving a prescribed level of insulation in the dwellings of low-income persons, particularly elderly and handicapped low-income persons, in order both to aid those persons least able to afford higher utility costs and to conserve needed energy.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdbdb368-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdbdb369-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Weatherization Assistance Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dD/tV/s40551">Pub. L. 117–58, div. D, title V, § 40551</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1075">135 Stat. 1075</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dD/tV/s40551">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary [of Energy] for the weatherization assistance program established under part A of title IV of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6861">42 U.S.C. 6861</ref> et seq.) $3,500,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application of Wage Rate Requirements to Weatherization Assistance Program</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to work performed under the weatherization assistance program established under part A of title IV of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6861">42 U.S.C. 6861</ref> et seq.) on a project assisted in whole or in part by funding made available under subsection (a), the requirements of section 41101 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18851">42 U.S.C. 18851</ref>] shall apply only to work performed on multifamily buildings with not fewer than 5 units.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For provisions relating to rates of wages to be paid to laborers and mechanics on projects for construction, alteration, or repair work funded under div. D or an amendment by div. D of <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, including authority of Secretary of Labor, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18851">section 18851 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
