<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdc0238e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863"><num value="6863">§ 6863.</num><heading> Weatherization program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc0238f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development and conduct of program by Secretary; grants to States and Indian tribal organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall develop and conduct, in accordance with the purpose and provisions of this part, a weatherization program. In developing and conducting such program, the Secretary may, in accordance with this part and regulations promulgated under this part, make grants (1) to States, and (2) in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d), to Indian tribal organizations to serve Native Americans. Such grants shall be made for the purpose of providing financial assistance with regard to projects designed to provide for the weatherization of dwelling units, particularly those where elderly or handicapped low-income persons reside, occupied by low-income families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc02390-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation by Secretary with other Federal departments and agencies on development and publication in Federal Register of proposed regulations; required regulatory provisions; standards and procedures; rental units</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdc02391-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, after consultation with the Director, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, and the heads of such other Federal departments and agencies as the Secretary deems appropriate, shall develop and publish in the Federal Register for public comment, not later than 60 days after <date date="1976-08-14">August 14, 1976</date>, proposed regulations to carry out the provisions of this part. The Secretary shall take into consideration comments submitted regarding such proposed regulations and shall promulgate and publish final regulations for such purpose not later than 90 days after <date date="1976-08-14">August 14, 1976</date>. The development of regulations under this part shall be fully coordinated with the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdc02392-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The regulations promulgated pursuant to this section shall include provisions—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc02393-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> prescribing, in coordination with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology in the Department of Commerce, for use in various climatic, structural, and human need settings, standards for weatherization materials, energy conservation techniques, and balance combinations thereof, which are designed to achieve a balance of a healthful dwelling environment and maximum practicable energy conservation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc02394-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that provide guidance to the States in the implementation of this part, including guidance designed to ensure that a State establishes (i) procedures that provide protection under paragraph (5) to tenants paying for energy as a portion of their rent, and (ii) a process for monitoring compliance with its obligations pursuant to this part; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc02395-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that secure the Federal investment made under this part and address the issues of eviction from and sale of property receiving weatherization materials under this part.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdc02396-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretaries and Director described in paragraph (2)(A) and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall develop and publish in the Federal Register for public comment, not later than 60 days after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>, proposed amendments to the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1). Such amendments shall provide that the standards described in paragraph (2)(A) shall include a set of procedures to be applied to each dwelling unit to determine the optimum set of cost-effective measures, within the cost guidelines set for the program, to be installed in such dwelling unit. Such standards shall, in order to achieve such optimum savings of energy, take into consideration the following factors—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc02397-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the cost of the weatherization material;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc02398-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> variation in climate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc02399-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the value of energy saved by the application of the weatherization material.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such standards shall be utilized by the Secretary in carrying out this part, and by the Secretary of Agriculture in carrying out the weatherization program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1474/c">section 1474(c) of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall take into consideration comments submitted regarding such proposed amendment and shall promulgate and publish final amended regulations not later than 120 days after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdc0239a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary may amend the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) to provide that the standards described in paragraph (2)(A) take into consideration improvements in the health and safety of occupants of dwelling units, and other non-energy benefits, from weatherization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdc0239b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In carrying out paragraphs (2)(A) and (3), the Secretary shall establish the standards and procedures described in such paragraphs so that weatherization efforts being carried out under this part and under programs described in the fourth sentence of paragraph (3) will accomplish uniform results among the States in any area with a similar climatic condition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdc0239c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> In any case in which a dwelling consists of a rental unit or rental units, the State, in the implementation of this part, shall ensure that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc0239d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the benefits of weatherization assistance in connection with such rental units, including units where the tenants pay for their energy through their rent, will accrue primarily to the low-income tenants residing in such units;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc0239e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for a reasonable period of time after weatherization work has been completed on a dwelling containing a unit occupied by an eligible household, the tenants in that unit (including households paying for their energy through their rent) will not be subjected to rent increases unless those increases are demonstrably related to matters other than the weatherization work performed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc0239f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the enforcement of subparagraph (B) is provided through procedures established by the State by which tenants may file complaints and owners, in response to such complaints, shall demonstrate that the rent increase concerned is related to matters other than the weatherization work performed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> no undue or excessive enhancement will occur to the value of such dwelling units.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdc023a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> As a condition of having assistance provided under this part with respect to multifamily buildings, a State may require financial participation from the owners of such buildings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure of State to submit application; alternate application by any unit of general purpose local government or community action agency; submission of amended application by State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a State does not, within 90 days after the date on which final regulations are promulgated under this section, submit an application to the Secretary which meets the requirements set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6864">section 6864 of this title</ref>, any unit of general purpose local government of sufficient size (as determined by the Secretary), or a community action agency carrying out programs under title II of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2781">42 U.S.C. 2781</ref> et seq.], may, in lieu of such State, submit an application (meeting such requirements and subject to all other provisions of this part) for carrying out projects under this part within the geographical area which is subject to the jurisdiction of such government or is served by such agency. A State may, in accordance with regulations promulgated under this part, submit an amended application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct grants to low-income members of Indian tribal organizations or alternate service organizations; application for funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Reservation of amounts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B) and notwithstanding any other provision of this part, the Secretary shall reserve from amounts that would otherwise be allocated to a State under this part not less than 100 percent, but not more than 150 percent, of an amount which bears the same proportion to the allocation of that State for the applicable fiscal year as the population of all low-income members of an Indian tribe in that State bears to the population of all low-income individuals in that State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall apply only if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdc023a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the tribal organization serving the low-income members of the applicable Indian tribe requests that the Secretary make a grant directly; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdc023a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Secretary determines that the low-income members of the applicable Indian tribe would be equally or better served by making a grant directly than a grant made to the State in which the low-income members reside.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Presumption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the tribal organization requesting the grant is a tribally designated housing entity (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s4103">section 4103 of title 25</ref>) that has operated without material audit exceptions (or without any material audit exceptions that were not corrected within a 3-year period), the Secretary shall presume that the low-income members of the applicable Indian tribe would be equally or better served by making a grant directly to the tribal organization than by a grant made to the State in which the low-income members reside.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amounts reserved by the Secretary under this subsection shall be granted to the tribal organization serving the low-income members of the Indian tribe, or, where there is no tribal organization, to such other entity as the Secretary determines has the capacity to provide services pursuant to this part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order for a tribal organization or other entity to be eligible for a grant for a fiscal year under this subsection, it shall submit to the Secretary an application meeting the requirements set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6864">section 6864 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6863/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may transfer to the Director sums appropriated under this part to be utilized in order to carry out programs, under section 222(a)(12) of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2809/a/12">42 U.S.C. 2809(a)(12)</ref>], which further the purpose of this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdc023ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/385/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 94–385, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1976-08-14">Aug. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1152">90 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tII/s231/a/2">Pub. L. 95–619, title II, § 231(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3224">92 Stat. 3224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tV">Pub. L. 96–294, title V</ref>, §§ 573(b), 574, 577(2), <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/759">94 Stat. 759</ref>, 760; <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/tII/s201/h">Pub. L. 98–479, title II, § 201(h)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2228">98 Stat. 2228</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/b">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-18">Oct. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1012">104 Stat. 1012</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tIV/s405">Pub. L. 103–82, title IV, § 405</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/922">107 Stat. 922</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/325/tII/s203">Pub. L. 115–325, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2018-12-18">Dec. 18, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4462">132 Stat. 4462</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dZ/tI/s1011/c">Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title I, § 1011(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2442">134 Stat. 2442</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdc023ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdc023af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdc023b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/452">Pub. L. 88–452</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/508">78 Stat. 508</ref>. Title II of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 was classified generally to subchapter II (§ 2781 et seq.) of chapter 34 of this title prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s683/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 683(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/519">95 Stat. 519</ref>. Prior to that repeal, section 222(a)(12) of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2809/a/12">42 U.S.C. 2809(a)(12)</ref>] was redesignated as section 222(a)(5) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2809/a/5">42 U.S.C. 2809(a)(5)</ref>] by <ref href="/us/pl/95/568/s5/a/2/E">Pub. L. 95–568, § 5(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2426">94 Stat. 2426</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdc023b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s1011/c/1">Pub. L. 116–260, § 1011(c)(1)</ref>, in introductory provisions, struck out “and with the Director of the Community Services Administration” after “Director described in paragraph (2)(A)” and, in concluding provisions, inserted “and by” after “in carrying out this part,” and struck out “, and the Director of the Community Services Administration in carrying out weatherization programs under section 222(a)(12) of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1474/c">section 1474(c) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s1011/c/2">Pub. L. 116–260, § 1011(c)(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (4) and redesignated former pars. (4) to (6) as (5) to (7), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/325/s203/1">Pub. L. 115–325, § 203(1)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which related to conditions for reserving funds for direct grants to provide assistance to low-income members of Indian tribes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/325/s203/2">Pub. L. 115–325, § 203(2)</ref>, inserted heading, substituted “The amounts” for “The sums”, “low-income members of the Indian tribe” for “individuals for whom such a determination has been made”, and “as the Secretary determines” for “as he determines”, and struck out “on the basis of his determination” before “under this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/325/s203/3">Pub. L. 115–325, § 203(3)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> struck out “the Director of the ACTION Agency,” after “Labor,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/b/1">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(b)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (B) and (C) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “designed to insure that (i) the benefits of weatherization assistance in connection with leased dwelling units will accrue primarily to low-income tenants; (ii) the rents on such dwelling units will not be raised because of any increase in the value thereof due solely to weatherization assistance provided under this part; and (iii) no undue or excessive enhancement will occur to the value of such dwelling units.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/b/2">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(b)(2)</ref>, added pars. (5) and (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b)(1), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/479">Pub. L. 98–479</ref> substituted “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsecs. (a), (b)(1), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/s577/2">Pub. L. 96–294, § 577(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/s574">Pub. L. 96–294, § 574</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/294">Pub. L. 96–294</ref>, §§ 573(b), 577(2), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing, and struck out provisions relating to determinations respecting inapplicability of allocation requirement and priority for an applicable community action agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/s577/2">Pub. L. 96–294, § 577(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/s231/a/2">Pub. L. 95–619, § 231(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “occupied by low-income families” for “in which the head of the household is a low-income person”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/619/s231/b/1">Pub. L. 95–619, § 231(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdc023b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbdc023b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> effective <date date="1994-04-04">Apr. 4, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdc023b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Weatherization Assistance Grants Cost Sharing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/291/tII">Pub. L. 106–291, title II</ref>, <date date="2000-10-11">Oct. 11, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/976">114 Stat. 976</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/291/tII">“That, hereafter, Indian tribal direct grantees of weatherization assistance shall not be required to provide matching funds.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/3/tII">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–180, which provided that sums appropriated for weatherization assistance grants were to be contingent on a cost share of 25 percent by each participating State or other qualified participant, were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/106/469/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 106–469, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2040">114 Stat. 2040</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdc023b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Community Services Administration</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Community Services Administration, which was established by section 601 of Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2941">42 U.S.C. 2941</ref>), terminated when Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, <ref href="/us/pl/88/452">Pub. L. 88–452</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/508">78 Stat. 508</ref>, as amended, was repealed, except for titles VIII and X, effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s683/a">section 683(a) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, title VI, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/519">95 Stat. 519</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9912/a">42 U.S.C. 9912(a)</ref>. An Office of Community Services, headed by a Director, was established in Department of Health and Human Services by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s676">section 676 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9905">42 U.S.C. 9905</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
