<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdc023b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864"><num value="6864">§ 6864.</num><heading> Financial assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual application; contents; allocation to States</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide financial assistance, from sums appropriated for any fiscal year under this part, only upon annual application. Each such application shall describe the estimated number and characteristics of the low-income persons and the number of dwelling units to be assisted and the criteria and methods to be used by the applicant in providing weatherization assistance to such persons. The application shall also contain such other information (including information needed for evaluation purposes) and assurances as may be required (1) in the regulations promulgated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6863">section 6863 of this title</ref> and (2) to carry out this section. The Secretary shall allocate financial assistance to each State on the basis of the relative need for weatherization assistance among low-income persons throughout the States, taking into account the following factors:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/a/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The number of dwelling units to be weatherized.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/a/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The climatic conditions in the State respecting energy conservation, which may include consideration of annual degree days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/a/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The type of weatherization work to be done in the various settings.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/a/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Such other factors as the Secretary may determine necessary, such as the cost of heating and cooling, in order to carry out the purpose and provisions of this part.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall not provide financial assistance under this part unless the applicant has provided reasonable assurances that it has—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> established a policy advisory council which (A) has special qualifications and sensitivity with respect to solving the problems of low-income persons (including the weatherization and energy-conservation problems of such persons), (B) is broadly representative of organizations and agencies which are providing services to such persons in the State or geographical area in question, and (C) is responsible for advising the responsible official or agency administering the allocation of financial assistance in such State or area with respect to the development and implementation of such weatherization assistance program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> established priorities to govern the provision of weatherization assistance to low-income persons, including methods to provide priority to elderly and handicapped low-income persons, and such priority as the applicant determines is appropriate for single-family or other high-energy-consuming dwelling units;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> established policies and procedures designed to assure that financial assistance provided under this part will be used to supplement, and not to supplant, State or local funds, and, to the extent practicable, to increase the amounts of such funds that would be made available in the absence of Federal funds for carrying out the purpose of this part, including plans and procedures (A) for securing, to the maximum extent practicable, the services of volunteers and training participants and public service employment workers, pursuant to title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</ref> et seq.], to work under the supervision of qualified supervisors and foremen, (B) for using Federal financial assistance under this part to increase the portion of low-income weatherization assistance that the State obtains from non-Federal sources, including private sources, and (C) for complying with the limitations set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6865">section 6865 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdc023c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> selected on the basis of public comment received during a public hearing conducted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6865/b/1">section 6865(b)(1) of this title</ref>, and other appropriate findings, community action agencies or other public or nonprofit entities to undertake the weatherization activities authorized by this subchapter: <i>Provided</i>, Such selection shall be based on the agency’s experience and performance in weatherization or housing renovation activities, experience in assisting low-income persons in the area to be served, and the capacity to undertake a timely and effective weatherization program: <i>Provided further</i>, That in making such selection preference shall be given to any community action agency or other public or nonprofit entity which has, or is currently administering, an effective program under this subchapter or under title II of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2781">42 U.S.C. 2781</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdc023c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6864/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual update of data used in allocating funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective with fiscal year 1991, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall update the population, eligible households, climatic, residential energy use, and all other data used in allocating the funds under this part among the States pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdc023c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/385/tIV/s414">Pub. L. 94–385, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="1976-08-14">Aug. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1154">90 Stat. 1154</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tV">Pub. L. 96–294, title V</ref>, §§ 573(c), 577(2), <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/759">94 Stat. 759</ref>, 760; <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/c">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(c)</ref>, (g), <date date="1990-10-18">Oct. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1012">104 Stat. 1012</ref>, 1014; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/38">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(38), (f)(29)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–427, 2681–434; <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tV/s512/k">Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(k)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1709">128 Stat. 1709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdc023c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdc023c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdc023c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1425">128 Stat. 1425</ref>. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 3111 et seq.) of chapter 32 of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, referred to in subsec. (b)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/452">Pub. L. 88–452</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/508">78 Stat. 508</ref>. Title II of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 was classified generally to subchapter II (§ 2781 et seq.) of chapter 34 of this title prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s683/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 683(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/519">95 Stat. 519</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdc023c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> substituted “securing, to the maximum extent practicable, the services of volunteers and training participants and public service employment workers, pursuant to title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act” for “securing, to the maximum extent practicable, the services of volunteers and training participants and public service employment workers, pursuant to title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/f/29">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(29)]</ref>, struck out “the Job Training Partnership Act or” after “pursuant to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/38">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(38)]</ref>, substituted “the Job Training Partnership Act or title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998” for “the Comprehensive Employment and Training Act of 1973”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/c/1">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “, such as the cost of heating and cooling,” after “necessary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/g">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(g)</ref>, added cl. (B) and redesignated former cl. (B) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/440/s7/c/2">Pub. L. 101–440, § 7(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/s577/2">Pub. L. 96–294, § 577(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/294">Pub. L. 96–294</ref>, §§ 573(c), 577(2), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” and added par. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdc023c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbdc023c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> effective on the first day of the first full program year after <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date> (<date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s506">section 506 of Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbdc023c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(38)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, and amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(29)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>, see section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(g)(1), (2)(B)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3502">section 3502 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
