<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdd0c549-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925"><num value="6925">§ 6925.</num><heading> Permits for treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c54a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than eighteen months after <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations requiring each person owning or operating an existing facility or planning to construct a new facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter to have a permit issued pursuant to this section. Such regulations shall take effect on the date provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6930">section 6930 of this title</ref> and upon and after such date the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste and the construction of any new facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste is prohibited except in accordance with such a permit. No permit shall be required under this section in order to construct a facility if such facility is constructed pursuant to an approval issued by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2605/e">section 2605(e) of title 15</ref> for the incineration of polychlorinated biphenyls and any person owning or operating such a facility may, at any time after operation or construction of such facility has begun, file an application for a permit pursuant to this section authorizing such facility to incinerate hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c54b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements of permit application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each application for a permit under this section shall contain such information as may be required under regulations promulgated by the Administrator, including information respecting—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c54c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> estimates with respect to the composition, quantities, and concentrations of any hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter, or combinations of any such hazardous waste and any other solid waste, proposed to be disposed of, treated, transported, or stored, and the time, frequency, or rate of which such waste is proposed to be disposed of, treated, transported, or stored; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c54d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the site at which such hazardous waste or the products of treatment of such hazardous waste will be disposed of, treated, transported to, or stored.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c54e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit issuance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c54f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon a determination by the Administrator (or a State, if applicable), of compliance by a facility for which a permit is applied for under this section with the requirements of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref>, the Administrator (or the State) shall issue a permit for such facilities. In the event permit applicants propose modification of their facilities, or in the event the Administrator (or the State) determines that modifications are necessary to conform to the requirements under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref>, the permit shall specify the time allowed to complete the modifications.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c550-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c551-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c552-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Not later than the date four years after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, in the case of each application under this subsection for a permit for a land disposal facility which was submitted before such date, the Administrator shall issue a final permit pursuant to such application or issue a final denial of such application.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c553-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Not later than the date five years after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, in the case of each application for a permit under this subsection for an incinerator facility which was submitted before such date, the Administrator shall issue a final permit pursuant to such application or issue a final denial of such application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c554-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Not later than the date eight years after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, in the case of each application for a permit under this subsection for any facility (other than a facility referred to in subparagraph (A)) which was submitted before such date, the Administrator shall issue a final permit pursuant to such application or issue a final denial of such application.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c555-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> The time periods specified in this paragraph shall also apply in the case of any State which is administering an authorized hazardous waste program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6926">section 6926 of this title</ref>. Interim status under subsection (e) shall terminate for each facility referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) or (B) on the expiration of the five- or eight-year period referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B), whichever is applicable, unless the owner or operator of the facility applies for a final determination regarding the issuance of a permit under this subsection within—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c556-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> two years after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date> (in the case of a facility referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii)), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c557-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> four years after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date> (in the case of a facility referred to in subparagraph (B)).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c558-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any permit under this section shall be for a fixed term, not to exceed 10 years in the case of any land disposal facility, storage facility, or incinerator or other treatment facility. Each permit for a land disposal facility shall be reviewed five years after date of issuance or reissuance and shall be modified as necessary to assure that the facility continues to comply with the currently applicable requirements of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref>. Nothing in this subsection shall preclude the Administrator from reviewing and modifying a permit at any time during its term. Review of any application for a permit renewal shall consider improvements in the state of control and measurement technology as well as changes in applicable regulations. Each permit issued under this section shall contain such terms and conditions as the Administrator (or the State) determines necessary to protect human health and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c559-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit revocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon a determination by the Administrator (or by a State, in the case of a State having an authorized hazardous waste program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6926">section 6926 of this title</ref>) of noncompliance by a facility having a permit under this chapter with the requirements of this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref>, the Administrator (or State, in the case of a State having an authorized hazardous waste program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6926">section 6926 of this title</ref>) shall revoke such permit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c55a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim status</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c55b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any person who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c55c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> owns or operates a facility required to have a permit under this section which facility—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdd0c55d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> was in existence on <date date="1980-11-19">November 19, 1980</date>, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdd0c55e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is in existence on the effective date of statutory or regulatory changes under this chapter that render the facility subject to the requirement to have a permit under this section,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c55f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has complied with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6930/a">section 6930(a) of this title</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c560-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has made an application for a permit under this section,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be treated as having been issued such permit until such time as final administrative disposition of such application is made, unless the Administrator or other plaintiff proves that final administrative disposition of such application has not been made because of the failure of the applicant to furnish information reasonably required or requested in order to process the application. This paragraph shall not apply to any facility which has been previously denied a permit under this section or if authority to operate the facility under this section has been previously terminated.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c561-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In the case of each land disposal facility which has been granted interim status under this subsection before <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, interim status shall terminate on the date twelve months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, unless the owner or operator of such facility—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c562-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> applies for a final determination regarding the issuance of a permit under subsection (c) for such facility before the date twelve months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c563-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> certifies that such facility is in compliance with all applicable groundwater monitoring and financial responsibility requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c564-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In the case of each land disposal facility which is in existence on the effective date of statutory or regulatory changes under this chapter that render the facility subject to the requirement to have a permit under this section and which is granted interim status under this subsection, interim status shall terminate on the date twelve months after the date on which the facility first becomes subject to such permit requirement unless the owner or operator of such facility—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c565-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> applies for a final determination regarding the issuance of a permit under subsection (c) for such facility before the date twelve months after the date on which the facility first becomes subject to such permit requirement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c566-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> certifies that such facility is in compliance with all applicable groundwater monitoring and financial responsibility requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c567-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Coal mining wastes and reclamation permits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a) through (e) of this section, any surface coal mining and reclamation permit covering any coal mining wastes or overburden which has been issued or approved under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1201">30 U.S.C. 1201</ref> et seq.] shall be deemed to be a permit issued pursuant to this section with respect to the treatment, storage, or disposal of such wastes or overburden. Regulations promulgated by the Administrator under this subchapter shall not be applicable to treatment, storage, or disposal of coal mining wastes and overburden which are covered by such a permit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c568-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Research, development, and demonstration permits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c569-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator may issue a research, development, and demonstration permit for any hazardous waste treatment facility which proposes to utilize an innovative and experimental hazardous waste treatment technology or process for which permit standards for such experimental activity have not been promulgated under this subchapter. Any such permit shall include such terms and conditions as will assure protection of human health and the environment. Such permits—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c56a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall provide for the construction of such facilities, as necessary, and for operation of the facility for not longer than one year (unless renewed as provided in paragraph (4)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c56b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall provide for the receipt and treatment by the facility of only those types and quantities of hazardous waste which the Administrator deems necessary for purposes of determining the efficacy and performance capabilities of the technology or process and the effects of such technology or process on human health and the environment, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c56c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall include such requirements as the Administrator deems necessary to protect human health and the environment (including, but not limited to, requirements regarding monitoring, operation, insurance or bonding, financial reponsibility,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003520">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003520"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “responsibility”.</note> closure, and remedial action), and such requirements as the Administrator deems necessary regarding testing and providing of information to the Administrator with respect to the operation of the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Administrator may apply the criteria set forth in this paragraph in establishing the conditions of each permit without separate establishment of regulations implementing such criteria.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c56d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the purpose of expediting review and issuance of permits under this subsection, the Administrator may, consistent with the protection of human health and the environment, modify or waive permit application and permit issuance requirements established in the Administrator’s general permit regulations except that there may be no modification or waiver of regulations regarding financial responsibility (including insurance) or of procedures established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6974/b/2">section 6974(b)(2) of this title</ref> regarding public participation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c56e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Administrator may order an immediate termination of all operations at the facility at any time he determines that termination is necessary to protect human health and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c56f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any permit issued under this subsection may be renewed not more than three times. Each such renewal shall be for a period of not more than 1 year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c570-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Waste minimization</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective <date date="1985-09-01">September 1, 1985</date>, it shall be a condition of any permit issued under this section for the treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste on the premises where such waste was generated that the permittee certify, no less often than annually, that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c571-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the generator of the hazardous waste has a program in place to reduce the volume or quantity and toxicity of such waste to the degree determined by the generator to be economically practicable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c572-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the proposed method of treatment, storage, or disposal is that practicable method currently available to the generator which minimizes the present and future threat to human health and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c573-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim status facilities receiving wastes after <date date="1982-07-26">July 26, 1982</date></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The standards concerning ground water monitoring, unsaturated zone monitoring, and corrective action, which are applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref> to new landfills, surface impoundments, land treatment units, and waste-pile units required to be permitted under subsection (c) shall also apply to any landfill, surface impoundment, land treatment unit, or waste-pile unit qualifying for the authorization to operate under subsection (e) which receives hazardous waste after <date date="1982-07-26">July 26, 1982</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd0c574-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim status surface impoundments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c575-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), (3), or (4), each surface impoundment in existence on <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, and qualifying for the authorization to operate under subsection (e) of this section shall not receive, store, or treat hazardous waste after the date four years after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, unless such surface impoundment is in compliance with the requirements of section 6924(<i>o</i>)(1)(A) of this title which would apply to such impoundment if it were new.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c576-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to any surface impoundment which (A) has at least one liner, for which there is no evidence that such liner is leaking; (B) is located more than one-quarter mile from an underground source of drinking water; and (C) is in compliance with generally applicable ground water monitoring requirements for facilities with permits under subsection (c) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c577-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to any surface impoundment which (A) contains treated waste water during the secondary or subsequent phases of an aggressive biological treatment facility subject to a permit issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342">section 1342 of title 33</ref> (or which holds such treated waste water after treatment and prior to discharge); (B) is in compliance with generally applicable ground water monitoring requirements for facilities with permits under subsection (c) of this section; and (C)(i) is part of a facility in compliance with <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1311/b/2">section 1311(b)(2) of title 33</ref>, or (ii) in the case of a facility for which no effluent guidelines required under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1314/b/2">section 1314(b)(2) of title 33</ref> are in effect and no permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342/a/1">section 1342(a)(1) of title 33</ref> implementing <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1311/b/2">section 1311(b)(2) of title 33</ref> has been issued, is part of a facility in compliance with a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342">section 1342 of title 33</ref>, which is achieving significant degradation of toxic pollutants and hazardous constituents contained in the untreated waste stream and which has identified those toxic pollutants and hazardous constituents in the untreated waste stream to the appropriate permitting authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c578-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Administrator (or the State, in the case of a State with an authorized program), after notice and opportunity for comment, may modify the requirements of paragraph (1) for any surface impoundment if the owner or operator demonstrates that such surface impoundment is located, designed and operated so as to assure that there will be no migration of any hazardous constitutent <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003521">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003521"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “constituent”.</note> into ground water or surface water at any future time. The Administrator or the State shall take into account locational criteria established under section 6924(<i>o</i>)(7) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c579-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The owner or operator of any surface impoundment potentially subject to paragraph (1) who has reason to believe that on the basis of paragraph (2), (3), or (4) such surface impoundment is not required to comply with the requirements of paragraph (1), shall apply to the Administrator (or the State, in the case of a State with an authorized program) not later than twenty-four months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, for a determination of the applicability of paragraph (1) (in the case of paragraph (2) or (3)) or for a modification of the requirements of paragraph (1) (in the case of paragraph (4)), with respect to such surface impoundment. Such owner or operator shall provide, with such application, evidence pertinent to such decision, including:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c57a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an application for a final determination regarding the issuance of a permit under subsection (c) of this section for such facility, if not previously submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c57b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> evidence as to compliance with all applicable ground water monitoring requirements and the information and analysis from such monitoring;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c57c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> all reasonably ascertainable evidence as to whether such surface impoundment is leaking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c57d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> in the case of applications under paragraph (2) or (3), a certification by a registered professional engineer with academic training and experience in ground water hydrology that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdd0c57e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/5/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> under paragraph (2), the liner of such surface impoundment is designed, constructed, and operated in accordance with applicable requirements, such surface impoundment is more than one-quarter mile from an underground source of drinking water and there is no evidence such liner is leaking; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdd0c57f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/5/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> under paragraph (3), based on analysis of those toxic pollutants and hazardous constituents that are likely to be present in the untreated waste stream, such impoundment satisfies the conditions of paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of any surface impoundment for which the owner or operator fails to apply under this paragraph within the time provided by this paragraph or paragraph (6), such surface impoundment shall comply with paragraph (1) notwithstanding paragraph (2), (3), or (4). Within twelve months after receipt of such application and evidence and not later than thirty-six months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, and after notice and opportunity to comment, the Administrator (or, if appropriate, the State) shall advise such owner or operator on the applicability of paragraph (1) to such surface impoundment or as to whether and how the requirements of paragraph (1) shall be modified and applied to such surface impoundment.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c580-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c581-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In any case in which a surface impoundment becomes subject to paragraph (1) after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, due to the promulgation of additional listings or characteristics for the identification of hazardous waste under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6921">section 6921 of this title</ref>, the period for compliance in paragraph (1) shall be four years after the date of such promulgation, the period for demonstrations under paragraph (4) and for submission of evidence under paragraph (5) shall be not later than twenty-four months after the date of such promulgation, and the period for the Administrator (or if appropriate, the State) to advise such owners or operators under paragraph (5) shall be not later than thirty-six months after the date of promulgation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c582-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In any case in which a surface impoundment is initially determined to be excluded from the requirements of paragraph (1) but due to a change in condition (including the existence of a leak) no longer satisfies the provisions of paragraph (2), (3), or (4) and therefore becomes subject to paragraph (1), the period for compliance in paragraph (1) shall be two years after the date of discovery of such change of condition, or in the case of a surface impoundment excluded under paragraph (3) three years after such date of discovery.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c583-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c584-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator shall study and report to the Congress on the number, range of size, construction, likelihood of hazardous constituents migrating into ground water, and potential threat to human health and the environment of existing surface impoundments excluded by paragraph (3) from the requirements of paragraph (1). Such report shall address the need, feasibility, and estimated costs of subjecting such existing surface impoundments to the requirements of paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c585-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of any existing surface impoundment or class of surface impoundments from which the Administrator (or the State, in the case of a State with an authorized program) determines hazardous constituents are likely to migrate into ground water, the Administrator (or if appropriate, the State) is authorized to impose such requirements as may be necessary to protect human health and the environment, including the requirements of section 6924(<i>o</i>) of this title which would apply to such impoundments if they were new.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c586-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of any surface impoundment excluded by paragraph (3) from the requirements of paragraph (1) which is subsequently determined to be leaking, the Administrator (or, if appropriate, the State) shall require compliance with paragraph (1), unless the Administrator (or, if appropriate, the State) determines that such compliance is not necessary to protect human health and the environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c587-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> In the case of any surface impoundment in which the liners and leak detection system have been installed pursuant to the requirements of paragraph (1) and in good faith compliance with section 6924(<i>o</i>) of this title and the Administrator’s regulations and guidance documents governing liners and leak detection systems, no liner or leak detection system which is different from that which was so installed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be required for such unit by the Administrator when issuing the first permit under this section to such facility. Nothing in this paragraph shall preclude the Administrator from requiring installation of a new liner when the Administrator has reason to believe that any liner installed pursuant to the requirements of this subsection is leaking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c588-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> In the case of any surface impoundment which has been excluded by paragraph (2) on the basis of a liner meeting the definition under paragraph (12)(A)(ii), at the closure of such impoundment the Administrator shall require the owner or operator of such impoundment to remove or decontaminate all waste residues, all contaminated liner material, and contaminated soil to the extent practicable. If all contaminated soil is not removed or decontaminated, the owner or operator of such impoundment shall be required to comply with appropriate post-closure requirements, including but not limited to ground water monitoring and corrective action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c589-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><chapeau> Any incremental cost attributable to the requirements of this subsection or section 6924(<i>o</i>) of this title shall not be considered by the Administrator (or the State, in the case of a State with an authorized program under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342">section 1342 of title 33</ref>)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c58a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in establishing effluent limitations and standards under section 1311, 1314, 1316, 1317, or 1342 of title 33 based on effluent limitations guidelines and standards promulgated any time before twelve months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c58b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in establishing any other effluent limitations to carry out the provisions of section 1311, 1317, or 1342 of title 33 on or before <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c58c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c58d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If the Administrator allows a hazardous waste which is prohibited from one or more methods of land disposal under subsection (d), (e), or (g) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref> (or under regulations promulgated by the Administrator under such subsections) to be placed in a surface impoundment (which is operating pursuant to interim status) for storage or treatment, such impoundment shall meet the requirements that are applicable to new surface impoundments under section 6924(<i>o</i>)(1) of this title, unless such impoundment meets the requirements of paragraph (2) or (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c58e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of any hazardous waste which is prohibited from one or more methods of land disposal under subsection (d), (e), or (g) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref> (or under regulations promulgated by the Administrator under such subsection) the placement or maintenance of such hazardous waste in a surface impoundment for treatment is prohibited as of the effective date of such prohibition unless the treatment residues which are hazardous are, at a minimum, removed for subsequent management within one year of the entry of the waste into the surface impoundment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c58f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c590-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection, the term “liner” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c591-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a liner designed, constructed, installed, and operated to prevent hazardous waste from passing into the liner at any time during the active life of the facility; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c592-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a liner designed, constructed, installed, and operated to prevent hazardous waste from migrating beyond the liner to adjacent subsurface soil, ground water, or surface water at any time during the active life of the facility.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c593-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “aggressive biological treatment facility” means a system of surface impoundments in which the initial impoundment of the secondary treatment segment of the facility utilizes intense mechanical aeration to enhance biological activity to degrade waste water pollutants and</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c594-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the hydraulic retention time in such initial impoundment is no longer than 5 days under normal operating conditions, on an annual average basis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c595-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the hydraulic retention time in such initial impoundment is no longer than thirty days under normal operating conditions, on an annual average basis: <i>Provided</i>, That the sludge in such impoundment does not constitute a hazardous waste as identified by the extraction procedure toxicity characteristic in effect on <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd0c596-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such system utilizes activated sludge treatment in the first portion of secondary treatment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c597-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “underground source or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003522">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003522"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “of”.</note> drinking water” has the same meaning as provided in regulations under the Safe Drinking Water Act (title XIV of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</ref> et seq.]).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd0c598-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6925/j/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The Administrator may modify the requirements of paragraph (1) in the case of a surface impoundment for which the owner or operator, prior to <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, has entered into, and is in compliance with, a consent order, decree, or agreement with the Administrator or a State with an authorized program mandating corrective action with respect to such surface impoundment that provides a degree of protection of human health and the environment which is at a minimum equivalent to that provided by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdd0c599-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s3005">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 3005</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2808">90 Stat. 2808</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/609/s7/h">Pub. L. 95–609, § 7(h)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3082">92 Stat. 3082</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/482">Pub. L. 96–482</ref>, §§ 10, 11, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2338">94 Stat. 2338</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tII">Pub. L. 98–616, title II</ref>, §§ 211–213(a), (c), 214(a), 215, 224(b), 243(c), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3240-3243">98 Stat. 3240–3243</ref>, 3253, 3261; <ref href="/us/pl/104/119/s4/6">Pub. L. 104–119, § 4(6)</ref>, (7), <date date="1996-03-26">Mar. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/833">110 Stat. 833</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdd0c59a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdd0c59b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdd0c59c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/87">Pub. L. 95–87</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/445">91 Stat. 445</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 25 (§ 1201 et seq.) of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1201">section 1201 of Title 30</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Safe Drinking Water Act, referred to in subsec. (j)(12)(C), is title XIV of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, as added <date date="1974-12-16">Dec. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/93/523/s2/a">Pub. L. 93–523, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1660">88 Stat. 1660</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter XII (§ 300f et seq.) of chapter 6A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdd0c59d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/119/s4/6">Pub. L. 104–119, § 4(6)</ref>, substituted “polychlorinated” for “polycholorinated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/119/s4/7">Pub. L. 104–119, § 4(7)</ref>, inserted comma at end of subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s211">Pub. L. 98–616, § 211</ref>, substituted “an existing facility or planning to construct a new” for “a”, inserted “and the construction of any new facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste”, and inserted at end “No permit shall be required under this section in order to construct a facility if such facility is constructed pursuant to an approval issued by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2605/e">section 2605(e) of title 15</ref> for the incineration of polycholorinated [sic] biphenyls and any person owning or operating such a facility may, at any time after operation or construction of such facility has begun, file an application for a permit pursuant to this section authorizing such facility to incinerate hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s213/c">Pub. L. 98–616, § 213(c)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s212">Pub. L. 98–616, § 212</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s213/a">Pub. L. 98–616, § 213(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1), (2), and (3) thereof as subpars. (A), (B), and (C), respectively, designated existing provisions of previously redesignated subpar. (A) as cl. (i) and added cl. (ii), inserted “This paragraph shall not apply to any facility which has been previously denied a permit under this section or if authority to operate the facility under this section has been previously terminated.” to closing provisions of par. (1), and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s214/a">Pub. L. 98–616, § 214(a)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s224/b">Pub. L. 98–616, § 224(b)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s243/c">Pub. L. 98–616, § 243(c)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s215">Pub. L. 98–616, § 215</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s10">Pub. L. 96–482, § 10</ref>, substituted “<date date="1980-11-19">November 19, 1980</date>” for “<date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s11">Pub. L. 96–482, § 11</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/609">Pub. L. 95–609</ref> inserted “treatment, storage, or” after “and after such date the”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbdd0c59e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbdd0c59f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Administrator or other official of Environmental Protection Agency under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903">section 6903 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
