<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdd58154-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6936"><num value="6936">§ 6936.</num><heading> Expansion during interim status</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd58155-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6936/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Waste piles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The owner or operator of a waste pile qualifying for the authorization to operate under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e">section 6925(e) of this title</ref> shall be subject to the same requirements for liners and leachate collection systems or equivalent protection provided in regulations promulgated by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref> before <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, or revised under section 6924(<i>o</i>) of this title (relating to minimum technological requirements), for new facilities receiving individual permits under subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925">section 6925 of this title</ref>, with respect to each new unit, replacement of an existing unit, or lateral expansion of an existing unit that is within the waste management area identified in the permit application submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925">section 6925 of this title</ref>, and with respect to waste received beginning six months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd58156-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6936/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Landfills and surface impoundments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd58157-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6936/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The owner or operator of a landfill or surface impoundment qualifying for the authorization to operate under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925/e">section 6925(e) of this title</ref> shall be subject to the requirements of section 6924(<i>o</i>) of this title (relating to minimum technological requirements), with respect to each new unit, replacement of an existing unit, or lateral expansion of an existing unit that is within the waste management area identified in the permit application submitted under this section, and with respect to waste received beginning 6 months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd58158-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6936/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The owner or operator of each unit referred to in paragraph (1) shall notify the Administrator (or the State, if appropriate) at least sixty days prior to receiving waste. The Administrator (or the State) shall require the filing, within six months of receipt of such notice, of an application for a final determination regarding the issuance of a permit for each facility submitting such notice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd58159-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6936/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the case of any unit in which the liner and leachate collection system has been installed pursuant to the requirements of this section and in good faith compliance with the Administrator’s regulations and guidance documents governing liners and leachate collection systems, no liner or leachate collection system which is different from that which was so installed pursuant to this section shall be required for such unit by the Administrator when issuing the first permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925">section 6925 of this title</ref> to such facility, except that the Administrator shall not be precluded from requiring installation of a new liner when the Administrator has reason to believe that any liner installed pursuant to the requirements of this section is leaking. The Administrator may, under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref>, amend the requirements for liners and leachate collection systems required under this section as may be necessary to provide additional protection for human health and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdd5815a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s3015">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 3015</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tII/s243/a">Pub. L. 98–616, title II, § 243(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3260">98 Stat. 3260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
