<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdd7f1f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e"><num value="6939e">§ 6939e.</num><heading> Federally owned treatment works</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f1f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903/27">section 6903(27) of this title</ref>, the phrase “but does not include solid or dissolved material in domestic sewage” shall apply to any solid or dissolved material introduced by a source into a federally owned treatment works if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd7f1fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such solid or dissolved material is subject to a pretreatment standard under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1317">section 1317 of title 33</ref>, and the source is in compliance with such standard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd7f1fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for a solid or dissolved material for which a pretreatment standard has not been promulgated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1317">section 1317 of title 33</ref>, the Administrator has promulgated a schedule for establishing such a pretreatment standard which would be applicable to such solid or dissolved material not later than 7 years after <date date="1992-10-06">October 6, 1992</date>, such standard is promulgated on or before the date established in the schedule, and after the effective date of such standard the source is in compliance with such standard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd7f1fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> such solid or dissolved material is not covered by paragraph (1) or (2) and is not prohibited from land disposal under subsections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003529">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003529"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be singular.</note> (d), (e), (f), or (g) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924">section 6924 of this title</ref> because such material has been treated in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6924/m">section 6924(m) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd7f1fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> notwithstanding paragraphs <sup>1</sup> (1), (2), or (3), such solid or dissolved material is generated by a household or person which generates less than 100 kilograms of hazardous waste per month unless such solid or dissolved material would otherwise be an acutely hazardous waste and subject to standards, regulations, or other requirements under this chapter notwithstanding the quantity generated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f1fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is unlawful to introduce into a federally owned treatment works any pollutant that is a hazardous waste.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f1ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd7f200-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Actions taken to enforce this section shall not require closure of a treatment works if the hazardous waste is removed or decontaminated and such removal or decontamination is adequate, in the discretion of the Administrator or, in the case of an authorized State, of the State, to protect human health and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd7f201-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent the Administrator or an authorized State from ordering the closure of a treatment works if the Administrator or State determines such closure is necessary for protection of human health and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd7f202-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect any other enforcement authorities available to the Administrator or a State under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f203-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> “Federally owned treatment works” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “federally owned treatment works” means a facility that is owned and operated by a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government treating wastewater, a majority of which is domestic sewage, prior to discharge in accordance with a permit issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342">section 1342 of title 33</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f204-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939e/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting any agreement, permit, or administrative or judicial order, or any condition or requirement contained in such an agreement, permit, or order, that is in existence on <date date="1992-10-06">October 6, 1992</date>, and that requires corrective action or closure at a federally owned treatment works or solid waste management unit or facility related to such a treatment works.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdd7f205-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s3023">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 3023</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/386/tI/s108/a">Pub. L. 102–386, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1514">106 Stat. 1514</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
