<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdd5818b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a"><num value="6939a">§ 6939a.</num><heading> Exposure information and health assessments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd5818c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Exposure information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning on the date nine months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, each application for a final determination regarding a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c">section 6925(c) of this title</ref> for a landfill or surface impoundment shall be accompanied by information reasonably ascertainable by the owner or operator on the potential for the public to be exposed to hazardous wastes or hazardous constituents through releases related to the unit. At a minimum, such information must address:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd5818d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> reasonably foreseeable potential releases from both normal operations and accidents at the unit, including releases associated with transportation to or from the unit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd5818e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the potential pathways of human exposure to hazardous wastes or constituents resulting from the releases described under paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdd5818f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the potential magnitude and nature of the human exposure resulting from such releases.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The owner or operator of a landfill or surface impoundment for which an application for such a final determination under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925/c">section 6925(c) of this title</ref> has been submitted prior to <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, shall submit the information required by this subsection to the Administrator (or the State, in the case of a State with an authorized program) no later than the date nine months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd58190-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Health assessments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd58191-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administrator (or the State, in the case of a State with an authorized program) shall make the information required by subsection (a), together with other relevant information, available to the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry established by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/i">section 9604(i) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdd7f192-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Whenever in the judgment of the Administrator, or the State (in the case of a State with an authorized program), a landfill or a surface impoundment poses a substantial potential risk to human health, due to the existence of releases of hazardous constituents, the magnitude of contamination with hazardous constituents which may be the result of a release, or the magnitude of the population exposed to such release or contamination, the Administrator or the State (with the concurrence of the Administrator) may request the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry to conduct a health assessment in connection with such facility and take other appropriate action with respect to such risks as authorized by section 9604(b) and (i) of this title. If funds are provided in connection with such request the Administrator of such Agency shall conduct such health assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f193-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Members of the public</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any member of the public may submit evidence of releases of or exposure to hazardous constituents from such a facility, or as to the risks or health effects associated with such releases or exposure, to the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, the Administrator, or the State (in the case of a State with an authorized program).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f194-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining the order in which to conduct health assessments under this subsection, the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry shall give priority to those facilities or sites at which there is documented evidence of release of hazardous constituents, at which the potential risk to human health appears highest, and for which in the judgment of the Administrator of such Agency existing health assessment data is inadequate to assess the potential risk to human health as provided in subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f195-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodic reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of such Agency shall issue periodic reports which include the results of all the assessments carried out under this section. Such assessments or other activities shall be reported after appropriate peer review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f196-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> “Health assessments” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “health assessments” shall include preliminary assessments of the potential risk to human health posed by individual sites and facilities subject to this section, based on such factors as the nature and extent of contamination, the existence of potential for pathways of human exposure (including ground or surface water contamination, air emissions, and food chain contamination), the size and potential susceptibility of the community within the likely pathways of exposure, the comparison of expected human exposure levels to the short-term and long-term health effects associated with identified contaminants and any available recommended exposure or tolerance limits for such contaminants, and the comparison of existing morbidity and mortality data on diseases that may be associated with the observed levels of exposure. The assessment shall include an evaluation of the risks to the potentially affected population from all sources of such contaminants, including known point or nonpoint sources other than the site or facility in question. A purpose of such preliminary assessments shall be to help determine whether full-scale health or epidemiological studies and medical evaluations of exposed populations shall be undertaken.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdd7f197-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6939a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost recovery</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any case in which a health assessment performed under this section discloses the exposure of a population to the release of a hazardous substance, the costs of such health assessment may be recovered as a cost of response under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607">section 9607 of this title</ref> from persons causing or contributing to such release of such hazardous substance or, in the case of multiple releases contributing to such exposure, to all such release.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdd7f198-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s3019">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 3019</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tII/s247/a">Pub. L. 98–616, title II, § 247(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3265">98 Stat. 3265</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
