<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdda62b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6941a"><num value="6941a">§ 6941a.</num><heading> Energy and materials conservation and recovery; Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdda62ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6941a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> significant savings could be realized by conserving materials in order to reduce the volume or quantity of material which ultimately becomes waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdda62bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6941a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> solid waste contains valuable energy and material resources which can be recovered and used thereby conserving increasingly scarce and expensive fossil fuels and virgin materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdda62bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6941a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the recovery of energy and materials from municipal waste, and the conservation of energy and materials contributing to such waste streams, can have the effect of reducing the volume of the municipal waste stream and the burden of disposing of increasing volumes of solid waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdda62bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6941a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the technology to conserve resources exists and is commercially feasible to apply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdda62be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6941a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the technology to recover energy and materials from solid waste is of demonstrated commercial feasibility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdda62bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6941a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> various communities throughout the nation have different needs and different potentials for conserving resources and for utilizing techniques for the recovery of energy and materials from waste, and Federal assistance in planning and implementing such energy and materials conservation and recovery programs should be available to all such communities on an equitable basis in relation to their needs and potential.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbdda62c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s32/a">Pub. L. 96–482, § 32(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2353">94 Stat. 2353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdda62c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdda62c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbdda62c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Solid Waste Disposal Act Amendments of 1980, and not as part of the Solid Waste Disposal Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
