<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdda6307-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945"><num value="6945">§ 6945.</num><heading> Upgrading of open dumps</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6308-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Closing or upgrading of existing open dumps</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon promulgation of criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6907/a/3">section 6907(a)(3) of this title</ref>, any solid waste management practice or disposal of solid waste or hazardous waste which constitutes the open dumping of solid waste or hazardous waste is prohibited, except in the case of any practice or disposal of solid waste under a timetable or schedule for compliance established under this section. The prohibition contained in the preceding sentence shall be enforceable under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6972">section 6972 of this title</ref> against persons engaged in the act of open dumping. For purposes of complying with section 6943(a)(2) and 6943(a)(3) of this title, each State plan shall contain a requirement that all existing disposal facilities or sites for solid waste in such State which are open dumps listed in the inventory under subsection (b) shall comply with such measures as may be promulgated by the Administrator to eliminate health hazards and minimize potential health hazards. Each such plan shall establish, for any entity which demonstrates that it has considered other public or private alternatives for solid waste management to comply with the prohibition on open dumping and is unable to utilize such alternatives to so comply, a timetable or schedule for compliance for such practice or disposal of solid waste which specifies a schedule of remedial measures, including an enforceable sequence of actions or operations, leading to compliance with the prohibition on open dumping of solid waste within a reasonable time (not to exceed 5 years from the date of publication of criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6907/a/3">section 6907(a)(3) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6309-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Inventory</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To assist the States in complying with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943/a/3">section 6943(a)(3) of this title</ref>, not later than one year after promulgation of regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6944">section 6944 of this title</ref>, the Administrator, with the cooperation of the Bureau of the Census shall publish an inventory of all disposal facilities or sites in the United States which are open dumps within the meaning of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda630a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Control of hazardous disposal</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdda630b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdda630c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than 36 months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, each State shall adopt and implement a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions to assure that each solid waste management facility within such State which may receive hazardous household waste or hazardous waste due to the provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6921/d">section 6921(d) of this title</ref> for small quantity generators (otherwise not subject to the requirement for a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925">section 6925 of this title</ref>) will comply with the applicable criteria promulgated under section 6944(a) and 6907(a)(3) of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdda630d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Not later than eighteen months after the promulgation of revised criteria under subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003531">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003531"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> 6944(a) of this title (as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c">section 6949a(c) of this title</ref>), each State shall adopt and implement a permit program or other system or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003532">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003532"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “of”.</note> prior approval and conditions, to assure that each solid waste management facility within such State which may receive hazardous household waste or hazardous waste due to the provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6921/d">section 6921(d) of this title</ref> for small quantity generators (otherwise not subject to the requirement for a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925">section 6925 of this title</ref>) will comply with the criteria revised under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6944/a">section 6944(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdda630e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Administrator shall determine whether each State has developed an adequate program under this paragraph. The Administrator may make such a determination in conjunction with approval, disapproval or partial approval of a State plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6947">section 6947 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdda630f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdda6310-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In any State that the Administrator determines has not adopted an adequate program for such facilities under paragraph (1)(B) by the date provided in such paragraph, the Administrator may use the authorities available under sections 6927 and 6928 of this title to enforce the prohibition contained in subsection (a) of this section with respect to such facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdda6311-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “requirement of this subchapter” in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6928">section 6928 of this title</ref> shall be deemed to include criteria promulgated by the Administrator under sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title, and the term “hazardous wastes” in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6927">section 6927 of this title</ref> shall be deemed to include solid waste at facilities that may handle hazardous household wastes or hazardous wastes from small quantity generators.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6312-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> State programs for control of coal combustion residuals</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6313-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval by Administrator</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6314-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each State may submit to the Administrator, in such form as the Administrator may establish, evidence of a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under State law for regulation by the State of coal combustion residuals units that are located in the State that, after approval by the Administrator, will operate in lieu of regulation of coal combustion residuals units in the State by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda6315-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> application of part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda6316-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> implementation by the Administrator of a permit program under paragraph (2)(B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6317-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after the date on which a State submits the evidence described in subparagraph (A), the Administrator, after public notice and an opportunity for public comment, shall approve, in whole or in part, a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions submitted under subparagraph (A) if the Administrator determines that the program or other system requires each coal combustion residuals unit located in the State to achieve compliance with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda6318-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the applicable criteria for coal combustion residuals units under part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda6319-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such other State criteria that the Administrator, after consultation with the State, determines to be at least as protective as the criteria described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda631a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator shall approve under subparagraph (B)(ii) a State permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions that allows a State to include technical standards for individual permits or conditions of approval that differ from the criteria under part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title) if, based on site-specific conditions, the Administrator determines that the technical standards established pursuant to a State permit program or other system are at least as protective as the criteria under that part.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda631b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Program review and notification</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda631c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Program review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Administrator shall review a State permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions that is approved under subparagraph (B)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda631d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> from time to time, as the Administrator determines necessary, but not less frequently than once every 12 years;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda631e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> not later than 3 years after the date on which the Administrator revises the applicable criteria for coal combustion residuals units under part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda631f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> not later than 1 year after the date of a significant release (as defined by the Administrator), that was not authorized at the time the release occurred, from a coal combustion residuals unit located in the State; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda6320-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> on request of any other State that asserts that the soil, groundwater, or surface water of the State is or is likely to be adversely affected by a release or potential release from a coal combustion residuals unit located in the State for which the program or other system was approved.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6321-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification and opportunity for a public hearing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Administrator shall provide to a State notice of deficiencies with respect to the permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions of the State that is approved under subparagraph (B), and an opportunity for a public hearing, if the Administrator determines that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda6322-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a revision or correction to the permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions of the State is necessary to ensure that the permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions continues to ensure that each coal combustion residuals unit located in the State achieves compliance with the criteria described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (B);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda6323-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the State has not implemented an adequate permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions that requires each coal combustion residuals unit located in the State to achieve compliance with the criteria described in subparagraph (B); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda6324-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/D/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the State has, at any time, approved or failed to revoke a permit for a coal combustion residuals unit, a release from which adversely affects or is likely to adversely affect the soil, groundwater, or surface water of another State.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6325-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawal</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6326-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Administrator shall withdraw approval of a State permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions if, after the Administrator provides notice and an opportunity for a public hearing to the relevant State under subparagraph (D)(ii), the Administrator determines that the State has not corrected the deficiencies identified by the Administrator under subparagraph (D)(ii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6327-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/1/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Reinstatement of State approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Any withdrawal of approval under clause (i) shall cease to be effective on the date on which the Administrator makes a determination that the State has corrected the deficiencies identified by the Administrator under subparagraph (D)(ii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6328-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonparticipating states</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6329-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of nonparticipating State</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “nonparticipating State” means a State—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda632a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for which the Administrator has not approved a State permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under paragraph (1)(B);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda632b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Governor of which has not submitted to the Administrator for approval evidence to operate a State permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under paragraph (1)(A);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda632c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the Governor of which provides notice to the Administrator that, not fewer than 90 days after the date on which the Governor provides the notice to the Administrator, the State will relinquish an approval under paragraph (1)(B) to operate a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda632d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> for which the Administrator has withdrawn approval for a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under paragraph (1)(E).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda632e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation of permit program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a nonparticipating State and subject to the availability of appropriations specifically provided in an appropriations Act to carry out a program in a nonparticipating State, the Administrator shall implement a permit program to require each coal combustion residuals unit located in the nonparticipating State to achieve compliance with applicable criteria established by the Administrator under part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda632f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The applicable criteria for coal combustion residuals units under part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title), shall apply to each coal combustion residuals unit in a State unless—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdda6330-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a permit under a State permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions approved by the Administrator under paragraph (1)(B) is in effect for the coal combustion residuals unit; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdda6331-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a permit issued by the Administrator in a State in which the Administrator is implementing a permit program under paragraph (2)(B) is in effect for the coal combustion residuals unit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6332-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on open dumping</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6333-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator may use the authority provided by sections 6927 and 6928 of this title to enforce the prohibition on open dumping under subsection (a) with respect to a coal combustion residuals unit—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda6334-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in a nonparticipating State (as defined in paragraph (2)); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbdda6335-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> located in a State that is approved to operate a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under paragraph (1)(B), in accordance with subparagraph (B) of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6336-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal enforcement in an approved State</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda6337-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of a coal combustion residuals unit located in a State that is approved to operate a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under paragraph (1)(B), the Administrator may commence an administrative or judicial enforcement action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6928">section 6928 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda6338-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the State requests that the Administrator provide assistance in the performance of an enforcement action; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbdda6339-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> after consideration of any other administrative or judicial enforcement action involving the coal combustion residuals unit, the Administrator determines that an enforcement action is likely to be necessary to ensure that the coal combustion residuals unit is operating in accordance with the criteria established under the permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda633a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of an enforcement action by the Administrator under clause (i)(II), before issuing an order or commencing a civil action, the Administrator shall notify the State in which the coal combustion residuals unit is located.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda633b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report to Congress</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda633c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Subject to subclause (II), not later than <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>, and December 31 of each year thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that describes any enforcement action commenced under clause (i), including a description of the basis for the enforcement action.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda633d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/4/B/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Subclause (I) shall not apply for any calendar year during which the Administrator does not commence an enforcement action under clause (i).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdda633e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Indian country</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall establish and carry out a permit program, in accordance with this subsection, for coal combustion residuals units in Indian country (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1151">section 1151 of title 18</ref>) to require each coal combustion residuals unit located in Indian country to achieve compliance with the applicable criteria established by the Administrator under part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcac2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of coal combustion residuals units</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A coal combustion residuals unit shall be considered to be a sanitary landfill for purposes of this chapter, including subsection (a), only if the coal combustion residuals unit is operating in accordance with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbddcac30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the requirements of a permit issued by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbddcac31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the State in accordance with a program or system approved under paragraph (1)(B); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbddcac32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Administrator pursuant to paragraph (2)(B) or paragraph (5); or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbddcac33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the applicable criteria for coal combustion residuals units under part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations promulgated pursuant to sections 6907(a)(3) and 6944(a) of this title).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcac34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6945/d/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of subsection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection affects any authority, regulatory determination, other law, or legal obligation in effect on the day before <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbddcac35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s4005">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 4005</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2815">90 Stat. 2815</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s19/a">Pub. L. 96–482, § 19(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2345">94 Stat. 2345</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tIII/s302/c">Pub. L. 98–616, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, title IV, § 403(c), title V, § 502(c), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3268">98 Stat. 3268</ref>, 3272, 3276; <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/tII/s2301">Pub. L. 114–322, title II, § 2301</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1736">130 Stat. 1736</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbddcac36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbddcac37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbddcac38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s19/b">section 19(b) of Pub. L. 96–482</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6946">section 6946 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbddcac39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322">Pub. L. 114–322</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s403/c">Pub. L. 98–616, § 403(c)</ref>, inserted after first sentence “The prohibition contained in the preceding sentence shall be enforceable under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6972">section 6972 of this title</ref> against persons engaged in the act of open dumping.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s502/c">Pub. L. 98–616, § 502(c)</ref>, inserted a closing parenthesis before the period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s302/c">Pub. L. 98–616, § 302(c)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s19/a">Pub. L. 96–482, § 19(a)</ref>, (b)(1), struck out subsec. (a) which defined “open dump”, which is covered in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903/14">section 6903(14) of this title</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (a) and substituted “Upon promulgation of criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6907/a/3">section 6907(a)(3) of this title</ref>, any” for “Any”, “section 6943(a)(2) and 6943(a)(3) of this title” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943/2">section 6943(2) of this title</ref>”, and “criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6907/a/3">section 6907(a)(3) of this title</ref>” for “the inventory under subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s19/b/1">section 19(b)(1) of Pub. L. 96–482</ref>, directing that following reference to “4003(2)”, which had been editorially translated as <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943/2">section 6943(2) of this title</ref>, the phrase “and 4003(3)” be inserted, was executed by translating “4003(2) and 4003(3)” as section 6943(a)(2) and 6943(a)(3) of this title, in view of the designation of the existing provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943">section 6943 of this title</ref> as subsec. (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943">section 6943 of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/96/463/s5/b">section 5(b) of Pub. L. 96–463</ref> and also by <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s32/d/2">section 32(d)(2) of Pub. L. 96–482</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s19/b/2">Pub. L. 96–482, § 19(b)(2)</ref>, inserted introductory phrase “To assist the States in complying with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943/a/3">section 6943(a)(3) of this title</ref>”. Amendment referring to section “4003(3)” was executed by translating “4003(3)” as <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943/a/3">section 6943(a)(3) of this title</ref>, in view of the designation of the existing provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943">section 6943 of this title</ref> as subsec. (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6943">section 6943 of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/96/463/s5/b">section 5(b) of Pub. L. 96–463</ref> and also by <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s32/d/2">section 32(d)(2) of Pub. L. 96–482</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s19/a">Pub. L. 96–482, § 19(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (a).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbddcac3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbddcac3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Administrator or other official of Environmental Protection Agency under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903">section 6903 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
