<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbddcaca1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a"><num value="6949a">§ 6949a.</num><heading> Adequacy of certain guidelines and criteria</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcaca2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall conduct a study of the extent to which the guidelines and criteria under this chapter (other than guidelines and criteria for facilities to which subchapter III applies) which are applicable to solid waste management and disposal facilities, including, but not limited to landfills and surface impoundments, are adequate to protect human health and the environment from ground water contamination. Such study shall include a detailed assessment of the degree to which the criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6907/a">section 6907(a) of this title</ref> and the criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6944">section 6944 of this title</ref> regarding monitoring, prevention of contamination, and remedial action are adequate to protect ground water and shall also include recommendation with respect to any additional enforcement authorities which the Administrator, in consultation with the Attorney General, deems necessary for such purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcaca3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than thirty-six months after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Congress setting forth the results of the study required under this section, together with any recommendations made by the Administrator on the basis of such study.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcaca4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Revisions of guidelines and criteria</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcaca5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1988-03-31">March 31, 1988</date>, the Administrator shall promulgate revisions of the criteria promulgated under paragraph (1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6944/a">section 6944(a) of this title</ref> and under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6907/a/3">section 6907(a)(3) of this title</ref> for facilities that may receive hazardous household wastes or hazardous wastes from small quantity generators under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6921/d">section 6921(d) of this title</ref>. The criteria shall be those necessary to protect human health and the environment and may take into account the practicable capability of such facilities. At a minimum such revisions for facilities potentially receiving such wastes should require ground water monitoring as necessary to detect contamination, establish criteria for the acceptable location of new or existing facilities, and provide for corrective action as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcaca6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional revisions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (3), the requirements of the criteria described in paragraph (1) relating to ground water monitoring shall not apply to an owner or operator of a new municipal solid waste landfill unit, an existing municipal solid waste landfill unit, or a lateral expansion of a municipal solid waste landfill unit, that disposes of less than 20 tons of municipal solid waste daily, based on an annual average, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbddcaca7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> there is no evidence of ground water contamination from the municipal solid waste landfill unit or expansion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbddcaca8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the municipal solid waste landfill unit or expansion serves—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbddcaca9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a community that experiences an annual interruption of at least 3 consecutive months of surface transportation that prevents access to a regional waste management facility; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbddcacaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a community that has no practicable waste management alternative and the landfill unit is located in an area that annually receives less than or equal to 25 inches of precipitation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of ground water resources</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State may require ground water monitoring of a solid waste landfill unit that would otherwise be exempt under paragraph (2) if necessary to protect ground water resources and ensure compliance with a State ground water protection plan, where applicable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Methods</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a State requires ground water monitoring of a solid waste landfill unit under subparagraph (A), the State may allow the use of a method other than the use of ground water monitoring wells to detect a release of contamination from the unit.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Corrective action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a State finds a release from a solid waste landfill unit, the State shall require corrective action as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> No-migration exemption</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Ground water monitoring requirements may be suspended by the Director of an approved State for a landfill operator if the operator demonstrates that there is no potential for migration of hazardous constituents from the unit to the uppermost aquifer during the active life of the unit and the post-closure care period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacb1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A demonstration under subparagraph (A) shall be certified by a qualified ground-water scientist and approved by the Director of an approved State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacb2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 6 months after <date date="1996-03-26">March 26, 1996</date>, the Administrator shall issue a guidance document to facilitate small community use of the no migration <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003536">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003536"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “no-migration”.</note> exemption under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Alaska Native villages</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon certification by the Governor of the State of Alaska that application of the requirements described in paragraph (1) to a solid waste landfill unit of a Native village (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602">section 1602 of title 43</ref>) or unit that is located in or near a small, remote Alaska village would be infeasible, or would not be cost-effective, or is otherwise inappropriate because of the remote location of the unit, the State may exempt the unit from some or all of those requirements. This paragraph shall apply only to solid waste landfill units that dispose of less than 20 tons of municipal solid waste daily, based on an annual average.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbddcacb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Further revisions of guidelines and criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Recognizing the unique circumstances of small communities, the Administrator shall, not later than two years after <date date="1996-03-26">March 26, 1996</date>, promulgate revisions to the guidelines and criteria promulgated under this subchapter to provide additional flexibility to approved States to allow landfills that receive 20 tons or less of municipal solid waste per day, based on an annual average, to use alternative frequencies of daily cover application, frequencies of methane gas monitoring, infiltration layers for final cover, and means for demonstrating financial assurance: <i>Provided</i>, That such alternative requirements take into account climatic and hydrogeologic conditions and are protective of human health and environment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbddcacb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s4010">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 4010</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tIII/s302/a/1">Pub. L. 98–616, title III, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3267">98 Stat. 3267</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/119/s3/a">Pub. L. 104–119, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-03-26">Mar. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/831">110 Stat. 831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbddcacb6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbddcacb7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbddcacb8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/119">Pub. L. 104–119</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted heading, and added pars. (2) to (6).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbddcacb9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbddcacba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reinstatement of Regulatory Exemption</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/119/s3/b">Pub. L. 104–119, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-03-26">Mar. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/833">110 Stat. 833</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/119/s3/b">“It is the intent of section 4010(c)(2) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6949a/c/2">42 U.S.C. 6949a(c)(2)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), to immediately reinstate subpart E of part 258 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, as added by the final rule published at 56 Federal Register 50798 on <date date="1991-10-09">October 9, 1991</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
