<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbddcacc2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6952"><num value="6952">§ 6952.</num><heading> Development of specifications for secondary materials</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and in conjunction with national standards-setting organizations in resource recovery, shall, after public hearings, and not later than two years after <date date="1979-09-01">September 1, 1979</date>, publish guidelines for the development of specifications for the classification of materials recovered from waste which were destined for disposal. The specifications shall pertain to the physical and chemical properties and characteristics of such materials with regard to their use in replacing virgin materials in various industrial, commercial, and governmental uses. In establishing such guidelines the Secretary shall also, to the extent feasible, provide such information as may be necessary to assist Federal agencies with procurement of items containing recovered materials. The Secretary shall continue to cooperate with national standards-setting organizations, as may be necessary, to encourage the publication, promulgation and updating of standards for recovered materials and for the use of recovered materials in various industrial, commercial, and governmental uses.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbddcacc3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s5002">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 5002</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2820">90 Stat. 2820</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s21/a">Pub. L. 96–482, § 21(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2346">94 Stat. 2346</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbddcacc4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbddcacc5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbddcacc6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/482">Pub. L. 96–482</ref> substituted “<date date="1979-09-01">September 1, 1979</date>” for “<date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
