<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbde16801-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971"><num value="6971">§ 6971.</num><heading> Employee protection</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16802-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall fire, or in any other way discriminate against, or cause to be fired or discriminated against, any employee or any authorized representative of employees by reason of the fact that such employee or representative has filed, instituted, or caused to be filed or instituted any proceeding under this chapter or under any applicable implementation plan, or has testified or is about to testify in any proceeding resulting from the administration or enforcement of the provisions of this chapter or of any applicable implementation plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16803-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any employee or a representative of employees who believes that he has been fired or otherwise discriminated against by any person in violation of subsection (a) of this section may, within thirty days after such alleged violation occurs, apply to the Secretary of Labor for a review of such firing or alleged discrimination. A copy of the application shall be sent to such person who shall be the respondent. Upon receipt of such application, the Secretary of Labor shall cause such investigation to be made as he deems appropriate. Such investigation shall provide an opportunity for a public hearing at the request of any party to such review to enable the parties to present information relating to such alleged violation. The parties shall be given written notice of the time and place of the hearing at least five days prior to the hearing. Any such hearing shall be of record and shall be subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref>. Upon receiving the report of such investigation, the Secretary of Labor shall make findings of fact. If he finds that such violation did occur, he shall issue a decision, incorporating an order therein and his findings, requiring the party committing such violation to take such affirmative action to abate the violation as the Secretary of Labor deems appropriate, including, but not limited to, the rehiring or reinstatement of the employee or representative of employees to his former position with compensation. If he finds that there was no such violation, he shall issue an order denying the application. Such order issued by the Secretary of Labor under this subparagraph shall be subject to judicial review in the same manner as orders and decisions of the Administrator or subject to judicial review under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16804-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever an order is issued under this section to abate such violation, at the request of the applicant, a sum equal to the aggregate amount of all costs and expenses (including the attorney’s fees) as determined by the Secretary of Labor, to have been reasonably incurred by the applicant for, or in connection with, the institution and prosecution of such proceedings, shall be assessed against the person committing such violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16805-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall have no application to any employee who, acting without direction from his employer (or his agent) deliberately violates any requirement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16806-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment shifts and loss</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall conduct continuing evaluations of potential loss or shifts of employment which may result from the administration or enforcement of the provisions of this chapter and applicable implementation plans, including, where appropriate, investigating threatened plant closures or reductions in employment allegedly resulting from such administration or enforcement. Any employee who is discharged, or laid off, threatened with discharge or layoff, or otherwise discriminated against by any person because of the alleged results of such administration or enforcement, or any representative of such employee, may request the Administrator to conduct a full investigation of the matter. The Administrator shall thereupon investigate the matter and, at the request of any party, shall hold public hearings on not less than five days’ notice, and shall at such hearings require the parties, including the employer involved, to present information relating to the actual or potential effect of such administration or enforcement on employment and on any alleged discharge, layoff, or other discrimination and the detailed reasons or justification therefor. Any such hearing shall be of record and shall be subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref>. Upon receiving the report of such investigation, the Administrator shall make findings of fact as to the effect of such administration or enforcement on employment and on the alleged discharge, layoff, or discrimination and shall make such recommendations as he deems appropriate. Such report, findings, and recommendations shall be available to the public. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require or authorize the Administrator or any State to modify or withdraw any standard, limitation, or any other requirement of this chapter or any applicable implementation plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16807-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Occupational safety and health</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to assist the Secretary of Labor and the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health in carrying out their duties under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.], the Administrator shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16808-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> provide the following information, as such information becomes available, to the Secretary and the Director:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbde16809-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the identity of any hazardous waste generation, treatment, storage, disposal facility or site where cleanup is planned or underway;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbde1680a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information identifying the hazards to which persons working at a hazardous waste generation, treatment, storage, disposal facility or site or otherwise handling hazardous waste may be exposed, the nature and extent of the exposure, and methods to protect workers from such hazards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbde1680b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> incidents of worker injury or harm at a hazardous waste generation, treatment, storage or disposal facility or site; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde1680c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6971/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> notify the Secretary and the Director of the Administrator’s receipt of notifications under section 6930 or reports under sections 6922, 6923, and 6924 of this title and make such notifications and reports available to the Secretary and the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbde1680d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s7001">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 7001</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2824">90 Stat. 2824</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s24">Pub. L. 96–482, § 24</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2347">94 Stat. 2347</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbde1680e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbde1680f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbde16810-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/596">Pub. L. 91–596</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1590">84 Stat. 1590</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 651 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">section 651 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbde16811-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/482">Pub. L. 96–482</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbde16812-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbde16813-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Administrator or other official of Environmental Protection Agency under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903">section 6903 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
