<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbde16814-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972"><num value="6972">§ 6972.</num><heading> Citizen suits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16815-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b) or (c) of this section, any person may commence a civil action on his own behalf—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16816-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16817-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> against any person (including (a) the United States, and (b) any other governmental instrumentality or agency, to the extent permitted by the eleventh amendment to the Constitution) who is alleged to be in violation of any permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, prohibition, or order which has become effective pursuant to this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16818-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> against any person, including the United States and any other governmental instrumentality or agency, to the extent permitted by the eleventh amendment to the Constitution, and including any past or present generator, past or present transporter, or past or present owner or operator of a treatment, storage, or disposal facility, who has contributed or who is contributing to the past or present handling, storage, treatment, transportation, or disposal of any solid or hazardous waste which may present an imminent and substantial endangerment to health or the environment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16819-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> against the Administrator where there is alleged a failure of the Administrator to perform any act or duty under this chapter which is not discretionary with the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any action under paragraph (a)(1) of this subsection shall be brought in the district court for the district in which the alleged violation occurred or the alleged endangerment may occur. Any action brought under paragraph (a)(2) of this subsection may be brought in the district court for the district in which the alleged violation occurred or in the District Court of the District of Columbia. The district court shall have jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties, to enforce the permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, prohibition, or order, referred to in paragraph (1)(A), to restrain any person who has contributed or who is contributing to the past or present handling, storage, treatment, transportation, or disposal of any solid or hazardous waste referred to in paragraph (1)(B), to order such person to take such other action as may be necessary, or both, or to order the Administrator to perform the act or duty referred to in paragraph (2), as the case may be, and to apply any appropriate civil penalties under section 6928(a) and (g) of this title.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde1681a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions prohibited</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde1681b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> No action may be commenced under subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde1681c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> prior to 60 days after the plaintiff has given notice of the violation to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbde1681d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Administrator;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbde1681e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the State in which the alleged violation occurs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbde1681f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to any alleged violator of such permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, prohibition, or order,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that such action may be brought immediately after such notification in the case of an action under this section respecting a violation of subchapter III of this chapter; or</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16820-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the Administrator or State has commenced and is diligently prosecuting a civil or criminal action in a court of the United States or a State to require compliance with such permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, prohibition, or order.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In any action under subsection (a)(1)(A) in a court of the United States, any person may intervene as a matter of right.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde16821-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde16822-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> No action may be commenced under subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section prior to ninety days after the plaintiff has given notice of the endangerment to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16823-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Administrator;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16824-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the State in which the alleged endangerment may occur;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16825-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any person alleged to have contributed or to be contributing to the past or present handling, storage, treatment, transportation, or disposal of any solid or hazardous waste referred to in subsection (a)(1)(B),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that such action may be brought immediately after such notification in the case of an action under this section respecting a violation of subchapter III of this chapter.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde16826-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> No action may be commenced under subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section if the Administrator, in order to restrain or abate acts or conditions which may have contributed or are contributing to the activities which may present the alleged endangerment—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16827-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has commenced and is diligently prosecuting an action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6973">section 6973 of this title</ref> or under section 106 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">42 U.S.C. 9606</ref>],<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003537">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003537"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should be a semicolon.</note></content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16828-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is actually engaging in a removal action under section 104 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">42 U.S.C. 9604</ref>];</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde16829-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> has incurred costs to initiate a Remedial Investigation and Feasibility Study under section 104 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">42 U.S.C. 9604</ref>] and is diligently proceeding with a remedial action under that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde1682a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> has obtained a court order (including a consent decree) or issued an administrative order under section 106 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 980 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003538">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003538"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “1980”.</note> [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">42 U.S.C. 9606</ref>] or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6973">section 6973 of this title</ref> pursuant to which a responsible party is diligently conducting a removal action, Remedial Investigation and Feasibility Study (RIFS), or proceeding with a remedial action.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of an administrative order referred to in clause (iv), actions under subsection (a)(1)(B) are prohibited only as to the scope and duration of the administrative order referred to in clause (iv).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde1682b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> No action may be commenced under subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section if the State, in order to restrain or abate acts or conditions which may have contributed or are contributing to the activities which may present the alleged endangerment—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde1682c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has commenced and is diligently prosecuting an action under subsection (a)(1)(B);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde1682d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is actually engaging in a removal action under section 104 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">42 U.S.C. 9604</ref>]; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde1682e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> has incurred costs to initiate a Remedial Investigation and Feasibility Study under section 104 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">42 U.S.C. 9604</ref>] and is diligently proceeding with a remedial action under that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.].</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde1682f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> No action may be commenced under subsection (a)(1)(B) by any person (other than a State or local government) with respect to the siting of a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or a disposal facility, nor to restrain or enjoin the issuance of a permit for such facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde16830-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> In any action under subsection (a)(1)(B) in a court of the United States, any person may intervene as a matter of right when the applicant claims an interest relating to the subject of the action and he is so situated that the disposition of the action may, as a practical matter, impair or impede his ability to protect that interest, unless the Administrator or the State shows that the applicant’s interest is adequately represented by existing parties.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde16831-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Whenever any action is brought under subsection (a)(1)(B) in a court of the United States, the plaintiff shall serve a copy of the complaint on the Attorney General of the United States and with the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16832-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No action may be commenced under paragraph (a)(2) of this section prior to sixty days after the plaintiff has given notice to the Administrator that he will commence such action, except that such action may be brought immediately after such notification in the case of an action under this section respecting a violation of subchapter III. Notice under this subsection shall be given in such manner as the Administrator shall prescribe by regulation. Any action respecting a violation under this chapter may be brought under this section only in the judicial district in which such alleged violation occurs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16833-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Intervention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any action under this section the Administrator, if not a party, may intervene as a matter of right.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16834-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The court, in issuing any final order in any action brought pursuant to this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6976">section 6976 of this title</ref>, may award costs of litigation (including reasonable attorney and expert witness fees) to the prevailing or substantially prevailing party, whenever the court determines such an award is appropriate. The court may, if a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction is sought, require the filing of a bond or equivalent security in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16835-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Other rights preserved</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall restrict any right which any person (or class of persons) may have under any statute or common law to seek enforcement of any standard or requirement relating to the management of solid waste or hazardous waste, or to seek any other relief (including relief against the Administrator or a State agency).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde16836-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6972/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Transporters</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A transporter shall not be deemed to have contributed or to be contributing to the handling, storage, treatment, or disposal, referred to in subsection (a)(1)(B) taking place after such solid waste or hazardous waste has left the possession or control of such transporter, if the transportation of such waste was under a sole contractual arrangement arising from a published tariff and acceptance for carriage by common carrier by rail and such transporter has exercised due care in the past or present handling, storage, treatment, transportation and disposal of such waste.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbde16837-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s7002">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 7002</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2825">90 Stat. 2825</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/609/s7/p">Pub. L. 95–609, § 7(p)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3083">92 Stat. 3083</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 98–616, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3268">98 Stat. 3268</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbde16838-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbde16839-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbde1683a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">That Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(B)(iii), (C)(iii), means <ref href="/us/pl/96/510">Pub. L. 96–510</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2767">94 Stat. 2767</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, which is classified principally to chapter 103 (§ 9601 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">section 9601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, referred to in subsec. (e), are set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbde1683b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s401/a">Pub. L. 98–616, § 401(a)</ref>, (b), designated existing provisions of subsec. (a)(1) as subpar. (A) thereof, inserted “prohibition,” after “requirement,”, added subpar. (B), and in provisions following par. (2) inserted “or the alleged endangerment may occur” in first sentence and substituted “to enforce the permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, prohibition, or order, referred to in paragraph (1)(A), to restrain any person who has contributed or who is contributing to the past or present handling, storage, treatment, transportation, or disposal of any solid or hazardous waste referred to in paragraph (1)(B), to order such person to take such other action as may be necessary, or both, or to order the Administrator to perform the act or duty referred to in paragraph (2), as the case may be, and to apply any appropriate civil penalties under section 6928(a) and (g) of this title” for “to enforce such regulation or order, or to order the Administrator to perform such act or duty as the case may be”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s401/d">Pub. L. 98–616, § 401(d)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “No action may be commenced under paragraph (a)(1) of this section—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) prior to sixty days after the plaintiff has given notice of the violation (A) to the Administrator; (B) to the State in which the alleged violation occurs; and (C) to any alleged violator of such permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, or order; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) if the Administrator or State has commenced and is diligently prosecuting a civil or criminal action in a court of the United States or a State to require compliance with such permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, or order: <i>Provided, however</i>, That in any such action in a court of the United States, any person may intervene as a matter of right.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s401/e">Pub. L. 98–616, § 401(e)</ref>, substituted “to the prevailing or substantially prevailing party” for “to any party” and inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6976">section 6976 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/s401/c">Pub. L. 98–616, § 401(c)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/609/s7/p/1">Pub. L. 95–609, § 7(p)(1)</ref>, substituted “subchapter III” for “section 212 of this Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/609/s7/p/2">Pub. L. 95–609, § 7(p)(2)</ref>, substituted “require” for “requiring”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbde1683c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbde1683d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Administrator or other official of Environmental Protection Agency under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903">section 6903 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
