<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbde3d84a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6974"><num value="6974">§ 6974.</num><heading> Petition for regulations; public participation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde3d84b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6974/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person may petition the Administrator for the promulgation, amendment, or repeal of any regulation under this chapter. Within a reasonable time following receipt of such petition, the Administrator shall take action with respect to such petition and shall publish notice of such action in the Federal Register, together with the reasons therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde3d84c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6974/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde3d84d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6974/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Public participation in the development, revision, implementation, and enforcement of any regulation, guideline, information, or program under this chapter shall be provided for, encouraged, and assisted by the Administrator and the States. The Administrator, in cooperation with the States, shall develop and publish minimum guidelines for public participation in such processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde3d84e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6974/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Before the issuing of a permit to any person with any respect to any facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous wastes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925">section 6925 of this title</ref>, the Administrator shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde3d84f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6974/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> cause to be published in major local newspapers of general circulation and broadcast over local radio stations notice of the agency’s intention to issue such permit, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde3d850-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6974/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> transmit in writing notice of the agency’s intention to issue such permit to each unit of local government having jurisdiction over the area in which such facility is proposed to be located and to each State agency having any authority under State law with respect to the construction or operation of such facility.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If within 45 days the Administrator receives written notice of opposition to the agency’s intention to issue such permit and a request for a hearing, or if the Administrator determines on his own initiative, he shall hold an informal public hearing (including an opportunity for presentation of written and oral views) on whether he should issue a permit for the proposed facility. Whenever possible the Administrator shall schedule such hearing at a location convenient to the nearest population center to such proposed facility and give notice in the aforementioned manner of the date, time, and subject matter of such hearing. No State program which provides for the issuance of permits referred to in this paragraph may be authorized by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6926">section 6926 of this title</ref> unless such program provides for the notice and hearing required by the paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbde3d851-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s7004">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 7004</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2826">90 Stat. 2826</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/482/s26">Pub. L. 96–482, § 26</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2348">94 Stat. 2348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbde3d852-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbde3d853-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbde3d854-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/482">Pub. L. 96–482</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbde3d855-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbde3d856-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Administrator or other official of Environmental Protection Agency under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903">section 6903 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
