<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbde64a38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984"><num value="6984">§ 6984.</num><heading> Full-scale demonstration facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde64a39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may enter into contracts with public agencies or authorities or private persons for the construction and operation of a full-scale demonstration facility under this chapter, or provide financial assistance in the form of grants to a full-scale demonstration facility under this chapter only if the Administrator finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde64a3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such facility or proposed facility will demonstrate at full scale a new or significantly improved technology or process, a practical and significant improvement in solid waste management practice, or the technological feasibility and cost effectiveness of an existing, but unproven technology, process, or practice, and will not duplicate any other Federal, State, local, or commercial facility which has been constructed or with respect to which construction has begun (determined as of the date action is taken by the Administrator under this chapter),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde64a3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such contract or assistance meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6981">section 6981 of this title</ref> and meets other applicable requirements of this chapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde64a3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> such facility will be able to comply with the guidelines published under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6907">section 6907 of this title</ref> and with other laws and regulations for the protection of health and the environment,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde64a3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in the case of a contract for construction or operation, such facility is not likely to be constructed or operated by State, local, or private persons or in the case of an application for financial assistance, such facility is not likely to receive adequate financial assistance from other sources, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbde64a3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> any Federal interest in, or assistance to, such facility will be disposed of or terminated, with appropriate compensation, within such period of time as may be necessary to carry out the basic objectives of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde64a3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Time limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No obligation may be made by the Administrator for financial assistance under this subchapter for any full-scale demonstration facility after the date ten years after <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>. No expenditure of funds for any such full-scale demonstration facility under this subchapter may be made by the Administrator after the date fourteen years after <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde64a40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde64a41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Wherever practicable, in constructing, operating, or providing financial assistance under this subchapter to a full-scale demonstration facility, the Administrator shall endeavor to enter into agreements and make other arrangements for maximum practicable cost sharing with other Federal, State, and local agencies, private persons, or any combination thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbde64a42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator shall enter into arrangements, wherever practicable and desirable, to provide monitoring of full-scale solid waste facilities (whether or not constructed or operated under this chapter) for purposes of obtaining information concerning the performance, and other aspects, of such facilities. Where the Administrator provides only monitoring and evaluation instruments or personnel (or both) or funds for such instruments or personnel and provides no other financial assistance to a facility, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6981/c/3">section 6981(c)(3) of this title</ref>, title to any invention made or conceived of in the course of developing, constructing, or operating such facility shall not be required to vest in the United States and patents respecting such invention shall not be required to be issued to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbde64a43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6984/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After <date date="1976-10-21">October 21, 1976</date>, the Administrator shall not construct or operate any full-scale facility (except by contract with public agencies or authorities or private persons).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbde64a44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s8004">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 8004</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2836">90 Stat. 2836</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/609/s7/v">Pub. L. 95–609, § 7(v)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3084">92 Stat. 3084</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tV/s502/f">Pub. L. 98–616, title V, § 502(f)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3276">98 Stat. 3276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbde64a45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbde64a46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbde64a47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/616">Pub. L. 98–616</ref> inserted “(1)” before “Wherever”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/609">Pub. L. 95–609</ref> substituted “solid waste” for “discarded material”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbde64a48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbde64a49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of certain enforcement functions of Administrator or other official of Environmental Protection Agency under this chapter to Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, and subsequent transfer to Secretary of Energy, then to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903">section 6903 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
