<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdeb0466-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d"><num value="6991d">§ 6991d.</num><heading> Inspections, monitoring, testing, and corrective action</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb0467-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Furnishing information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of developing or assisting in the development of any regulation, conducting any study, taking any corrective action, or enforcing the provisions of this subchapter, any owner or operator of an underground storage tank (or any tank subject to study under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6991h">section 6991h of this title</ref> that is used for storing regulated substances) shall, upon request of any officer, employee or representative of the Environmental Protection Agency, duly designated by the Administrator, or upon request of any duly designated officer, employee, or representative of a State acting pursuant to subsection (h)(7) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6991b">section 6991b of this title</ref> or with an approved program, furnish information relating to such tanks, their associated equipment, their contents, conduct monitoring or testing, permit such officer at all reasonable times to have access to, and to copy all records relating to such tanks and permit such officer to have access for corrective action. For the purposes of developing or assisting in the development of any regulation, conducting any study, taking corrective action, or enforcing the provisions of this subchapter, such officers, employees, or representatives are authorized—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0468-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to enter at reasonable times any establishment or other place where an underground storage tank is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0469-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to inspect and obtain samples from any person of any regulated substances contained in such tank;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb046a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to conduct monitoring or testing of the tanks, associated equipment, contents, or surrounding soils, air, surface water or ground water; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb046b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to take corrective action.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each such inspection shall be commenced and completed with reasonable promptness.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb046c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdeb046d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any records, reports, or information obtained from any persons under this section shall be available to the public, except that upon a showing satisfactory to the Administrator (or the State, as the case may be) by any person that records, reports, or information, or a particular part thereof, to which the Administrator (or the State, as the case may be) or any officer, employee, or representative thereof has access under this section if made public, would divulge information entitled to protection under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref>, such information or particular portion thereof shall be considered confidential in accordance with the purposes of that section, except that such record, report, document, or information may be disclosed to other officers, employees, or authorized representatives of the United States concerned with carrying out this chapter, or when relevant in any proceeding under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdeb046e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any person not subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref> who knowingly and willfully divulges or discloses any information entitled to protection under this subsection shall, upon conviction, be subject to a fine of not more than $5,000 or to imprisonment not to exceed one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdeb046f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In submitting data under this subchapter, a person required to provide such data may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0470-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> designate the data which such person believes is entitled to protection under this subsection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0471-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> submit such designated data separately from other data submitted under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">A designation under this paragraph shall be made in writing and in such manner as the Administrator may prescribe.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdeb0472-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Notwithstanding any limitation contained in this section or any other provision of law, all information reported to, or otherwise obtained, by the Administrator (or any representative of the Administrator) under this chapter shall be made available, upon written request of any duly authorized committee of the Congress, to such committee (including records, reports, or information obtained by representatives of the Environmental Protection Agency).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb0473-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspection requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb0474-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Uninspected tanks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of underground storage tanks regulated under this subchapter that have not undergone an inspection since <date date="1998-12-22">December 22, 1998</date>, not later than 2 years after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Administrator or a State that receives funding under this subchapter, as appropriate, shall conduct on-site inspections of all such tanks to determine compliance with this subchapter and the regulations under this subchapter (40 CFR 280) or a requirement or standard of a State program developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6991c">section 6991c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb0475-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodic inspections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After completion of all inspections required under paragraph (1), the Administrator or a State that receives funding under this subchapter, as appropriate, shall conduct on-site inspections of each underground storage tank regulated under this subchapter at least once every 3 years to determine compliance with this subchapter and the regulations under this subchapter (40 CFR 280) or a requirement or standard of a State program developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6991c">section 6991c of this title</ref>. The Administrator may extend for up to one additional year the first 3-year inspection interval under this paragraph if the State demonstrates that it has insufficient resources to complete all such inspections within the first 3-year period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb0476-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6991d/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspection authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to diminish the Administrator’s or a State’s authorities under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdeb0477-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s9005">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 9005</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/616/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 98–616, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3284">98 Stat. 3284</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s205/f">Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 205(f)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1702">100 Stat. 1702</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXV">Pub. L. 109–58, title XV</ref>, §§ 1523(a), 1533(4), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1094">119 Stat. 1094</ref>, 1105.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdeb0478-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdeb0479-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdeb047a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1533/4/A">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1533(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “study, taking” for “study taking” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1533/4/B">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1533(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “relevant” for “relevent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1533/4/C">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1533(4)(C)</ref>, substituted “Environmental” for “Evironmental”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1523/a">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1523(a)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/499/s205/f/3">Pub. L. 99–499, § 205(f)(3)</ref>, inserted reference to corrective action in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/s205/f/1">Pub. L. 99–499, § 205(f)(1)</ref>, in first sentence, inserted “taking any corrective action” after “conducting any study”, inserted “acting pursuant to subsection (h)(7) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6991b">section 6991b of this title</ref> or”, struck out “and” before “permit such officer”, and inserted “and permit such officer to have access for corrective action”, and in second sentence, inserted “taking corrective action,” after “study,”. The amendment directing insertion of “taking any corrective action” after “study” in first sentence was executed by inserting that language after “conducting any study” rather than after “subject to study”, as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/s205/f/2">Pub. L. 99–499, § 205(f)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
