<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbded7532-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d"><num value="6992d">§ 6992d.</num><heading> Enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbded7533-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance orders</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbded7534-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever on the basis of any information the Administrator determines that any person has violated, or is in violation of, any requirement or prohibition in effect under this subchapter (including any requirement or prohibition in effect under regulations under this subchapter) (A) the Administrator may issue an order (i) assessing a civil penalty for any past or current violation, (ii) requiring compliance immediately or within a specified time period, or (iii) both, or (B) the Administrator may commence a civil action in the United States district court in the district in which the violation occurred for appropriate relief, including a temporary or permanent injunction. Any order issued pursuant to this subsection shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbded7535-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Orders assessing penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any penalty assessed in an order under this subsection shall not exceed $25,000 per day of noncompliance for each violation of a requirement or prohibition in effect under this subchapter. In assessing such a penalty, the Administrator shall take into account the seriousness of the violation and any good faith efforts to comply with applicable requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbded7536-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Public hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any order issued under this subsection shall become final unless, not later than 30 days after issuance of the order, the persons named therein request a public hearing. Upon such request, the Administrator shall promptly conduct a public hearing. In connection with any proceeding under this section, the Administrator may issue subpoenas for the production of relevant papers, books, and documents, and may promulgate rules for discovery procedures.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbded7537-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Violation of compliance orders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of an order under this subsection requiring compliance with any requirement of or regulation under this subchapter, if a violator fails to take corrective action within the time specified in an order, the Administrator may assess a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each day of continued noncompliance with the order.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbded7538-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbded7539-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> knowingly violates the requirements of or regulations under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbded753a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> knowingly omits material information or makes any false material statement or representation in any label, record, report, or other document filed, maintained, or used for purposes of compliance with this subchapter or regulations thereunder; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbded753b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> knowingly generates, stores, treats, transports, disposes of, or otherwise handles any medical waste (whether such activity took place before or takes place after <date date="1988-11-01">November 1, 1988</date>) and who knowingly destroys, alters, conceals, or fails to file any record, report, or other document required to be maintained or filed for purposes of compliance with this subchapter or regulations thereunder</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall, upon conviction, be subject to a fine of not more than $50,000 for each day of violation, or imprisonment not to exceed 2 years (5 years in the case of a violation of paragraph (1)). If the conviction is for a violation committed after a first conviction of such person under this paragraph, the maximum punishment under the respective paragraph shall be doubled with respect to both fine and imprisonment.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbded753c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Knowing endangerment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who knowingly violates any provision of subsection (b) who knows at that time that he thereby places another person in imminent danger of death or serious bodily injury, shall upon conviction be subject to a fine of not more than $250,000 or imprisonment for not more than 15 years, or both. A defendant that is an organization shall, upon conviction under this subsection, be subject to a fine of not more than $1,000,000. The terms of this paragraph shall be interpreted in accordance with the rules provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6928/f">section 6928(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbded753d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who violates any requirement of or regulation under this subchapter shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed $25,000 for each such violation. Each day of such violation shall, for purposes of this section, constitute a separate violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbded753e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalty policy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Civil penalties assessed by the United States or by the States under this subchapter shall be assessed in accordance with the Administrator’s “RCRA Civil Penalty Policy”, as such policy may be amended from time to time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbded753f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s11005">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 11005</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/582/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–582, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-01">Nov. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2953">102 Stat. 2953</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
