<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdeb0512-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a"><num value="6992a">§ 6992a.</num><heading> Listing of medical wastes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb0513-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> List</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after <date date="1988-11-01">November 1, 1988</date>, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations listing the types of medical waste to be tracked under the demonstration program. Except as provided in subsection (b), such list shall include, but need not be limited to, each of the following types of solid waste:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0514-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Cultures and stocks of infectious agents and associated biologicals, including cultures from medical and pathological laboratories, cultures and stocks of infectious agents from research and industrial laboratories, wastes from the production of biologicals, discarded live and attenuated vaccines, and culture dishes and devices used to transfer, inoculate, and mix cultures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0515-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Pathological wastes, including tissues, organs, and body parts that are removed during surgery or autopsy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0516-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Waste human blood and products of blood, including serum, plasma, and other blood components.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0517-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Sharps that have been used in patient care or in medical, research, or industrial laboratories, including hypodermic needles, syringes, pasteur pipettes, broken glass, and scalpel blades.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0518-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Contaminated animal carcasses, body parts, and bedding of animals that were exposed to infectious agents during research, production of biologicals, or testing of pharmaceuticals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb0519-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Wastes from surgery or autopsy that were in contact with infectious agents, including soiled dressings, sponges, drapes, lavage tubes, drainage sets, underpads, and surgical gloves.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb051a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Laboratory wastes from medical, pathological, pharmaceutical, or other research, commercial, or industrial laboratories that were in contact with infectious agents, including slides and cover slips, disposable gloves, laboratory coats, and aprons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb051b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Dialysis wastes that were in contact with the blood of patients undergoing hemodialysis, including contaminated disposable equipment and supplies such as tubing, filters, disposable sheets, towels, gloves, aprons, and laboratory coats.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb051c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Discarded medical equipment and parts that were in contact with infectious agents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb051d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Biological waste and discarded materials contaminated with blood, excretion, excudates <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003552">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003552"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “exudates”.</note> or secretion from human beings or animals who are isolated to protect others from communicable diseases.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdeb051e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Such other waste material that results from the administration of medical care to a patient by a health care provider and is found by the Administrator to pose a threat to human health or the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdeb051f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s6992a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusions from list</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may exclude from the list under this section any categories or items described in paragraphs (6) through (10) of subsection (a) which he determines do not pose a substantial present or potential hazard to human health or the environment when improperly treated, stored, transported, disposed of, or otherwise managed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdeb0520-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tII/s11002">Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 11002</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/582/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–582, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-01">Nov. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2951">102 Stat. 2951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
