<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdefbf87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112"><num value="7112">§ 7112.</num><heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress therefore declares that the establishment of a Department of Energy is in the public interest and will promote the general welfare by assuring coordinated and effective administration of Federal energy policy and programs. It is the purpose of this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To establish a Department of Energy in the executive branch.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To achieve, through the Department, effective management of energy functions of the Federal Government, including consultation with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies in order to encourage them to establish and observe policies consistent with a coordinated energy policy, and to promote maximum possible energy conservation measures in connection with the activities within their respective jurisdictions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To provide for a mechanism through which a coordinated national energy policy can be formulated and implemented to deal with the short-, mid- and long-term energy problems of the Nation; and to develop plans and programs for dealing with domestic energy production and import shortages.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> To create and implement a comprehensive energy conservation strategy that will receive the highest priority in the national energy program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> To carry out the planning, coordination, support, and management of a balanced and comprehensive energy research and development program, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdefbf8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> assessing the requirements for energy research and development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdefbf8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> developing priorities necessary to meet those requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdefbf8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> undertaking programs for the optimal development of the various forms of energy production and conservation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbdefbf90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> disseminating information resulting from such programs, including disseminating information on the commercial feasibility and use of energy from fossil, nuclear, solar, geothermal, and other energy technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> To place major emphasis on the development and commercial use of solar, geothermal, recycling and other technologies utilizing renewable energy resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> To continue and improve the effectiveness and objectivity of a central energy data collection and analysis program within the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> To facilitate establishment of an effective strategy for distributing and allocating fuels in periods of short supply and to provide for the administration of a national energy supply reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> To promote the interests of consumers through the provision of an adequate and reliable supply of energy at the lowest reasonable cost.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> To establish and implement through the Department, in coordination with the Secretaries of State, Treasury, and Defense, policies regarding international energy issues that have a direct impact on research, development, utilization, supply, and conservation of energy in the United States and to undertake activities involving the integration of domestic and foreign policy relating to energy, including provision of independent technical advice to the President on international negotiations involving energy resources, energy technologies, or nuclear weapons issues, except that the Secretary of State shall continue to exercise primary authority for the conduct of foreign policy relating to energy and nuclear nonproliferation, pursuant to policy guidelines established by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> To provide for the cooperation of Federal, State, and local governments in the development and implementation of national energy policies and programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> To foster and assure competition among parties engaged in the supply of energy and fuels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> To assure incorporation of national environmental protection goals in the formulation and implementation of energy programs, and to advance the goals of restoring, protecting, and enhancing environmental quality, and assuring public health and safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> To assure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the productive capacity of private enterprise shall be utilized in the development and achievement of the policies and purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> To provide for, encourage, and assist public participation in the development and enforcement of national energy programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> To create an awareness of, and responsibility for, the fuel and energy needs of rural and urban residents as such needs pertain to home heating and cooling, transportation, agricultural production, electrical generation, conservation, and research and development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> To foster insofar as possible the continued good health of the Nation’s small business firms, public utility districts, municipal utilities, and private cooperatives involved in energy production, transportation, research, development, demonstration, marketing, and merchandising.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> To provide for the administration of the functions of the Energy Research and Development Administration related to nuclear weapons and national security which are transferred to the Department by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdefbf9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7112/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> To ensure that the Department can continue current support of mathematics, science, and engineering education programs by using the personnel, facilities, equipment, and resources of its laboratories and by working with State and local education agencies, institutions of higher education, and business and industry. The Department’s involvement in mathematics, science, and engineering education should be consistent with its main mission and should be coordinated with all Federal efforts in mathematics, science, and engineering education, especially with the Department of Education and the National Science Foundation (which have the primary Federal responsibility for mathematics, science, and engineering education).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbdefbf9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tI/s102">Pub. L. 95–91, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/567">91 Stat. 567</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dC/tXXXI/s3163">Pub. L. 101–510, div. C, title XXXI, § 3163</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1841">104 Stat. 1841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdefbfa0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdefbfa1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdefbfa2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in introductory provisions and pars. (14) and (18), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/565">91 Stat. 565</ref>, known as the Department of Energy Organization Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7101">section 7101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdefbfa3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Pub. L. 101–510</ref> substituted “chapter:” for “chapter—” in introductory provisions, capitalized the first letter of the first word in each of pars. (1) to (18), substituted a period for last semicolon in each of pars. (1) to (17), struck out “and” at end of par. (17), and added par. (19).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
