<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdf22ff7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7134"><num value="7134">§ 7134.</num><heading> Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; compensation of Chairman and members</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be within the Department, a Federal Energy Regulatory Commission established by subchapter IV of this chapter (hereinafter referred to in this chapter as the “Commission”). The Chairman shall be compensated at the rate provided for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5314">section 5314 of title 5</ref>. The other members of the Commission shall be compensated at the rate provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of title 5</ref>. The Chairman and members of the Commission shall be individuals who, by demonstrated ability, background, training, or experience, are specially qualified to assess fairly the needs and concerns of all interests affected by Federal energy policy.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbdf22ff8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tII/s204">Pub. L. 95–91, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/571">91 Stat. 571</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdf22ff9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdf22ffa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdf22ffb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/565">91 Stat. 565</ref>, known as the Department of Energy Organization Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7101">section 7101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
