<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdf4a231-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152"><num value="7152">§ 7152.</num><heading> Transfers from Department of the Interior</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf4a232-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions relating to electric power</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf4a233-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> There are transferred to, and vested in, the Secretary all functions of the Secretary of the Interior under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s825s">section 825s of title 16</ref>, and all other functions of the Secretary of the Interior, and officers and components of the Department of the Interior, with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a234-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Southeastern Power Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a235-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Southwestern Power Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a236-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Bonneville Power Administration including but not limited to the authority contained in the Bonneville Project Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s832">16 U.S.C. 832</ref> et seq.] and the Federal Columbia River Transmission System Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s838">16 U.S.C. 838</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a237-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the power marketing functions of the Bureau of Reclamation, including the construction, operation, and maintenance of transmission lines and attendant facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a238-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the transmission and disposition of the electric power and energy generated at Falcon Dam and Amistad Dam, international storage reservoir projects on the Rio Grande, pursuant to the Act of <date date="1954-06-18">June 18, 1954</date>, as amended by the Act of <date date="1963-12-23">December 23, 1963</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf4a239-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Southeastern Power Administration, the Southwestern Power Administration, and the Bonneville Power Administration,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003561">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003561"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> shall be preserved as separate and distinct organizational entities within the Department. Each such entity shall be headed by an Administrator appointed by the Secretary. The functions transferred to the Secretary in paragraphs (1)(A), (1)(B), (1)(C), and (1)(D) shall be exercised by the Secretary, acting by and through such Administrators. Each such Administrator shall maintain his principal office at a place located in the region served by his respective Federal power marketing entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf4a23a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The functions transferred in paragraphs (1)(E) and (1)(F) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003562">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003562"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this subsection shall be exercised by the Secretary, acting by and through a separate and distinct Administration within the Department which shall be headed by an Administrator appointed by the Secretary. The Administrator shall establish and shall maintain such regional offices as necessary to facilitate the performance of such functions. Neither the transfer of functions effected by paragraph (1)(E) of this subsection nor any changes in cost allocation or project evaluation standards shall be deemed to authorize the reallocation of joint costs of multipurpose facilities theretofore allocated unless and to the extent that such change is hereafter approved by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf4a23b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold">, (c) Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/100/tII/s201">Pub. L. 97–100, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1981-12-23">Dec. 23, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1407">95 Stat. 1407</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf4a23c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions of Bureau of Mines</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are transferred to, and vested in, the Secretary those functions of the Secretary of the Interior, the Department of the Interior, and officers and components of that Department under the Act of <date date="1910-05-15">May 15, 1910</date>, and other authorities, exercised by the Bureau of Mines, but limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a23d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> fuel supply and demand analysis and data gathering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a23e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> research and development relating to increased efficiency of production technology of solid fuel minerals, other than research relating to mine health and safety and research relating to the environmental and leasing consequences of solid fuel mining (which shall remain in the Department of the Interior); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf4a23f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7152/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> coal preparation and analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdf4a240-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/578">91 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/100/tII/s201">Pub. L. 97–100, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1981-12-23">Dec. 23, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1407">95 Stat. 1407</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/58/tI/s104/h">Pub. L. 104–58, title I, § 104(h)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/560">109 Stat. 560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdf4a241-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdf4a242-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdf4a243-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Bonneville Project Act of 1937, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(C), is <ref href="/us/act/1937-08-20/ch720">act Aug. 20, 1937, ch. 720</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/731">50 Stat. 731</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 12B (§ 832 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s832">section 832 of Title 16</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Columbia River Transmission System Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/454">Pub. L. 93–454</ref>, <date date="1974-10-18">Oct. 18, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1376">88 Stat. 1376</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 12G (§ 838 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s838">section 838 of Title 16</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1954-06-18">June 18, 1954</date>, as amended by the Act of <date date="1963-12-23">December 23, 1963</date>, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(E), is <ref href="/us/act/1954-06-18/ch310">act June 18, 1954, ch. 310</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/255">68 Stat. 255</ref>, which was not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraphs (1)(E) and (1)(F) of this subsection, referred to in subsec. (a)(3), were redesignated as pars. (1)(D) and (1)(E) of this subsection, respectively, by <ref href="/us/pl/104/58/tI/s104/h/1/B">Pub. L. 104–58, title I, § 104(h)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/560">109 Stat. 560</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1910-05-15">May 15, 1910</date>, referred to in subsec. (d), probably means <ref href="/us/act/1910-05-16/ch240">act May 16, 1910, ch. 240</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/369">36 Stat. 369</ref>, which is classified to sections 1, 3, and 5 to 7 of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdf4a244-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (a)(1)(C) to (F). <ref href="/us/pl/104/58/s104/h/1">Pub. L. 104–58, § 104(h)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (D) to (F) as (C) to (E), respectively, and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “the Alaska Power Administration;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/58/s104/h/2">Pub. L. 104–58, § 104(h)(2)</ref>, inserted “and” after “Southwestern Power Administration,” and struck out “and the Alaska Power Administration” after “Bonneville Power Administration,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/100">Pub. L. 97–100</ref> struck out subsecs. (b) and (c) which related, respectively, to the functions of the Secretary of Energy to promulgate regulations under certain provisions of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, the Mineral Lands Leasing Act, the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands, the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, and the Energy Policy and Conservation Act and to the functions of establishing production rates for all Federal leases.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdf4a245-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbdf4a246-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Bureau of Mines redesignated United States Bureau of Mines by <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">section 10(b) of Pub. L. 102–285</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of Title 30</ref>, Mineral Lands and Mining. For provisions relating to closure and transfer of functions of the United States Bureau of Mines, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of Title 30</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbdf4a247-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1995 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/58">Pub. L. 104–58</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/58/s104/h">section 104(h) of Pub. L. 104–58</ref>, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdf4a248-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Alaska Power Administration Asset Sale and Termination</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/58/tI">Pub. L. 104–58, title I</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/557">109 Stat. 557</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/58/tI">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="101">“SEC. 101.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This title may be cited as the ‘Alaska Power Administration Asset Sale and Termination Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="102">“SEC. 102.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“For purposes of this title:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘Eklutna’ means the Eklutna Hydroelectric Project and related assets as described in section 4 and Exhibit A of the Eklutna Purchase Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Eklutna Purchase Agreement’ means the <date date="1989-08-02">August 2, 1989</date>, Eklutna Purchase Agreement between the Alaska Power Administration of the Department of Energy and the Eklutna Purchasers, together with any amendments thereto adopted before the enactment of this section [<date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘Eklutna Purchasers’ means the Municipality of Anchorage doing business as Municipal Light and Power, the Chugach Electric Association, Inc. and the Matanuska Electric Association, Inc.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The term ‘Snettisham’ means the Snettisham Hydroelectric Project and related assets as described in section 4 and Exhibit A of the Snettisham Purchase Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The term ‘Snettisham Purchase Agreement’ means the <date date="1989-02-10">February 10, 1989</date>, Snettisham Purchase Agreement between the Alaska Power Administration of the Department of Energy and the Alaska Power Authority and its successors in interest, together with any amendments thereto adopted before the enactment of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The term ‘Snettisham Purchaser’ means the Alaska Industrial Development and Export Authority or a successor State agency or authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="103">“SEC. 103.</num><heading> SALE OF EKLUTNA AND SNETTISHAM HYDROELECTRIC PROJECTS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sale of Eklutna</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Energy is authorized and directed to sell Eklutna to the Eklutna Purchasers in accordance with the terms of this Act and the Eklutna Purchase Agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sale of Snettisham</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Energy is authorized and directed to sell Snettisham to the Snettisham Purchaser in accordance with the terms of this Act and the Snettisham Purchase Agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation of Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading><content>The heads of other Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States shall assist the Secretary of Energy in implementing the sales and conveyances authorized and directed by this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Proceeds</inline>.—</heading><content>Proceeds from the sales required by this title shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to prepare, survey, and acquire Eklutna and Snettisham for sale and conveyance. Such preparations and acquisitions shall provide sufficient title to ensure the beneficial use, enjoyment, and occupancy by the purchasers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contributed Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Alaska Power Administration is authorized to receive, administer, and expend such contributed funds as may be provided by the Eklutna Purchasers or customers or the Snettisham Purchaser or customers for the purposes of upgrading, improving, maintaining, or administering Eklutna or Snettisham. Upon the termination of the Alaska Power Administration under section 104(f), the Secretary of Energy shall administer and expend any remaining balances of such contributed funds for the purposes intended by the contributors.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="104">“SEC. 104.</num><heading> EXEMPTION AND OTHER PROVISIONS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal Power Act</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> After the sales authorized by this Act occur, Eklutna and Snettisham, including future modifications, shall continue to be exempt from the requirements of Part I of the Federal Power Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.), except as provided in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The exemption provided by paragraph (1) shall not affect the Memorandum of Agreement entered into among the State of Alaska, the Eklutna Purchasers, the Alaska Energy Authority, and Federal fish and wildlife agencies regarding the protection, mitigation of, damages to, and enhancement of fish and wildlife, dated <date date="1991-08-07">August 7, 1991</date>, which remains in full force and effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Nothing in this title or the Federal Power Act preempts the State of Alaska from carrying out the responsibilities and authorities of the Memorandum of Agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subsequent Transfers</inline>.—</heading><content>Except for subsequent assignment of interest in Eklutna by the Eklutna Purchasers to the Alaska Electric Generation and Transmission Cooperative Inc. pursuant to section 19 of the Eklutna Purchase Agreement, upon any subsequent sale or transfer of any portion of Eklutna or Snettisham from the Eklutna Purchasers or the Snettisham Purchaser to any other person, the exemption set forth in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section shall cease to apply to such portion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The United States District Court for the District of Alaska shall have jurisdiction to review decisions made under the Memorandum of Agreement and to enforce the provisions of the Memorandum of Agreement, including the remedy of specific performance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> An action seeking review of a Fish and Wildlife Program (‘Program’) of the Governor of Alaska under the Memorandum of Agreement or challenging actions of any of the parties to the Memorandum of Agreement prior to the adoption of the Program shall be brought not later than 90 days after the date on which the Program is adopted by the Governor of Alaska, or be barred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> An action seeking review of implementation of the Program shall be brought not later than 90 days after the challenged act implementing the Program, or be barred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eklutna Lands</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>With respect to Eklutna lands described in Exhibit A of the Eklutna Purchase Agreement:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Interior shall issue rights-of-way to the Alaska Power Administration for subsequent reassignment to the Eklutna Purchasers—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> at no cost to the Eklutna Purchasers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to remain effective for a period equal to the life of Eklutna as extended by improvements, repairs, renewals, or replacements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> sufficient for the operation of, maintenance of, repair to, and replacement of, and access to, Eklutna facilities located on military lands and lands managed by the Bureau of Land Management, including lands selected by the State of Alaska.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Fee title to lands at Anchorage Substation shall be transferred to Eklutna Purchasers at no additional cost if the Secretary of the Interior determines that pending claims to, and selections of, those lands are invalid or relinquished.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> With respect to the Eklutna lands identified in paragraph 1 of Exhibit A of the Eklutna Purchase Agreement, the State of Alaska may select, and the Secretary of the Interior shall convey to the State, improved lands under the selection entitlements in <ref href="/us/act/1958-07-07/s6">section 6 of the Act of July 7, 1958</ref> (commonly referred to as the Alaska Statehood Act, <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>) [set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions], and the North Anchorage Land Agreement dated <date date="1983-01-31">January 31, 1983</date>. This conveyance shall be subject to the rights-of-way provided to the Eklutna Purchasers under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Snettisham Lands</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to the Snettisham lands identified in paragraph 1 of Exhibit A of the Snettisham Purchase Agreement and Public Land Order No. 5108, the State of Alaska may select, and the Secretary of the Interior shall convey to the State of Alaska, improved lands under the selection entitlements in <ref href="/us/act/1958-07-07/s6">section 6 of the Act of July 7, 1958</ref> (commonly referred to as the Alaska Statehood Act, <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Alaska Power Administration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after both of the sales authorized in section 103 have occurred, as measured by the Transaction Dates stipulated in the Purchase Agreements, the Secretary of Energy shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> complete the business of, and close out, the Alaska Power Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> submit to Congress a report documenting the sales; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> return unobligated balances of funds appropriated for the Alaska Power Administration to the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repeals</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Act of <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/64/382">64 Stat. 382</ref>) [enacting sections 312 to 312d of Title 48, Territories and Insular Possessions, and provisions formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s312">section 312 of Title 48</ref>] is repealed effective on the date that Eklutna is conveyed to the Eklutna Purchasers [ownership of Eklutna project transferred <date date="1997-10-02">Oct. 2, 1997</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Section 204 of the Flood Control Act of 1962 (<ref href="/us/stat/76/1193">76 Stat. 1193</ref>) is repealed effective on the date that Snettisham is conveyed to the Snettisham Purchaser [purchase of Snettisham project completed <date date="1998-08-19">Aug. 19, 1998</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Act of <date date="1955-08-09">August 9, 1955</date> [enacting sections 1962d–12 to 1962d–14 of this title], concerning water resources investigation in Alaska (<ref href="/us/stat/69/618">69 Stat. 618</ref>), is repealed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">DOE Organization Act</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As of the later of the two dates determined in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (g), section 302(a) of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7152/a">42 U.S.C. 7152(a)</ref>) is amended—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> in paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> by striking subparagraph (C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> by redesignating subparagraphs (D), (E), and (F) as subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E) respectively; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in paragraph (2) by striking out ‘and the Alaska Power Administration’ and by inserting ‘and’ after ‘Southwestern Power Administration,’.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disposal</inline>.—</heading><content>The sales of Eklutna and Snettisham under this title are not considered disposal of Federal surplus property under the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 [see chapters 1 to 11 of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of Title 41, Public Contracts] (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s484">40 U.S.C. 484</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s541–555">40 U.S.C. 541–555</ref>] or the Act of <date date="1944-10-03">October 3, 1944</date>, popularly referred to as the ‘Surplus Property Act of 1944’ (50 U.S.C. App. 1622) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s545">40 U.S.C. 545</ref> note].</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="105">“SEC. 105.</num><heading> OTHER FEDERAL HYDROELECTRIC PROJECTS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The provisions of this title regarding the sale of the Alaska Power Administration’s hydroelectric projects under section 103 and the exemption of these projects from Part I of the Federal Power Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.] under section 104 do not apply to other Federal hydroelectric projects.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdf4a249-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Funds To Study Noncost-Based Methods of Pricing Hydroelectric Power</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/377/tV/s505">Pub. L. 102–377, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1343">106 Stat. 1343</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/377/tV/s505">“Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, subsequent Energy and Water Development Appropriations Acts or any other provision of law hereafter, none of the funds made available under this Act, subsequent Energy and Water Development Appropriations Acts or any other law hereafter shall be used for the purposes of conducting any studies relating or leading to the possibility of changing from the currently required ‘at cost’ to a ‘market rate’ or any other noncost-based method for the pricing of hydroelectric power by the six Federal public power authorities, or other agencies or authorities of the Federal Government, except as may be specifically authorized by Act of Congress hereafter enacted.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbdf6eb3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfers to Secretary of the Interior of Certain Fossil Energy Research and Development Authorities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/257/tI/s100">Pub. L. 97–257, title I, § 100</ref>, <date date="1982-09-10">Sept. 10, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/841">96 Stat. 841</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/257/tI/s100">“That there are transferred to, and vested in, the Secretary of the Interior all functions vested in, or delegated to, the Secretary of Energy and the Department of Energy under or with respect to (1) the Act of <date date="1910-05-16">May 16, 1910</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">30 U.S.C. 1</ref>, 3, 5–7], and other authorities formerly exercised by the Bureau of Mines [now United States Bureau of Mines], but limited to research and development relating to increased efficiency of production technology of solid fuel minerals; (2) section 908 of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977, relating to research and development concerning alternative coal mining technologies (<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1328">30 U.S.C. 1328</ref>); (3) sections 5(g)(2), 8(a)(4), 8(a)(9), 27(b)(2)(3) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1334/g/2">43 U.S.C. 1334(g)(2)</ref> and 1337(a)(4) and 1337(a)(9) [and 1353(b)(2) and (3)]); and (4) section 105 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6213">42 U.S.C. 6213</ref>): <i>Provided further</i>, That the personnel employed, personnel positions, equipment, facilities, and unexpended balances of the aforementioned transferred programs shall be merged with the ‘Mines and minerals’ account of the Bureau of Mines.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
