<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdf95cf1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191"><num value="7191">§ 7191.</num><heading> Procedures for issuance of rules, regulations, or orders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf95cf2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95cf3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to the other requirements of this subchapter, the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 shall apply in accordance with its terms to any rule or regulation, or any order having the applicability and effect of a rule (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s551/4">section 551(4) of title 5</ref>), issued pursuant to authority vested by law in, or transferred or delegated to, the Secretary, or required by this chapter or any other Act to be carried out by any other officer, employee, or component of the Department, other than the Commission, including any such rule, regulation, or order of a State, or local government agency or officer thereof, issued pursuant to authority delegated by the Secretary in accordance with this subchapter. If any provision of any Act, the functions of which are transferred, vested, or delegated pursuant to this chapter, provides administrative procedure requirements in addition to the requirements provided in this subchapter, such additional requirements shall also apply to actions under that provision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95cf4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), this subchapter shall apply to the Commission to the same extent this subchapter applies to the Secretary in the exercise of any of the Commission’s functions under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7172/c/1">section 7172(c)(1) of this title</ref> or which the Secretary has assigned under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7172/e">section 7172(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf95cf5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Substantial issue of fact or law or likelihood of substantial impact on Nation’s economy, etc.; oral presentation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95cf6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the Secretary determines, on his own initiative or in response to any showing made pursuant to paragraph (2) (with respect to a proposed rule, regulation, or order described in subsection (a)) that no substantial issue of fact or law exists and that such rule, regulation, or order is unlikely to have a substantial impact on the Nation’s economy or large numbers of individuals or businesses, such proposed rule, regulation, or order may be promulgated in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>. If the Secretary determines that a substantial issue of fact or law exists or that such rule, regulation, or order is likely to have a substantial impact on the Nation’s economy or large numbers of individuals or businesses, an opportunity for oral presentation of views, data, and arguments shall be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95cf7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any person, who would be adversely affected by the implementation of any proposed rule, regulation, or order who desires an opportunity for oral presentation of views, data, and arguments, may submit material supporting the existence of such substantial issues or such impact.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95cf8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A transcript shall be kept of any oral presentation with respect to a rule, regulation, or order described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf95cf9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver of requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The requirements of subsection (b) of this section may be waived where strict compliance is found by the Secretary to be likely to cause serious harm or injury to the public health, safety, or welfare, and such finding is set out in detail in such rule, regulation, or order. In the event the requirements of this section are waived, the requirements shall be satisfied within a reasonable period of time subsequent to the promulgation of such rule, regulation, or order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf95cfa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effects confined to single unit of local government, geographic area within State, or State; hearing or oral presentation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95cfb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> With respect to any rule, regulation, or order described in subsection (a), the effects of which, except for indirect effects of an inconsequential nature, are confined to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf95cfc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a single unit of local government or the residents thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf95cfd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a single geographic area within a State or the residents thereof; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf95cfe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a single State or the residents thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall, in any case where appropriate, afford an opportunity for a hearing or the oral presentation of views, and provide procedures for the holding of such hearing or oral presentation within the boundaries of the unit of local government, geographic area, or State described in paragraphs (A) through (C) of this paragraph as the case may be.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95cff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf95d00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “unit of local government” means a county, municipality, town, township, village, or other unit of general government below the State level; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdf95d01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “geographic area within a State” means a special purpose district or other region recognized for governmental purposes within such State which is not a unit of local government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdf95d02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as requiring a hearing or an oral presentation of views where none is required by this section or other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdf95d03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7191/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Prescription of procedures for State and local government agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where authorized by any law vested, transferred, or delegated pursuant to this chapter, the Secretary may, by rule, prescribe procedures for State or local government agencies authorized by the Secretary to carry out such functions as may be permitted under applicable law. Such procedures shall apply to such agencies in lieu of this section, and shall require that prior to taking any action, such agencies shall take steps reasonably calculated to provide notice to persons who may be affected by the action, and shall afford an opportunity for presentation of views (including oral presentation of views where practicable) within a reasonable time before taking the action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdf95d04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tV/s501">Pub. L. 95–91, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/587">91 Stat. 587</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/28/s2/a">Pub. L. 105–28, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-07-18">July 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/245">111 Stat. 245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdf95d05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdf95d06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdf95d07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (e), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/565">91 Stat. 565</ref>, known as the Department of Energy Organization Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7101">section 7101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbdf95d08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/28/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 105–28, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) In addition to the requirements of subsection (a) of this section, notice of any proposed rule, regulation, or order described in subsection (a) of this section shall be given by publication of such proposed rule, regulation, or order in the Federal Register. Such publication shall be accompanied by a statement of the research, analysis, and other available information in support of, the need for, and the probable effect of, any such proposed rule, regulation, or order. Other effective means of publicity shall be utilized as may be reasonably calculated to notify concerned or affected persons of the nature and probable effect of any such proposed rule, regulation, or order. In each case, a minimum of thirty days following such publication shall be provided for an opportunity to comment prior to promulgation of any such rule, regulation, or order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) Public notice of all rules, regulations, or orders described in subsection (a) of this section which are promulgated by officers of a State or local government agency pursuant to a delegation under this chapter shall be provided by publication of such proposed rules, regulations, or orders in at least two newspapers of statewide circulation. If such publication is not practicable, notice of any such rule, regulation, or order shall be given by such other means as the officer promulgating such rule, regulation, or order determines will reasonably assure wide public notice.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) For the purposes of this subchapter, the exception from the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref> provided by subsection (a)(2) of such section with respect to public property, loans, grants, or contracts shall not be available.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/28/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 105–28, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (e) as (c) and substituted “subsection (b)” for “subsections (b), (c), and (d)”. Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/28/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 105–28, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (f) as (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “Following the notice and comment period, including any oral presentation required by this subsection, the Secretary may promulgate a rule if the rule is accompanied by an explanation responding to the major comments, criticisms, and alternatives offered during the comment period.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/28/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 105–28, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (e) to (g) as (c) to (e), respectively.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
