<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdfba680-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7238"><num value="7238">§ 7238.</num><heading> Temporary appointments for scientific and technical experts in Department of Energy research and development programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfba681-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7238/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary, utilizing authority under other applicable law and the authority of this section, may appoint for a limited term, or on a temporary basis, scientists, engineers, and other technical and professional personnel on leave of absence from academic, industrial, or research institutions to work for the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfba682-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7238/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Department may pay, to the extent authorized for certain other Federal employees by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5723">section 5723 of title 5</ref>, travel expenses for any individual appointed for a limited term or on a temporary basis and transportation expenses of his or her immediate family and his or her household goods and personal effects from that individual’s residence at the time of selection or assignment to his or her duty station. The Department may pay such travel expenses to the same extent for such an individual’s return to the former place of residence from his or her duty station, upon separation from the Federal service following an agreed period of service. The Department may also pay a per diem allowance at a rate not to exceed the daily amounts prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5702">section 5702 of title 5</ref> to such an individual, in lieu of transportation expenses of the immediate family and household goods and personal effects, for the period of his or her employment with the Department. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the employer’s contribution to any retirement, life insurance, or health benefit plan for an individual appointed for a term of one year or less, which could be extended for no more than one additional year, may be made or reimbursed from appropriations available to the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdfba683-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/271/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 104–271, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3307">110 Stat. 3307</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdfba684-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdfba685-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbdfba686-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Hydrogen Future Act of 1996, and not as part of the Department of Energy Organization Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbdfba687-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbdfba688-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/271/s2">Pub. L. 104–271, § 2</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3304">110 Stat. 3304</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/271/s2">
<inline>“For purposes of titles II and III [enacting this section and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12403">section 12403 of this title</ref>]—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘Department’ means the Department of Energy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Energy.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
