<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdfe1727-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a"><num value="7259a">§ 7259a.</num><heading> Activities of Department of Energy facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdfe1728-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and activities on behalf of non-department persons and entities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1729-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy may conduct research and other activities referred to in paragraph (2) at facilities of the Department of Energy on behalf of other departments and agencies of the Government, agencies of State and local governments, and private persons and entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe172a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The research and other activities that may be conducted under paragraph (1) are those which the Secretary is authorized to conduct by law, including research and activities authorized under the following provisions of law:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdfe172b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdfe172c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5801">42 U.S.C. 5801</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdfe172d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5901">42 U.S.C. 5901</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdfe172e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe172f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall impose on the department, agency, or person or entity for which research and other activities are carried out under subsection (a) a charge for such research and activities in carrying out such research and activities, which shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdfe1730-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the direct cost incurred in carrying out such research and activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbdfe1731-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the overhead cost, including site-wide indirect costs, associated with such research and activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1732-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1733-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall also impose on the department, agency, or person or entity concerned a Federal administrative charge (which includes any depreciation and imputed interest charges) in an amount not to exceed 3 percent of the full cost incurred in carrying out the research and activities concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1734-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary may waive the imposition of the Federal administrative charge required by subparagraph (A) in the case of research and other activities conducted on behalf of small business concerns, institutions of higher education, non-profit entities, and State and local governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1735-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not later than 2 years after <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>, the Secretary shall terminate any waiver of charges under section 33 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2053">42 U.S.C. 2053</ref>) that were made before such date, unless the Secretary determines that such waiver should be continued.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdfe1736-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Pilot program of reduced facility overhead charges</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1737-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may, with the cooperation of participating contractors of the contractor-operated facilities of the Department, carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary and such contractors reduce the facility overhead charges imposed under this section for research and other activities conducted under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1738-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program at contractor-operated facilities selected by the Secretary in consultation with the contractors concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe1739-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall determine the facility overhead charges to be imposed under the pilot program at a facility based on a joint review by the Secretary and the contractor for the facility of all items included in the overhead costs of the facility in order to determine which items are appropriately incurred as facility overhead charges by the contractor in carrying out research and other activities at such facility under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe173a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary shall commence carrying out the pilot program under this subsection not later than <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>, and shall terminate the pilot program on <date date="2003-09-30">September 30, 2003</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe173b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Not later than <date date="2003-01-31">January 31, 2003</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an interim report on the results of the pilot program under this subsection. The report shall include any recommendations for the extension or expansion of the pilot program, including the establishment of multiple rates of overhead charges for various categories of persons and entities seeking research and other activities in contractor-operated facilities of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbdfe173c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7259a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability with respect to user fee practice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section does not apply to the practice of the Department of Energy with respect to user fees at Department facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdfe173d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dC/tXXXI/s3137">Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXI, § 3137</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2248">112 Stat. 2248</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdfe173e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdfe173f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdfe1740-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(A), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Reorganization Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/438">Pub. L. 93–438</ref>, <date date="1974-10-11">Oct. 11, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1233">88 Stat. 1233</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 73 (§ 5801 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5801">section 5801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/577">Pub. L. 93–577</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1878">88 Stat. 1878</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 74 (§ 5901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5901">section 5901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbdfe1741-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999, and not as part of the Department of Energy Organization Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
