<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbdfe17be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7270b"><num value="7270b">§ 7270b.</num><heading> Trespass on Strategic Petroleum Reserve facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe17bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7270b/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary may issue regulations relating to the entry upon or carrying, transporting, or otherwise introducing or causing to be introduced any dangerous weapon, explosive, or other dangerous instrument or material likely to produce substantial injury or damage to persons or property into or onto the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, its storage or related facilities, or real property subject to the jurisdiction, administration, or in the custody of the Secretary under part B of title I of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6231–624">42 U.S.C. 6231–624</ref>7). The Secretary shall post conspicuously, on the property subject to the regulations, notification that the property is subject to the regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbdfe17c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7270b/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Whoever willfully violates a regulation of the Secretary issued under subsection (a) shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and punished upon conviction by a fine of not more than $5,000, imprisonment for not more than one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbdfe17c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tVI/s662">Pub. L. 95–91, title VI, § 662</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/531/s1/a">Pub. L. 100–531, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-25">Oct. 25, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2652">102 Stat. 2652</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbdfe17c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbdfe17c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbdfe17c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Policy and Conservation Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/163">Pub. L. 94–163</ref>, <date date="1975-12-22">Dec. 22, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/871">89 Stat. 871</ref>. Part B of title I of the Act is classified generally to part B (§ 6231 et seq.) of subchapter I of chapter 77 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
