<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe00885c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7274l–1"><num value="7274l–1">§ 7274l–1.</num><heading> Vesting title in property interests related to energy development, demonstration, and deployment programs funded under Department of Energy appropriations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe00885d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7274l–1/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Hereafter, for energy development, demonstration, and deployment programs funded under Department of Energy appropriations (other than those for the National Nuclear Security Administration and Office of Environmental Management) provided for fiscal year 2022, the current fiscal year, or any fiscal year thereafter (including by Acts other than appropriations Acts), the Secretary may vest unconditional title or other property interests acquired under projects in an award recipient, subrecipient, or successor in interest, including the United States, at the conclusion of the award period for projects receiving an initial award in fiscal year 2022 or later.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe00885e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7274l–1/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Upon vesting unconditional title pursuant to subsection (a) in an award recipient, subrecipient, or successor in interest other than the United States, the United States shall have no liabilities or obligations to the property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe00885f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7274l–1/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> For purposes of this section, the term “property interest” does not include any interest in intellectual property developed using funding provided under a project.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe008860-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dD/tIII/s309">Pub. L. 117–328, div. D, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4645">136 Stat. 4645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe008861-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe008862-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe008863-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2023, and also as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023, and not as part of the Department of Energy Organization Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
