<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe00887d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7275"><num value="7275">§ 7275.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in sections 7275 to 7276c of this title:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe00887e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7275/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe00887f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7275/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “integrated resource planning” means a planning process for new energy resources that evaluates the full range of alternatives, including new generating capacity, power purchases, energy conservation and efficiency, cogeneration and district heating and cooling applications, and renewable energy resources, in order to provide adequate and reliable service to its electric customers at the lowest system cost. The process shall take into account necessary features for system operation, such as diversity, reliability, dispatchability, and other factors of risk; shall take into account the ability to verify energy savings achieved through energy conservation and efficiency and the projected durability of such savings measured over time; and shall treat demand and supply resources on a consistent and integrated basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe008880-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7275/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “least cost option” means an option for providing reliable electric services to electric customers which will, to the extent practicable, minimize life-cycle system costs, including adverse environmental effects, of providing such service. To the extent practicable, energy efficiency and renewable resources may be given priority in any least-cost option.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe008881-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7275/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “long-term firm power service contract” means any contract for the sale by Western Area Power Administration of firm capacity, with or without energy, which is to be delivered over a period of more than one year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe008882-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7275/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The terms “customer” or “customers” means any entity or entities purchasing firm capacity with or without energy, from the Western Area Power Administration under a long-term firm power service contract. Such terms include parent-type entities and their distribution or user members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe008883-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7275/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> For any customer, the term “applicable integrated resource plan” means the integrated resource plan approved by the Administrator under sections 7275 to 7276c of this title for that customer.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbe008884-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/381/tII/s201">Pub. L. 98–381, title II, § 201</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s114">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2799">106 Stat. 2799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe008885-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe008886-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe008887-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Hoover Power Plant Act of 1984, and not as part of the Department of Energy Organization Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbe008888-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 7275, <ref href="/us/pl/98/381/tII/s201">Pub. L. 98–381, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1984-08-17">Aug. 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1340">98 Stat. 1340</ref>, related to energy conservation program of Western Area Power Administration, prior to the general amendment of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/98/381">Pub. L. 98–381</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s114">section 114 of Pub. L. 102–486</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
