<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe02d304-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7293"><num value="7293">§ 7293.</num><heading> Agency terminations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, whenever all of the functions vested by law in any agency, commission, or other body, or any component thereof, have been terminated or transferred from that agency, commission, or other body, or component by this chapter, the agency, commission, or other body, or component, shall terminate. If an agency, commission, or other body, or any component thereof, terminates pursuant to the preceding sentence, each position and office therein which was expressly authorized by law, or the incumbent of which was authorized to receive compensation at the rates prescribed for an office or position at level II, III, IV, or V of the Executive Schedule (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313–531">5 U.S.C. 5313–531</ref>6), shall terminate.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbe02d305-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 95–91, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/606">91 Stat. 606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe02d306-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe02d307-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe02d308-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/565">91 Stat. 565</ref>, known as the Department of Energy Organization Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7101">section 7101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
