<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe054395-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7373"><num value="7373">§ 7373.</num><heading> Coordinated dissemination of information on renewable energy resources and conservation</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to improve the effectiveness of Federal information dissemination activities in the fields of renewable energy resources and energy conservation with the objective of developing and promoting better public understanding of these resources and their potential uses, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe054396-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7373/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> take affirmative steps to coordinate all of the activities of the Department of Energy, whether conducted by the Department itself or by other public or private entities with assistance from the Department, which are aimed at or involve the dissemination of information with respect to renewable energy resources or energy conservation, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe054397-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7373/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> report annually to the Congress on the status of such activities, including a description of how the information dissemination activities and services of the Department of Energy in the fields of renewable energy resources and energy conservation are being coordinated with similar or related activities and services of other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbe054398-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tIV/s404">Pub. L. 96–294, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/716">94 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe054399-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe05439a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe05439b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of reporting provisions in par. (2) of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and the 18th item on page 87 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
