<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe05439c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374"><num value="7374">§ 7374.</num><heading> Energy self-sufficiency initiatives</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe05439d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of 3-year pilot program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established under the direction of the Secretary a 3-year pilot energy self-sufficiency program to demonstrate energy self-sufficiency through the use of renewable energy resources in one or more States in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe05439e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of subprograms to pilot programs; scope of subprograms</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As a part of the pilot program, the Secretary shall establish such subprograms as the Secretary determines are necessary to achieve the purpose of this section, including subprograms—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe05439f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to promote the development and utilization of synergistic combinations of different renewable energy resources in specific projects aimed at reducing fossil fuel importation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe0543a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to initiate and encourage energy self-sufficiency at appropriate levels of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe0543a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to stimulate private industry participation in the realization of the objective stated in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe0543a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to stimulate the utilization of abandoned or underutilized industrial facilities for the generation of energy from any locally available renewable resource, such as municipal solid waste, agricultural waste, or forest products waste.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe0543a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation of subprograms; preparation of plan of program and additional Federal actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Secretary is authorized to assign to an existing office in the Department of Energy the responsibility of undertaking and carrying out the subprograms established under subsection (b). In addition, the Secretary shall prepare a detailed plan within one hundred eighty days of <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, setting forth (1) the 3-year pilot program itself, and (2) any additional Federal actions needed to encourage and promote the adoption of programs for energy self-sufficiency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe0543a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7374/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of plan and implementation report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit to the Congress, within one year after <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, the plan prepared under the second sentence of subsection (c) along with a report suggesting the legislative initiatives needed to fully implement such plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe0543a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tIV/s406">Pub. L. 96–294, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/716">94 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
