<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe112a5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7402"><num value="7402">§ 7402.</num><heading> Cooperative activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7402/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Interstate cooperation; uniform State laws; State compacts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall encourage cooperative activities by the States and local governments for the prevention and control of air pollution; encourage the enactment of improved and, so far as practicable in the light of varying conditions and needs, uniform State and local laws relating to the prevention and control of air pollution; and encourage the making of agreements and compacts between States for the prevention and control of air pollution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7402/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal cooperation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall cooperate with and encourage cooperative activities by all Federal departments and agencies having functions relating to the prevention and control of air pollution, so as to assure the utilization in the Federal air pollution control program of all appropriate and available facilities and resources within the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7402/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent of Congress to compacts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The consent of the Congress is hereby given to two or more States to negotiate and enter into agreements or compacts, not in conflict with any law or treaty of the United States, for (1) cooperative effort and mutual assistance for the prevention and control of air pollution and the enforcement of their respective laws relating thereto, and (2) the establishment of such agencies, joint or otherwise, as they may deem desirable for making effective such agreements or compacts. No such agreement or compact shall be binding or obligatory upon any State a party thereto unless and until it has been approved by Congress. It is the intent of Congress that no agreement or compact entered into between States after <date date="1967-11-21">November 21, 1967</date>, which relates to the control and abatement of air pollution in an air quality control region, shall provide for participation by a State which is not included (in whole or in part) in such air quality control region.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe112a5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 102, formerly § 2, as added <ref href="/us/pl/88/206/s1">Pub. L. 88–206, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-12-17">Dec. 17, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/393">77 Stat. 393</ref>; renumbered § 102, <ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tI/s101/3">Pub. L. 89–272, title I, § 101(3)</ref>, <date date="1965-10-20">Oct. 20, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/992">79 Stat. 992</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/148/s2">Pub. L. 90–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="1967-11-21">Nov. 21, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/485">81 Stat. 485</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s15/c/2">Pub. L. 91–604, § 15(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1713">84 Stat. 1713</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe112a60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe112a61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe112a62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857a">section 1857a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbe112a63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in the first clause of subsec. (a) of this section were contained in subsec. (b)(1) of a prior section 1857a, of this title, <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360/s2">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/322">69 Stat. 322</ref>, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/88/206">Pub. L. 88–206</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe112a64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref> substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/148">Pub. L. 90–148</ref> inserted declaration that it is the intent of Congress that no agreement or compact entered into between States after the date of enactment of the Air Quality Act of 1967, which for purposes of codification was changed to <date date="1967-11-21">November 21, 1967</date>, the date of approval of such Act, relating to the control and abatement of air pollution in an air quality control region, shall provide for participation by a State which is not included (in whole or in part) in such air quality control region.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
