<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe112a65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403"><num value="7403">§ 7403.</num><heading> Research, investigation, training, and other activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and development program for prevention and control of air pollution</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall establish a national research and development program for the prevention and control of air pollution and as part of such program shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> conduct, and promote the coordination and acceleration of, research, investigations, experiments, demonstrations, surveys, and studies relating to the causes, effects (including health and welfare effects), extent, prevention, and control of air pollution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> encourage, cooperate with, and render technical services and provide financial assistance to air pollution control agencies and other appropriate public or private agencies, institutions, and organizations, and individuals in the conduct of such activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> conduct investigations and research and make surveys concerning any specific problem of air pollution in cooperation with any air pollution control agency with a view to recommending a solution of such problem, if he is requested to do so by such agency or if, in his judgment, such problem may affect any community or communities in a State other than that in which the source of the matter causing or contributing to the pollution is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> establish technical advisory committees composed of recognized experts in various aspects of air pollution to assist in the examination and evaluation of research progress and proposals and to avoid duplication of research; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> conduct and promote coordination and acceleration of training for individuals relating to the causes, effects, extent, prevention, and control of air pollution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorized activities of Administrator in establishing research and development program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of the preceding subsection the Administrator is authorized to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> collect and make available, through publications and other appropriate means, the results of and other information, including appropriate recommendations by him in connection therewith, pertaining to such research and other activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> cooperate with other Federal departments and agencies, with air pollution control agencies, with other public and private agencies, institutions, and organizations, and with any industries involved, in the preparation and conduct of such research and other activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> make grants to air pollution control agencies, to other public or nonprofit private agencies, institutions, and organizations, and to individuals, for purposes stated in subsection (a)(1) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> contract with public or private agencies, institutions, and organizations, and with individuals, without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31 and <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> establish and maintain research fellowships, in the Environmental Protection Agency and at public or nonprofit private educational institutions or research organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> collect and disseminate, in cooperation with other Federal departments and agencies, and with other public or private agencies, institutions, and organizations having related responsibilities, basic data on chemical, physical, and biological effects of varying air quality and other information pertaining to air pollution and the prevention and control thereof;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> develop effective and practical processes, methods, and prototype devices for the prevention or control of air pollution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> construct facilities, provide equipment, and employ staff as necessary to carry out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In carrying out the provisions of subsection (a), the Administrator shall provide training for, and make training grants to, personnel of air pollution control agencies and other persons with suitable qualifications and make grants to such agencies, to other public or nonprofit private agencies, institutions, and organizations for the purposes stated in subsection (a)(5). Reasonable fees may be charged for such training provided to persons other than personnel of air pollution control agencies but such training shall be provided to such personnel of air pollution control agencies without charge.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Air pollutant monitoring, analysis, modeling, and inventory research</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall conduct a program of research, testing, and development of methods for sampling, measurement, monitoring, analysis, and modeling of air pollutants. Such program shall include the following elements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Consideration of individual, as well as complex mixtures of, air pollutants and their chemical transformations in the atmosphere.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a77-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Establishment of a national network to monitor, collect, and compile data with quantification of certainty in the status and trends of air emissions, deposition, air quality, surface water quality, forest condition, and visibility impairment, and to ensure the comparability of air quality data collected in different States and obtained from different nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Development of improved methods and technologies for sampling, measurement, monitoring, analysis, and modeling to increase understanding of the sources of ozone precursors, ozone formation, ozone transport, regional influences on urban ozone, regional ozone trends, and interactions of ozone with other pollutants. Emphasis shall be placed on those techniques which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> improve the ability to inventory emissions of volatile organic compounds and nitrogen oxides that contribute to urban air pollution, including anthropogenic and natural sources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> improve the understanding of the mechanism through which anthropogenic and biogenic volatile organic compounds react to form ozone and other oxidants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> improve the ability to identify and evaluate region-specific prevention and control options for ozone pollution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Submission of periodic reports to the Congress, not less than once every 5 years, which evaluate and assess the effectiveness of air pollution control regulations and programs using monitoring and modeling data obtained pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Environmental health effects research</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe112a7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall conduct a research program on the short-term and long-term effects of air pollutants, including wood smoke, on human health. In conducting such research program the Administrator—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall conduct studies, including epidemiological, clinical, and laboratory and field studies, as necessary to identify and evaluate exposure to and effects of air pollutants on human health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may utilize, on a reimbursable basis, the facilities of existing Federal scientific laboratories and research centers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall consult with other Federal agencies to ensure that similar research being conducted in other agencies is coordinated to avoid duplication.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe112a82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In conducting the research program under this subsection, the Administrator shall develop methods and techniques necessary to identify and assess the risks to human health from both routine and accidental exposures to individual air pollutants and combinations thereof. Such research program shall include the following elements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The creation of an Interagency Task Force to coordinate such program. The Task Force shall include representatives of the National Institute for Environmental Health Sciences, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, the National Toxicology Program, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the National Science Foundation, the Surgeon General, and the Department of Energy. This Interagency Task Force shall be chaired by a representative of the Environmental Protection Agency and shall convene its first meeting within 60 days after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An evaluation, within 12 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, of each of the hazardous air pollutants listed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7412/b">section 7412(b) of this title</ref>, to decide, on the basis of available information, their relative priority for preparation of environmental health assessments pursuant to subparagraph (C). The evaluation shall be based on reasonably anticipated toxicity to humans and exposure factors such as frequency of occurrence as an air pollutant and volume of emissions in populated areas. Such evaluation shall be reviewed by the Interagency Task Force established pursuant to subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Preparation of environmental health assessments for each of the hazardous air pollutants referred to in subparagraph (B), beginning 6 months after the first meeting of the Interagency Task Force and to be completed within 96 months thereafter. No fewer than 24 assessments shall be completed and published annually. The assessments shall be prepared in accordance with guidelines developed by the Administrator in consultation with the Interagency Task Force and the Science Advisory Board of the Environmental Protection Agency. Each such assessment shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an examination, summary, and evaluation of available toxicological and epidemiological information for the pollutant to ascertain the levels of human exposure which pose a significant threat to human health and the associated acute, subacute, and chronic adverse health effects;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a determination of gaps in available information related to human health effects and exposure levels; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/d/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> where appropriate, an identification of additional activities, including toxicological and inhalation testing, needed to identify the types or levels of exposure which may present significant risk of adverse health effects in humans.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Ecosystem research</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator, in cooperation, where appropriate, with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall conduct a research program to improve understanding of the short-term and long-term causes, effects, and trends of ecosystems damage from air pollutants on ecosystems. Such program shall include the following elements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Identification of regionally representative and critical ecosystems for research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Evaluation of risks to ecosystems exposed to air pollutants, including characterization of the causes and effects of chronic and episodic exposures to air pollutants and determination of the reversibility of those effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Development of improved atmospheric dispersion models and monitoring systems and networks for evaluating and quantifying exposure to and effects of multiple environmental stresses associated with air pollution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Evaluation of the effects of air pollution on water quality, including assessments of the short-term and long-term ecological effects of acid deposition and other atmospherically derived pollutants on surface water (including wetlands and estuaries) and groundwater.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Evaluation of the effects of air pollution on forests, materials, crops, biological diversity, soils, and other terrestrial and aquatic systems exposed to air pollutants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Estimation of the associated economic costs of ecological damage which have occurred as a result of exposure to air pollutants.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Consistent with the purpose of this program, the Administrator may use the estuarine research reserves established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1461">section 1461 of title 16</ref> to carry out this research.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Liquefied Gaseous Fuels Spill Test Facility</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe112a91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Federal Coordinating Council for Science, Engineering, and Technology, shall oversee an experimental and analytical research effort, with the experimental research to be carried out at the Liquefied Gaseous Fuels Spill Test Facility. In consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator shall develop a list of chemicals and a schedule for field testing at the Facility. Analysis of a minimum of 10 chemicals per year shall be carried out, with the selection of a minimum of 2 chemicals for field testing each year. Highest priority shall be given to those chemicals that would present the greatest potential risk to human health as a result of an accidental release—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> from a fixed site; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> related to the transport of such chemicals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe112a94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The purpose of such research shall be to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> develop improved predictive models for atmospheric dispersion which at a minimum—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> describe dense gas releases in complex terrain including man-made structures or obstacles with variable winds;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> improve understanding of the effects of turbulence on dispersion patterns; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> consider realistic behavior of aerosols by including physicochemical reactions with water vapor, ground deposition, and removal by water spray;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> evaluate existing and future atmospheric dispersion models by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the development of a rigorous, standardized methodology for dense gas models; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112a9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the application of such methodology to current dense gas dispersion models using data generated from field experiments; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe112a9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> evaluate the effectiveness of hazard mitigation and emergency response technology for fixed site and transportation related accidental releases of toxic chemicals.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Models pertaining to accidental release shall be evaluated and improved periodically for their utility in planning and implementing evacuation procedures and other mitigative strategies designed to minimize human exposure to hazardous air pollutants released accidentally.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe112a9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy shall make available to interested persons (including other Federal agencies and businesses) the use of the Liquefied Gaseous Fuels Spill Test Facility to conduct research and other activities in connection with the activities described in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Pollution prevention and emissions control</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112a9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall conduct a basic engineering research and technology program to develop, evaluate, and demonstrate nonregulatory strategies and technologies for air pollution prevention.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112aa0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Participation requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Such strategies and technologies described in paragraph (1) shall be developed with priority on those pollutants which pose a significant risk to human health and the environment, and with opportunities for participation by industry, public interest groups, scientists, States, institutions of higher education, and other interested persons in the development of such strategies and technologies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe112aa1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Program inclusions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The program under this subsection shall include the following elements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe112aa2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Improvements in nonregulatory strategies and technologies for preventing or reducing multiple air pollutants, including sulfur oxides, nitrogen oxides, heavy metals, PM–10 (particulate matter), carbon monoxide, and carbon dioxide, from stationary sources, including fossil fuel power plants. Such strategies and technologies shall include improvements in the relative cost effectiveness and long-range implications of various air pollutant reduction and nonregulatory control strategies such as energy conservation, including end-use efficiency, and fuel-switching to cleaner fuels. Such strategies and technologies shall be considered for existing and new facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139aa3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Improvements in nonregulatory strategies and technologies for reducing air emissions from area sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139aa4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Improvements in nonregulatory strategies and technologies for preventing, detecting, and correcting accidental releases of hazardous air pollutants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139aa5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Improvements in nonregulatory strategies and technologies that dispose of tires in ways that avoid adverse air quality impacts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aa6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of subsection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize the imposition on any person of air pollution control requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aa7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination and avoidance of duplication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall consult with other appropriate Federal agencies to ensure coordination and to avoid duplication of activities authorized under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aa8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain carbon dioxide activities</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aa9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out paragraph (3)(A) with respect to carbon dioxide, the Administrator—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe139aaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is authorized to carry out the activities described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe139aab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall carry out the activities described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct air capture research</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In this subparagraph:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Board</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The term “Board” means the Direct Air Capture Technology Advisory Board established by clause (iii)(I).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Dilute</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The term “dilute” means a concentration of less than 1 percent by volume.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ab0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct air capture</heading><item style="-uslm-lc:I580469" class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold" id="idbe139ab1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><heading> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5">The term “direct air capture”, with respect to a facility, technology, or system, means that the facility, technology, or system uses carbon capture equipment to capture carbon dioxide directly from the air.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580469" class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold" id="idbe139ab2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><heading> Exclusion</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5">The term “direct air capture” does not include any facility, technology, or system that captures carbon dioxide—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ab3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/III/bb/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> that is deliberately released from a naturally occurring subsurface spring; or</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ab4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/III/bb/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> using natural photosynthesis.</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ab5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/IV"><num value="IV" class="bold">(IV)</num><heading class="bold"> Intellectual property</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The term “intellectual property” means—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ab6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> an invention that is patentable under title 35; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ab7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/i/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> any patent on an invention described in item (aa).</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ab8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Technology prizes</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ab9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, is authorized to establish a program to provide financial awards on a competitive basis for direct air capture from media in which the concentration of carbon dioxide is dilute.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In carrying out this clause, the Administrator shall—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139abb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><chapeau> subject to subclause (III), develop specific requirements for—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139abc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/aa/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> the competition process; and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139abd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/aa/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> the demonstration of performance of approved projects;</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139abe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><chapeau> offer financial awards for a project designed—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139abf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/bb/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> to the maximum extent practicable, to capture more than 10,000 tons of carbon dioxide per year;</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ac0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/bb/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> to operate in a manner that would be commercially viable in the foreseeable future (as determined by the Board); and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ac1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/bb/CC"><num value="CC">(CC)</num><content> to improve the technologies or information systems that enable monitoring and verification methods for direct air capture projects; and</content>
</subitem>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ac2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><chapeau> to the maximum extent practicable, make financial awards to geographically diverse projects, including at least—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ac3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/cc/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> 1 project in a coastal State; and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ac4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/II/cc/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> 1 project in a rural State.</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ac5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In carrying out subclause (II)(aa), the Administrator shall—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ac6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> provide notice of and, for a period of not less than 60 days, an opportunity for public comment on, any draft or proposed version of the requirements described in subclause (II)(aa); and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ac7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/ii/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> take into account public comments received in developing the final version of those requirements.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ac8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct Air Capture Technology Advisory Board</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ac9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Administrator may establish an advisory board to be known as the “Direct Air Capture Technology Advisory Board”.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Board, on the establishment of the Board, shall be composed of 9 members appointed by the Administrator, who shall provide expertise in—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139acb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> climate science;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139acc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> physics;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139acd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> chemistry;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ace-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><content> biology;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139acf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/ee"><num value="ee">(ee)</num><content> engineering;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ad0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/ff"><num value="ff">(ff)</num><content> economics;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ad1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/gg"><num value="gg">(gg)</num><content> business management; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ad2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/II/hh"><num value="hh">(hh)</num><content> such other disciplines as the Administrator determines to be necessary to achieve the purposes of this subparagraph.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ad3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Term; vacancies</heading><item style="-uslm-lc:I580469" class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold" id="idbe139ad4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><heading> Term</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5">A member of the Board shall serve for a term of 6 years.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580469" class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold" id="idbe139ad5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><heading> Vacancies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5">A vacancy on the Board—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ad6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/III/bb/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> shall not affect the powers of the Board; and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="idbe139ad7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/III/bb/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ad8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/IV"><num value="IV" class="bold">(IV)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial meeting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Board have been appointed, the Board shall hold the initial meeting of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ad9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/V"><num value="V" class="bold">(V)</num><heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Board shall meet at the call of the Chairperson or on the request of the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ada-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/VI"><num value="VI" class="bold">(VI)</num><heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139adb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/VII"><num value="VII" class="bold">(VII)</num><heading class="bold"> Chairperson and Vice Chairperson</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Board shall select a Chairperson and Vice Chairperson from among the members of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139adc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/VIII"><num value="VIII" class="bold">(VIII)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Each member of the Board may be compensated at not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for a position at level V of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5316">section 5316 of title 5</ref> for each day during which the member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139add-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/IX"><num value="IX" class="bold">(IX)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Board shall—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ade-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/IX/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> advise the Administrator on carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this subparagraph; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139adf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iii/IX/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> provide other assistance and advice as requested by the Administrator.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Intellectual property</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iv/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">As a condition of receiving a financial award under this subparagraph, an applicant shall agree to vest the intellectual property of the applicant derived from the technology in 1 or more entities that are incorporated in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iv/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Reservation of license</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The United States—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ae3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iv/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> may reserve a nonexclusive, nontransferable, irrevocable, paid-up license, to have practiced for or on behalf of the United States, in connection with any intellectual property described in subclause (I); but</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idbe139ae4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iv/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> shall not, in the exercise of a license reserved under item (aa), publicly disclose proprietary information relating to the license.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/iv/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of title</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Title to any intellectual property described in subclause (I) shall not be transferred or passed, except to an entity that is incorporated in the United States, until the expiration of the first patent obtained in connection with the intellectual property.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subparagraph $35,000,000, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/B/vi"><num value="vi" class="bold">(vi)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003583">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003583"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the Board and all authority provided under this subparagraph shall terminate not later than 12 years after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Deep saline formation report</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139ae9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of deep saline formation</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C/i/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In this subparagraph, the term “deep saline formation” means a formation of subsurface geographically extensive sedimentary rock layers saturated with waters or brines that have a high total dissolved solids content and that are below the depth where carbon dioxide can exist in the formation as a supercritical fluid.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aeb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C/i/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Clarification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In this subparagraph, the term “deep saline formation” does not include oil and gas reservoirs.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139aec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In consultation with the Secretary of Energy, and, as appropriate, with the head of any other relevant Federal agency and relevant stakeholders, not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Administrator shall prepare, submit to Congress, and make publicly available a report that includes—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbe139aed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a comprehensive identification of potential risks and benefits to project developers associated with increased storage of carbon dioxide captured from stationary sources in deep saline formations, using existing research;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbe139aee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> recommendations for managing the potential risks identified under subclause (I), including potential risks unique to public land; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbe139aef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> recommendations for Federal legislation or other policy changes to mitigate any potential risks identified under subclause (I).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139af0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> GAO report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 5 years after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe139af1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> identifies all Federal grant programs in which a purpose of a grant under the program is to perform research on carbon capture and utilization technologies, including direct air capture technologies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe139af2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/g/6/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> examines the extent to which the Federal grant programs identified pursuant to clause (i) overlap or are duplicative.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139af3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> NIEHS studies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe139af4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences may conduct a program of basic research to identify, characterize, and quantify risks to human health from air pollutants. Such research shall be conducted primarily through a combination of university and medical school-based grants, as well as through intramural studies and contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe139af5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences shall conduct a program for the education and training of physicians in environmental health.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe139af6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Director shall assure that such programs shall not conflict with research undertaken by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe139af7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139af8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of research</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall develop and implement a plan for identifying areas in which activities authorized under this section can be carried out in conjunction with other Federal ecological and air pollution research efforts. The plan, which shall be submitted to Congress within 6 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139af9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an assessment of ambient monitoring stations and networks to determine cost effective ways to expand monitoring capabilities in both urban and rural environments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139afa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a consideration of the extent of the feasibility and scientific value of conducting the research program under subsection (e) to include consideration of the effects of atmospheric processes and air pollution effects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139afb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a methodology for evaluating and ranking pollution prevention technologies, such as those developed under subsection (g), in terms of their ability to reduce cost effectively the emissions of air pollutants and other airborne chemicals of concern.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, and every 4 years thereafter, the Administrator shall report to Congress on the progress made in implementing the plan developed under this subsection, and shall include in such report any revisions of the plan.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139afc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuation of national acid precipitation assessment program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe139afd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The acid precipitation research program set forth in the Acid Precipitation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8901">42 U.S.C. 8901</ref> et seq.] shall be continued with modifications pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe139afe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Acid Precipitation Task Force shall consist of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and such additional members as the President may select. The President shall appoint a chairman for the Task Force from among its members within 30 days after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe139aff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The responsibilities of the Task Force shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139b00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Review of the status of research activities conducted to date under the comprehensive research plan developed pursuant to the Acid Precipitation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8901">42 U.S.C. 8901</ref> et seq.], and development of a revised plan that identifies significant research gaps and establishes a coordinated program to address current and future research priorities. A draft of the revised plan shall be submitted by the Task Force to Congress within 6 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>. The plan shall be available for public comment during the 60 day period after its submission, and a final plan shall be submitted by the President to the Congress within 45 days after the close of the comment period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139b01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Coordination with participating Federal agencies, augmenting the agencies’ research and monitoring efforts and sponsoring additional research in the scientific community as necessary to ensure the availability and quality of data and methodologies needed to evaluate the status and effectiveness of the acid deposition control program. Such research and monitoring efforts shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> continuous monitoring of emissions of precursors of acid deposition;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> maintenance, upgrading, and application of models, such as the Regional Acid Deposition Model, that describe the interactions of emissions with the atmosphere, and models that describe the response of ecosystems to acid deposition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> analysis of the costs, benefits, and effectiveness of the acid deposition control program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139b05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Publication and maintenance of a National Acid Lakes Registry that tracks the condition and change over time of a statistically representative sample of lakes in regions that are known to be sensitive to surface water acidification.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139b06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Submission every two years of a unified budget recommendation to the President for activities of the Federal Government in connection with the research program described in this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139b07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> Beginning in 1992 and biennially thereafter, submission of a report to Congress describing the results of its investigations and analyses. The reporting of technical information about acid deposition shall be provided in a format that facilitates communication with policymakers and the public. The report shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> actual and projected emissions and acid deposition trends;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> average ambient concentrations of acid deposition percursors <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003584">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003584"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “precursors”.</note> and their transformation products;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the status of ecosystems (including forests and surface waters), materials, and visibility affected by acid deposition;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the causes and effects of such deposition, including changes in surface water quality and forest and soil conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/E/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the occurrence and effects of episodic acidification, particularly with respect to high elevation watersheds; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/E/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the confidence level associated with each conclusion to aid policymakers in use of the information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe139b0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> Beginning in 1996, and every 4 years thereafter, the report under subparagraph (E) shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the reduction in deposition rates that must be achieved in order to prevent adverse ecological effects; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe139b10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/j/3/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the costs and benefits of the acid deposition control program created by subchapter IV–A of this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe139b11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7403/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Air pollution conferences</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, in the judgment of the Administrator, an air pollution problem of substantial significance may result from discharge or discharges into the atmosphere, the Administrator may call a conference concerning this potential air pollution problem to be held in or near one or more of the places where such discharge or discharges are occurring or will occur. All interested persons shall be given an opportunity to be heard at such conference, either orally or in writing, and shall be permitted to appear in person or by representative in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Administrator. If the Administrator finds, on the basis of the evidence presented at such conference, that the discharge or discharges if permitted to take place or continue are likely to cause or contribute to air pollution subject to abatement under this part, the Administrator shall send such findings, together with recommendations concerning the measures which the Administrator finds reasonable and suitable to prevent such pollution, to the person or persons whose actions will result in the discharge or discharges involved; to air pollution agencies of the State or States and of the municipality or municipalities where such discharge or discharges will originate; and to the interstate air pollution control agency, if any, in the jurisdictional area of which any such municipality is located. Such findings and recommendations shall be advisory only, but shall be admitted together with the record of the conference, as part of the proceedings under subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7408">section 7408 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe139b12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 103, formerly § 3, as added <ref href="/us/pl/88/206/s1">Pub. L. 88–206, § 1</ref>, <date date="1963-12-17">Dec. 17, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/394">77 Stat. 394</ref>; renumbered § 103 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tI">Pub. L. 89–272, title I</ref>, §§ 101(3), 103, <date date="1965-10-20">Oct. 20, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/992">79 Stat. 992</ref>, 996; <ref href="/us/pl/90/148/s2">Pub. L. 90–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="1967-11-21">Nov. 21, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/486">81 Stat. 486</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref>, §§ 2(a), 4(2), 15(a)(2), (c)(2), <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1676">84 Stat. 1676</ref>, 1689, 1710, 1713; <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 95–95, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/686">91 Stat. 686</ref>, 687; <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIX/s901/a">Pub. L. 101–549, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2700-2703">104 Stat. 2700–2703</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dS/s102/b">Pub. L. 116–260, div. S, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2243">134 Stat. 2243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe139b13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe139b14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe139b15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, referred to in subsec. (g)(6)(B)(vi), is <ref href="/us/pl/92/463/s14">section 14 of Pub. L. 92–463</ref>, which was set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref>, §§ 3(a), 7, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4204">136 Stat. 4204</ref>, 4361.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Acid Precipitation Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (j)(1), (3)(A), is title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/96/294">Pub. L. 96–294</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/770">94 Stat. 770</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 97 (§ 8901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8901">section 8901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe139b16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b)(4), “section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31 and <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “sections 3648 and 3709 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s529">31 U.S.C. 529</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, which Act enacted Title 31, Money and Finance, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857b">section 1857b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbe139b17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in subsec. (a)(3) of this section were contained in subsec. (a) of a prior <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857b">section 1857b of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360/s3">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/322">69 Stat. 322</ref>, as amended <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/87/761/s2">Pub. L. 87–761, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/760">76 Stat. 760</ref>, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/88/206">Pub. L. 88–206</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in prior sections 1857a to 1857d of this title, <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, §§ 2 to 5, <ref href="/us/stat/69/322">69 Stat. 322</ref> (section 1857b as amended <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/87/761/s2">Pub. L. 87–761, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/760">76 Stat. 760</ref>; section 1857d as amended <date date="1959-09-22">Sept. 22, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/365/s1">Pub. L. 86–365, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/646">73 Stat. 646</ref> and <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/87/761/s1">Pub. L. 87–761, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/760">76 Stat. 760</ref>), prior to the general amendment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/88/206">Pub. L. 88–206</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe139b18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s102/b/1">Pub. L. 116–260, § 102(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “precursors” for “percursors” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s102/b/2/C/iii">Pub. L. 116–260, § 102(b)(2)(C)(iii)</ref>, designated first sentence of introductory provisions as par. (1) and inserted heading. Former par. (1) redesignated subpar. (A) of par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s102/b/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 116–260, § 102(b)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, designated second sentence of introductory provisions as par. (2), inserted heading, substituted “Such strategies and technologies described in paragraph (1) shall be developed” for “Such strategies and technologies shall be developed”, and inserted “States, institutions of higher education,” after “scientists,”. Former par. (2) redesignated subpar. (B) of par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s102/b/2/C/i">Pub. L. 116–260, § 102(b)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, designated third sentence of introductory provisions as par. (3), inserted heading, and substituted “The program under this subsection” for “Such program”. Former par. (3) redesignated subpar. (C) of par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3)(A) to (D). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s102/b/2/A">Pub. L. 116–260, § 102(b)(2)(A)</ref>, redesignated pars. (1) to (4) of subsec. (g) as subpars. (A) to (D), respectively, of par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s102/b/2/B">Pub. L. 116–260, § 102(b)(2)(B)</ref>, designated first and second sentences of concluding provisions as pars. (4) and (5), respectively, and inserted headings. Former par. (4) redesignated subpar. (D) of par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s102/b/2/D">Pub. L. 116–260, § 102(b)(2)(D)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s901/a/1">Pub. L. 101–549, § 901(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “(including health and welfare effects)” after “effects”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s901/a/2">Pub. L. 101–549, § 901(a)(2)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (b) by adding par. (8) at end, was executed by adding par. (8) after par. (7) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s901/b">Pub. L. 101–549, § 901(b)</ref>, amended subsecs. (c) to (f) generally, substituting present provisions for provisions which related to: in subsec. (c), results of other scientific studies; in subsec. (d), construction of facilities; in subsec. (e), potential air pollution problems, conferences, and findings and recommendations of the Administrator; and, in subsec. (f), accelerated research programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s901/c">Pub. L. 101–549, § 901(c)</ref>, added subsecs. (g) to (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s101/b">Pub. L. 95–95, § 101(b)</ref>, struck out reference to “training” in par. (1) and added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s101/a">Pub. L. 95–95, § 101(a)</ref>, struck out par. (5) which provided for training and training grants to personnel of air pollution control agencies and other persons with suitable qualifications, redesignated pars. (6), (7), and (8) as (5), (6), and (7), respectively, and, following par. (7) as so redesignated, inserted provisions directing the Administrator, in carrying out subsec. (a), to provide training for, and make training grants to, personnel of air pollution control agencies and other persons with suitable qualifications and to make grants to such agencies, to other public or nonprofit private agencies, institutions, and organizations for the purposes stated in subsec. (a)(5) and allowing reasonable fees to be charged for such training provided to persons other than personnel of air pollution control agencies but requiring that such training be provided to such personnel of air pollution control agencies without charge.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s15/c/2">Pub. L. 91–604, § 15(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s15/c/2">Pub. L. 91–604, § 15(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary” and “Environmental Protection Agency” for “Department of Health, Education, and Welfare”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s15/a/2">Pub. L. 91–604, § 15(a)(2)</ref>, (c)(2), substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary” and “air pollutants” for “air pollution agents (or combinations of agents)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s15/c/2">Pub. L. 91–604, § 15(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s15/c/2">Pub. L. 91–604, § 15(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary” wherever appearing, substituted “7415” for “7415(a)”, and inserted references to subsecs. (b) and (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7415">section 7415 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s2/a">Pub. L. 91–604, § 2(a)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/148">Pub. L. 90–148</ref> substituted “establish technical advisory committees composed of recognized experts in various aspects of air pollution to assist in the examination and evaluation of research progress and proposals and to avoid duplication of research” for “initiate and conduct a program of research directed toward the development of improved, low-cost techniques for extracting sulfur from fuels” as cl. (4) and struck out cl. (5) which related to research programs relating to the control of hydrocarbon emissions from evaporation of gasoline and nitrogen and aldehyde oxide emission from gasoline and diesel powered vehicles and relating to the development of improved low-cost techniques to reduce emissions of oxides of sulfur produced by the combustion of sulfur-containing fuels.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/148">Pub. L. 90–148</ref> struck out provision for promulgation of criteria in the case of particular air pollution agents present in the air in certain quantities reflecting the latest scientific knowledge and allowing for availability and revision and provided for recommendation by Secretary of air quality criteria.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/90/148">Pub. L. 90–148</ref> substituted references to subsections (d), (e), and (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7415">section 7415 of this title</ref> for references to subsections (c), (d), and (e) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7415">section 7415 of this title</ref> in provision for admission of advisory findings and recommendations together with the record of the conference and made such findings and recommendations part of the proceedings of the conference, not merely part of the record of proceedings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/89/272/s103/3">Pub. L. 89–272, § 103(3)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/272/s103/4">Pub. L. 89–272, § 103(4)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe139b19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe139b1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (i) of this section requiring quadrennial reports to Congress and of reporting provisions in subsec. (j)(3)(E) and (F) of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and the 7th and 8th items on page 163 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other Actions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All rules, regulations, orders, determinations, contracts, certifications, authorizations, delegations, or other actions duly issued, made, or taken by or pursuant to act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>] to continue in full force and effect until modified or rescinded in accordance with act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [this chapter], see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b1d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b1e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Design Programs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/246/dB/tII/s2603">Pub. L. 106–246, div. B, title II, § 2603</ref>, <date date="2000-07-13">July 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/558">114 Stat. 558</ref>, required the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make grants to carry out a 2-year program to implement in five metropolitan areas pilot design programs and report to Congress on the results not later than 360 days from first day of the second year of the 2-year program.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b1f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Acid Lakes Registry</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIV/s405">Pub. L. 101–549, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2632">104 Stat. 2632</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/549/tIV/s405">“The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall create a National Acid Lakes Registry that shall list, to the extent practical, all lakes that are known to be acidified due to acid deposition, and shall publish such list within one year of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>]. Lakes shall be added to the registry as they become acidic or as data becomes available to show they are acidic. Lakes shall be deleted from the registry as they become nonacidic.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b20-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assessment of International Air Pollution Control Technologies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIX/s901/e">Pub. L. 101–549, title IX, § 901(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2706">104 Stat. 2706</ref>, directed Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study that compares international air pollution control technologies of selected industrialized countries to determine if there exist air pollution control technologies in countries outside the United States that may have beneficial applications to this Nation’s air pollution control efforts, including, with respect to each country studied, the topics of urban air quality, motor vehicle emissions, toxic air emissions, and acid deposition, and within 2 years after <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, submit to Congress a report detailing the results of such study.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Western States Acid Deposition Research</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIX/s901/g">Pub. L. 101–549, title IX, § 901(g)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2707">104 Stat. 2707</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/549/tIX/s901/g">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall sponsor monitoring and research and submit to Congress annual and periodic assessment reports on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the occurrence and effects of acid deposition on surface waters located in that part of the United States west of the Mississippi River;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the occurrence and effects of acid deposition on high elevation ecosystems (including forests, and surface waters); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the occurrence and effects of episodic acidification, particularly with respect to high elevation watersheds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall analyze data generated from the studies conducted under paragraph (1), data from the Western Lakes Survey, and other appropriate research and utilize predictive modeling techniques that take into account the unique geographic, climatological, and atmospheric conditions which exist in the western United States to determine the potential occurrence and effects of acid deposition due to any projected increases in the emission of sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides in that part of the United States located west of the Mississippi River. The Administrator shall include the results of the project conducted under this paragraph in the reports issued to Congress under paragraph (1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Consultation With and Transmission of Reports and Studies to Congressional Committee</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI/s101/c">Pub. L. 95–95, title I, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/687">91 Stat. 687</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/95/tI/s101/c">“The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall consult with the House Committee on Science and Technology [now Committee on Science, Space, and Technology] on the environmental and atmospheric research, development, and demonstration aspects of this Act [see Short Title of 1977 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>]. In addition, the reports and studies required by this Act that relate to research, development, and demonstration issues shall be transmitted to the Committee on Science and Technology [now Committee on Science, Space, and Technology] at the same time they are made available to other committees of the Congress.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe139b23-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Substances Discharged From Exhausts of Motor Vehicles</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/86/493">Pub. L. 86–493</ref>, <date date="1960-06-08">June 8, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/162">74 Stat. 162</ref>, directed Surgeon General of Public Health Service to conduct a thorough study for purposes of determining, with respect to the various substances discharged from exhausts of motor vehicles, the amounts and kinds of such substances which, from the standpoint of human health, it is safe for motor vehicles to discharge into the atmosphere under the various conditions under which such vehicles may operate, and, not later than two years after <date date="1960-06-08">June 8, 1960</date>, submit to Congress a report on results of the study, together with such recommendations, if any, based upon the findings made in such study, as he deemed necessary for the protection of the public health.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
