<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe15e54b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7406"><num value="7406">§ 7406.</num><heading> Interstate air quality agencies; program cost limitations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of developing implementation plans for any interstate air quality control region designated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407">section 7407 of this title</ref> or of implementing <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7506a">section 7506a of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate air pollution) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511c">section 7511c of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate ozone pollution), the Administrator is authorized to pay, for two years, up to 100 per centum of the air quality planning program costs of any commission established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7506a">section 7506a of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate air pollution) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511c">section 7511c of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate ozone pollution) or any agency designated by the Governors of the affected States, which agency shall be capable of recommending to the Governors plans for implementation of national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards and shall include representation from the States and appropriate political subdivisions within the air quality control region. After the initial two-year period the Administrator is authorized to make grants to such agency or such commission in an amount up to three-fifths of the air quality implementation program costs of such agency or commission.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbe15e54c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 106, as added <ref href="/us/pl/90/148/s2">Pub. L. 90–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="1967-11-21">Nov. 21, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/490">81 Stat. 490</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s3/c">Pub. L. 91–604, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1677">84 Stat. 1677</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s102/f/2">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 102(f)(2)</ref>, title VIII, § 802(f), <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2420">104 Stat. 2420</ref>, 2688.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe15e54d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe15e54e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe15e54f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857c–1">section 1857c–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbe15e550-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 106 of act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, was renumbered section 117 by <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref> and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7417">section 7417 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe15e551-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s102/f/2/A">Pub. L. 101–549, § 102(f)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “or of implementing <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7506a">section 7506a of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate air pollution) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511c">section 7511c of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate ozone pollution)” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407">section 7407 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s102/f/2/B">Pub. L. 101–549, § 102(f)(2)(B)</ref>, which directed insertion of “any commission established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7506a">section 7506a of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate air pollution) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511c">section 7511c of this title</ref> (relating to control of interstate ozone pollution) or” after “program costs of”, was executed by making the insertion after that phrase the first place it appeared to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s102/f/2/C">Pub. L. 101–549, § 102(f)(2)(C)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or such commission” after “such agency” in last sentence, was executed by making insertion after “such agency” the first place it appeared in the last sentence to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/549">Pub. L. 101–549</ref>, §§ 102(f)(2)(D), 802(f), substituted “three-fifths of the air quality implementation program costs of such agency or commission” for “three-fourths of the air quality planning program costs of such agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref> struck out designation “(a)”, substituted provisions authorizing Federal grants for the purpose of developing implementation plans and provisions requiring the designated State agency to be capable of recommending plans for implementation of national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards, for provisions authorizing Federal grants for the purpose of expediting the establishment of air quality standards and provisions requiring the designated State agency to be capable of recommending standards of air quality and plans for implementation thereof, respectively, and struck out subsec. (b) which authorized establishment of air quality planning commissions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
