<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe15e552-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407"><num value="7407">§ 7407.</num><heading> Air quality control regions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e553-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibility of each State for air quality; submission of implementation plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State shall have the primary responsibility for assuring air quality within the entire geographic area comprising such State by submitting an implementation plan for such State which will specify the manner in which national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards will be achieved and maintained within each air quality control region in such State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e554-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Designated regions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of developing and carrying out implementation plans under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410">section 7410 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e555-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an air quality control region designated under this section before <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, or a region designated after such date under subsection (c), shall be an air quality control region; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e556-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the portion of such State which is not part of any such designated region shall be an air quality control region, but such portion may be subdivided by the State into two or more air quality control regions with the approval of the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e557-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Administrator to designate regions; notification of Governors of affected States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall, within 90 days after <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, after consultation with appropriate State and local authorities, designate as an air quality control region any interstate area or major intrastate area which he deems necessary or appropriate for the attainment and maintenance of ambient air quality standards. The Administrator shall immediately notify the Governors of the affected States of any designation made under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e558-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Designations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e559-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Designations generally</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e55a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission by Governors of initial designations following promulgation of new or revised standards</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">By such date as the Administrator may reasonably require, but not later than 1 year after promulgation of a new or revised national ambient air quality standard for any pollutant under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7409">section 7409 of this title</ref>, the Governor of each State shall (and at any other time the Governor of a State deems appropriate the Governor may) submit to the Administrator a list of all areas (or portions thereof) in the State, designating as—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe15e55b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> nonattainment, any area that does not meet (or that contributes to ambient air quality in a nearby area that does not meet) the national primary or secondary ambient air quality standard for the pollutant,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe15e55c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> attainment, any area (other than an area identified in clause (i)) that meets the national primary or secondary ambient air quality standard for the pollutant, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe15e55d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> unclassifiable, any area that cannot be classified on the basis of available information as meeting or not meeting the national primary or secondary ambient air quality standard for the pollutant.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The Administrator may not require the Governor to submit the required list sooner than 120 days after promulgating a new or revised national ambient air quality standard.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e55e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation by EPA of designations</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e55f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Upon promulgation or revision of a national ambient air quality standard, the Administrator shall promulgate the designations of all areas (or portions thereof) submitted under subparagraph (A) as expeditiously as practicable, but in no case later than 2 years from the date of promulgation of the new or revised national ambient air quality standard. Such period may be extended for up to one year in the event the Administrator has insufficient information to promulgate the designations.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e560-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> In making the promulgations required under clause (i), the Administrator may make such modifications as the Administrator deems necessary to the designations of the areas (or portions thereof) submitted under subparagraph (A) (including to the boundaries of such areas or portions thereof). Whenever the Administrator intends to make a modification, the Administrator shall notify the State and provide such State with an opportunity to demonstrate why any proposed modification is inappropriate. The Administrator shall give such notification no later than 120 days before the date the Administrator promulgates the designation, including any modification thereto. If the Governor fails to submit the list in whole or in part, as required under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall promulgate the designation that the Administrator deems appropriate for any area (or portion thereof) not designated by the State.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e561-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> If the Governor of any State, on the Governor’s own motion, under subparagraph (A), submits a list of areas (or portions thereof) in the State designated as nonattainment, attainment, or unclassifiable, the Administrator shall act on such designations in accordance with the procedures under paragraph (3) (relating to redesignation).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e562-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> A designation for an area (or portion thereof) made pursuant to this subsection shall remain in effect until the area (or portion thereof) is redesignated pursuant to paragraph (3) or (4).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e563-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Designations by operation of law</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e564-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any area designated with respect to any air pollutant under the provisions of paragraph (1)(A), (B), or (C) of this subsection (as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>) is designated, by operation of law, as a nonattainment area for such pollutant within the meaning of subparagraph (A)(i).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e565-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any area designated with respect to any air pollutant under the provisions of paragraph (1)(E) (as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>) is designated by operation of law, as an attainment area for such pollutant within the meaning of subparagraph (A)(ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e566-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Any area designated with respect to any air pollutant under the provisions of paragraph (1)(D) (as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>) is designated, by operation of law, as an unclassifiable area for such pollutant within the meaning of subparagraph (A)(iii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e567-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of designations and redesignations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e568-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator shall publish a notice in the Federal Register promulgating any designation under paragraph (1) or (5), or announcing any designation under paragraph (4), or promulgating any redesignation under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e569-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Promulgation or announcement of a designation under paragraph (1), (4) or (5) shall not be subject to the provisions of sections 553 through 557 of title 5 (relating to notice and comment), except nothing herein shall be construed as precluding such public notice and comment whenever possible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e56a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Redesignation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e56b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Subject to the requirements of subparagraph (E), and on the basis of air quality data, planning and control considerations, or any other air quality-related considerations the Administrator deems appropriate, the Administrator may at any time notify the Governor of any State that available information indicates that the designation of any area or portion of an area within the State or interstate area should be revised. In issuing such notification, which shall be public, to the Governor, the Administrator shall provide such information as the Administrator may have available explaining the basis for the notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e56c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> No later than 120 days after receiving a notification under subparagraph (A), the Governor shall submit to the Administrator such redesignation, if any, of the appropriate area (or areas) or portion thereof within the State or interstate area, as the Governor considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e56d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> No later than 120 days after the date described in subparagraph (B) (or paragraph (1)(B)(iii)), the Administrator shall promulgate the redesignation, if any, of the area or portion thereof, submitted by the Governor in accordance with subparagraph (B), making such modifications as the Administrator may deem necessary, in the same manner and under the same procedure as is applicable under clause (ii) of paragraph (1)(B), except that the phrase “60 days” shall be substituted for the phrase “120 days” in that clause. If the Governor does not submit, in accordance with subparagraph (B), a redesignation for an area (or portion thereof) identified by the Administrator under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall promulgate such redesignation, if any, that the Administrator deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e56e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Governor of any State may, on the Governor’s own motion, submit to the Administrator a revised designation of any area or portion thereof within the State. Within 18 months of receipt of a complete State redesignation submittal, the Administrator shall approve or deny such redesignation. The submission of a redesignation by a Governor shall not affect the effectiveness or enforceability of the applicable implementation plan for the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e56f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> The Administrator may not promulgate a redesignation of a nonattainment area (or portion thereof) to attainment unless—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e570-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Administrator determines that the area has attained the national ambient air quality standard;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e571-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Administrator has fully approved the applicable implementation plan for the area under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k">section 7410(k) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e572-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the Administrator determines that the improvement in air quality is due to permanent and enforceable reductions in emissions resulting from implementation of the applicable implementation plan and applicable Federal air pollutant control regulations and other permanent and enforceable reductions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e573-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the Administrator has fully approved a maintenance plan for the area as meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7505a">section 7505a of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e574-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/E/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the State containing such area has met all requirements applicable to the area under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410">section 7410 of this title</ref> and part D.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe15e575-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The Administrator shall not promulgate any redesignation of any area (or portion thereof) from nonattainment to unclassifiable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e576-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonattainment designations for ozone, carbon monoxide and particulate matter (PM–10)</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e577-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Ozone and carbon monoxide</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e578-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Within 120 days after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, each Governor of each State shall submit to the Administrator a list that designates, affirms or reaffirms the designation of, or redesignates (as the case may be), all areas (or portions thereof) of the Governor’s State as attainment, nonattainment, or unclassifiable with respect to the national ambient air quality standards for ozone and carbon monoxide.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e579-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> No later than 120 days after the date the Governor is required to submit the list of areas (or portions thereof) required under clause (i) of this subparagraph, the Administrator shall promulgate such designations, making such modifications as the Administrator may deem necessary, in the same manner, and under the same procedure, as is applicable under clause (ii) of paragraph (1)(B), except that the phrase “60 days” shall be substituted for the phrase “120 days” in that clause. If the Governor does not submit, in accordance with clause (i) of this subparagraph, a designation for an area (or portion thereof), the Administrator shall promulgate the designation that the Administrator deems appropriate.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e57a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> No nonattainment area may be redesignated as an attainment area under this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e57b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(C)(ii) of this subsection, if an ozone or carbon monoxide nonattainment area located within a metropolitan statistical area or consolidated metropolitan statistical area (as established by the Bureau of the Census) is classified under part D of this subchapter as a Serious, Severe, or Extreme Area, the boundaries of such area are hereby revised (on the date 45 days after such classification) by operation of law to include the entire metropolitan statistical area or consolidated metropolitan statistical area, as the case may be, unless within such 45-day period the Governor (in consultation with State and local air pollution control agencies) notifies the Administrator that additional time is necessary to evaluate the application of clause (v). Whenever a Governor has submitted such a notice to the Administrator, such boundary revision shall occur on the later of the date 8 months after such classification or 14 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, unless the Governor makes the finding referred to in clause (v), and the Administrator concurs in such finding, within such period. Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, a boundary revision under this clause or clause (v) shall apply for purposes of any State implementation plan revision required to be submitted after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe15e57c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Whenever the Governor of a State has submitted a notice under clause (iv), the Governor, in consultation with State and local air pollution control agencies, shall undertake a study to evaluate whether the entire metropolitan statistical area or consolidated metropolitan statistical area should be included within the nonattainment area. Whenever a Governor finds and demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator, and the Administrator concurs in such finding, that with respect to a portion of a metropolitan statistical area or consolidated metropolitan statistical area, sources in the portion do not contribute significantly to violation of the national ambient air quality standard, the Administrator shall approve the Governor’s request to exclude such portion from the nonattainment area. In making such finding, the Governor and the Administrator shall consider factors such as population density, traffic congestion, commercial development, industrial development, meteorological conditions, and pollution transport.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e57d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> PM–10 designations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">By operation of law, until redesignation by the Administrator pursuant to paragraph (3)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe15e57e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> each area identified in 52 Federal Register 29383 (<date date="1987-08-07">Aug. 7, 1987</date>) as a Group I area (except to the extent that such identification was modified by the Administrator before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>) is designated nonattainment for PM–10;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe15e57f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any area containing a site for which air quality monitoring data show a violation of the national ambient air quality standard for PM–10 before <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date> (as determined under part 50, appendix K of title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations) is hereby designated nonattainment for PM–10; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe15e580-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> each area not described in clause (i) or (ii) is hereby designated unclassifiable for PM–10.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">Any designation for particulate matter (measured in terms of total suspended particulates) that the Administrator promulgated pursuant to this subsection (as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>) shall remain in effect for purposes of implementing the maximum allowable increases in concentrations of particulate matter (measured in terms of total suspended particulates) pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7473/b">section 7473(b) of this title</ref>, until the Administrator determines that such designation is no longer necessary for that purpose.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e581-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Designations for lead</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator may, in the Administrator’s discretion at any time the Administrator deems appropriate, require a State to designate areas (or portions thereof) with respect to the national ambient air quality standard for lead in effect as of <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, in accordance with the procedures under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1), except that in applying subparagraph (B)(i) of paragraph (1) the phrase “2 years from the date of promulgation of the new or revised national ambient air quality standard” shall be replaced by the phrase “1 year from the date the Administrator notifies the State of the requirement to designate areas with respect to the standard for lead”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e582-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Designations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e583-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than <date date="2004-02-15">February 15, 2004</date>, the Governor of each State shall submit designations referred to in paragraph (1) for the July 1997 PM<sub>2.5</sub> national ambient air quality standards for each area within the State, based on air quality monitoring data collected in accordance with any applicable Federal reference methods for the relevant areas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e584-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>, the Administrator shall, consistent with paragraph (1), promulgate the designations referred to in subparagraph (A) for each area of each State for the July 1997 PM<sub>2.5</sub> national ambient air quality standards.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e585-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation plan for regional haze</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e586-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 3 years after the date on which the Administrator promulgates the designations referred to in paragraph (6)(B) for a State, the State shall submit, for the entire State, the State implementation plan revisions to meet the requirements promulgated by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7492/e/1">section 7492(e)(1) of this title</ref> (referred to in this paragraph as “regional haze requirements”).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e587-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> No preclusion of other provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph precludes the implementation of the agreements and recommendations stemming from the Grand Canyon Visibility Transport Commission Report dated June 1996, including the submission of State implementation plan revisions by the States of Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, Utah, or Wyoming by <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>, for implementation of regional haze requirements applicable to those States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe15e588-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Redesignation of air quality control regions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe15e589-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2), the Governor of each State is authorized, with the approval of the Administrator, to redesignate from time to time the air quality control regions within such State for purposes of efficient and effective air quality management. Upon such redesignation, the list under subsection (d) shall be modified accordingly.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe15e58a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of an air quality control region in a State, or part of such region, which the Administrator finds may significantly affect air pollution concentrations in another State, the Governor of the State in which such region, or part of a region, is located may redesignate from time to time the boundaries of so much of such air quality control region as is located within such State only with the approval of the Administrator and with the consent of all Governors of all States which the Administrator determines may be significantly affected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe15e58b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7407/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No compliance date extension granted under section 7413(d)(5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003589">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003589"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title (relating to coal conversion) shall cease to be effective by reason of the regional limitation provided in section 7413(d)(5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003589">1</ref> of this title if the violation of such limitation is due solely to a redesignation of a region under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe15e58c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 107, as added <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s4/a">Pub. L. 91–604, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1678">84 Stat. 1678</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI/s103">Pub. L. 95–95, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/687">91 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2399">104 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dG/tIV/s425/a">Pub. L. 108–199, div. G, title IV, § 425(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/417">118 Stat. 417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe15e58d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe15e58e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe15e58f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7413">Section 7413 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (e)(3), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 101–549, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2672">104 Stat. 2672</ref>, and, as so amended, subsec. (d) of section 7413 no longer relates to final compliance orders.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe15e590-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857c–2">section 1857c–2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbe15e591-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 107 of act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as added <date date="1967-11-21">Nov. 21, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/90/148/s2">Pub. L. 90–148, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/490">81 Stat. 490</ref>, related to air quality control regions and was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857c–2">section 1857c–2 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 107 of act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as added <date date="1963-12-17">Dec. 17, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/88/206/s1">Pub. L. 88–206, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/399">77 Stat. 399</ref>, was renumbered section 111 by <ref href="/us/pl/90/148">Pub. L. 90–148</ref> and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe15e592-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (d)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/108/199">Pub. L. 108–199</ref> added pars. (6) and (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549">Pub. L. 101–549</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally, substituting present provisions for provisions which required States to submit lists of regions not in compliance on <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, with certain air quality standards to be submitted to the Administrator, and which authorized States to revise and resubmit such lists from time to time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> added subsecs. (d) and (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe15e593-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe15e594-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe15e595-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Ozone and Particulate Matter Standards</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dG/tIV/s425/b">Pub. L. 108–199, div. G, title IV, § 425(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/417">118 Stat. 417</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/199/dG/tIV/s425/b">“Except as provided in paragraphs (6) and (7) of section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act [subsec. (d)(6), (7) of this section] (as added by subsection (a)), section 6101, subsections (a) and (b) of section 6102, and section 6103 of the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century [<ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407">42 U.S.C. 7407</ref> note; <ref href="/us/stat/112/463">112 Stat. 463</ref>), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>], shall remain in effect.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tVI">Pub. L. 105–178, title VI</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/463">112 Stat. 463</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tVI/s6012/a">Pub. L. 109–59, title VI, § 6012(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1882">119 Stat. 1882</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/59/tVI/s6012/a">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6101">“SEC. 6101.</num><heading> FINDINGS AND PURPOSE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> there is a lack of air quality monitoring data for fine particle levels, measured as PM<sub>2.5</sub>, in the United States and the States should receive full funding for the monitoring efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> such data would provide a basis for designating areas as attainment or nonattainment for any PM<sub>2.5</sub> national ambient air quality standards pursuant to the standards promulgated in July 1997;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the President of the United States directed the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (referred to in this title as the ‘Administrator’) in a memorandum dated <date date="1997-07-16">July 16, 1997</date>, to complete the next periodic review of the particulate matter national ambient air quality standards by July 2002 in order to determine ‘whether to revise or maintain the standards’;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Administrator has stated that 3 years of air quality monitoring data for fine particle levels, measured as PM<sub>2.5</sub> and performed in accordance with any applicable Federal reference methods, is appropriate for designating areas as attainment or nonattainment pursuant to the July 1997 promulgated standards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the Administrator has acknowledged that in drawing boundaries for attainment and nonattainment areas for the July 1997 ozone national air quality standards, Governors would benefit from considering implementation guidance from EPA on drawing area boundaries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The purposes of this title are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to ensure that 3 years of air quality monitoring data regarding fine particle levels are gathered for use in the determination of area attainment or nonattainment designations respecting any PM<sub>2.5</sub> national ambient air quality standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to ensure that the Governors have adequate time to consider implementation guidance from EPA on drawing area boundaries prior to submitting area designations respecting the July 1997 ozone national ambient air quality standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to ensure that the schedule for implementation of the July 1997 revisions of the ambient air quality standards for particulate matter and the schedule for the Environmental Protection Agency’s visibility regulations related to regional haze are consistent with the timetable for implementation of such particulate matter standards as set forth in the President’s Implementation Memorandum dated <date date="1997-07-16">July 16, 1997</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6102">“SEC. 6102.</num><heading> PARTICULATE MATTER MONITORING PROGRAM.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Through grants under section 103 of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7403">42 U.S.C. 7403</ref>] the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall use appropriated funds no later than fiscal year 2000 to fund 100 percent of the cost of the establishment, purchase, operation and maintenance of a PM<sub>2.5</sub> monitoring network necessary to implement the national ambient air quality standards for PM<sub>2.5</sub> under section 109 of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</ref>]. This implementation shall not result in a diversion or reprogramming of funds from other Federal, State or local Clean Air Act activities. Any funds previously diverted or reprogrammed from section 105 Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7405">42 U.S.C. 7405</ref>] grants for PM<sub>2.5</sub> monitors must be restored to State or local air programs in fiscal year 1999.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> EPA and the States, consistent with their respective authorities under the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.], shall ensure that the national network (designated in subsection (a)) which consists of the PM<sub>2.5</sub> monitors necessary to implement the national ambient air quality standards is established by <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Governors shall be required to submit designations referred to in section 107(d)(1) of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)(1)</ref>] for each area following promulgation of the July 1997 PM<sub>2.5</sub> national ambient air quality standard within 1 year after receipt of 3 years of air quality monitoring data performed in accordance with any applicable Federal reference methods for the relevant areas. Only data from the monitoring network designated in subsection (a) and other Federal reference method PM<sub>2.5</sub> monitors shall be considered for such designations. Nothing in the previous sentence shall be construed as affecting the Governor’s authority to designate an area initially as nonattainment, and the Administrator’s authority to promulgate the designation of an area as nonattainment, under section 107(d)(1) of the Clean Air Act, based on its contribution to ambient air quality in a nearby nonattainment area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> For any area designated as nonattainment for the July 1997 PM<sub>2.5</sub> national ambient air quality standard in accordance with the schedule set forth in this section, notwithstanding the time limit prescribed in paragraph (2) of section 169B(e) of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7492/e/2">42 U.S.C. 7492(e)(2)</ref>], the Administrator shall require State implementation plan revisions referred to in such paragraph (2) to be submitted at the same time as State implementation plan revisions referred to in section 172 of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7502">42 U.S.C. 7502</ref>] implementing the revised national ambient air quality standard for fine particulate matter are required to be submitted. For any area designated as attainment or unclassifiable for such standard, the Administrator shall require the State implementation plan revisions referred to in such paragraph (2) to be submitted 1 year after the area has been so designated. The preceding provisions of this paragraph shall not preclude the implementation of the agreements and recommendations set forth in the Grand Canyon Visibility Transport Commission Report dated June 1996.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The Administrator shall promulgate the designations referred to in section 107(d)(1) of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)(1)</ref>] for each area following promulgation of the July 1997 PM<sub>2.5</sub> national ambient air quality standard by the earlier of 1 year after the initial designations required under subsection (c)(1) are required to be submitted or <date date="2005-12-31">December 31, 2005</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Field Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the SAFETEA–LU [<date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>], the Administrator shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> conduct a field study of the ability of the PM<sub>2.5</sub> Federal Reference Method to differentiate those particles that are larger than 2.5 micrometers in diameter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> develop a Federal reference method to measure directly particles that are larger than 2.5 micrometers in diameter without reliance on subtracting from coarse particle measurements those particles that are equal to or smaller than 2.5 micrometers in diameter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> develop a method of measuring the composition of coarse particles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> submit a report on the study and responsibilities of the Administrator under paragraphs (1) through (3) to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6103">“SEC. 6103.</num><heading> OZONE DESIGNATION REQUIREMENTS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Governors shall be required to submit the designations referred to in section 107(d)(1) of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/1">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)(1)</ref>] within 2 years following the promulgation of the July 1997 ozone national ambient air quality standards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Administrator shall promulgate final designations no later than 1 year after the designations required under subsection (a) are required to be submitted.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6104">“SEC. 6104.</num><heading> ADDITIONAL PROVISIONS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Nothing in sections 6101 through 6103 shall be construed by the Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency or any court, State, or person to affect any pending litigation or to be a ratification of the ozone or PM<sub>2.5</sub> standards.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe15e596-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pending Actions and Proceedings</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Suits, actions, and other proceedings lawfully commenced by or against the Administrator or any other officer or employee of the United States in his official capacity or in relation to the discharge of his official duties under act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>], not to abate by reason of the taking effect of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/a">section 406(a) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe185597-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other Actions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All rules, regulations, orders, determinations, contracts, certifications, authorizations, delegations, or other actions duly issued, made, or taken by or pursuant to act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>] to continue in full force and effect until modified or rescinded in accordance with act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [this chapter], see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
