<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe185598-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408"><num value="7408">§ 7408.</num><heading> Air quality criteria and control techniques</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe185599-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Air pollutant list; publication and revision by Administrator; issuance of air quality criteria for air pollutants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18559a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> For the purpose of establishing national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards, the Administrator shall within 30 days after <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, publish, and shall from time to time thereafter revise, a list which includes each air pollutant—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18559b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> emissions of which, in his judgment, cause or contribute to air pollution which may reasonably be anticipated to endanger public health or welfare;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18559c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the presence of which in the ambient air results from numerous or diverse mobile or stationary sources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18559d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for which air quality criteria had not been issued before <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date> but for which he plans to issue air quality criteria under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18559e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Administrator shall issue air quality criteria for an air pollutant within 12 months after he has included such pollutant in a list under paragraph (1). Air quality criteria for an air pollutant shall accurately reflect the latest scientific knowledge useful in indicating the kind and extent of all identifiable effects on public health or welfare which may be expected from the presence of such pollutant in the ambient air, in varying quantities. The criteria for an air pollutant, to the extent practicable, shall include information on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18559f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> those variable factors (including atmospheric conditions) which of themselves or in combination with other factors may alter the effects on public health or welfare of such air pollutant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the types of air pollutants which, when present in the atmosphere, may interact with such pollutant to produce an adverse effect on public health or welfare; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any known or anticipated adverse effects on welfare.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance by Administrator of information on air pollution control techniques; standing consulting committees for air pollutants; establishment; membership</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1855a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Simultaneously with the issuance of criteria under subsection (a), the Administrator shall, after consultation with appropriate advisory committees and Federal departments and agencies, issue to the States and appropriate air pollution control agencies information on air pollution control techniques, which information shall include data relating to the cost of installation and operation, energy requirements, emission reduction benefits, and environmental impact of the emission control technology. Such information shall include such data as are available on available technology and alternative methods of prevention and control of air pollution. Such information shall also include data on alternative fuels, processes, and operating methods which will result in elimination or significant reduction of emissions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1855a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In order to assist in the development of information on pollution control techniques, the Administrator may establish a standing consulting committee for each air pollutant included in a list published pursuant to subsection (a)(1), which shall be comprised of technically qualified individuals representative of State and local governments, industry, and the academic community. Each such committee shall submit, as appropriate, to the Administrator information related to that required by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Review, modification, and reissuance of criteria or information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall from time to time review, and, as appropriate, modify, and reissue any criteria or information on control techniques issued pursuant to this section. Not later than six months after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, the Administrator shall revise and reissue criteria relating to concentrations of NO<sub>2</sub> over such period (not more than three hours) as he deems appropriate. Such criteria shall include a discussion of nitric and nitrous acids, nitrites, nitrates, nitrosamines, and other carcinogenic and potentially carcinogenic derivatives of oxides of nitrogen.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register; availability of copies for general public</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The issuance of air quality criteria and information on air pollution control techniques shall be announced in the Federal Register and copies shall be made available to the general public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Transportation planning and guidelines</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, and after providing public notice and opportunity for comment, and with State and local officials, within nine months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003590">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003590"><num>1</num> See Codification note below.</note> and periodically thereafter as necessary to maintain a continuous transportation-air quality planning process, update the June 1978 Transportation-Air Quality Planning Guidelines and publish guidance on the development and implementation of transportation and other measures necessary to demonstrate and maintain attainment of national ambient air quality standards. Such guidelines shall include information on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> methods to identify and evaluate alternative planning and control activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> methods of reviewing plans on a regular basis as conditions change or new information is presented;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> identification of funds and other resources necessary to implement the plan, including interagency agreements on providing such funds and resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> methods to assure participation by the public in all phases of the planning process; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> such other methods as the Administrator determines necessary to carry out a continuous planning process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Information regarding processes, procedures, and methods to reduce or control pollutants in transportation; reduction of mobile source related pollutants; reduction of impact on public health</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1855ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator shall publish and make available to appropriate Federal, State, and local environmental and transportation agencies not later than one year after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, and from time to time thereafter—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> information prepared, as appropriate, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, and after providing public notice and opportunity for comment, regarding the formulation and emission reduction potential of transportation control measures related to criteria pollutants and their precursors, including, but not limited to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> programs for improved public transit;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> restriction of certain roads or lanes to, or construction of such roads or lanes for use by, passenger buses or high occupancy vehicles;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> employer-based transportation management plans, including incentives;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> trip-reduction ordinances;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> traffic flow improvement programs that achieve emission reductions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> fringe and transportation corridor parking facilities serving multiple occupancy vehicle programs or transit service;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> programs to limit or restrict vehicle use in downtown areas or other areas of emission concentration particularly during periods of peak use;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> programs for the provision of all forms of high-occupancy, shared-ride services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> programs to limit portions of road surfaces or certain sections of the metropolitan area to the use of non-motorized vehicles or pedestrian use, both as to time and place;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> programs for secure bicycle storage facilities and other facilities, including bicycle lanes, for the convenience and protection of bicyclists, in both public and private areas;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/xi"><num value="xi">(xi)</num><content> programs to control extended idling of vehicles;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/xii"><num value="xii">(xii)</num><content> programs to reduce motor vehicle emissions, consistent with subchapter II, which are caused by extreme cold start conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/xiii"><num value="xiii">(xiii)</num><content> employer-sponsored programs to permit flexible work schedules;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/xiv"><num value="xiv">(xiv)</num><content> programs and ordinances to facilitate non-automobile travel, provision and utilization of mass transit, and to generally reduce the need for single-occupant vehicle travel, as part of transportation planning and development efforts of a locality, including programs and ordinances applicable to new shopping centers, special events, and other centers of vehicle activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/xv"><num value="xv">(xv)</num><content> programs for new construction and major reconstructions of paths, tracks or areas solely for the use by pedestrian or other non-motorized means of transportation when economically feasible and in the public interest. For purposes of this clause, the Administrator shall also consult with the Secretary of the Interior; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A/xvi"><num value="xvi">(xvi)</num><content> program to encourage the voluntary removal from use and the marketplace of pre-1980 model year light duty vehicles and pre-1980 model light duty trucks.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003591">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003591"><num>2</num> So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.</note></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information on additional methods or strategies that will contribute to the reduction of mobile source related pollutants during periods in which any primary ambient air quality standard will be exceeded and during episodes for which an air pollution alert, warning, or emergency has been declared;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> information on other measures which may be employed to reduce the impact on public health or protect the health of sensitive or susceptible individuals or groups; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> information on the extent to which any process, procedure, or method to reduce or control such air pollutant may cause an increase in the emissions or formation of any other pollutant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1855c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In publishing such information the Administrator shall also include an assessment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the relative effectiveness of such processes, procedures, and methods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the potential effect of such processes, procedures, and methods on transportation systems and the provision of transportation services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the environmental, energy, and economic impact of such processes, procedures, and methods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessment of risks to ecosystems</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may assess the risks to ecosystems from exposure to criteria air pollutants (as identified by the Administrator in the Administrator’s sole discretion).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7408/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> RACT/BACT/LAER clearinghouse</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall make information regarding emission control technology available to the States and to the general public through a central database. Such information shall include all control technology information received pursuant to State plan provisions requiring permits for sources, including operating permits for existing sources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe1855c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 108, as added <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s4/a">Pub. L. 91–604, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1678">84 Stat. 1678</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI">Pub. L. 95–95, title I</ref>, §§ 104, 105, title IV, § 401(a), <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/689">91 Stat. 689</ref>, 790; <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI">Pub. L. 101–549, title I</ref>, §§ 108(a)–(c), (<i>o</i>), 111, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2465">104 Stat. 2465</ref>, 2466, 2469, 2470; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tXV/s1501/b">Pub. L. 105–362, title XV, § 1501(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3294">112 Stat. 3294</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe1855ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe1855cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe1855cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, referred to in subsec. (e), was in the original “enactment of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1989”, and was translated as meaning the date of the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/101/549">Pub. L. 101–549</ref>, popularly known as the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857c–3">section 1857c–3 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbe1855cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 108 of act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, was renumbered section 115 by <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref> and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7415">section 7415 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe1855ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (f)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> struck out par. (3), which required reports by the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator to be submitted to Congress by <date date="1993-01-01">Jan. 1, 1993</date>, and every 3 years thereafter, reviewing and analyzing existing State and local air quality related transportation programs, evaluating achievement of goals, and recommending changes to existing programs, and par. (4), which required that in each report after the first report the Secretary of Transportation include a description of the actions taken to implement the changes recommended in the preceding report.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s108/a">Pub. L. 101–549, § 108(a)</ref>, inserted first sentence and struck out former first sentence which read as follows: “The Administrator shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and State and local officials and within 180 days after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, and from time to time thereafter, publish guidelines on the basic program elements for the planning process assisted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7505">section 7505 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s108/b">Pub. L. 101–549, § 108(b)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted present provisions for provisions relating to Federal agencies, States, and air pollution control agencies within either 6 months or one year after <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s108/b">Pub. L. 101–549, § 108(b)</ref>, substituted present provisions for provisions relating to information prepared in cooperation with Secretary of Transportation, regarding processes, procedures, and methods to reduce certain pollutants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s111">Pub. L. 101–549, § 111</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s108">Pub. L. 101–549, § 108</ref>(<i>o</i>), added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s108/c">Pub. L. 101–549, § 108(c)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s401/a">Pub. L. 95–95, § 401(a)</ref>, substituted “emissions of which, in his judgment, cause or contribute to air pollution which may reasonably be anticipated to endanger public health or welfare” for “which in his judgment has an adverse effect on public health or welfare”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s104/a">Pub. L. 95–95, § 104(a)</ref>, substituted “cost of installation and operation, energy requirements, emission reduction benefits, and environmental impact of the emission control technology” for “technology and costs of emission control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s104/b">Pub. L. 95–95, § 104(b)</ref>, inserted provision directing the Administrator, not later than six months after <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, to revise and reissue criteria relating to concentrations of NO<sub>2</sub> over such period (not more than three hours) as he deems appropriate, with the criteria to include a discussion of nitric and nitrous acids, nitrites, nitrates, nitrosamines, and other carcinogenic and potentially carcinogenic derivatives of oxides of nitrogen.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s105">Pub. L. 95–95, § 105</ref>, added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe1855cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe1855d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe1855d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other Actions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All rules, regulations, orders, determinations, contracts, certifications, authorizations, delegations, or other actions duly issued, made, or taken by or pursuant to act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>] to continue in full force and effect until modified or rescinded in accordance with act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [this chapter], see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
