<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe1855ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410"><num value="7410">§ 7410.</num><heading> State implementation plans for national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1855ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Adoption of plan by State; submission to Administrator; content of plan; revision; new sources; indirect source review program; supplemental or intermittent control systems</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1855ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each State shall, after reasonable notice and public hearings, adopt and submit to the Administrator, within 3 years (or such shorter period as the Administrator may prescribe) after the promulgation of a national primary ambient air quality standard (or any revision thereof) under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7409">section 7409 of this title</ref> for any air pollutant, a plan which provides for implementation, maintenance, and enforcement of such primary standard in each air quality control region (or portion thereof) within such State. In addition, such State shall adopt and submit to the Administrator (either as a part of a plan submitted under the preceding sentence or separately) within 3 years (or such shorter period as the Administrator may prescribe) after the promulgation of a national ambient air quality secondary standard (or revision thereof), a plan which provides for implementation, maintenance, and enforcement of such secondary standard in each air quality control region (or portion thereof) within such State. Unless a separate public hearing is provided, each State shall consider its plan implementing such secondary standard at the hearing required by the first sentence of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1855f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Each implementation plan submitted by a State under this chapter shall be adopted by the State after reasonable notice and public hearing. Each such plan shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> include enforceable emission limitations and other control measures, means, or techniques (including economic incentives such as fees, marketable permits, and auctions of emissions rights), as well as schedules and timetables for compliance, as may be necessary or appropriate to meet the applicable requirements of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> provide for establishment and operation of appropriate devices, methods, systems, and procedures necessary to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> monitor, compile, and analyze data on ambient air quality, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> upon request, make such data available to the Administrator;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> include a program to provide for the enforcement of the measures described in subparagraph (A), and regulation of the modification and construction of any stationary source within the areas covered by the plan as necessary to assure that national ambient air quality standards are achieved, including a permit program as required in parts C and D;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> contain adequate provisions—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> prohibiting, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, any source or other type of emissions activity within the State from emitting any air pollutant in amounts which will—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe1855f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> contribute significantly to nonattainment in, or interfere with maintenance by, any other State with respect to any such national primary or secondary ambient air quality standard, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe1855f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> interfere with measures required to be included in the applicable implementation plan for any other State under part C to prevent significant deterioration of air quality or to protect visibility,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> insuring compliance with the applicable requirements of sections 7426 and 7415 of this title (relating to interstate and international pollution abatement);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> provide (i) necessary assurances that the State (or, except where the Administrator deems inappropriate, the general purpose local government or governments, or a regional agency designated by the State or general purpose local governments for such purpose) will have adequate personnel, funding, and authority under State (and, as appropriate, local) law to carry out such implementation plan (and is not prohibited by any provision of Federal or State law from carrying out such implementation plan or portion thereof), (ii) requirements that the State comply with the requirements respecting State boards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7428">section 7428 of this title</ref>, and (iii) necessary assurances that, where the State has relied on a local or regional government, agency, or instrumentality for the implementation of any plan provision, the State has responsibility for ensuring adequate implementation of such plan provision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe1855fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> require, as may be prescribed by the Administrator—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the installation, maintenance, and replacement of equipment, and the implementation of other necessary steps, by owners or operators of stationary sources to monitor emissions from such sources,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> periodic reports on the nature and amounts of emissions and emissions-related data from such sources, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1855ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> correlation of such reports by the State agency with any emission limitations or standards established pursuant to this chapter, which reports shall be available at reasonable times for public inspection;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185600-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> provide for authority comparable to that in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7603">section 7603 of this title</ref> and adequate contingency plans to implement such authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185601-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><chapeau> provide for revision of such plan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe185602-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> from time to time as may be necessary to take account of revisions of such national primary or secondary ambient air quality standard or the availability of improved or more expeditious methods of attaining such standard, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe185603-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> except as provided in paragraph (3)(C), whenever the Administrator finds on the basis of information available to the Administrator that the plan is substantially inadequate to attain the national ambient air quality standard which it implements or to otherwise comply with any additional requirements established under this chapter;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185604-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> in the case of a plan or plan revision for an area designated as a nonattainment area, meet the applicable requirements of part D (relating to nonattainment areas);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185605-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> meet the applicable requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7421">section 7421 of this title</ref> (relating to consultation), <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7427">section 7427 of this title</ref> (relating to public notification), and part C (relating to prevention of significant deterioration of air quality and visibility protection);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185606-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><chapeau> provide for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe185607-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/K/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the performance of such air quality modeling as the Administrator may prescribe for the purpose of predicting the effect on ambient air quality of any emissions of any air pollutant for which the Administrator has established a national ambient air quality standard, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe185608-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/K/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the submission, upon request, of data related to such air quality modeling to the Administrator;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185609-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><chapeau> require the owner or operator of each major stationary source to pay to the permitting authority, as a condition of any permit required under this chapter, a fee sufficient to cover—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe18560a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/L/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the reasonable costs of reviewing and acting upon any application for such a permit, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe18560b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/L/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the owner or operator receives a permit for such source, the reasonable costs of implementing and enforcing the terms and conditions of any such permit (not including any court costs or other costs associated with any enforcement action),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">until such fee requirement is superseded with respect to such sources by the Administrator’s approval of a fee program under subchapter V; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18560c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> provide for consultation and participation by local political subdivisions affected by the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18560d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18560e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s101/d/1">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2409">104 Stat. 2409</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18560f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> As soon as practicable, the Administrator shall, consistent with the purposes of this chapter and the Energy Supply and Environmental Coordination Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s791">15 U.S.C. 791</ref> et seq.], review each State’s applicable implementation plans and report to the State on whether such plans can be revised in relation to fuel burning stationary sources (or persons supplying fuel to such sources) without interfering with the attainment and maintenance of any national ambient air quality standard within the period permitted in this section. If the Administrator determines that any such plan can be revised, he shall notify the State that a plan revision may be submitted by the State. Any plan revision which is submitted by the State shall, after public notice and opportunity for public hearing, be approved by the Administrator if the revision relates only to fuel burning stationary sources (or persons supplying fuel to such sources), and the plan as revised complies with paragraph (2) of this subsection. The Administrator shall approve or disapprove any revision no later than three months after its submission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185610-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Neither the State, in the case of a plan (or portion thereof) approved under this subsection, nor the Administrator, in the case of a plan (or portion thereof) promulgated under subsection (c), shall be required to revise an applicable implementation plan because one or more exemptions under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7418">section 7418 of this title</ref> (relating to Federal facilities), enforcement orders under section 7413(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003592">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003592"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title, suspensions under subsection (f) or (g) (relating to temporary energy or economic authority), orders under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7419">section 7419 of this title</ref> (relating to primary nonferrous smelters), or extensions of compliance in decrees entered under section 7413(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003592">1</ref> of this title (relating to iron- and steel-producing operations) have been granted, if such plan would have met the requirements of this section if no such exemptions, orders, or extensions had been granted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185611-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s101/d/2">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2409">104 Stat. 2409</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185612-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185613-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185614-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any State may include in a State implementation plan, but the Administrator may not require as a condition of approval of such plan under this section, any indirect source review program. The Administrator may approve and enforce, as part of an applicable implementation plan, an indirect source review program which the State chooses to adopt and submit as part of its plan.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185615-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no plan promulgated by the Administrator shall include any indirect source review program for any air quality control region, or portion thereof.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185616-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Any State may revise an applicable implementation plan approved under this subsection to suspend or revoke any such program included in such plan, provided that such plan meets the requirements of this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185617-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Administrator shall have the authority to promulgate, implement and enforce regulations under subsection (c) respecting indirect source review programs which apply only to federally assisted highways, airports, and other major federally assisted indirect sources and federally owned or operated indirect sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185618-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “indirect source” means a facility, building, structure, installation, real property, road, or highway which attracts, or may attract, mobile sources of pollution. Such term includes parking lots, parking garages, and other facilities subject to any measure for management of parking supply (within the meaning of subsection (c)(2)(D)(ii)), including regulation of existing off-street parking but such term does not include new or existing on-street parking. Direct emissions sources or facilities at, within, or associated with, any indirect source shall not be deemed indirect sources for the purpose of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185619-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph the term “indirect source review program” means the facility-by-facility review of indirect sources of air pollution, including such measures as are necessary to assure, or assist in assuring, that a new or modified indirect source will not attract mobile sources of air pollution, the emissions from which would cause or contribute to air pollution concentrations—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18561a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> exceeding any national primary ambient air quality standard for a mobile source-related air pollutant after the primary standard attainment date, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18561b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> preventing maintenance of any such standard after such date.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18561c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph and paragraph (2)(B), the term “transportation control measure” does not include any measure which is an “indirect source review program”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18561d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> No State plan shall be treated as meeting the requirements of this section unless such plan provides that in the case of any source which uses a supplemental, or intermittent control system for purposes of meeting the requirements of an order under section 7413(d) <sup>1</sup> of this title or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7419">section 7419 of this title</ref> (relating to primary nonferrous smelter orders), the owner or operator of such source may not temporarily reduce the pay of any employee by reason of the use of such supplemental or intermittent or other dispersion dependent control system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe18561e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension of period for submission of plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may, wherever he determines necessary, extend the period for submission of any plan or portion thereof which implements a national secondary ambient air quality standard for a period not to exceed 18 months from the date otherwise required for submission of such plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe18561f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation and publication by Administrator of proposed regulations setting forth implementation plan; transportation regulations study and report; parking surcharge; suspension authority; plan implementation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185620-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator shall promulgate a Federal implementation plan at any time within 2 years after the Administrator—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185621-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> finds that a State has failed to make a required submission or finds that the plan or plan revision submitted by the State does not satisfy the minimum criteria established under subsection (k)(1)(A), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185622-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> disapproves a State implementation plan submission in whole or in part,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless the State corrects the deficiency, and the Administrator approves the plan or plan revision, before the Administrator promulgates such Federal implementation plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185623-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185624-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s101/d/3/A">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(d)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2409">104 Stat. 2409</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185625-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> No parking surcharge regulation may be required by the Administrator under paragraph (1) of this subsection as a part of an applicable implementation plan. All parking surcharge regulations previously required by the Administrator shall be void upon <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>. This subparagraph shall not prevent the Administrator from approving parking surcharges if they are adopted and submitted by a State as part of an applicable implementation plan. The Administrator may not condition approval of any implementation plan submitted by a State on such plan’s including a parking surcharge regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185626-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s101/d/3/B">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(d)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2409">104 Stat. 2409</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185627-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185628-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The term “parking surcharge regulation” means a regulation imposing or requiring the imposition of any tax, surcharge, fee, or other charge on parking spaces, or any other area used for the temporary storage of motor vehicles.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185629-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The term “management of parking supply” shall include any requirement providing that any new facility containing a given number of parking spaces shall receive a permit or other prior approval, issuance of which is to be conditioned on air quality considerations.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18562a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The term “preferential bus/carpool lane” shall include any requirement for the setting aside of one or more lanes of a street or highway on a permanent or temporary basis for the exclusive use of buses or carpools, or both.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18562b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> No standard, plan, or requirement, relating to management of parking supply or preferential bus/carpool lanes shall be promulgated after <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, by the Administrator pursuant to this section, unless such promulgation has been subjected to at least one public hearing which has been held in the area affected and for which reasonable notice has been given in such area. If substantial changes are made following public hearings, one or more additional hearings shall be held in such area after such notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18562c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon application of the chief executive officer of any general purpose unit of local government, if the Administrator determines that such unit has adequate authority under State or local law, the Administrator may delegate to such unit the authority to implement and enforce within the jurisdiction of such unit any part of a plan promulgated under this subsection. Nothing in this paragraph shall prevent the Administrator from implementing or enforcing any applicable provision of a plan promulgated under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18562d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s101/d/3/C">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(d)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2409">104 Stat. 2409</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18562e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18562f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any measure in an applicable implementation plan which requires a toll or other charge for the use of a bridge located entirely within one city shall be eliminated from such plan by the Administrator upon application by the Governor of the State, which application shall include a certification by the Governor that he will revise such plan in accordance with subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185630-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> In the case of any applicable implementation plan with respect to which a measure has been eliminated under subparagraph (A), such plan shall, not later than one year after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, be revised to include comprehensive measures to:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185631-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> establish, expand, or improve public transportation measures to meet basic transportation needs, as expeditiously as is practicable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185632-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> implement transportation control measures necessary to attain and maintain national ambient air quality standards,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and such revised plan shall, for the purpose of implementing such comprehensive public transportation measures, include requirements to use (insofar as is necessary) Federal grants, State or local funds, or any combination of such grants and funds as may be consistent with the terms of the legislation providing such grants and funds. Such measures shall, as a substitute for the tolls or charges eliminated under subparagraph (A), provide for emissions reductions equivalent to the reductions which may reasonably be expected to be achieved through the use of the tolls or charges eliminated.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185633-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any revision of an implementation plan for purposes of meeting the requirements of subparagraph (B) shall be submitted in coordination with any plan revision required under part D.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe185634-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold">, (e) Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s101/d/4">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(d)(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2409">104 Stat. 2409</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe185635-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> National or regional energy emergencies; determination by President</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185636-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon application by the owner or operator of a fuel burning stationary source, and after notice and opportunity for public hearing, the Governor of the State in which such source is located may petition the President to determine that a national or regional energy emergency exists of such severity that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185637-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a temporary suspension of any part of the applicable implementation plan or of any requirement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651j">section 7651j of this title</ref> (concerning excess emissions penalties or offsets) may be necessary, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185638-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> other means of responding to the energy emergency may be inadequate.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such determination shall not be delegable by the President to any other person. If the President determines that a national or regional energy emergency of such severity exists, a temporary emergency suspension of any part of an applicable implementation plan or of any requirement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651j">section 7651j of this title</ref> (concerning excess emissions penalties or offsets) adopted by the State may be issued by the Governor of any State covered by the President’s determination under the condition specified in paragraph (2) and may take effect immediately.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185639-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A temporary emergency suspension under this subsection shall be issued to a source only if the Governor of such State finds that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18563a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> there exists in the vicinity of such source a temporary energy emergency involving high levels of unemployment or loss of necessary energy supplies for residential dwellings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe18563b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such unemployment or loss can be totally or partially alleviated by such emergency suspension.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Not more than one such suspension may be issued for any source on the basis of the same set of circumstances or on the basis of the same emergency.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18563c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A temporary emergency suspension issued by a Governor under this subsection shall remain in effect for a maximum of four months or such lesser period as may be specified in a disapproval order of the Administrator, if any. The Administrator may disapprove such suspension if he determines that it does not meet the requirements of paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18563d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> This subsection shall not apply in the case of a plan provision or requirement promulgated by the Administrator under subsection (c) of this section, but in any such case the President may grant a temporary emergency suspension for a four month period of any such provision or requirement if he makes the determinations and findings specified in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe18563e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Governor may include in any temporary emergency suspension issued under this subsection a provision delaying for a period identical to the period of such suspension any compliance schedule (or increment of progress) to which such source is subject under section 1857c–10 <sup>1</sup> of this title, as in effect before <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, or section 7413(d) <sup>1</sup> of this title, upon a finding that such source is unable to comply with such schedule (or increment) solely because of the conditions on the basis of which a suspension was issued under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe18563f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Governor’s authority to issue temporary emergency suspensions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe185640-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the case of any State which has adopted and submitted to the Administrator a proposed plan revision which the State determines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185641-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> meets the requirements of this section, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe185642-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is necessary (i) to prevent the closing for one year or more of any source of air pollution, and (ii) to prevent substantial increases in unemployment which would result from such closing, and</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">which the Administrator has not approved or disapproved under this section within 12 months of submission of the proposed plan revision, the Governor may issue a temporary emergency suspension of the part of the applicable implementation plan for such State which is proposed to be revised with respect to such source. The determination under subparagraph (B) may not be made with respect to a source which would close without regard to whether or not the proposed plan revision is approved.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1ac743-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A temporary emergency suspension issued by a Governor under this subsection shall remain in effect for a maximum of four months or such lesser period as may be specified in a disapproval order of the Administrator. The Administrator may disapprove such suspension if he determines that it does not meet the requirements of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1ac744-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Governor may include in any temporary emergency suspension issued under this subsection a provision delaying for a period identical to the period of such suspension any compliance schedule (or increment of progress) to which such source is subject under section 1857c–10 <sup>1</sup> of this title as in effect before <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, or under section 7413(d) <sup>1</sup> of this title upon a finding that such source is unable to comply with such schedule (or increment) solely because of the conditions on the basis of which a suspension was issued under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac745-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of comprehensive document for each State setting forth requirements of applicable implementation plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1ac746-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 5 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, and every 3 years thereafter, the Administrator shall assemble and publish a comprehensive document for each State setting forth all requirements of the applicable implementation plan for such State and shall publish notice in the Federal Register of the availability of such documents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe1ac747-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator may promulgate such regulations as may be reasonably necessary to carry out the purpose of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac748-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Modification of requirements prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except for a primary nonferrous smelter order under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7419">section 7419 of this title</ref>, a suspension under subsection (f) or (g) (relating to emergency suspensions), an exemption under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7418">section 7418 of this title</ref> (relating to certain Federal facilities), an order under section 7413(d) <sup>1</sup> of this title (relating to compliance orders), a plan promulgation under subsection (c), or a plan revision under subsection (a)(3); no order, suspension, plan revision, or other action modifying any requirement of an applicable implementation plan may be taken with respect to any stationary source by the State or by the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac749-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Technological systems of continuous emission reduction on new or modified stationary sources; compliance with performance standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As a condition for issuance of any permit required under this subchapter, the owner or operator of each new or modified stationary source which is required to obtain such a permit must show to the satisfaction of the permitting authority that the technological system of continuous emission reduction which is to be used at such source will enable it to comply with the standards of performance which are to apply to such source and that the construction or modification and operation of such source will be in compliance with all other requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac74a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Environmental Protection Agency action on plan submissions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac74b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Completeness of plan submissions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac74c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Completeness criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 9 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall promulgate minimum criteria that any plan submission must meet before the Administrator is required to act on such submission under this subsection. The criteria shall be limited to the information necessary to enable the Administrator to determine whether the plan submission complies with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac74d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Completeness finding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 60 days of the Administrator’s receipt of a plan or plan revision, but no later than 6 months after the date, if any, by which a State is required to submit the plan or revision, the Administrator shall determine whether the minimum criteria established pursuant to subparagraph (A) have been met. Any plan or plan revision that a State submits to the Administrator, and that has not been determined by the Administrator (by the date 6 months after receipt of the submission) to have failed to meet the minimum criteria established pursuant to subparagraph (A), shall on that date be deemed by operation of law to meet such minimum criteria.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac74e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of finding of incompleteness</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Where the Administrator determines that a plan submission (or part thereof) does not meet the minimum criteria established pursuant to subparagraph (A), the State shall be treated as not having made the submission (or, in the Administrator’s discretion, part thereof).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac74f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadline for action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 12 months of a determination by the Administrator (or a determination deemed by operation of law) under paragraph (1) that a State has submitted a plan or plan revision (or, in the Administrator’s discretion, part thereof) that meets the minimum criteria established pursuant to paragraph (1), if applicable (or, if those criteria are not applicable, within 12 months of submission of the plan or revision), the Administrator shall act on the submission in accordance with paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac750-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Full and partial approval and disapproval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any submittal on which the Administrator is required to act under paragraph (2), the Administrator shall approve such submittal as a whole if it meets all of the applicable requirements of this chapter. If a portion of the plan revision meets all the applicable requirements of this chapter, the Administrator may approve the plan revision in part and disapprove the plan revision in part. The plan revision shall not be treated as meeting the requirements of this chapter until the Administrator approves the entire plan revision as complying with the applicable requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac751-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditional approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator may approve a plan revision based on a commitment of the State to adopt specific enforceable measures by a date certain, but not later than 1 year after the date of approval of the plan revision. Any such conditional approval shall be treated as a disapproval if the State fails to comply with such commitment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac752-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Calls for plan revisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the Administrator finds that the applicable implementation plan for any area is substantially inadequate to attain or maintain the relevant national ambient air quality standard, to mitigate adequately the interstate pollutant transport described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7506a">section 7506a of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511c">section 7511c of this title</ref>, or to otherwise comply with any requirement of this chapter, the Administrator shall require the State to revise the plan as necessary to correct such inadequacies. The Administrator shall notify the State of the inadequacies, and may establish reasonable deadlines (not to exceed 18 months after the date of such notice) for the submission of such plan revisions. Such findings and notice shall be public. Any finding under this paragraph shall, to the extent the Administrator deems appropriate, subject the State to the requirements of this chapter to which the State was subject when it developed and submitted the plan for which such finding was made, except that the Administrator may adjust any dates applicable under such requirements as appropriate (except that the Administrator may not adjust any attainment date prescribed under part D, unless such date has elapsed).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac753-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Corrections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the Administrator determines that the Administrator’s action approving, disapproving, or promulgating any plan or plan revision (or part thereof), area designation, redesignation, classification, or reclassification was in error, the Administrator may in the same manner as the approval, disapproval, or promulgation revise such action as appropriate without requiring any further submission from the State. Such determination and the basis thereof shall be provided to the State and public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac754-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan revisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each revision to an implementation plan submitted by a State under this chapter shall be adopted by such State after reasonable notice and public hearing. The Administrator shall not approve a revision of a plan if the revision would interfere with any applicable requirement concerning attainment and reasonable further progress (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7501">section 7501 of this title</ref>), or any other applicable requirement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac755-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may apply any of the sanctions listed in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7509/b">section 7509(b) of this title</ref> at any time (or at any time after) the Administrator makes a finding, disapproval, or determination under paragraphs (1) through (4), respectively, of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7509/a">section 7509(a) of this title</ref> in relation to any plan or plan item (as that term is defined by the Administrator) required under this chapter, with respect to any portion of the State the Administrator determines reasonable and appropriate, for the purpose of ensuring that the requirements of this chapter relating to such plan or plan item are met. The Administrator shall, by rule, establish criteria for exercising his authority under the previous sentence with respect to any deficiency referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7509/a">section 7509(a) of this title</ref> to ensure that, during the 24-month period following the finding, disapproval, or determination referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7509/a">section 7509(a) of this title</ref>, such sanctions are not applied on a statewide basis where one or more political subdivisions covered by the applicable implementation plan are principally responsible for such deficiency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac756-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings clauses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac757-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/n/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing plan provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any provision of any applicable implementation plan that was approved or promulgated by the Administrator pursuant to this section as in effect before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, shall remain in effect as part of such applicable implementation plan, except to the extent that a revision to such provision is approved or promulgated by the Administrator pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac758-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/n/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Attainment dates</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For any area not designated nonattainment, any plan or plan revision submitted or required to be submitted by a State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1ac759-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/n/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in response to the promulgation or revision of a national primary ambient air quality standard in effect on <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe1ac75a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/n/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in response to a finding of substantial inadequacy under subsection (a)(2) (as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall provide for attainment of the national primary ambient air quality standards within 3 years of <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, or within 5 years of issuance of such finding of substantial inadequacy, whichever is later.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac75b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/n/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of construction moratorium in certain areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of an area to which, immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the prohibition on construction or modification of major stationary sources prescribed in subsection (a)(2)(I) (as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>) applied by virtue of a finding of the Administrator that the State containing such area had not submitted an implementation plan meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7502/b/6">section 7502(b)(6) of this title</ref> (relating to establishment of a permit program) (as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>) or 7502(a)(1) of this title (to the extent such requirements relate to provision for attainment of the primary national ambient air quality standard for sulfur oxides by <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>) as in effect immediately before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, no major stationary source of the relevant air pollutant or pollutants shall be constructed or modified in such area until the Administrator finds that the plan for such area meets the applicable requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7502/c/5">section 7502(c)(5) of this title</ref> (relating to permit programs) or subpart 5 of part D (relating to attainment of the primary national ambient air quality standard for sulfur dioxide), respectively.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac75c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Indian tribes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If an Indian tribe submits an implementation plan to the Administrator pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7601/d">section 7601(d) of this title</ref>, the plan shall be reviewed in accordance with the provisions for review set forth in this section for State plans, except as otherwise provided by regulation promulgated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7601/d/2">section 7601(d)(2) of this title</ref>. When such plan becomes effective in accordance with the regulations promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7601/d">section 7601(d) of this title</ref>, the plan shall become applicable to all areas (except as expressly provided otherwise in the plan) located within the exterior boundaries of the reservation, notwithstanding the issuance of any patent and including rights-of-way running through the reservation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe1ac75d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7410/p"><num value="p" class="bold">(p)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any State shall submit, according to such schedule as the Administrator may prescribe, such reports as the Administrator may require relating to emission reductions, vehicle miles traveled, congestion levels, and any other information the Administrator may deem necessary to assess the development <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003593">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003593"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> effectiveness, need for revision, or implementation of any plan or plan revision required under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe1ac75e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 110, as added <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s4/a">Pub. L. 91–604, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1680">84 Stat. 1680</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/319/s4">Pub. L. 93–319, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/256">88 Stat. 256</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI">Pub. L. 95–95, title I</ref>, §§ 107, 108, <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/691">91 Stat. 691</ref>, 693; <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/1">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(1)</ref>–(6), <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1399">91 Stat. 1399</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/23/s3">Pub. L. 97–23, § 3</ref>, <date date="1981-07-17">July 17, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/142">95 Stat. 142</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI">Pub. L. 101–549, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b)–(d), 102(h), 107(c), 108(d), title IV, § 412, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2404-2408">104 Stat. 2404–2408</ref>, 2422, 2464, 2466, 2634.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe1ac75f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe1ac760-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe1ac761-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Supply and Environmental Coordination Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(3)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/319">Pub. L. 93–319</ref>, <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/246">88 Stat. 246</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 16C (§ 791 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s791">section 791 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7413">Section 7413 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3)(C), (6), (f)(5), (g)(3), and (i), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 101–549, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2672">104 Stat. 2672</ref>, and, as so amended, subsecs. (d) and (e) of section 7413 no longer relates to final compliance orders and steel industry compliance extension, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857c–10">Section 1857c–10 of this title</ref>, as in effect before <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, referred to in subsecs. (f)(5) and (g)(3), was in the original “section 119, as in effect before the date of the enactment of this paragraph”, meaning section 119 of <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360/tI">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title I</ref>, as added <date date="1974-06-22">June 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/93/319/s3">Pub. L. 93–319, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/248">88 Stat. 248</ref>, (which was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857c–10">section 1857c–10 of this title</ref>) as in effect prior to the enactment of subsecs. (f)(5) and (g)(3) of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s107">Pub. L. 95–95, § 107</ref>, <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/691">91 Stat. 691</ref>, effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>. <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s112/b/1">Section 112(b)(1) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref> repealed section 119 of <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360/tI">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title I</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/93/319">Pub. L. 93–319</ref>, and provided that all references to such section 119 in any subsequent enactment which supersedes <ref href="/us/pl/93/319">Pub. L. 93–319</ref> shall be construed to refer to section 113(d) of the Clean Air Act and to paragraph (5) thereof in particular which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7413/d/5">section 7413(d)(5) of this title</ref>. <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7413">Section 7413 of this title</ref> was subsequently amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 101–549, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2672">104 Stat. 2672</ref>, see note above. <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s117/b">Section 117(b) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref> added a new section 119 of act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7419">section 7419 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe1ac762-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857c–5">section 1857c–5 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbe1ac763-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 110 of act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, was renumbered section 117 by <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref> and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7417">section 7417 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe1ac764-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/8">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(8)</ref>, substituted “3 years (or such shorter period as the Administrator may prescribe)” for “nine months” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/b">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(b)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally, substituting present provisions for provisions setting the time within which the Administrator was to approve or disapprove a plan or portion thereof and listing the conditions under which the plan or portion thereof was to be approved after reasonable notice and hearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/1">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(1)</ref>, struck out subpar. (A) which directed Administrator to approve any revision of an implementation plan if it met certain requirements and had been adopted by the State after reasonable notice and public hearings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/1">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(1)</ref>, struck out subpar. (D) which directed that certain implementation plans be revised to include comprehensive measures and requirements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/2">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(2)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which set forth requirements for review procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s102/h">Pub. L. 101–549, § 102(h)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally, substituting present provisions for provisions relating to preparation and publication of regulations setting forth an implementation plan, after opportunity for a hearing, upon failure of a State to make required submission or revision.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/3/A">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(3)(A)</ref>, struck out subpar. (A) which required a study and report on necessity of parking surcharge, management of parking supply, and preferential bus/carpool lane regulations to achieve and maintain national primary ambient air quality standards.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/3/B">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(3)(B)</ref>, struck out subpar. (C) which authorized suspension of certain regulations and requirements relating to management of parking supply.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/3/C">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(3)(C)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which permitted Governors to temporarily suspend measures in implementation plans relating to retrofits, gas rationing, and reduction of on-street parking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/3/D">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(3)(D)</ref>, struck out “(including the written evidence required by part D),” after “include comprehensive measures”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/4">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(4)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which defined an applicable implementation plan for purposes of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/5">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(5)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which permitted an extension of time for attainment of a national primary ambient air quality standard.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s412">Pub. L. 101–549, § 412</ref>, inserted “or of any requirement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651j">section 7651j of this title</ref> (concerning excess emissions penalties or offsets)” in subpar. (A) and in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/6">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(6)</ref>, substituted “12 months of submission of the proposed plan revision” for “the required four month period” in closing provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/d/7">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(d)(7)</ref>, substituted “5 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, and every three years thereafter” for “one year after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, and annually thereafter” and struck out at end “Each such document shall be revised as frequently as practicable but not less often than annually.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k) to (n). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s101/c">Pub. L. 101–549, § 101(c)</ref>, added subsecs. (k) to (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s107/c">Pub. L. 101–549, § 107(c)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s108/d">Pub. L. 101–549, § 108(d)</ref>, added subsec. (p).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/97/23">Pub. L. 97–23</ref> inserted reference to extensions of compliance in decrees entered under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7413/e">section 7413(e) of this title</ref> (relating to iron- and steel-producing operations).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/a/1">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “(A) except as may be provided in subparagraph (I)(i) in the case of a plan” for “(A)(i) in the case of a plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/a/2">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “transportation controls, air quality maintenance plans, and preconstruction review of direct sources of air pollution as provided in subparagraph (D)” for “land use and transportation controls”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/a/3">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “it includes a program to provide for the enforcement of emission limitations and regulation of the modification, construction, and operation of any stationary source, including a permit program as required in parts C and D and a permit or equivalent program for any major emitting facility, within such region as necessary to assure (i) that national ambient air quality standards are achieved and maintained, and (ii) a procedure” for “it includes a procedure”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/a/4">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “it contains adequate provisions (i) prohibiting any stationary source within the State from emitting any air pollutant in amounts which will (I) prevent attainment or maintenance by any other State of any such national primary or secondary ambient air quality standard, or (II) interfere with measures required to be included in the applicable implementation plan for any other State under part C to prevent significant deterioration of air quality or to protect visibility, and (ii) insuring compliance with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7426">section 7426 of this title</ref>, relating to interstate pollution abatement” for “it contains adequate provisions for intergovernmental cooperation, including measures necessary to insure that emissions of air pollutants from sources located in any air quality control region will not interfere with the attainment or maintenance of such primary or secondary standard in any portion of such region outside of such State or in any other air quality control region”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/a/5">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(a)(5)</ref>, added cl. (vi).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/1">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “1977;” for “1977”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/a/6">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(a)(6)</ref>, inserted “except as provided in paragraph (3)(C),” after “or (ii)” and “or to otherwise comply with any additional requirements established under the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1977” after “to achieve the national ambient air quality primary or secondary standard which it implements”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/b">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(b)</ref>, added subpar. (I).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(J). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/2">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “; and” for “, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/b">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(b)</ref>, added subpar. (J).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(K). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/b">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(b)</ref> added subpar. (K).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/c">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(c)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/4">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(4)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/e">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(e)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/3">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(3)</ref>, struck out “preconstruction or premodification” before “review”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/e">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(e)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/d/1">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(d)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “plan which meets the requirements of this section” for “plan for any national ambient air quality primary or secondary standard within the time prescribed” in subpar. (A) and, in provisions following subpar. (C), directed that any portion of a plan relating to any measure described in first sentence of 7421 of this title (relating to consultation) or the consultation process required under such <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7421">section 7421 of this title</ref> not be required to be promulgated before the date eight months after such date required for submission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/d/3">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(d)(3)</ref>, added pars. (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/f">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(f)</ref>, substituted “and which implements the requirements of this section” for “and which implements a national primary or secondary ambient air quality standard in a State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s107/a">Pub. L. 95–95, § 107(a)</ref>, substituted provisions relating to the handling of national or regional energy emergencies for provisions relating to the postponement of compliance by stationary sources or classes of moving sources with any requirement of applicable implementation plans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/g">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(g)</ref>, added subsec. (g) relating to publication of comprehensive document.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s107/b">Pub. L. 95–95, § 107(b)</ref>, added subsec. (g) relating to Governor’s authority to issue temporary emergency suspensions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/5">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g), added by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/g">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(g)</ref>, as (h). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/5">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h), added by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/g">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(g)</ref>, as (i). Former subsec. (i) redesignated (j) and amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190">Pub. L. 95–190</ref> § 14(a)(5), (6), redesignated subsec. (i), added by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s108/g">Pub. L. 95–95, § 108(g)</ref>, as (j) and in subsec. (j) as so redesignated, substituted “will enable such source” for “at such source will enable it”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/93/319/s4/a">Pub. L. 93–319, § 4(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/319/s4/b">Pub. L. 93–319, § 4(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and existing pars. (1), (2), and (3) as subpars. (A), (B), and (C), respectively, of such redesignated par. (1), and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe1ac765-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe1ac766-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe1ac767-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pending Actions and Proceedings</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Suits, actions, and other proceedings lawfully commenced by or against the Administrator or any other officer or employee of the United States in his official capacity or in relation to the discharge of his official duties under act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>], not to abate by reason of the taking effect of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/a">section 406(a) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe1ac768-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other Actions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All rules, regulations, orders, determinations, contracts, certifications, authorizations, delegations, or other actions duly issued, made, or taken by or pursuant to act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>] to continue in full force and effect until modified or rescinded in accordance with act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [this chapter], see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe1ac769-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification or Rescission of Implementation Plans Approved and In Effect Prior to <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1977 [<ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref>] to affect any requirement of an approved implementation plan under this section or any other provision in effect under this chapter before <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, until modified or rescinded in accordance with this chapter as amended by the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1977, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/c">section 406(c) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="idbe1ac76a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s16">Pub. L. 91–604, § 16</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1713">84 Stat. 1713</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/604/s16">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any implementation plan adopted by any State and submitted to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, or to the Administrator pursuant to the Clean Air Act [this chapter] prior to enactment of this Act [<date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>] may be approved under section 110 of the Clean Air Act [this section] (as amended by this Act) [<ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref>] and shall remain in effect, unless the Administrator determines that such implementation plan, or any portion thereof, is not consistent with applicable requirements of the Clean Air Act [this chapter] (as amended by this Act) and will not provide for the attainment of national primary ambient air quality standards in the time required by such Act. If the Administrator so determines, he shall, within 90 days after promulgation of any national ambient air quality standards pursuant to section 109(a) of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7409/a">section 7409(a) of this title</ref>], notify the State and specify in what respects changes are needed to meet the additional requirements of such Act, including requirements to implement national secondary ambient air quality standards. If such changes are not adopted by the State after public hearings and within six months after such notification, the Administrator shall promulgate such changes pursuant to section 110(c) of such Act [subsec. (c) of this section].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The amendments made by section 4(b) [amending sections 7403 and 7415 of this title] shall not be construed as repealing or modifying the powers of the Administrator with respect to any conference convened under section 108(d) of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7415">section 7415 of this title</ref>] before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Regulations or standards issued under this title II of the Clean Air Act [subchapter II of this chapter] prior to the enactment of this Act [<date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>] shall continue in effect until revised by the Administrator consistent with the purposes of such Act [this chapter].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe1ac76b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Federal Energy Administrator</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Federal Energy Administrator”, for purposes of this chapter, to mean Administrator of Federal Energy Administration established by <ref href="/us/pl/93/275">Pub. L. 93–275</ref>, <date date="1974-05-07">May 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/97">88 Stat. 97</ref>, which is classified to section 761 et seq. of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, but with the term to mean any officer of the United States designated as such by the President until Federal Energy Administrator takes office and after Federal Energy Administration ceases to exist, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s798">section 798 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Energy Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
