<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe2dda51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7423"><num value="7423">§ 7423.</num><heading> Stack heights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2dda52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7423/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Heights in excess of good engineering practice; other dispersion techniques</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The degree of emission limitation required for control of any air pollutant under an applicable implementation plan under this subchapter shall not be affected in any manner by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2dda53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7423/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> so much of the stack height of any source as exceeds good engineering practice (as determined under regulations promulgated by the Administrator), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2dda54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7423/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any other dispersion technique.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to stack heights in existence before <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, or dispersion techniques implemented before such date. In establishing an emission limitation for coal-fired steam electric generating units which are subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7418">section 7418 of this title</ref> and which commenced operation before <date date="1957-07-01">July 1, 1957</date>, the effect of the entire stack height of stacks for which a construction contract was awarded before <date date="1974-02-08">February 8, 1974</date>, may be taken into account.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2dda55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7423/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Dispersion technique</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this section, the term “dispersion technique” includes any intermittent or supplemental control of air pollutants varying with atmospheric conditions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2dda56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7423/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations; good engineering practice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than six months after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, the Administrator, shall after notice and opportunity for public hearing, promulgate regulations to carry out this section. For purposes of this section, good engineering practice means, with respect to stack heights, the height necessary to insure that emissions from the stack do not result in excessive concentrations of any air pollutant in the immediate vicinity of the source as a result of atmospheric downwash, eddies and wakes which may be created by the source itself, nearby structures or nearby terrain obstacles (as determined by the Administrator). For purposes of this section such height shall not exceed two and a half times the height of such source unless the owner or operator of the source demonstrates, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, to the satisfaction of the Administrator, that a greater height is necessary as provided under the preceding sentence. In no event may the Administrator prohibit any increase in any stack height or restrict in any manner the stack height of any source.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe2dda57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 123, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI/s121">Pub. L. 95–95, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/721">91 Stat. 721</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe2dda58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe2dda59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbe2dda5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
