<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe2ddaa3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429"><num value="7429">§ 7429.</num><heading> Solid waste combustion</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddaa4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> New source performance standards</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddaa5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddaa6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator shall establish performance standards and other requirements pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section for each category of solid waste incineration units. Such standards shall include emissions limitations and other requirements applicable to new units and guidelines (under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411/d">section 7411(d) of this title</ref> and this section) and other requirements applicable to existing units.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddaa7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section applicable to solid waste incineration units with capacity greater than 250 tons per day combusting municipal waste shall be promulgated not later than 12 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>. Nothing in this subparagraph shall alter any schedule for the promulgation of standards applicable to such units under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> pursuant to any settlement and consent decree entered by the Administrator before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That, such standards are subsequently modified pursuant to the schedule established in this subparagraph to include each of the requirements of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddaa8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section applicable to solid waste incineration units with capacity equal to or less than 250 tons per day combusting municipal waste and units combusting hospital waste, medical waste and infectious waste shall be promulgated not later than 24 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddaa9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section applicable to solid waste incineration units combusting commercial or industrial waste shall be proposed not later than 36 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, and promulgated not later than 48 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddaaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Not later than 18 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall publish a schedule for the promulgation of standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section applicable to other categories of solid waste incineration units.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddaab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Emissions standard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Standards applicable to solid waste incineration units promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section shall reflect the maximum degree of reduction in emissions of air pollutants listed under section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003623">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003623"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection”.</note> (a)(4) that the Administrator, taking into consideration the cost of achieving such emission reduction, and any non-air quality health and environmental impacts and energy requirements, determines is achievable for new or existing units in each category. The Administrator may distinguish among classes, types (including mass-burn, refuse-derived fuel, modular and other types of units), and sizes of units within a category in establishing such standards. The degree of reduction in emissions that is deemed achievable for new units in a category shall not be less stringent than the emissions control that is achieved in practice by the best controlled similar unit, as determined by the Administrator. Emissions standards for existing units in a category may be less stringent than standards for new units in the same category but shall not be less stringent than the average emissions limitation achieved by the best performing 12 percent of units in the category (excluding units which first met lowest achievable emissions rates 18 months before the date such standards are proposed or 30 months before the date such standards are promulgated, whichever is later).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddaac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Control methods and technologies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section applicable to solid waste incineration units shall be based on methods and technologies for removal or destruction of pollutants before, during, or after combustion, and shall incorporate for new units siting requirements that minimize, on a site specific basis, to the maximum extent practicable, potential risks to public health or the environment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddaad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Numerical emissions limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The performance standards promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and this section and applicable to solid waste incineration units shall specify numerical emission limitations for the following substances or mixtures: particulate matter (total and fine), opacity (as appropriate), sulfur dioxide, hydrogen chloride, oxides of nitrogen, carbon monoxide, lead, cadmium, mercury, and dioxins and dibenzofurans. The Administrator may promulgate numerical emissions limitations or provide for the monitoring of postcombustion concentrations of surrogate substances, parameters or periods of residence time in excess of stated temperatures with respect to pollutants other than those listed in this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddaae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and revision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 5 years following the initial promulgation of any performance standards and other requirements under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> applicable to a category of solid waste incineration units, and at 5 year intervals thereafter, the Administrator shall review, and in accordance with this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref>, revise such standards and requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddaaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing units</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddab0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Performance standards under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> for solid waste incineration units shall include guidelines promulgated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411/d">section 7411(d) of this title</ref> and this section applicable to existing units. Such guidelines shall include, as provided in this section, each of the elements required by subsection (a) (emissions limitations, notwithstanding any restriction in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411/d">section 7411(d) of this title</ref> regarding issuance of such limitations), subsection (c) (monitoring), subsection (d) (operator training), subsection (e) (permits), and subsection (h)(4) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003624">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003624"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be subsection “(h)(3)”.</note> (residual risk).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddab1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> State plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after the Administrator promulgates guidelines for a category of solid waste incineration units, each State in which units in the category are operating shall submit to the Administrator a plan to implement and enforce the guidelines with respect to such units. The State plan shall be at least as protective as the guidelines promulgated by the Administrator and shall provide that each unit subject to the guidelines shall be in compliance with all requirements of this section not later than 3 years after the State plan is approved by the Administrator but not later than 5 years after the guidelines were promulgated. The Administrator shall approve or disapprove any State plan within 180 days of the submission, and if a plan is disapproved, the Administrator shall state the reasons for disapproval in writing. Any State may modify and resubmit a plan which has been disapproved by the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddab2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall develop, implement and enforce a plan for existing solid waste incineration units within any category located in any State which has not submitted an approvable plan under this subsection with respect to units in such category within 2 years after the date on which the Administrator promulgated the relevant guidelines. Such plan shall assure that each unit subject to the plan is in compliance with all provisions of the guidelines not later than 5 years after the date the relevant guidelines are promulgated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe2ddab3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall, as part of each performance standard promulgated pursuant to subsection (a) and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref>, promulgate regulations requiring the owner or operator of each solid waste incineration unit—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddab4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to monitor emissions from the unit at the point at which such emissions are emitted into the ambient air (or within the stack, combustion chamber or pollution control equipment, as appropriate) and at such other points as necessary to protect public health and the environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddab5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to monitor such other parameters relating to the operation of the unit and its pollution control technology as the Administrator determines are appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe2ddab6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to report the results of such monitoring.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such regulations shall contain provisions regarding the frequency of monitoring, test methods and procedures validated on solid waste incineration units, and the form and frequency of reports containing the results of monitoring and shall require that any monitoring reports or test results indicating an exceedance of any standard under this section shall be reported separately and in a manner that facilitates review for purposes of enforcement actions. Such regulations shall require that copies of the results of such monitoring be maintained on file at the facility concerned and that copies shall be made available for inspection and copying by interested members of the public during business hours.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Operator training</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 24 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall develop and promote a model State program for the training and certification of solid waste incineration unit operators and high-capacity fossil fuel fired plant operators. The Administrator may authorize any State to implement a model program for the training of solid waste incineration unit operators and high-capacity fossil fuel fired plant operators, if the State has adopted a program which is at least as effective as the model program developed by the Administrator. Beginning on the date 36 months after the date on which performance standards and guidelines are promulgated under subsection (a) and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> for any category of solid waste incineration units it shall be unlawful to operate any unit in the category unless each person with control over processes affecting emissions from such unit has satisfactorily completed a training program meeting the requirements established by the Administrator under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Permits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning (1) 36 months after the promulgation of a performance standard under subsection (a) and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> applicable to a category of solid waste incineration units, or (2) the effective date of a permit program under subchapter V in the State in which the unit is located, whichever is later, each unit in the category shall operate pursuant to a permit issued under this subsection and subchapter V. Permits required by this subsection may be renewed according to the provisions of subchapter V. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, each permit for a solid waste incineration unit combusting municipal waste issued under this chapter shall be issued for a period of up to 12 years and shall be reviewed every 5 years after date of issuance or reissuance. Each permit shall continue in effect after the date of issuance until the date of termination, unless the Administrator or State determines that the unit is not in compliance with all standards and conditions contained in the permit. Such determination shall be made at regular intervals during the term of the permit, such intervals not to exceed 5 years, and only after public comment and public hearing. No permit for a solid waste incineration unit may be issued under this chapter by an agency, instrumentality or person that is also responsible, in whole or part, for the design and construction or operation of the unit. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the Administrator or the State shall require the owner or operator of any unit to comply with emissions limitations or implement any other measures, if the Administrator or the State determines that emissions in the absence of such limitations or measures may reasonably be anticipated to endanger public health or the environment. The Administrator’s determination under the preceding sentence is a discretionary decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date and enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> New units</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Performance standards and other requirements promulgated pursuant to this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and applicable to new solid waste incineration units shall be effective as of the date 6 months after the date of promulgation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing units</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Performance standards and other requirements promulgated pursuant to this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and applicable to existing solid waste incineration units shall be effective as expeditiously as practicable after approval of a State plan under subsection (b)(2) (or promulgation of a plan by the Administrator under subsection (b)(3)) but in no event later than 3 years after the State plan is approved or 5 years after the date such standards or requirements are promulgated, whichever is earlier.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After the effective date of any performance standard, emission limitation or other requirement promulgated pursuant to this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref>, it shall be unlawful for any owner or operator of any solid waste incineration unit to which such standard, limitation or requirement applies to operate such unit in violation of such limitation, standard or requirement or for any other person to violate an applicable requirement of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with other authorities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of sections 7411(e), 7413, 7414, 7416, 7420, 7603, 7604, 7607 of this title and other provisions for the enforcement of this chapter, each performance standard, emission limitation or other requirement established pursuant to this section by the Administrator or a State or local government, shall be treated in the same manner as a standard of performance under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> which is an emission limitation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of section 306 of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 and this section only—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Solid waste incineration unit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “solid waste incineration unit” means a distinct operating unit of any facility which combusts any solid waste material from commercial or industrial establishments or the general public (including single and multiple residences, hotels, and motels). Such term does not include incinerators or other units required to have a permit under section 3005 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6925">42 U.S.C. 6925</ref>]. The term “solid waste incineration unit” does not include (A) materials recovery facilities (including primary or secondary smelters) which combust waste for the primary purpose of recovering metals, (B) qualifying small power production facilities, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s796/17/C">section 796(17)(C) of title 16</ref>, or qualifying cogeneration facilities, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s796/18/B">section 796(18)(B) of title 16</ref>, which burn homogeneous waste (such as units which burn tires or used oil, but not including refuse-derived fuel) for the production of electric energy or in the case of qualifying cogeneration facilities which burn homogeneous waste for the production of electric energy and steam or forms of useful energy (such as heat) which are used for industrial, commercial, heating or cooling purposes, or (C) air curtain incinerators provided that such incinerators only burn wood wastes, yard wastes and clean lumber and that such air curtain incinerators comply with opacity limitations to be established by the Administrator by rule.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> New solid waste incineration unit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “new solid waste incineration unit” means a solid waste incineration unit the construction of which is commenced after the Administrator proposes requirements under this section establishing emissions standards or other requirements which would be applicable to such unit or a modified solid waste incineration unit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Modified solid waste incineration unit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “modified solid waste incineration unit” means a solid waste incineration unit at which modifications have occurred after the effective date of a standard under subsection (a) if (A) the cumulative cost of the modifications, over the life of the unit, exceed 50 per centum of the original cost of construction and installation of the unit (not including the cost of any land purchased in connection with such construction or installation) updated to current costs, or (B) the modification is a physical change in or change in the method of operation of the unit which increases the amount of any air pollutant emitted by the unit for which standards have been established under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing solid waste incineration unit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “existing solid waste incineration unit” means a solid waste unit which is not a new or modified solid waste incineration unit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Municipal waste</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “municipal waste” means refuse (and refuse-derived fuel) collected from the general public and from residential, commercial, institutional, and industrial sources consisting of paper, wood, yard wastes, food wastes, plastics, leather, rubber, and other combustible materials and non-combustible materials such as metal, glass and rock, provided that: (A) the term does not include industrial process wastes or medical wastes that are segregated from such other wastes; and (B) an incineration unit shall not be considered to be combusting municipal waste for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> or this section if it combusts a fuel feed stream, 30 percent or less of the weight of which is comprised, in aggregate, of municipal waste.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/g/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Other terms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The terms “solid waste” and “medical waste” shall have the meanings established by the Administrator pursuant to the Solid Waste Disposal Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Other authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> State authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall preclude or deny the right of any State or political subdivision thereof to adopt or enforce any regulation, requirement, limitation or standard relating to solid waste incineration units that is more stringent than a regulation, requirement, limitation or standard in effect under this section or under any other provision of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Other authority under this chapter</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall diminish the authority of the Administrator or a State to establish any other requirements applicable to solid waste incineration units under any other authority of law, including the authority to establish for any air pollutant a national ambient air quality standard, except that no solid waste incineration unit subject to performance standards under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> shall be subject to standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7412/d">section 7412(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Residual risk</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall promulgate standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7412/f">section 7412(f) of this title</ref> for a category of solid waste incineration units, if promulgation of such standards is required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7412/f">section 7412(f) of this title</ref>. For purposes of this <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003625">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003625"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “the”.</note> preceding sentence only—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3023b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the performance standards under subsection (a) and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> applicable to a category of solid waste incineration units shall be deemed standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7412/d/2">section 7412(d)(2) of this title</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3023ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Administrator shall consider and regulate, if required, the pollutants listed under subsection (a)(4) and no others.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Acid rain</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A solid waste incineration unit shall not be a utility unit as defined in subchapter IV–A: <i>Provided</i>, That, more than 80 per centum of its annual average fuel consumption measured on a Btu basis, during a period or periods to be determined by the Administrator, is from a fuel (including any waste burned as a fuel) other than a fossil fuel.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3023bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7429/h/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements of parts C and D</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No requirement of an applicable implementation plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7475">section 7475 of this title</ref> (relating to construction of facilities in regions identified pursuant to section 7407(d)(1)(A)(ii) or (iii) of this title) or under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7502/c/5">section 7502(c)(5) of this title</ref> (relating to permits for construction and operation in nonattainment areas) may be used to weaken the standards in effect under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe3023bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 129, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIII/s305/a">Pub. L. 101–549, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2577">104 Stat. 2577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe3023be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe3023bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe3023c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 306 of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990, referred to in subsec. (g), probably means <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s306">section 306 of Pub. L. 101–549</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6921">section 6921 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Solid Waste Disposal Act, referred to in subsec. (g)(6), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/89/272">Pub. L. 89–272</ref>, <date date="1965-10-20">Oct. 20, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/997">79 Stat. 997</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2795">90 Stat. 2795</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 82 (§ 6901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">section 6901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe3023c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe3023c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Acid Gas Scrubbing Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIII/s305/c">Pub. L. 101–549, title III, § 305(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2583">104 Stat. 2583</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/549/tIII/s305/c">“Prior to the promulgation of any performance standard for solid waste incineration units combusting municipal waste under section 111 or section 129 of the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</ref>, 7429], the Administrator shall review the availability of acid gas scrubbers as a pollution control technology for small new units and for existing units (as defined in 54 Federal Register 52190 (<date date="1989-12-20">December 20, 1989</date>)[)], taking into account the provisions of subsection (a)(2) of section 129 of the Clean Air Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
