<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe3294ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474"><num value="7474">§ 7474.</num><heading> Area redesignation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of States to redesignate areas</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided under subsection (c), a State may redesignate such areas as it deems appropriate as class I areas. The following areas may be redesignated only as class I or II:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3294af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an area which exceeds ten thousand acres in size and is a national monument, a national primitive area, a national preserve, a national recreation area, a national wild and scenic river, a national wildlife refuge, a national lakeshore or seashore, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3294b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a national park or national wilderness area established after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, which exceeds ten thousand acres in size.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The extent of the areas referred to in paragraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003629">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003629"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraphs”.</note> (1) and (2) shall conform to any changes in the boundaries of such areas which have occurred subsequent to <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, or which may occur subsequent to <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>. Any area (other than an area referred to in paragraph (1) or (2) or an area established as class I under the first sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7472/a">section 7472(a) of this title</ref>) may be redesignated by the State as class III if—</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3294b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/a/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such redesignation has been specifically approved by the Governor of the State, after consultation with the appropriate Committees of the legislature if it is in session or with the leadership of the legislature if it is not in session (unless State law provides that such redesignation must be specifically approved by State legislation) and if general purpose units of local government representing a majority of the residents of the area so redesignated enact legislation (including for such units of local government resolutions where appropriate) concurring in the State’s redesignation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3294b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/a/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such redesignation will not cause, or contribute to, concentrations of any air pollutant which exceed any maximum allowable increase or maximum allowable concentration permitted under the classification of any other area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3294b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/a/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such redesignation otherwise meets the requirements of this part.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not apply to area redesignations by Indian tribes.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice and hearing; notice to Federal land manager; written comments and recommendations; regulations; disapproval of redesignation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3294b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3294b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Prior to redesignation of any area under this part, notice shall be afforded and public hearings shall be conducted in areas proposed to be redesignated and in areas which may be affected by the proposed redesignation. Prior to any such public hearing a satisfactory description and analysis of the health, environmental, economic, social, and energy effects of the proposed redesignation shall be prepared and made available for public inspection and prior to any such redesignation, the description and analysis of such effects shall be reviewed and examined by the redesignating authorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3294b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Prior to the issuance of notice under subparagraph (A) respecting the redesignation of any area under this subsection, if such area includes any Federal lands, the State shall provide written notice to the appropriate Federal land manager and afford adequate opportunity (but not in excess of 60 days) to confer with the State respecting the intended notice of redesignation and to submit written comments and recommendations with respect to such intended notice of redesignation. In redesignating any area under this section with respect to which any Federal land manager has submitted written comments and recommendations, the State shall publish a list of any inconsistency between such redesignation and such recommendations and an explanation of such inconsistency (together with the reasons for making such redesignation against the recommendation of the Federal land manager).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3294b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Administrator shall promulgate regulations not later than six months after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, to assure, insofar as practicable, that prior to any public hearing on redesignation of any area, there shall be available for public inspection any specific plans for any new or modified major emitting facility which may be permitted to be constructed and operated only if the area in question is designated or redesignated as class III.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3294b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator may disapprove the redesignation of any area only if he finds, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, that such redesignation does not meet the procedural requirements of this section or is inconsistent with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7472/a">section 7472(a) of this title</ref> or of subsection (a) of this section. If any such disapproval occurs, the classification of the area shall be that which was in effect prior to the redesignation which was disapproved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Indian reservations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Lands within the exterior boundaries of reservations of federally recognized Indian tribes may be redesignated only by the appropriate Indian governing body. Such Indian governing body shall be subject in all respect to the provisions of subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of national monuments, primitive areas, and national preserves</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Land Manager shall review all national monuments, primitive areas, and national preserves, and shall recommend any appropriate areas for redesignation as class I where air quality related values are important attributes of the area. The Federal Land Manager shall report such recommendations, within <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003630">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003630"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “with”.</note> supporting analysis, to the Congress and the affected States within one year after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>. The Federal Land Manager shall consult with the appropriate States before making such recommendations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7474/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Resolution of disputes between State and Indian tribes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any State affected by the redesignation of an area by an Indian tribe or any Indian tribe affected by the redesignation of an area by a State disagrees with such redesignation of any area, or if a permit is proposed to be issued for any new major emitting facility proposed for construction in any State which the Governor of an affected State or governing body of an affected Indian tribe determines will cause or contribute to a cumulative change in air quality in excess of that allowed in this part within the affected State or tribal reservation, the Governor or Indian ruling body may request the Administrator to enter into negotiations with the parties involved to resolve such dispute. If requested by any State or Indian tribe involved, the Administrator shall make a recommendation to resolve the dispute and protect the air quality related values of the lands involved. If the parties involved do not reach agreement, the Administrator shall resolve the dispute and his determination, or the results of agreements reached through other means, shall become part of the applicable plan and shall be enforceable as part of such plan. In resolving such disputes relating to area redesignation, the Administrator shall consider the extent to which the lands involved are of sufficient size to allow effective air quality management or have air quality related values of such an area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe3294bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 164, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI/s127/a">Pub. L. 95–95, title I, § 127(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/733">91 Stat. 733</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/42">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(42)</ref>, (43), <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1402">91 Stat. 1402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s108/n">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 108(n)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2469">104 Stat. 2469</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe3294be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe3294bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe3294c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549">Pub. L. 101–549</ref>, which directed the insertion of “The extent of the areas referred to in paragraph (1) and (2) shall conform to any changes in the boundaries of such areas which have occurred subsequent to <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, or which may occur subsequent to <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.” before “Any area (other than an area referred to in paragraph (1) or (2))”, was executed by making the insertion before “Any area (other than an area referred to in paragraph (1) or (2)”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/42">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(42)</ref>, inserted “or is inconsistent with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7472/a">section 7472(a) of this title</ref> or of subsection (a) of this section” after “this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/43">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(43)</ref>, inserted “an” after “If any State affected by the redesignation of”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
