<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe3294ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7476"><num value="7476">§ 7476.</num><heading> Other pollutants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7476/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, petrochemical oxidants, and nitrogen oxides</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of the pollutants hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, photochemical oxidants, and nitrogen oxides, the Administrator shall conduct a study and not later than two years after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, promulgate regulations to prevent the significant deterioration of air quality which would result from the emissions of such pollutants. In the case of pollutants for which national ambient air quality standards are promulgated after <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, he shall promulgate such regulations not more than 2 years after the date of promulgation of such standards.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7476/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date of regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Regulations referred to in subsection (a) shall become effective one year after the date of promulgation. Within 21 months after such date of promulgation such plan revision shall be submitted to the Administrator who shall approve or disapprove the plan within 25 months after such date or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003631">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003631"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “of”.</note> promulgation in the same manner as required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410">section 7410 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7476/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such regulations shall provide specific numerical measures against which permit applications may be evaluated, a framework for stimulating improved control technology, protection of air quality values, and fulfill the goals and purposes set forth in section 7401 and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7470">section 7470 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7476/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific measures to fulfill goals and purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The regulations of the Administrator under subsection (a) shall provide specific measures at least as effective as the increments established in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7473">section 7473 of this title</ref> to fulfill such goals and purposes, and may contain air quality increments, emission density requirements, or other measures.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7476/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Area classification plan not required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to any air pollutant for which a national ambient air quality standard is established other than sulfur oxides or particulate matter, an area classification plan shall not be required under this section if the implementation plan adopted by the State and submitted for the Administrator’s approval or promulgated by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410/c">section 7410(c) of this title</ref> contains other provisions which when considered as a whole, the Administrator finds will carry out the purposes in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7470">section 7470 of this title</ref> at least as effectively as an area classification plan for such pollutant. Such other provisions referred to in the preceding sentence need not require the establishment of maximum allowable increases with respect to such pollutant for any area to which this section applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3294f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7476/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> PM–10 increments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to substitute, for the maximum allowable increases in particulate matter specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7473/b">section 7473(b) of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7475/d/2/C/iv">section 7475(d)(2)(C)(iv) of this title</ref>, maximum allowable increases in particulate matter with an aerodynamic diameter smaller than or equal to 10 micrometers. Such substituted maximum allowable increases shall be of equal stringency in effect as those specified in the provisions for which they are substituted. Until the Administrator promulgates regulations under the authority of this subsection, the current maximum allowable increases in concentrations of particulate matter shall remain in effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe3294f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 166, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tI/s127/a">Pub. L. 95–95, title I, § 127(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/739">91 Stat. 739</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2462">104 Stat. 2462</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe3294f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe3294f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe3294f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549">Pub. L. 101–549</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
