<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe34df24-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492"><num value="7492">§ 7492.</num><heading> Visibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df25-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Studies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe34df26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Administrator, in conjunction with the National Park Service and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall conduct research to identify and evaluate sources and source regions of both visibility impairment and regions that provide predominantly clean air in class I areas. A total of $8,000,000 per year for 5 years is authorized to be appropriated for the Environmental Protection Agency and the other Federal agencies to conduct this research. The research shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe34df27-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> expansion of current visibility related monitoring in class I areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe34df28-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assessment of current sources of visibility impairing pollution and clean air corridors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe34df29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> adaptation of regional air quality models for the assessment of visibility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe34df2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> studies of atmospheric chemistry and physics of visibility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe34df2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Based on the findings available from the research required in subsection (a)(1) as well as other available scientific and technical data, studies, and other available information pertaining to visibility source-receptor relationships, the Administrator shall conduct an assessment and evaluation that identifies, to the extent possible, sources and source regions of visibility impairment including natural sources as well as source regions of clear air for class I areas. The Administrator shall produce interim findings from this study within 3 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Impacts of other provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 24 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of the progress and improvements in visibility in class I areas that are likely to result from the implementation of the provisions of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 other than the provisions of this section. Every 5 years thereafter the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of actual progress and improvement in visibility in class I areas. The Administrator shall prepare a written report on each assessment and transmit copies of these reports to the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of visibility transport regions and commissions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to establish visibility transport regions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever, upon the Administrator’s motion or by petition from the Governors of at least two affected States, the Administrator has reason to believe that the current or projected interstate transport of air pollutants from one or more States contributes significantly to visibility impairment in class I areas located in the affected States, the Administrator may establish a transport region for such pollutants that includes such States. The Administrator, upon the Administrator’s own motion or upon petition from the Governor of any affected State, or upon the recommendations of a transport commission established under subsection (b) of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003632">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003632"><num>1</num> So in original. Words “subsection (b) of this section” probably should be “paragraph (2)”.</note> may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> add any State or portion of a State to a visibility transport region when the Administrator determines that the interstate transport of air pollutants from such State significantly contributes to visibility impairment in a class I area located within the transport region, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> remove any State or portion of a State from the region whenever the Administrator has reason to believe that the control of emissions in that State or portion of the State pursuant to this section will not significantly contribute to the protection or enhancement of visibility in any class I area in the region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Visibility transport commissions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the Administrator establishes a transport region under subsection (c)(1), the Administrator shall establish a transport commission comprised of (as a minimum) each of the following members:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Governor of each State in the Visibility Transport Region, or the Governor’s designee;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003633">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003633"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> Administrator or the Administrator’s designee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A <sup>2</sup> representative of each Federal agency charged with the direct management of each class I area or areas within the Visibility Transport Region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Ex officio members</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">All representatives of the Federal Government shall be ex officio members.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Chapter 10 of title 5</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The visibility transport commissions shall be exempt from the requirements of chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of visibility transport commissions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A Visibility Transport Commission—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe34df38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall assess the scientific and technical data, studies, and other currently available information, including studies conducted pursuant to subsection (a)(1), pertaining to adverse impacts on visibility from potential or projected growth in emissions from sources located in the Visibility Transport Region; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe34df39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> shall, within 4 years of establishment, issue a report to the Administrator recommending what measures, if any, should be taken under this chapter to remedy such adverse impacts. The report required by this subsection shall address at least the following measures:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the establishment of clean air corridors, in which additional restrictions on increases in emissions may be appropriate to protect visibility in affected class I areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the imposition of the requirements of part D of this subchapter affecting the construction of new major stationary sources or major modifications to existing sources in such clean air corridors specifically including the alternative siting analysis provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7503/a/5">section 7503(a)(5) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe34df3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the promulgation of regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7491">section 7491 of this title</ref> to address long range strategies for addressing regional haze which impairs visibility in affected class I areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of Administrator</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe34df3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administrator shall, taking into account the studies pursuant to subsection (a)(1) and the reports pursuant to subsection (d)(2) and any other relevant information, within eighteen months of receipt of the report referred to in subsection (d)(2) of this section, carry out the Administrator’s regulatory responsibilities under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7491">section 7491 of this title</ref>, including criteria for measuring “reasonable progress” toward the national goal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe34df3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any regulations promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7491">section 7491 of this title</ref> pursuant to this subsection shall require affected States to revise within 12 months their implementation plans under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410">section 7410 of this title</ref> to contain such emission limits, schedules of compliance, and other measures as may be necessary to carry out regulations promulgated pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe34df40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7492/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Grand Canyon visibility transport commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator pursuant to subsection (c)(1) shall, within 12 months, establish a visibility transport commission for the region affecting the visibility of the Grand Canyon National Park.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe34df41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 169B, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tVIII/s816">Pub. L. 101–549, title VIII, § 816</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2695">104 Stat. 2695</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/269">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(269)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4335">136 Stat. 4335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe34df42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe34df43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe34df44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means <ref href="/us/pl/101/549">Pub. L. 101–549</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2399">104 Stat. 2399</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe34df45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
