<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe374ff9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a"><num value="7506a">§ 7506a.</num><heading> Interstate transport commissions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe374ffa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to establish interstate transport regions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever, on the Administrator’s own motion or by petition from the Governor of any State, the Administrator has reason to believe that the interstate transport of air pollutants from one or more States contributes significantly to a violation of a national ambient air quality standard in one or more other States, the Administrator may establish, by rule, a transport region for such pollutant that includes such States. The Administrator, on the Administrator’s own motion or upon petition from the Governor of any State, or upon the recommendation of a transport commission established under subsection (b), may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe374ffb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> add any State or portion of a State to any region established under this subsection whenever the Administrator has reason to believe that the interstate transport of air pollutants from such State significantly contributes to a violation of the standard in the transport region, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe374ffc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> remove any State or portion of a State from the region whenever the Administrator has reason to believe that the control of emissions in that State or portion of the State pursuant to this section will not significantly contribute to the attainment of the standard in any area in the region.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Administrator shall approve or disapprove any such petition or recommendation within 18 months of its receipt. The Administrator shall establish appropriate proceedings for public participation regarding such petitions and motions, including notice and comment.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe374ffd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transport commissions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe374ffe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the Administrator establishes a transport region under subsection (a), the Administrator shall establish a transport commission comprised of (at a minimum) each of the following members:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe374fff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Governor of each State in the region or the designee of each such Governor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe375000-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Administrator or the Administrator’s designee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe375001-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Regional Administrator (or the Administrator’s designee) for each Regional Office for each Environmental Protection Agency Region affected by the transport region concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe375002-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> An air pollution control official representing each State in the region, appointed by the Governor.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Decisions of, and recommendations and requests to, the Administrator by each transport commission may be made only by a majority vote of all members other than the Administrator and the Regional Administrators (or designees thereof).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe375003-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The transport commission shall assess the degree of interstate transport of the pollutant or precursors to the pollutant throughout the transport region, assess strategies for mitigating the interstate pollution, and recommend to the Administrator such measures as the Commission determines to be necessary to ensure that the plans for the relevant States meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/D">section 7410(a)(2)(D) of this title</ref>. Such commission shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe375004-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7506a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Commission requests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A transport commission established under subsection (b) may request the Administrator to issue a finding under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/5">section 7410(k)(5) of this title</ref> that the implementation plan for one or more of the States in the transport region is substantially inadequate to meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410/a/2/D">section 7410(a)(2)(D) of this title</ref>. The Administrator shall approve, disapprove, or partially approve and partially disapprove such a request within 18 months of its receipt and, to the extent the Administrator approves such request, issue the finding under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7410/k/5">section 7410(k)(5) of this title</ref> at the time of such approval. In acting on such request, the Administrator shall provide an opportunity for public participation and shall address each specific recommendation made by the commission. Approval or disapproval of such a request shall constitute final agency action within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7607/b">section 7607(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe375005-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 176A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s102/f/1">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 102(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2419">104 Stat. 2419</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/270">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(270)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4335">136 Stat. 4335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe375006-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe375007-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe375008-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
