<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe3c0ace-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b"><num value="7511b">§ 7511b.</num><heading> Federal ozone measures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0acf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Control techniques guidelines for VOC sources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 3 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall issue control techniques guidelines, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7408">section 7408 of this title</ref>, for 11 categories of stationary sources of VOC emissions for which such guidelines have not been issued as of <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, not including the categories referred to in paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (b) of this section. The Administrator may issue such additional control techniques guidelines as the Administrator deems necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ad0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing and new CTGS</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3c0ad1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 36 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, and periodically thereafter, the Administrator shall review and, if necessary, update control technique guidance issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7408">section 7408 of this title</ref> before <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3c0ad2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In issuing the guidelines the Administrator shall give priority to those categories which the Administrator considers to make the most significant contribution to the formation of ozone air pollution in ozone nonattainment areas, including hazardous waste treatment, storage, and disposal facilities which are permitted under subtitle C of the Solid Waste Disposal Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6921">42 U.S.C. 6921</ref> et seq.]. Thereafter the Administrator shall periodically review and, if necessary, revise such guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3c0ad3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Within 3 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall issue control techniques guidelines in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7408">section 7408 of this title</ref> to reduce the aggregate emissions of volatile organic compounds into the ambient air from aerospace coatings and solvents. Such control techniques guidelines shall, at a minimum, be adequate to reduce aggregate emissions of volatile organic compounds into the ambient air from the application of such coatings and solvents to such level as the Administrator determines may be achieved through the adoption of best available control measures. Such control technology guidance shall provide for such reductions in such increments and on such schedules as the Administrator determines to be reasonable, but in no event later than 10 years after the final issuance of such control technology guidance. In developing control technology guidance under this subsection, the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration with regard to the establishment of specifications for such coatings. In evaluating VOC reduction strategies, the guidance shall take into account the applicable requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7412">section 7412 of this title</ref> and the need to protect stratospheric ozone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3c0ad4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Within 3 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall issue control techniques guidelines in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7408">section 7408 of this title</ref> to reduce the aggregate emissions of volatile organic compounds and PM–10 into the ambient air from paints, coatings, and solvents used in shipbuilding operations and ship repair. Such control techniques guidelines shall, at a minimum, be adequate to reduce aggregate emissions of volatile organic compounds and PM–10 into the ambient air from the removal or application of such paints, coatings, and solvents to such level as the Administrator determines may be achieved through the adoption of the best available control measures. Such control techniques guidelines shall provide for such reductions in such increments and on such schedules as the Administrator determines to be reasonable, but in no event later than 10 years after the final issuance of such control technology guidance. In developing control techniques guidelines under this subsection, the Administrator shall consult with the appropriate Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ad5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative control techniques</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 3 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall issue technical documents which identify alternative controls for all categories of stationary sources of volatile organic compounds and oxides of nitrogen which emit, or have the potential to emit 25 tons per year or more of such air pollutant. The Administrator shall revise and update such documents as the Administrator determines necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ad6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance for evaluating cost-effectiveness</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 1 year after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall provide guidance to the States to be used in evaluating the relative cost-effectiveness of various options for the control of emissions from existing stationary sources of air pollutants which contribute to nonattainment of the national ambient air quality standards for ozone.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ad7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Control of emissions from certain sources</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ad8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ad9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Best available controls</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “best available controls” means the degree of emissions reduction that the Administrator determines, on the basis of technological and economic feasibility, health, environmental, and energy impacts, is achievable through the application of the most effective equipment, measures, processes, methods, systems or techniques, including chemical reformulation, product or feedstock substitution, repackaging, and directions for use, consumption, storage, or disposal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ada-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Consumer or commercial product</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “consumer or commercial product” means any substance, product (including paints, coatings, and solvents), or article (including any container or packaging) held by any person, the use, consumption, storage, disposal, destruction, or decomposition of which may result in the release of volatile organic compounds. The term does not include fuels or fuel additives regulated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7545">section 7545 of this title</ref>, or motor vehicles, non-road vehicles, and non-road engines as defined under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7550">section 7550 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0adb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulated entities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “regulated entities” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0adc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> manufacturers, processors, wholesale distributors, or importers of consumer or commercial products for sale or distribution in interstate commerce in the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0add-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> manufacturers, processors, wholesale distributors, or importers that supply the entities listed under clause (i) with such products for sale or distribution in interstate commerce in the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ade-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Study and report</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0adf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator shall conduct a study of the emissions of volatile organic compounds into the ambient air from consumer and commercial products (or any combination thereof) in order to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0ae0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> determine their potential to contribute to ozone levels which violate the national ambient air quality standard for ozone; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0ae1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> establish criteria for regulating consumer and commercial products or classes or categories thereof which shall be subject to control under this subsection.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The study shall be completed and a report submitted to Congress not later than 3 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ae2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of certain factors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In establishing the criteria under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Administrator shall take into consideration each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0ae3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The uses, benefits, and commercial demand of consumer and commercial products.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0ae4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The health or safety functions (if any) served by such consumer and commercial products.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0ae5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Those consumer and commercial products which emit highly reactive volatile organic compounds into the ambient air.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0ae6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Those consumer and commercial products which are subject to the most cost-effective controls.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0ae7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The availability of alternatives (if any) to such consumer and commercial products which are of comparable costs, considering health, safety, and environmental impacts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ae8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations to require emission reductions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0ae9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Upon submission of the final report under paragraph (2), the Administrator shall list those categories of consumer or commercial products that the Administrator determines, based on the study, account for at least 80 percent of the VOC emissions, on a reactivity-adjusted basis, from consumer or commercial products in areas that violate the NAAQS for ozone. Credit toward the 80 percent emissions calculation shall be given for emission reductions from consumer or commercial products made after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>. At such time, the Administrator shall divide the list into 4 groups establishing priorities for regulation based on the criteria established in paragraph (2). Every 2 years after promulgating such list, the Administrator shall regulate one group of categories until all 4 groups are regulated. The regulations shall require best available controls as defined in this section. Such regulations may exempt health use products for which the Administrator determines there is no suitable substitute. In order to carry out this section, the Administrator may, by regulation, control or prohibit any activity, including the manufacture or introduction into commerce, offering for sale, or sale of any consumer or commercial product which results in emission of volatile organic compounds into the ambient air.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0aea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulated entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Regulations under this subsection may be imposed only with respect to regulated entities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0aeb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of CTGS</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For any consumer or commercial product the Administrator may issue control techniques guidelines under this chapter in lieu of regulations required under subparagraph (A) if the Administrator determines that such guidance will be substantially as effective as regulations in reducing emissions of volatile organic compounds which contribute to ozone levels in areas which violate the national ambient air quality standard for ozone.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0aec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Systems of regulation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The regulations under this subsection may include any system or systems of regulation as the Administrator may deem appropriate, including requirements for registration and labeling, self-monitoring and reporting, prohibitions, limitations, or economic incentives (including marketable permits and auctions of emissions rights) concerning the manufacture, processing, distribution, use, consumption, or disposal of the product.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0aed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Special fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any amounts collected by the Administrator under such regulations shall be deposited in a special fund in the United States Treasury for licensing and other services, which thereafter shall be available until expended, subject to annual appropriation Acts, solely to carry out the activities of the Administrator for which such fees, charges, or collections are established or made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0aee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any regulation established under this subsection shall be treated, for purposes of enforcement of this chapter, as a standard under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and any violation of such regulation shall be treated as a violation of a requirement of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411/e">section 7411(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0aef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> State administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each State may develop and submit to the Administrator a procedure under State law for implementing and enforcing regulations promulgated under this subsection. If the Administrator finds the State procedure is adequate, the Administrator shall approve such procedure. Nothing in this paragraph shall prohibit the Administrator from enforcing any applicable regulations under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0af0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Size, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No regulations regarding the size, shape, or labeling of a product may be promulgated, unless the Administrator determines such regulations to be useful in meeting any national ambient air quality standard.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0af1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/e/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> State consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any State which proposes regulations other than those adopted under this subsection shall consult with the Administrator regarding whether any other State or local subdivision has promulgated or is promulgating regulations on any products covered under this part. The Administrator shall establish a clearinghouse of information, studies, and regulations proposed and promulgated regarding products covered under this subsection and disseminate such information collected as requested by State or local subdivisions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0af2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Tank vessel standards</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0af3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Schedule for standards</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3c0af4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Within 2 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall promulgate standards applicable to the emission of VOCs and any other air pollutant from loading and unloading of tank vessels (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s2101">section 2101 of title 46</ref>) which the Administrator finds causes, or contributes to, air pollution that may be reasonably anticipated to endanger public health or welfare. Such standards shall require the application of reasonably available control technology, considering costs, any nonair-quality benefits, environmental impacts, energy requirements and safety factors associated with alternative control techniques. To the extent practicable such standards shall apply to loading and unloading facilities and not to tank vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3c0af5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any regulation prescribed under this subsection (and any revision thereof) shall take effect after such period as the Administrator finds (after consultation with the Secretary of the department <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003650">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003650"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be capitalized.</note> in which the Coast Guard is operating) necessary to permit the development and application of the requisite technology, giving appropriate consideration to the cost of compliance within such period, except that the effective date shall not be more than 2 years after promulgation of such regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0af6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations on equipment safety</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 6 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall issue regulations to ensure the safety of the equipment and operations which are to control emissions from the loading and unloading of tank vessels, under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3703">section 3703 of title 46</ref> and section 1225 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003651">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003651"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 33. The standards promulgated by the Administrator under paragraph (1) and the regulations issued by a State or political subdivision regarding emissions from the loading and unloading of tank vessels shall be consistent with the regulations regarding safety of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0af7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency authority</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3c0af8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator shall ensure compliance with the tank vessel emission standards prescribed under paragraph (1)(A). The Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall also ensure compliance with the tank vessel standards prescribed under paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe3c0af9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall ensure compliance with the regulations issued under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0afa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> State or local standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After the Administrator promulgates standards under this section, no State or political subdivision thereof may adopt or attempt to enforce any standard respecting emissions from tank vessels subject to regulation under paragraph (1) unless such standard is no less stringent than the standards promulgated under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0afb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any standard established under paragraph (1)(A) shall be treated, for purposes of enforcement of this chapter, as a standard under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref> and any violation of such standard shall be treated as a violation of a requirement of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411/e">section 7411(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0afc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Ozone design value study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall conduct a study of whether the methodology in use by the Environmental Protection Agency as of <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, for establishing a design value for ozone provides a reasonable indicator of the ozone air quality of ozone nonattainment areas. The Administrator shall obtain input from States, local subdivisions thereof, and others. The study shall be completed and a report submitted to Congress not later than 3 years after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>. The results of the study shall be subject to peer and public review before submitting it to Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0afd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Vehicles entering ozone nonattainment areas</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0afe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority regarding ozone inspection and maintenance testing</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0aff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No noncommercial motor vehicle registered in a foreign country and operated by a United States citizen or by an alien who is a permanent resident of the United States, or who holds a visa for the purposes of employment or educational study in the United States, may enter a covered ozone nonattainment area from a foreign country bordering the United States and contiguous to the nonattainment area more than twice in a single calendar-month period, if State law has requirements for the inspection and maintenance of such vehicles under the applicable implementation plan in the nonattainment area.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0b00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the operator presents documentation at the United States border entry point establishing that the vehicle has complied with such inspection and maintenance requirements as are in effect and are applicable to motor vehicles of the same type and model year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0b01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanctions for violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may impose and collect from the operator of any motor vehicle who violates, or attempts to violate, paragraph (1) a civil penalty of not more than $200 for the second violation or attempted violation and $400 for the third and each subsequent violation or attempted violation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0b02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> State election</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The prohibition set forth in paragraph (1) shall not apply in any State that elects to be exempt from the prohibition. Such an election shall take effect upon the President’s receipt of written notice from the Governor of the State notifying the President of such election.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0b03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative approach</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The prohibition set forth in paragraph (1) shall not apply in a State, and the President may implement an alternative approach, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3c0b04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the Governor of the State submits to the President a written description of an alternative approach to facilitate the compliance, by some or all foreign-registered motor vehicles, with the motor vehicle inspection and maintenance requirements that are—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0b05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> related to emissions of air pollutants;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0b06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in effect under the applicable implementation plan in the covered ozone nonattainment area; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3c0b07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> applicable to motor vehicles of the same types and model years as the foreign-registered motor vehicles; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3c0b08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the President approves the alternative approach as facilitating compliance with the motor vehicle inspection and maintenance requirements referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3c0b09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7511b/h/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of covered ozone nonattainment area</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this section, the term “covered ozone nonattainment area” means a Serious Area, as classified under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511">section 7511 of this title</ref> as of <date date="1998-10-27">October 27, 1998</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe3c0b0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 183, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s103">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2443">104 Stat. 2443</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/286/s2">Pub. L. 105–286, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2773">112 Stat. 2773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe3c0b0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe3c0b0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe3c0b0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Solid Waste Disposal Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/89/272">Pub. L. 89–272</ref>, <date date="1965-10-20">Oct. 20, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/997">79 Stat. 997</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2795">90 Stat. 2795</ref>. Subtitle C of the Act is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 6921 et seq.) of chapter 82 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">section 6901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1225">Section 1225 of title 33</ref>, referred to in subsec. (f)(2), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tIV/s402/e">Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 402(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4264">132 Stat. 4264</ref>. See Transitional and Savings Provisions note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s101">section 101 of Title 46</ref>, Shipping, and <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70011">section 70011 of Title 46</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe3c0b0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/105/286">Pub. L. 105–286</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe3c0b0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe3c0b10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment; Publication of Prohibition</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/286/s3">Pub. L. 105–286, § 3</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2774">112 Stat. 2774</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/286/s3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by section 2 [amending this section] takes effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>]. Nothing in that amendment shall require action that is inconsistent with the obligations of the United States under any international agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information</inline>.—</heading><content>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the appropriate agency of the United States shall distribute information to publicize the prohibition set forth in the amendment made by section 2.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbe3c0b11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
