<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe3e7c7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a"><num value="7513a">§ 7513a.</num><heading> Plan provisions and schedules for plan submissions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Moderate Areas</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan provisions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each State in which all or part of a Moderate Area is located shall submit, according to the applicable schedule under paragraph (2), an implementation plan that includes each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3e7c7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> For the purpose of meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7502/c/5">section 7502(c)(5) of this title</ref>, a permit program providing that permits meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7503">section 7503 of this title</ref> are required for the construction and operation of new and modified major stationary sources of PM–10.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3e7c7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Either (i) a demonstration (including air quality modeling) that the plan will provide for attainment by the applicable attainment date; or (ii) a demonstration that attainment by such date is impracticable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3e7c80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Provisions to assure that reasonably available control measures for the control of PM–10 shall be implemented no later than <date date="1993-12-10">December 10, 1993</date>, or 4 years after designation in the case of an area classified as moderate after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Schedule for plan submissions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State shall submit the plan required under subparagraph (1) no later than the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3e7c82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Within 1 year of <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, for areas designated nonattainment under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4">section 7407(d)(4) of this title</ref>, except that the provision required under subparagraph (1)(A) shall be submitted no later than <date date="1992-06-30">June 30, 1992</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3e7c83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 18 months after the designation as nonattainment, for those areas designated nonattainment after the designations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d/4">section 7407(d)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Serious Areas</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan provisions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to the provisions submitted to meet the requirements of paragraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003656">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003656"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection”.</note> (a)(1) (relating to Moderate Areas), each State in which all or part of a Serious Area is located shall submit an implementation plan for such area that includes each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3e7c86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A demonstration (including air quality modeling)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3e7c87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that the plan provides for attainment of the PM–10 national ambient air quality standard by the applicable attainment date, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe3e7c88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for any area for which the State is seeking, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7513/e">section 7513(e) of this title</ref>, an extension of the attainment date beyond the date set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7513/c">section 7513(c) of this title</ref>, that attainment by that date would be impracticable, and that the plan provides for attainment by the most expeditious alternative date practicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe3e7c89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Provisions to assure that the best available control measures for the control of PM–10 shall be implemented no later than 4 years after the date the area is classified (or reclassified) as a Serious Area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Schedule for plan submissions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State shall submit the demonstration required for an area under paragraph (1)(A) no later than 4 years after reclassification of the area to Serious, except that for areas reclassified under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7513/b/2">section 7513(b)(2) of this title</ref>, the State shall submit the attainment demonstration within 18 months after reclassification to Serious. A State shall submit the provisions described under paragraph (1)(B) no later than 18 months after reclassification of the area as a Serious Area.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Major sources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For any Serious Area, the terms “major source” and “major stationary source” include any stationary source or group of stationary sources located within a contiguous area and under common control that emits, or has the potential to emit, at least 70 tons per year of PM–10.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Milestones</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3e7c8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Plan revisions demonstrating attainment submitted to the Administrator for approval under this subpart shall contain quantitative milestones which are to be achieved every 3 years until the area is redesignated attainment and which demonstrate reasonable further progress, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7501/1">section 7501(1) of this title</ref>, toward attainment by the applicable date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3e7c8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Not later than 90 days after the date on which a milestone applicable to the area occurs, each State in which all or part of such area is located shall submit to the Administrator a demonstration that all measures in the plan approved under this section have been implemented and that the milestone has been met. A demonstration under this subsection shall be submitted in such form and manner, and shall contain such information and analysis, as the Administrator shall require. The Administrator shall determine whether or not a State’s demonstration under this subsection is adequate within 90 days after the Administrator’s receipt of a demonstration which contains the information and analysis required by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe3e7c8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If a State fails to submit a demonstration under paragraph (2) with respect to a milestone within the required period or if the Administrator determines that the area has not met any applicable milestone, the Administrator shall require the State, within 9 months after such failure or determination to submit a plan revision that assures that the State will achieve the next milestone (or attain the national ambient air quality standard for PM–10, if there is no next milestone) by the applicable date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to attain</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a Serious PM–10 nonattainment area in which the PM–10 standard is not attained by the applicable attainment date, the State in which such area is located shall, after notice and opportunity for public comment, submit within 12 months after the applicable attainment date, plan revisions which provide for attainment of the PM–10 air quality standard and, from the date of such submission until attainment, for an annual reduction in PM–10 or PM–10 precursor emissions within the area of not less than 5 percent of the amount of such emissions as reported in the most recent inventory prepared for such area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe3e7c91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7513a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> PM–10 precursors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The control requirements applicable under plans in effect under this part for major stationary sources of PM–10 shall also apply to major stationary sources of PM–10 precursors, except where the Administrator determines that such sources do not contribute significantly to PM–10 levels which exceed the standard in the area. The Administrator shall issue guidelines regarding the application of the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe3e7c92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title I, § 189, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tI/s105/a">Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2460">104 Stat. 2460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
