<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe43371e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522"><num value="7522">§ 7522.</num><heading> Prohibited acts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe43371f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Enumerated prohibitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The following acts and the causing thereof are prohibited—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433720-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of a manufacturer of new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines for distribution in commerce, the sale, or the offering for sale, or the introduction, or delivery for introduction, into commerce, or (in the case of any person, except as provided by regulation of the Administrator), the importation into the United States, of any new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine, manufactured after the effective date of regulations under this part which are applicable to such vehicle or engine unless such vehicle or engine is covered by a certificate of conformity issued (and in effect) under regulations prescribed under this part or part C in the case of clean-fuel vehicles (except as provided in subsection (b));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433721-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433722-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for any person to fail or refuse to permit access to or copying of records or to fail to make reports or provide information required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7542">section 7542 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433723-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for any person to fail or refuse to permit entry, testing or inspection authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7525/c">section 7525(c) of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7542">section 7542 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433724-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for any person to fail or refuse to perform tests, or have tests performed as required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7542">section 7542 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433725-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> for any manufacturer to fail to make information available as provided by regulation under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7521/m/5">section 7521(m)(5) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433726-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433727-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for any person to remove or render inoperative any device or element of design installed on or in a motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine in compliance with regulations under this subchapter prior to its sale and delivery to the ultimate purchaser, or for any person knowingly to remove or render inoperative any such device or element of design after such sale and delivery to the ultimate purchaser; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433728-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for any person to manufacture or sell, or offer to sell, or install, any part or component intended for use with, or as part of, any motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine, where a principal effect of the part or component is to bypass, defeat, or render inoperative any device or element of design installed on or in a motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine in compliance with regulations under this subchapter, and where the person knows or should know that such part or component is being offered for sale or installed for such use or put to such use; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe433729-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> for any manufacturer of a new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine subject to standards prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7521">section 7521 of this title</ref> or part C—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe43372a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to sell or lease any such vehicle or engine unless such manufacturer has complied with (i) the requirements of section 7541(a) and (b) of this title with respect to such vehicle or engine, and unless a label or tag is affixed to such vehicle or engine in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7541/c/3">section 7541(c)(3) of this title</ref>, or (ii) the corresponding requirements of part C in the case of clean fuel vehicles unless the manufacturer has complied with the corresponding requirements of part C <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003662">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003662"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe43372b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to fail or refuse to comply with the requirements of section 7541(c) or (e) of this title, or the corresponding requirements of part C in the case of clean fuel vehicles <sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe43372c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (c)(3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7541">section 7541 of this title</ref> and the corresponding requirements of part C in the case of clean fuel vehicles, to provide directly or indirectly in any communication to the ultimate purchaser or any subsequent purchaser that the coverage of any warranty under this chapter is conditioned upon use of any part, component, or system manufactured by such manufacturer or any person acting for such manufacturer or under his control, or conditioned upon service performed by any such person, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe43372d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to fail or refuse to comply with the terms and conditions of the warranty under section 7541(a) or (b) of this title or the corresponding requirements of part C in the case of clean fuel vehicles with respect to any vehicle; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe43372e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> for any person to violate <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7553">section 7553 of this title</ref>, 7554 of this title, or part C of this subchapter or any regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7553">section 7553 of this title</ref>, 7554 of this title, or part C.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">No action with respect to any element of design referred to in paragraph (3) (including any adjustment or alteration of such element) shall be treated as a prohibited act under such paragraph (3) if such action is in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7549">section 7549 of this title</ref>. Nothing in paragraph (3) shall be construed to require the use of manufacturer parts in maintaining or repairing any motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine. For the purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “manufacturer parts” means, with respect to a motor vehicle engine, parts produced or sold by the manufacturer of the motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine. No action with respect to any device or element of design referred to in paragraph (3) shall be treated as a prohibited act under that paragraph if (i) the action is for the purpose of repair or replacement of the device or element, or is a necessary and temporary procedure to repair or replace any other item and the device or element is replaced upon completion of the procedure, and (ii) such action thereafter results in the proper functioning of the device or element referred to in paragraph (3). No action with respect to any device or element of design referred to in paragraph (3) shall be treated as a prohibited act under that paragraph if the action is for the purpose of a conversion of a motor vehicle for use of a clean alternative fuel (as defined in this subchapter) and if such vehicle complies with the applicable standard under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7521">section 7521 of this title</ref> when operating on such fuel, and if in the case of a clean alternative fuel vehicle (as defined by rule by the Administrator), the device or element is replaced upon completion of the conversion procedure and such action results in proper functioning of the device or element when the motor vehicle operates on conventional fuel.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe43372f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions; refusal to admit vehicle or engine into United States; vehicles or engines intended for export</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe433730-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administrator may exempt any new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine, from subsection (a), upon such terms and conditions as he may find necessary for the purpose of research, investigations, studies, demonstrations, or training, or for reasons of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe433731-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine offered for importation or imported by any person in violation of subsection (a) shall be refused admission into the United States, but the Secretary of the Treasury and the Administrator may, by joint regulation, provide for deferring final determination as to admission and authorizing the delivery of such a motor vehicle or engine offered for import to the owner or consignee thereof upon such terms and conditions (including the furnishing of a bond) as may appear to them appropriate to insure that any such motor vehicle or engine will be brought into conformity with the standards, requirements, and limitations applicable to it under this part. The Secretary of the Treasury shall, if a motor vehicle or engine is finally refused admission under this paragraph, cause disposition thereof in accordance with the customs laws unless it is exported, under regulations prescribed by such Secretary, within ninety days of the date of notice of such refusal or such additional time as may be permitted pursuant to such regulations, except that disposition in accordance with the customs laws may not be made in such manner as may result, directly or indirectly, in the sale, to the ultimate consumer, of a new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine that fails to comply with applicable standards of the Administrator under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe433732-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7522/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine intended solely for export, and so labeled or tagged on the outside of the container and on the vehicle or engine itself, shall be subject to the provisions of subsection (a), except that if the country which is to receive such vehicle or engine has emission standards which differ from the standards prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7521">section 7521 of this title</ref>, then such vehicle or engine shall comply with the standards of such country which is to receive such vehicle or engine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe433733-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title II, § 203, as added <ref href="/us/pl/89/272/tI/s101/8">Pub. L. 89–272, title I, § 101(8)</ref>, <date date="1965-10-20">Oct. 20, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/993">79 Stat. 993</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/148/s2">Pub. L. 90–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="1967-11-21">Nov. 21, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/499">81 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref>, §§ 7(a), 11(a)(2)(A), 15(c)(2), <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1693">84 Stat. 1693</ref>, 1705, 1713; <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tII">Pub. L. 95–95, title II</ref>, §§ 206, 211(a), 218(a), (d), 219(a), (b), <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/755">91 Stat. 755</ref>, 757, 761, 762; <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/66">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(66)</ref>–(68), <date date="1977-11-16">Nov. 16, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1403">91 Stat. 1403</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tII">Pub. L. 101–549, title II</ref>, §§ 228(a), (b), (e), 230(6), <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2507">104 Stat. 2507</ref>, 2511, 2529.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe433734-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe433735-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe433736-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857f–2">section 1857f–2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe433737-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/b/2">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(b)(2)</ref>, inserted two sentences at end which set forth conditions under which actions with respect to devices or elements of design, referred to in par. (3), would not be deemed prohibited acts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/e/1">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or part C in the case of clean-fuel vehicles” before “(except”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/a">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(a)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “for any person to fail or refuse to permit access to or copying of records or to fail to make reports or provide information, required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7542">section 7542 of this title</ref> or for any person to fail or refuse to permit entry, testing, or inspection authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7525/c">section 7525(c) of this title</ref>;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/b/1">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(b)(1)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) for any person to remove or render inoperative any device or element of design installed on or in a motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine in compliance with regulations under this subchapter prior to its sale and delivery to the ultimate purchaser, or for any manufacturer or dealer knowingly to remove or render inoperative any such device or element of design after such sale and delivery to the ultimate purchaser; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) for any person engaged in the business of repairing, servicing, selling, leasing, or trading motor vehicles or motor vehicle engines, or who operates a fleet of motor vehicles, knowingly to remove or render inoperative any device or element of design installed on or in a motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine in compliance with regulations under this subchapter following its sale and delivery to the ultimate purchaser; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/e/2">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(e)(2)</ref>, inserted “or part C” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7521">section 7521 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/e/3">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(e)(3)</ref>, inserted cl. (i) designation and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/e/4">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(e)(4)</ref>, inserted at end “or the corresponding requirements of part C in the case of clean fuel vehicles”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/e/5">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(e)(5)</ref>, inserted “and the corresponding requirements of part C in the case of clean fuel vehicles” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7541">section 7541 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/e/6">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(e)(6)</ref>, inserted “or the corresponding requirements of part C in the case of clean fuel vehicles” before “with respect to any vehicle”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s228/e/7">Pub. L. 101–549, § 228(e)(7)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/s230/6">Pub. L. 101–549, § 230(6)</ref>, struck out subsec. (c) which related to exemptions to permit modifications of emission control devices or systems.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/68">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(68)</ref>, in closing text inserted a period after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7549">section 7549 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, §§ 206, 211(a), 218(a), 219(a), (b), inserted “or for any person to fail or refuse to permit entry, testing, or inspection authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7525/c">section 7525(c) of this title</ref>” in par. (2), designated existing provisions of par. (3) as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B), added subpars. (C) and (D) in par. (4), and, following par. (4), inserted provisions that no action with respect to any element of design referred to in par. (3) (including adjustment or alteration of such element) be treated as a prohibited act under par. (3) if the action is in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7549">section 7549 of this title</ref> and that nothing in par. (3) be construed to require the use of manufacturer parts in maintaining or repairing motor vehicles or motor vehicle engines.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/66">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(66)</ref>, substituted “purchaser;” for “purchaser,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/95/190/s14/a/67">Pub. L. 95–190, § 14(a)(67)</ref>, inserted “or” after “such person,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s218/d">Pub. L. 95–95, § 218(d)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7521">section 7521 of this title</ref>” for “subsection (a)” and “country which is to receive such vehicle or engine” for “country of export”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s7/a/1">Pub. L. 91–604, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, struck out reference to the manufacture of new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines for sale, inserted provision for issuance by the Administrator of regulations regarding exceptions in the case of importation of new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines, and substituted “importation” into the United States of such units for “importation for sale or resale” into the United States of such units.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s7/a/2">Pub. L. 91–604, § 7(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 208” for “section 207”, both of which, for purposes of codification, are translated as “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7542">section 7542 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref>, §§ 7(a)(3), 11(a)(2)(A), substituted “part” for “subchapter” and inserted provisions prohibiting the knowing removal or inoperation by manufacturers or dealers of devices or elements of design after sale and delivery to the ultimate purchaser.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s7/a/4">Pub. L. 91–604, § 7(a)(4)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref>, §§ 7(a)(5), 15(c)(2), struck out reference to the exemption of a class of new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines, struck out the protection of the public health and welfare from the enumeration of purposes for which exemptions may be made, and substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604">Pub. L. 91–604</ref>, §§ 7(a)(6), 11(a)(2)(A), 15(c)(2), substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare”, “importation or imported by any person” for “importation by a manufacturer”, and “part” for “subchapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s7/a/7/A">Pub. L. 91–604, § 7(a)(7)(A)</ref>, inserted provision that, if the country of export has emission standards which differ from the standards prescribed under subsec. (a), such vehicle or engine must comply with the standards of such country of export.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s7/a/7/B">Pub. L. 91–604, § 7(a)(7)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/148">Pub. L. 90–148</ref> substituted “conformity with regulations prescribed under this subchapter” for “conformity with regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7521">section 7521 of this title</ref>” in par. (1).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe433738-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe433739-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe43373a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other Actions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All rules, regulations, orders, determinations, contracts, certifications, authorizations, delegations, or other actions duly issued, made, or taken by or pursuant to act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>] to continue in full force and effect until modified or rescinded in accordance with act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [this chapter], see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
