<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe518e5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571"><num value="7571">§ 7571.</num><heading> Establishment of standards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe518e5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Study; proposed standards; hearings; issuance of regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe518e5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Within 90 days after <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, the Administrator shall commence a study and investigation of emissions of air pollutants from aircraft in order to determine—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe518e5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the extent to which such emissions affect air quality in air quality control regions throughout the United States, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe518e5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the technological feasibility of controlling such emissions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe518e5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe518e60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator shall, from time to time, issue proposed emission standards applicable to the emission of any air pollutant from any class or classes of aircraft engines which in his judgment causes, or contributes to, air pollution which may reasonably be anticipated to endanger public health or welfare.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe518e61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe518e62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Administrator shall consult with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration on aircraft engine emission standards.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe518e63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Administrator shall not change the aircraft engine emission standards if such change would significantly increase noise and adversely affect safety.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe518e64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Administrator shall hold public hearings with respect to such proposed standards. Such hearings shall, to the extent practicable, be held in air quality control regions which are most seriously affected by aircraft emissions. Within 90 days after the issuance of such proposed regulations, he shall issue such regulations with such modifications as he deems appropriate. Such regulations may be revised from time to time.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe518e65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date of regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any regulation prescribed under this section (and any revision thereof) shall take effect after such period as the Administrator finds necessary (after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation) to permit the development and application of the requisite technology, giving appropriate consideration to the cost of compliance within such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe518e66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7571/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations which create hazards to aircraft safety</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any regulations in effect under this section on <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, or proposed or promulgated thereafter, or amendments thereto, with respect to aircraft shall not apply if disapproved by the President, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, on the basis of a finding by the Secretary of Transportation that any such regulation would create a hazard to aircraft safety. Any such finding shall include a reasonably specific statement of the basis upon which the finding was made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe518e67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title II, § 231, as added <ref href="/us/pl/91/604/s11/a/1">Pub. L. 91–604, § 11(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1703">84 Stat. 1703</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/tII/s225">Pub. L. 95–95, title II, § 225</ref>, title IV, § 401(f), <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/769">91 Stat. 769</ref>, 791; <ref href="/us/pl/104/264/tIV/s406/b">Pub. L. 104–264, title IV, § 406(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3257">110 Stat. 3257</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe518e68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe518e69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe518e6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1857f–9">section 1857f–9 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe518e6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/264">Pub. L. 104–264</ref> designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s401/f">Pub. L. 95–95, § 401(f)</ref>, substituted “The Administrator shall, from time to time, issue proposed emission standards applicable to the emission of any air pollutant from any class or classes of aircraft engines which in his judgment causes, or contributes to, air pollution which may reasonably be anticipated to endanger public health or welfare” for “Within 180 days after commencing such study and investigation, the Administrator shall publish a report of such study and investigation and shall issue proposed emission standards applicable to emissions of any air pollutant from any class or classes of aircraft or aircraft engines which in his judgment cause or contribute to or are likely to cause or contribute to air pollution which endangers the public health or welfare”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s225">Pub. L. 95–95, § 225</ref>, substituted “Any regulations in effect under this section on <date date="1977-08-07">August 7, 1977</date>, or proposed or promulgated thereafter, or amendments thereto, with respect to aircraft shall not apply if disapproved by the President, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, on the basis of a finding by the Secretary of Transportation that any such regulation would create a hazard to aircraft safety” for “Any regulations under this section, or amendments thereto, with respect to aircraft, shall be prescribed only after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation in order to assure appropriate consideration for aircraft safety” and inserted provision that findings include a reasonably specific statement of the basis upon which the finding was made.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe518e6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe518e6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise specifically provided, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/264">Pub. L. 104–264</ref> applicable only to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, and not to be construed as affecting funds made available for a fiscal year ending before <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/264/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 104–264</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe518e6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> effective <date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/d">section 406(d) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe518e6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other Actions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All rules, regulations, orders, determinations, contracts, certifications, authorizations, delegations, or other actions duly issued, made, or taken by or pursuant to act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [<date date="1977-08-07">Aug. 7, 1977</date>] to continue in full force and effect until modified or rescinded in accordance with act <date date="1955-07-14">July 14, 1955</date>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/95">Pub. L. 95–95</ref> [this chapter], see <ref href="/us/pl/95/95/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 95–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe518e70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study and Investigation of Uninstalled Aircraft Engines</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tII/s233">Pub. L. 101–549, title II, § 233</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2529">104 Stat. 2529</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/549/tII/s233">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall commence a study and investigation of the testing of uninstalled aircraft engines in enclosed test cells that shall address at a minimum the following issues and such other issues as they shall deem appropriate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> whether technologies exist to control some or all emissions of oxides of nitrogen from test cells;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the effectiveness of such technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the cost of implementing such technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> whether such technologies affect the safety, design, structure, operation, or performance of aircraft engines;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> whether such technologies impair the effectiveness and accuracy of aircraft engine safety design, and performance tests conducted in test cells; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the impact of not controlling such oxides of nitrogen in the applicable nonattainment areas and on other sources, stationary and mobile, on oxides of nitrogen in such areas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report, Authority To Regulate</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 24 months after enactment of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 [<date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>], the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to Congress a report of the study conducted under this section. Following the completion of such study, any of the States may adopt or enforce any standard for emissions of oxides of nitrogen from test cells only after issuing a public notice stating whether such standards are in accordance with the findings of the study.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
