<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe64a1b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o"><num value="7651o">§ 7651o.</num><heading> Contingency guarantee, auctions, reserve</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a1b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “independent power producer” means any person who owns or operates, in whole or in part, one or more new independent power production facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a1b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The term “new independent power production facility” means a facility that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is used for the generation of electric energy, 80 percent or more of which is sold at wholesale;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is nonrecourse project-financed (as such term is defined by the Secretary of Energy within 3 months of <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> does not generate electric energy sold to any affiliate (as defined in section 79b(a)(11) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003771">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003771"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 15) of the facility’s owner or operator unless the owner or operator of the facility demonstrates that it cannot obtain allowances from the affiliate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> is a new unit required to hold allowances under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a1bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “required allowances” means the allowances required to operate such unit for so much of the unit’s useful life as occurs after <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Special reserve of allowances</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 36 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations establishing a Special Allowance Reserve containing allowances to be sold under this section. For purposes of establishing the Special Allowance Reserve, the Administrator shall withhold—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a1bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 2.8 percent of the allocation of allowances for each year from 1995 through 1999 inclusive; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a1c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> 2.8 percent of the basic Phase II allowance allocation of allowances for each year beginning in the year 2000</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">which would (but for this subsection) be issued for each affected unit at an affected source. The Administrator shall record such withholding for purposes of transferring the proceeds of the allowance sales under this subsection. The allowances so withheld shall be deposited in the Reserve under this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct sale at $1,500 per ton</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Subaccount for direct sales</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In accordance with regulations under this section, the Administrator shall establish a Direct Sale Subaccount in the Special Allowance Reserve established under this section. The Direct Sale Subaccount shall contain allowances in the amount of 50,000 tons per year for each year beginning in the year 2000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Sales</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Allowances in the subaccount shall be offered for direct sale to any person at the times and in the amounts specified in table 1 at a price of $1,500 per allowance, adjusted by the Consumer Price Index in the same manner as provided in paragraph (3). Requests to purchase allowances from the Direct Sale Subaccount established under paragraph (1) shall be approved in the order of receipt until no allowances remain in such subaccount, except that an opportunity to purchase such allowances shall be provided to the independent power producers referred to in this subsection before such allowances are offered to any other person. Each applicant shall be required to pay 50 percent of the total purchase price of the allowances within 6 months after the approval of the request to purchase. The remainder shall be paid on or before the transfer of the allowances.<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  -uslm-lc: c3,L1,tp7,p7,7/8,s10,xs42,xls48,tp7,p7,7/8,s10,xs42,xls48; " id="idbe64a1c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 108pt;" />
<html:col style="width:46pt ; max-width:46pt;" />
<html:col style="width:52pt ; max-width:52pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Table </html:span>1<html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">—Number of Allowances Available for Sale at </html:span>$1,500 <html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Per Ton</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 108.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;">Year of Sale</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:46.0pt ; max-width:46.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;">Spot Sale (same year)</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:52.0pt ; max-width:52.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;">Advance Sale</html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tfoot style="  border-top:1px solid black;"><html:tr><html:td colspan="3" style="text-align:justify; text-indent:1em; font-size:6pt ">
<html:p><html:a name="TAB_92_0" />Allowances sold in the spot sale in any year are allowances which may only be used in that year (unless banked for use in a later year). Allowances sold in the advance sale in any year are allowances which may only be used in the 7th year after the year in which they are first offered for sale (unless banked for use in a later year).</html:p>
</html:td></html:tr>
</html:tfoot>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I31;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify;" class="leaders"><html:span>1993–1999</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> </html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">25,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>2000 and after</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">25,000</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">25,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Entitlement to written guarantee</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any independent power producer that submits an application to the Administrator establishing that such independent power producer—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> proposes to construct a new independent power production facility for which allowances are required under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> will apply for financing to construct such facility after <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, and before the date of the first auction under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has submitted to each owner or operator of an affected unit listed in table A (in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651c">section 7651c of this title</ref>) a written offer to purchase the required allowances for $750 per ton; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> has not received (within 180 days after submitting offers to purchase under subparagraph (C)) an acceptance of the offer to purchase the required allowances,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall, within 30 days after submission of such application, be entitled to receive the Administrator’s written guarantee (subject to the eligibility requirements set forth in paragraph (4)) that such required allowances will be made available for purchase from the Direct Sale Subaccount established under this subsection and at a guaranteed price. The guaranteed price at which such allowances shall be made available for purchase shall be $1,500 per ton, adjusted by the percentage, if any, by which the Consumer Price Index (as determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7661a/b/3/B/v">section 7661a(b)(3)(B)(v) of this title</ref>) for the year in which the allowance is purchased exceeds the Consumer Price Index for the calendar year 1990.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The guarantee issued by the Administrator under paragraph (3) shall be subject to a demonstration by the independent power producer, satisfactory to the Administrator, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the independent power producer has—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe64a1cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> made good faith efforts to purchase the required allowances from the owners or operators of affected units to which allowances will be allocated, including efforts to purchase at annual auctions under this section, and from industrial sources that have elected to become affected units pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651i">section 7651i of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe64a1cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such bids and efforts were unsuccessful in obtaining the required allowances; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe64a1ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the independent power producer will continue to make good faith efforts to purchase the required allowances from the owners or operators of affected units and from industrial sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of guaranteed allowances from Direct Sale Subaccount under this section</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">From the allowances available in the Direct Sale Subaccount established under this subsection, upon payment of the guaranteed price, the Administrator shall issue to any person exercising the right to purchase allowances pursuant to a guarantee under this subsection the allowances covered by such guarantee. Persons to which guarantees under this subsection have been issued shall have the opportunity to purchase allowances pursuant to such guarantee from such subaccount before the allowances in such reserve are offered for sale to any other person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Proceeds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">section 3302 of title 31</ref> or any other provision of law, the Administrator shall require that the proceeds of any sale under this subsection be transferred, within 90 days after the sale, without charge, on a pro rata basis to the owners or operators of the affected units from whom the allowances were withheld under subsection (b) and that any unsold allowances be transferred to the Subaccount for Auction Sales established under subsection (d). No proceeds of any sale under this subsection shall be held by any officer or employee of the United States or treated for any purpose as revenue to the United States or to the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of subaccount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Administrator determines that, during any period of 2 consecutive calendar years, less than 20 percent of the allowances available in the subaccount for direct sales established under this subsection have been purchased under this paragraph, the Administrator shall terminate the subaccount and transfer such allowances to the Auction Subaccount under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Auction sales</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Subaccount for auctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall establish an Auction Subaccount in the Special Reserve established under this section. The Auction Subaccount shall contain allowances to be sold at auction under this section in the amount of 150,000 tons per year for each year from 1995 through 1999, inclusive and 250,000 tons per year for each year beginning in the calendar year 2000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual auctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Commencing in 1993 and in each year thereafter, the Administrator shall conduct auctions at which the allowances referred to in paragraph (1) shall be offered for sale in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, within 12 months of <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>. The allowances referred to in paragraph (1) shall be offered for sale at auction in the amounts specified in table 2. The auction shall be open to any person. A person wishing to bid for such allowances shall submit (by a date set by the Administrator) to the Administrator (on a sealed bid schedule provided by the Administrator) offers to purchase specified numbers of allowances at specified prices. Such regulations shall specify that the auctioned allowances shall be allocated and sold on the basis of bid price, starting with the highest-priced bid and continuing until all allowances for sale at such auction have been allocated. The regulations shall not permit that a minimum price be set for the purchase of withheld allowances. Allowances purchased at the auction may be used for any purpose and at any time after the auction, subject to the provisions of this subchapter.<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  -uslm-lc: c3,L1,tp7,p7,7/8,s36,xs42,xls48,tp7,p7,7/8,s36,xs42,xls48; " id="idbe64a1d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 108pt;" />
<html:col style="width:46pt ; max-width:46pt;" />
<html:col style="width:52pt ; max-width:52pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Table </html:span>2<html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">—Number of Allowances Available for Auction</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 108.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;">Year of Sale</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:46.0pt ; max-width:46.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;">Spot</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;">Auction (same year)</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:52.0pt ; max-width:52.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;">Advance Auction</html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tfoot style="  border-top:1px solid black;"><html:tr><html:td colspan="3" style="text-align:justify; text-indent:1em; font-size:6pt ">
<html:p><html:a name="TAB_93_0" />Allowances sold in the spot sale in any year are allowances which may only be used in that year (unless banked for use in a later year), except as otherwise noted. Allowances sold in the advance auction in any year are allowances which may only be used in the 7th year after the year in which they are first offered for sale (unless banked for use in a later year).</html:p>
</html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr><html:td colspan="3" style="text-align:justify; text-indent:1em; font-size:6pt ">
<html:p><html:a name="TAB_93_1" />*Available for use only in 1995 (unless banked for use in a later year).</html:p>
</html:td></html:tr>
</html:tfoot>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1993</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> 50,000<html:a href="#TAB_93_1">*</html:a></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1994</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> 50,000<html:a href="#TAB_93_1">*</html:a></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1995</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> 50,000<html:a href="#TAB_93_1">*</html:a></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1996</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">150,000 </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1997</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">150,000 </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1998</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">150,000 </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1999</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">150,000 </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>2000 and after</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000 </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100,000</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Proceeds</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a1d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">section 3302 of title 31</ref> or any other provision of law, within 90 days of receipt, the Administrator shall transfer the proceeds from the auction under this section, on a pro rata basis, to the owners or operators of the affected units at an affected source from whom allowances were withheld under subsection (b). No funds transferred from a purchaser to a seller of allowances under this paragraph shall be held by any officer or employee of the United States or treated for any purpose as revenue to the United States or the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a1d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> At the end of each year, any allowances offered for sale but not sold at the auction shall be returned without charge, on a pro rata basis, to the owner or operator of the affected units from whose allocation the allowances were withheld.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional auction participants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person holding allowances or to whom allowances are allocated by the Administrator may submit those allowances to the Administrator to be offered for sale at auction under this subsection. The proceeds of any such sale shall be transferred at the time of sale by the purchaser to the person submitting such allowances for sale. The holder of allowances offered for sale under this paragraph may specify a minimum sale price. Any person may purchase allowances offered for auction under this paragraph. Such allowances shall be allocated and sold to purchasers on the basis of bid price after the auction under paragraph (2) is complete. No funds transferred from a purchaser to a seller of allowances under this paragraph shall be held by any officer or employee of the United States or treated for any purpose as revenue to the United States or the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Recording by EPA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall record and publicly report the nature, prices and results of each auction under this subsection, including the prices of successful bids, and shall record the transfers of allowances as a result of each auction in accordance with the requirements of this section. The transfer of allowances at such auction shall be recorded in accordance with the regulations promulgated by the Administrator under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Changes in sales, auctions, and withholding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to rulemaking after public notice and comment the Administrator may at any time after the year 1998 (in the case of advance sales or advance auctions) and 2005 (in the case of spot sales or spot auctions) decrease the number of allowances withheld and sold under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a1dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651o/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of auctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may terminate the withholding of allowances and the auction sales under this section if the Administrator determines that, during any period of 3 consecutive calendar years after 2002, less than 20 percent of the allowances available in the auction subaccount have been purchased. Pursuant to regulations under this section, the Administrator may by delegation or contract provide for the conduct of sales or auctions under the Administrator’s supervision by other departments or agencies of the United States Government or by nongovernmental agencies, groups, or organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe64a1dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title IV, § 416, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 101–549, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2626">104 Stat. 2626</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe64a1de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe64a1df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe64a1e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s79b">Section 79b of title 15</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(C), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXII/s1263">Pub. L. 109–58, title XII, § 1263</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/974">119 Stat. 974</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s16451/1">section 16451(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
