<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe64a16e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h"><num value="7651h">§ 7651h.</num><heading> Repowered sources</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a16f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, the owner or operator of an existing unit subject to the emissions limitation requirements of section 7651d(b) and (c) of this title may demonstrate to the permitting authority that one or more units will be repowered with a qualifying clean coal technology to comply with the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651d">section 7651d of this title</ref>. The owner or operator shall, as part of any such demonstration, provide, not later than <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>, satisfactory documentation of a preliminary design and engineering effort for such repowering and an executed and binding contract for the majority of the equipment to repower such unit and such other information as the Administrator may require by regulation. The replacement of an existing utility unit with a new utility unit using a repowering technology referred to in section 7651a(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003760">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003760"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be section “7651a(12)”.</note> of this title which is located at a different site, shall be treated as repowering of the existing unit for purposes of this subchapter, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a170-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the replacement unit is designated by the owner or operator to replace such existing unit, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe64a171-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the existing unit is retired from service on or before the date on which the designated replacement unit enters commercial operation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a172-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe64a173-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An owner or operator satisfying the requirements of subsection (a) shall be granted an extension of the emission limitation requirement compliance date for that unit from <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>, to <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>. The extension shall be specified in the permit issued to the source under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651g">section 7651g of this title</ref>, together with any compliance schedule and other requirements necessary to meet second phase requirements by the extended date. Any unit that is granted an extension under this section shall not be eligible for a waiver under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411/j">section 7411(j) of this title</ref>, and shall continue to be subject to requirements under this subchapter as if it were a unit subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651d">section 7651d of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe64a174-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If (A) the owner or operator of an existing unit has been granted an extension under paragraph (1) in order to repower such unit with a clean coal unit, and (B) such owner or operator demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator that the repowering technology to be utilized by such unit has been properly constructed and tested on such unit, but nevertheless has been unable to achieve the emission reduction limitations and is economically or technologically infeasible, such existing unit may be retrofitted or repowered with equipment or facilities utilizing another clean coal technology or other available control technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a175-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Allowances</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe64a176-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the period of the extension under this section, the Administrator shall allocate to the owner or operator of the affected unit, annual allowances for sulfur dioxide equal to the affected unit’s baseline multiplied by the lesser of the unit’s federally approved State Implementation Plan emissions limitation or its actual emission rate for 1995 in lieu of any other allocation. Such allowances may not be transferred or used by any other source to meet emission requirements under this subchapter. The source owner or operator shall notify the Administrator sixty days in advance of the date on which the affected unit for which the extension has been granted is to be removed from operation to install the repowering technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe64a177-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Effective on that date, the unit shall be subject to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651d">section 7651d of this title</ref>. Allowances for the year in which the unit is removed from operation to install the repowering technology shall be calculated as the product of the unit’s baseline multiplied by 1.20 lbs/mmBtu, divided by 2,000, and prorated accordingly, and are transferable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe64a178-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Allowances for such existing utility units for calendar years after the year the repowering is complete shall be calculated as the product of the existing unit’s baseline multiplied by 1.20 lbs/mmBtu, divided by 2,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe64a179-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of section 7651b(a) and (e) of this title, allowances shall be allocated under this section for a designated replacement unit which replaces an existing unit (as provided in the last sentence of subsection (a)) in lieu of any further allocations of allowances for the existing unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe64a17a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For the purpose of meeting the aggregate emissions limitation requirement set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7651b/a/1">section 7651b(a)(1) of this title</ref>, the units with an extension under this subsection shall be treated in each calendar year during the extension period as holding allowances allocated under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a17b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Control requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any unit qualifying for an extension under this section that does not increase actual hourly emissions for any pollutant regulated under the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003761">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003761"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “this”.</note> chapter shall not be subject to any standard of performance under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, no new unit (1) designated as a replacement for an existing unit, (2) qualifying for the extension under subsection (b), and (3) located at a different site than the existing unit shall receive an exemption from the requirements imposed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7411">section 7411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a17c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited permitting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">State permitting authorities and, where applicable, the Administrator, are encouraged to give expedited consideration to permit applications under parts C and D of subchapter I of this chapter for any source qualifying for an extension under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe64a17d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7651h/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for the owner or operator of a repowered source to fail to comply with the requirement of this section, or any regulations of permit requirements to implement this section, including the prohibition against emitting sulfur dioxide in excess of allowances held.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe64a17e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title IV, § 409, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 101–549, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2619">104 Stat. 2619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
