<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe671230-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c"><num value="7661c">§ 7661c.</num><heading> Permit requirements and conditions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe671231-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each permit issued under this subchapter shall include enforceable emission limitations and standards, a schedule of compliance, a requirement that the permittee submit to the permitting authority, no less often than every 6 months, the results of any required monitoring, and such other conditions as are necessary to assure compliance with applicable requirements of this chapter, including the requirements of the applicable implementation plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe671232-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring and analysis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may by rule prescribe procedures and methods for determining compliance and for monitoring and analysis of pollutants regulated under this chapter, but continuous emissions monitoring need not be required if alternative methods are available that provide sufficiently reliable and timely information for determining compliance. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect any continuous emissions monitoring requirement of subchapter IV–A, or where required elsewhere in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe671233-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspection, entry, monitoring, certification, and reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each permit issued under this subchapter shall set forth inspection, entry, monitoring, compliance certification, and reporting requirements to assure compliance with the permit terms and conditions. Such monitoring and reporting requirements shall conform to any applicable regulation under subsection (b). Any report required to be submitted by a permit issued to a corporation under this subchapter shall be signed by a responsible corporate official, who shall certify its accuracy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe671234-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> General permits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The permitting authority may, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, issue a general permit covering numerous similar sources. Any general permit shall comply with all requirements applicable to permits under this subchapter. No source covered by a general permit shall thereby be relieved from the obligation to file an application under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7661b">section 7661b of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe671235-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Temporary sources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The permitting authority may issue a single permit authorizing emissions from similar operations at multiple temporary locations. No such permit shall be issued unless it includes conditions that will assure compliance with all the requirements of this chapter at all authorized locations, including, but not limited to, ambient standards and compliance with any applicable increment or visibility requirements under part C of subchapter I. Any such permit shall in addition require the owner or operator to notify the permitting authority in advance of each change in location. The permitting authority may require a separate permit fee for operations at each location.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe671236-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit shield</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Compliance with a permit issued in accordance with this subchapter shall be deemed compliance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7661a">section 7661a of this title</ref>. Except as otherwise provided by the Administrator by rule, the permit may also provide that compliance with the permit shall be deemed compliance with other applicable provisions of this chapter that relate to the permittee if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe671237-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the permit includes the applicable requirements of such provisions, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe671238-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7661c/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the permitting authority in acting on the permit application makes a determination relating to the permittee that such other provisions (which shall be referred to in such determination) are not applicable and the permit includes the determination or a concise summary thereof.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in the preceding sentence shall alter or affect the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7603">section 7603 of this title</ref>, including the authority of the Administrator under that section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe671239-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title V, § 504, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tV/s501">Pub. L. 101–549, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2642">104 Stat. 2642</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
