<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe695cea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f"><num value="7671f">§ 7671f.</num><heading> Exchange authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe695ceb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall, within 10 months after <date date="1990-11-15">November 15, 1990</date>, promulgate rules under this subchapter providing for the issuance of allowances for the production of class I and II substances in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter and governing the transfer of such allowances. Such rules shall insure that the transactions under the authority of this section will result in greater total reductions in the production in each year of class I and class II substances than would occur in that year in the absence of such transactions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe695cec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Interpollutant transfers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe695ced-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The rules under this section shall permit a production allowance for a substance for any year to be transferred for a production allowance for another substance for the same year on an ozone depletion weighted basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe695cee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Allowances for substances in each group of class I substances (as listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7671a">section 7671a of this title</ref>) may only be transferred for allowances for other substances in the same Group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe695cef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Administrator shall, as appropriate, establish groups of class II substances for trading purposes and assign class II substances to such groups. In the case of class II substances, allowances may only be transferred for allowances for other class II substances that are in the same Group.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe695cf0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Trades with other persons</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The rules under this section shall permit 2 or more persons to transfer production allowances (including interpollutant transfers which meet the requirements of subsections (a) and (b)) if the transferor of such allowances will be subject, under such rules, to an enforceable and quantifiable reduction in annual production which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe695cf1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> exceeds the reduction otherwise applicable to the transferor under this subchapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe695cf2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> exceeds the production allowances transferred to the transferee, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe695cf3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> would not have occurred in the absence of such transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe695cf4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671f/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Consumption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The rules under this section shall also provide for the issuance of consumption allowances in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter and for the trading of such allowances in the same manner as is applicable under this section to the trading of production allowances under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe695cf5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title VI, § 607, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tVI/s602/a">Pub. L. 101–549, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2660">104 Stat. 2660</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
