<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe695ce3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671e"><num value="7671e">§ 7671e.</num><heading> Accelerated schedule</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe695ce4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall promulgate regulations, after notice and opportunity for public comment, which establish a schedule for phasing out the production and consumption of class I and class II substances (or use of class II substances) that is more stringent than set forth in section 7671c or 7671d of this title, or both, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe695ce5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671e/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> based on an assessment of credible current scientific information (including any assessment under the Montreal Protocol) regarding harmful effects on the stratospheric ozone layer associated with a class I or class II substance, the Administrator determines that such more stringent schedule may be necessary to protect human health and the environment against such effects,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe695ce6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671e/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> based on the availability of substitutes for listed substances, the Administrator determines that such more stringent schedule is practicable, taking into account technological achievability, safety, and other relevant factors, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe695ce7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671e/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Montreal Protocol is modified to include a schedule to control or reduce production, consumption, or use of any substance more rapidly than the applicable schedule under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In making any determination under paragraphs (1) and (2), the Administrator shall consider the status of the period remaining under the applicable schedule under this subchapter.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe695ce8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7671e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person may petition the Administrator to promulgate regulations under this section. The Administrator shall grant or deny the petition within 180 days after receipt of any such petition. If the Administrator denies the petition, the Administrator shall publish an explanation of why the petition was denied. If the Administrator grants such petition, such final regulations shall be promulgated within 1 year. Any petition under this subsection shall include a showing by the petitioner that there are data adequate to support the petition. If the Administrator determines that information is not sufficient to make a determination under this subsection, the Administrator shall use any authority available to the Administrator, under any law administered by the Administrator, to acquire such information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe695ce9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, title VI, § 606, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/549/tVI/s602/a">Pub. L. 101–549, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2660">104 Stat. 2660</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
