<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe6e3e7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701"><num value="7701">§ 7701.</num><heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> All 50 States, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, are vulnerable to the hazards of earthquakes, and at least 39 of them are subject to major or moderate seismic risk, including Alaska, California, Hawaii, Illinois, Massachusetts, Missouri, Montana, Nevada, New Jersey, New York, Oregon, South Carolina Tennessee,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003784">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003784"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> Utah, and Washington. A large portion of the population of the United States lives in areas vulnerable to earthquake hazards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Earthquakes have caused, and can cause in the future, enormous loss of life, injury, destruction of property, and economic and social disruption. With respect to future earthquakes, such loss, destruction, and disruption can be substantially reduced through the development and implementation of earthquake hazards reduction measures, including (A) improved design and construction methods and practices, (B) land-use controls and redevelopment, (C) early-warning systems, (D) coordinated emergency preparedness plans, and (E) public education and involvement programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An expertly staffed and adequately financed earthquake hazards reduction program, based on Federal, State, local, and private research, planning, decisionmaking, and contributions would reduce the risk of such loss, destruction, and disruption in seismic areas by an amount far greater than the cost of such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A well-funded seismological research program could provide the scientific understanding needed to fully implement an effective earthquake early warning system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The geological study of active faults and features can reveal how recently and how frequently major earthquakes have occurred on those faults and how much risk they pose. Such long-term seismic risk assessments are needed in virtually every aspect of earthquake hazards management, whether emergency planning, public regulation, detailed building design, insurance rating, or investment decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The vulnerability of buildings, lifeline infrastructure, public works, and industrial and emergency facilities can be reduced through proper earthquake resistant design and construction practices. The economy and efficacy of such procedures can be substantially increased through research and development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Programs and practices of departments and agencies of the United States are important to the communities they serve; some functions, such as emergency communications and national defense, and lifeline infrastructure, such as dams, bridges, and public works, must remain in service during and after an earthquake. Federally owned, operated, and influenced structures and lifeline infrastructure should serve as models for how to reduce and minimize hazards to the community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The implementation of earthquake hazards reduction measures would, as an added benefit, also reduce the risk of loss, destruction, and disruption from other natural hazards and manmade hazards, including hurricanes, tornadoes, accidents, explosions, landslides, building and structural cave-ins, and fires.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Reduction of loss, destruction, and disruption from earthquakes will depend on the actions of individuals, and organizations in the private sector and governmental units at Federal, State, and local levels. The current capability to transfer knowledge and information to these sectors is insufficient. Improved mechanisms are needed to translate existing information and research findings into reasonable and usable specifications, criteria, and practices so that individuals, organizations, and governmental units may make informed decisions and take appropriate actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Severe earthquakes are a worldwide problem. Since damaging earthquakes occur infrequently in any one nation, international cooperation is desirable for mutual learning from limited experiences.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> An effective Federal program in earthquake hazards reduction will require input from and review by persons outside the Federal Government expert in the sciences of earthquake hazards reduction and in the practical application of earthquake hazards reduction measures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The built environment has generally been constructed and maintained to meet the needs of the users under normal conditions. When earthquakes occur, the built environment is generally designed to prevent severe injuries or loss of human life and is not expected to remain operational or able to recover under any specified schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe6e3e8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7701/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The National Research Council published a study on reducing hazards and risks associated with earthquakes based on the goals and objectives for achieving national earthquake resilience described in the strategic plan entitled “Strategic Plan for the National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program”. The study and an accompanying report called for work in 18 tasks focused on research, preparedness, and mitigation and annual funding of approximately $300,000,000 per year for 20 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbe6e3e8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/124/s2">Pub. L. 95–124, § 2</ref>, <date date="1977-10-07">Oct. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1098">91 Stat. 1098</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/614/s2">Pub. L. 101–614, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3231">104 Stat. 3231</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s2/a">Pub. L. 115–307, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4408">132 Stat. 4408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe6e3e8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe6e3e8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe6e3e8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 115–307, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico,” after “States”, “Oregon,” after “New York,”, and “Tennessee,” after “South Carolina”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 115–307, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, struck out “prediction techniques and” before “early-warning systems,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 115–307, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (4) and struck out former par. (4) which read as follows: “A well-funded seismological research program in earthquake prediction could provide data adequate for the design, of an operational system that could predict accurately the time, place, magnitude, and physical effects of earthquakes in selected areas of the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s2/a/4">Pub. L. 115–307, § 2(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “lifeline infrastructure” for “lifelines” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (12), (13). <ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s2/a/5">Pub. L. 115–307, § 2(a)(5)</ref>, added pars. (12) and (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Pars. (5) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/101/614">Pub. L. 101–614</ref> added pars. (5) to (7), struck out former pars. (5) and (6), and redesignated former pars. (7) to (10) as (8) to (11), respectively. Prior to amendment, pars. (5) and (6) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(5) An operational earthquake prediction system can produce significant social, economic, legal, and political consequences.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(6) There is a scientific basis for hypothesizing that major earthquakes may be moderated, in at least some seismic areas, by application of the findings of earthquake control and seismological research.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe6e3e8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idbe6e3e90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2018 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s1">Pub. L. 115–307, § 1</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4408">132 Stat. 4408</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/307/s1">“This Act [amending this section and sections 7702 to 7704, 7705b, 7705c, and 7705e to 7707 of this title and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7704">section 7704 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2018’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idbe6e3e91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/360/tI/s101">Pub. L. 108–360, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1668">118 Stat. 1668</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/360/tI/s101">“This title [amending sections 7703, 7704, and 7706 to 7708 of this title] may be cited as the ‘National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2004’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idbe6e3e92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/503/tII/s201">Pub. L. 106–503, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2304">114 Stat. 2304</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/503/tII/s201">“This title [enacting sections 7707 to 7709 of this title, amending sections 7703, 7704, and 7706 of this title, repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7705d">section 7705d of this title</ref>, enacting provisions set out as a note under this section, and amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7704">section 7704 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Earthquake Hazards Reduction Authorization Act of 2000’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idbe6e3e93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/614/s1">Pub. L. 101–614, § 1</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3231">104 Stat. 3231</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/614/s1">“This Act [enacting sections 7705a to 7705e, amending this section and sections 7702 to 7705, and 7706 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 7704, 7705b, and 7705e of this title] may be cited as the ‘National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idbe6e3e94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/124/s1">Pub. L. 95–124, § 1</ref>, <date date="1977-10-07">Oct. 7, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1098">91 Stat. 1098</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/124/s1">“That this Act [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe6e3e95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on At-Risk Populations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/503/tII/s207">Pub. L. 106–503, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2307">114 Stat. 2307</ref>, required the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to transmit to Congress a report no later than 1 year after <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, describing the elements of the National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program that specifically addressed the needs of at-risk populations.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbe6e3e96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="idbe6e3e97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 delegated, transferred, or reassigned to Secretary of Homeland Security pursuant to sections 1–104 and 4–204 of Ex. Ord. No. 12148, <date date="1979-07-20">July 20, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 43239, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5195">section 5195 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
