<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe72f94d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7705e"><num value="7705e">§ 7705e.</num><heading> Post-earthquake investigations program</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established within the United States Geological Survey a post-earthquake investigations program, the purpose of which is to investigate major earthquakes, so as to learn lessons which can be applied to reduce the loss of lives and property in future earthquakes. The United States Geological Survey, in consultation with each Program agency, shall organize investigations to study the implications of the earthquake in the areas of responsibility of each Program agency. The investigations shall begin as rapidly as possible and may be conducted by grantees and contractors. The Program agencies shall ensure that the results of investigations are disseminated widely. The Director of the Survey is authorized to utilize earthquake expertise from the Agency, the National Science Foundation, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, other Federal agencies, and private contractors, on a reimbursable basis, in the conduct of such earthquake investigations. At a minimum, investigations under this section shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe72f94e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7705e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> analysis by the National Science Foundation and the United States Geological Survey of the causes of the earthquake and the nature of the resulting ground motion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe72f94f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7705e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> analysis by the National Science Foundation and the National Institute of Standards and Technology of the behavior of structures and lifeline infrastructure, both those that were damaged and those that were undamaged; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe72f950-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7705e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> analysis by each of the Program agencies of the effectiveness of the earthquake hazards mitigation programs and actions relating to its area of responsibility under the Program, and how those programs and actions could be strengthened.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbe72f951-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/124/s11">Pub. L. 95–124, § 11</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/614/s11/a">Pub. L. 101–614, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3239">104 Stat. 3239</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/307/s2/c/1/B">Pub. L. 115–307, § 2(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4409">132 Stat. 4409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe72f952-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe72f953-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe72f954-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/307">Pub. L. 115–307</ref> substituted “lifeline infrastructure” for “lifelines”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe72f955-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbe72f956-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe72f957-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Funding of Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/614/s11/b">Pub. L. 101–614, § 11(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3239">104 Stat. 3239</ref>, directed Director of Federal Emergency Management Agency in consultation with other agencies of National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program, not later than one year after <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, to report to Congress on possible options for funding a program for post-earthquake investigations, which would, at a minimum, consider funding such a program either by setting aside a percentage of disaster relief funds provided by Federal Emergency Management Agency after a major earthquake or by a revolving fund, and which would also include a recommendation on how the funding for such investigations would be allocated among the other Program agencies.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
