<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe75433b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913"><num value="7913">§ 7913.</num><heading> State cooperative agreements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe75433c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary; prompt commencement of preparations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After notifying a State of the designation referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7912">section 7912 of this title</ref>, the Secretary subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7923">section 7923 of this title</ref>, is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with such State to perform remedial actions at each designated processing site in such State (other than a site located on Indian lands referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7915">section 7915 of this title</ref>). The Secretary shall, to the greatest extent practicable, enter into such agreements and carry out such remedial actions in accordance with the priorities established by him under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7912">section 7912 of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall commence preparations for cooperative agreements with respect to each designated processing site as promptly as practicable following the designation of each site.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe75433d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions; limitation of Federal assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each cooperative agreement under this section shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems appropriate and consistent with the purposes of this chapter, including, but not limited to, a limitation on the use of Federal assistance to those costs which are directly required to complete the remedial action selected pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7918">section 7918 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe75433e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Written consent of record interest holder; waiver</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe75433f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except where the State is required to acquire the processing site as provided in subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7914">section 7914 of this title</ref>, each cooperative agreement with a State under this section shall provide that the State shall obtain, in a form prescribed by the Secretary, written consent from any person holding any record interest in the designated processing site for the Secretary or any person designated by him to perform remedial action at such site.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe754340-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Such written consent shall include a waiver by each such person on behalf of himself, his heirs, successors, and assigns—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe754341-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> releasing the United States of any liability or claim thereof by such person, his heirs, successors, and assigns concerning such remedial action, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe754342-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> holding the United States harmless against any claim by such person on behalf of himself, his heirs, successors, or assigns arising out of the performance of any such remedial action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe754343-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspection entries; termination of right of entry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each cooperative agreement under this section shall require the State to assure that the Secretary, the Commission, and the Administrator and their authorized representatives have a permanent right of entry at any time to inspect the processing site and the site provided pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7914/b/1">section 7914(b)(1) of this title</ref> in furtherance of the provisions of this subchapter and to carry out such agreement and enforce this chapter and any rules prescribed under this chapter. Such right of entry under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7916">section 7916 of this title</ref> into an area described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7911/6/B">section 7911(6)(B) of this title</ref> shall terminate on completion of the remedial action, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe754344-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each agreement under this section shall take effect only upon the concurrence of the Commission with the terms and conditions thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe754345-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may, in any cooperative agreement entered into under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7915">section 7915 of this title</ref>, provide for reimbursement of the actual costs, as determined by the Secretary, of any remedial action performed with respect to so much of a designated processing site as is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7911/6/B">section 7911(6)(B) of this title</ref>. Such reimbursement shall be made only to a property owner of record at the time such remedial action was undertaken and only with respect to costs incurred by such property owner. No such reimbursement may be made unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe754346-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such remedial action was completed prior to <date date="1978-11-08">November 8, 1978</date>, and unless the application for such reimbursement was filed by such owner within one year after an agreement under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7915">section 7915 of this title</ref> is approved by the Secretary and the Commission, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe754347-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7913/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary is satisfied that such action adequately achieves the purposes of this chapter with respect to the site concerned and is consistent with the standards established by the Administrator pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2022/a">section 2022(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe754348-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/604/tI/s103">Pub. L. 95–604, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3024">92 Stat. 3024</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe754349-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe75434a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe75434b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b), (d), and (f)(2), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/604">Pub. L. 95–604</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3021">92 Stat. 3021</ref>, known as the Uranium Mill Tailings Radiation Control Act of 1978. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7901">section 7901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
