<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe77b3c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7925"><num value="7925">§ 7925.</num><heading> Active operations; liability for remedial action</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe77b3c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7925/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> No amount may be expended under this subchapter with respect to any site licensed by the Commission under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.] or by a State as permitted under section 274 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2021">42 U.S.C. 2021</ref>] at which production of any uranium product from ores (other than from residual radioactive materials) takes place. This subsection does not prohibit the disposal of residual radioactive material from a processing site under this subchapter at a site licensed under title II or the expenditure of funds under this subchapter for such disposal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe77b3c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s7925/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In the case of each processing site designated under this subchapter, the Attorney General shall conduct a study to determine the identity and legal responsibility which any person (other than the United States, a State, or Indian tribe) who owned or operated or controlled (as determined by the Attorney General) such site before <date date="1978-11-08">November 8, 1978</date>, may have under any law or rule of law for reclamation or other remedial action with respect to such site. The Attorney General shall publish the results of such study, and provide copies thereof to the Congress, as promptly as practicable following <date date="1978-11-08">November 8, 1978</date>. The Attorney General, based on such study, shall, to the extent he deems it appropriate and in the public interest, take such action under any provision of law in effect when uranium was produced at such site to require payment by such person of all or any part of the costs incurred by the United States for such remedial action for which he determines such person is liable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe77b3c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/604/tI/s115">Pub. L. 95–604, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3033">92 Stat. 3033</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/259/s4/c">Pub. L. 104–259, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3174">110 Stat. 3174</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe77b3c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe77b3c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe77b3c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title II, referred to in subsec. (a), is title II (§§ 201–209) of <ref href="/us/pl/95/604">Pub. L. 95–604</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3033">92 Stat. 3033</ref>, which enacted sections 2022, 2113, 2114 of this title, amended sections 2014, 2021, 2111, and 2201 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 2014, 2021, and 2113 of this title. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe77b3c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/259">Pub. L. 104–259</ref> inserted at end “This subsection does not prohibit the disposal of residual radioactive material from a processing site under this subchapter at a site licensed under title II or the expenditure of funds under this subchapter for such disposal.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
