<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe839b2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235e"><num value="8235e">§ 8235e.</num><heading> Authority of Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to exempt application of certain laws</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission may exempt from any provisions in sections 4, 5, and 7 of the Natural Gas Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s717c">15 U.S.C. 717c</ref>, 717d, and 717f) and titles II and IV of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3341">15 U.S.C. 3341</ref> through 3348 and 3391 through 3394) the sale or transportation, by any public utility, local distribution company, interstate or intrastate pipeline, or any other person, of any natural gas which is determined (in the case of a regulated utility, company, pipeline, or person) by the State regulatory authority having rate-making authority over such utility, company, pipeline, or person, or (in the case of a nonregulated utility, company, pipeline, or person) by such utility, company, pipeline, or person, to have been conserved because of a prototype residential energy efficiency program which is established under a plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8235a/a">section 8235a(a) of this title</ref>, if the Commission determines that such exemption is necessary to make feasible the demonstration of such prototype residential energy efficiency program.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbe839b2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tII/s266">Pub. L. 95–619, title II, § 266</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tV/s562">Pub. L. 96–294, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/749">94 Stat. 749</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/388/s5/c/4">Pub. L. 105–388, § 5(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3479">112 Stat. 3479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe839b2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe839b2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe839b2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/95/621">Pub. L. 95–621</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3350">92 Stat. 3350</ref>. Title II of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 was classified generally to subchapter II (§ 3341 et seq.) of chapter 60 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade, prior to its repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–42, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/314">101 Stat. 314</ref>. Title IV of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 3391 et seq.) of chapter 60 of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3301">section 3301 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe839b2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/388">Pub. L. 105–388</ref> substituted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s717c">15 U.S.C. 717c</ref>” for “(<ref href="/us/usc/t17/s717c">17 U.S.C. 717c</ref>”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
