<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe839b41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235g"><num value="8235g">§ 8235g.</num><heading> Records and reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe839b42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State and local government submitting any application for a plan which is approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8235a/a">section 8235a(a) of this title</ref>, and each public utility and person or persons entering into a contract under such a plan, shall keep such records and make such reports as the Secretary may require. The Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States shall have access, at reasonable times and under reasonable conditions, to any books, documents, papers, records, and reports of each such State and local government, utility, and person or persons which the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Comptroller General of the United States, are pertinent to this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe839b43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235g/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall make an annual report to the President on the activities carried out under this part which shall be submitted to the Congress with the annual report on the activities of the Department of Energy required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7267">section 7267 of this title</ref> and which shall contain—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe839b44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235g/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an estimate of the total amount of energy saved as a result of the activities carried out under this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe839b45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235g/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an estimate of the annual savings in energy anticipated as a result of each prototype residential energy efficiency program established under a plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8235a/a">section 8235a(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe839b46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235g/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an analysis, developed in consultation with the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Justice, of the impact on competition of each prototype residential energy efficiency program established under a plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8235a/a">section 8235a(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe839b47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8235g/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> if the Secretary determines that it is appropriate, an analysis of the impact of expanding the approval of plans under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8235a/a">section 8235a(a) of this title</ref> to establish prototype residential energy efficiency programs, and the provision of financial assistance to such programs, on a national basis and an assessment of the alternative methods by which such an expansion could be accomplished.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe839b48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tII/s268">Pub. L. 95–619, title II, § 268</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tV/s562">Pub. L. 96–294, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/750">94 Stat. 750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
