<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe8855af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256"><num value="8256">§ 8256.</num><heading> Incentives for agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8855b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each agency shall establish a program of incentives for conserving, and otherwise making more efficient use of, energy as a result of entering into contracts under subchapter VII of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall, not later than 18 months after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, and after consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator of General Services, develop appropriate procedures and methods for use by agencies to implement the incentives referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8855b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal Energy Efficiency Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish a Federal Energy Efficiency Fund to provide grants to agencies to assist them in meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8253">section 8253 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1993-06-30">June 30, 1993</date>, the Secretary shall issue guidelines to be followed by agencies submitting proposals for such grants. All agencies shall be eligible to submit proposals for grants under the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall award grants from the Fund after a competitive assessment of the technical and economic effectiveness of each agency proposal. The Secretary shall consider the following factors in determining whether to provide funding under this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The cost-effectiveness of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amount of energy and cost savings anticipated to the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The amount of funding committed to the project by the agency requesting financial assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The extent that a proposal leverages financing from other non-Federal sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Any other factor which the Secretary determines will result in the greatest amount of energy and cost savings to the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated, to remain available to be expended, to carry out this subsection not more than $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1994, $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1995, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8855bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Utility incentive programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Agencies are authorized and encouraged to participate in programs to increase energy efficiency and for water conservation or the management of electricity demand conducted by gas, water, or electric utilities and generally available to customers of such utilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each agency may accept any financial incentive, goods, or services generally available from any such utility, to increase energy efficiency or to conserve water or manage electricity demand.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Each agency is encouraged to enter into negotiations with electric, water, and gas utilities to design cost-effective demand management and conservation incentive programs to address the unique needs of facilities utilized by such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If an agency satisfies the criteria which generally apply to other customers of a utility incentive program, such agency may not be denied collection of rebates or other incentives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8855c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial incentive program for facility energy managers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Task Force established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8257">section 8257 of this title</ref>, establish a financial bonus program to reward, with funds made available for such purpose, outstanding Federal facility energy managers in agencies and the United States Postal Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="1993-06-01">June 1, 1993</date>, the Secretary shall issue procedures for implementing and conducting the award program, including the criteria to be used in selecting outstanding energy managers and contributors who have—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> improved energy performance through increased energy efficiency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> implemented proven energy efficiency and energy conservation techniques, devices, equipment, or procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> developed and implemented training programs for facility energy managers, operators, and maintenance personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> developed and implemented employee awareness programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> succeeded in generating utility incentives, shared energy savings contracts, and other federally approved performance based energy savings contracts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> made successful efforts to fulfill compliance with energy reduction mandates, including the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8253">section 8253 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8855cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> succeeded in the implementation of the guidelines established under section 8262e <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003821">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003821"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe8855cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection not more than $250,000 for each of the fiscal years 1993, 1994, and 1995.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8855cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8256/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of energy and water savings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An agency may retain any funds appropriated to that agency for energy expenditures, water expenditures, or wastewater treatment expenditures, at buildings subject to the requirements of section 8253(a) and (b) of this title, that are not made because of energy savings or water savings. Except as otherwise provided by law, such funds may be used only for energy efficiency, water conservation, or unconventional and renewable energy resources projects. Such projects shall be subject to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3307">section 3307 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe8855ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/619/tV/s546">Pub. L. 95–619, title V, § 546</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3278">92 Stat. 3278</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/615/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–615, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-05">Nov. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3187">102 Stat. 3187</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s152/f">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 152(f)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2846">106 Stat. 2846</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tI/s102/f">Pub. L. 109–58, title I, § 102(f)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/607">119 Stat. 607</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tV/s516">Pub. L. 110–140, title V, § 516</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1659">121 Stat. 1659</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe8855cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe8855d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe8855d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8262e">Section 8262e of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(G), was in the original “section 159” and was translated as meaning <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s159">section 159 of Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, title I, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2857">106 Stat. 2857</ref>, which enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8262e">section 8262e of this title</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe8855d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140">Pub. L. 110–140</ref> struck out par. (5) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(5)(A) An amount equal to fifty percent of the energy and water cost savings realized by an agency (other than the Department of Defense) with respect to funds appropriated for any fiscal year beginning after fiscal year 1992 (including financial benefits resulting from energy savings performance contracts under subchapter VII of this chapter and utility energy efficiency rebates) shall, subject to appropriation, remain available for expenditure by such agency for additional energy efficiency measures which may include related employee incentive programs, particularly at those facilities at which energy savings were achieved.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) Agencies shall establish a fund and maintain strict financial accounting and controls for savings realized and expenditures made under this subsection. Records maintained pursuant to this subparagraph shall be made available for public inspection upon request.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s152/f/1">Pub. L. 102–486, § 152(f)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “Contracts” for “In general” in heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), and redesignated former subsec. (b) as subsec. (a)(2) and amended it generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “The head of each agency shall, no later than 120 days after <date date="1988-11-05">November 5, 1988</date>, implement procedures for entering into such contracts and for identifying, verifying, and utilizing, on a fiscal year basis, the cost savings resulting from such contracts.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s152/f/4">Pub. L. 102–486, § 152(f)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated par. (2) of subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s152/f/3">Pub. L. 102–486, § 152(f)(3)</ref>, (4), added subsecs. (c) and (d) and struck out former subsec. (c) which read as follows: “The portion of the funds appropriated to an agency for energy expenses for a fiscal year that is equal to the amount of cost savings realized by such agency for such year from contracts entered into under subchapter VII of this chapter shall remain available for obligation, without further appropriation, to undertake additional energy conservation measures.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/615">Pub. L. 100–615</ref> amended section generally, substituting statement of incentives for agencies for provisions relating to energy performance targets for Federal buildings.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe8855d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe8855d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/140">Pub. L. 110–140</ref> effective on the date that is 1 day after <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s1601">section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1824">section 1824 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe8855d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Energy Efficiency and Water Conservation Measures; Use of Rebates and Savings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/52/tVI/s625">Pub. L. 104–52, title VI, § 625</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/502">109 Stat. 502</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/52/tVI/s625">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> Beginning in fiscal year 1996 and thereafter, for each Federal agency, except the Department of Defense (which has separate authority), and except as provided in <ref href="/us/pl/102/393/tIV">Public Law 102–393, title IV</ref>, section 13 (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s490g">40 U.S.C. 490g</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s592/f">40 U.S.C. 592(f)</ref>] with respect to the Fund established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s490/f">40 U.S.C. 490(f)</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s592/a">40 U.S.C. 592(a)</ref>–(c)(1), (d), (e)], an amount equal to 50 percent of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the amount of each utility rebate received by the agency for energy efficiency and water conservation measures, which the agency has implemented; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the amount of the agency’s share of the measured energy savings resulting from energy-savings performance contracts,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may be retained and credited to accounts that fund energy and water conservation activities at the agency’s facilities, and shall remain available until expended for additional specific energy efficiency or water conservation projects or activities, including improvements and retrofits, facility surveys, additional or improved utility metering, and employee training and awareness programs, as authorized by section 152(f) of the Energy Policy Act (<ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Public Law 102–486</ref>) [amending this section].</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The remaining 50 percent of each rebate, and the remaining 50 percent of the amount of the agency’s share of savings from energy-savings performance contracts, shall be transferred to the General Fund of the Treasury at the end of the fiscal year in which received.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
