<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe8ac7da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262f"><num value="8262f">§ 8262f.</num><heading> Inspector General review and agency accountability</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8ac7db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262f/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit survey</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, each Inspector General created to conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to the programs and operations of the establishments listed in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s401/1">section 401(1) of title 5</ref>, and the Chief Postal Inspector of the United States Postal Service, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s415/f">section 415(f) of title 5</ref> shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262f/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> identify agency compliance activities to meet the requirements of section 543 of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8253">42 U.S.C. 8253</ref>) and any other matters relevant to implementing the goals of such Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262f/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> determine if the agency has the internal accounting mechanisms necessary to assess the accuracy and reliability of energy consumption and energy cost figures required under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8ac7de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262f/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 150 days after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency shall submit a report to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Government Operations, and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives, on the review conducted by the Inspector General of each agency under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8ac7df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262f/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspector General review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Inspector General established under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s402">section 402 of title 5</ref> is encouraged to conduct periodic reviews of agency compliance with part 3 of title V of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8251">42 U.S.C. 8251</ref> et seq.], the provisions of this subtitle,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003826">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003826"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and other laws relating to energy consumption. Such reviews shall not be inconsistent with the performance of the required duties of the Inspector General’s office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe8ac7e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s160">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 160</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2858">106 Stat. 2858</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/b/82">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(82)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4351">136 Stat. 4351</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe8ac7e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe8ac7e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe8ac7e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Energy Conservation Policy Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/619">Pub. L. 95–619</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3206">92 Stat. 3206</ref>. Part 3 of title V of the Act is classified generally to part B (§ 8251 et seq.) of subchapter III of chapter 91 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8201">section 8201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subtitle, referred to in subsec. (c), is subtitle F (§§ 151–168) of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2843">106 Stat. 2843</ref>, which enacted this section and sections 8258a, 8258b, 8262a to 8262k of this title, amended sections 8252 to 8256, 8258, 8259, 8287, and 8287c of this title and section 490 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, enacted provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8262h">section 8262h of this title</ref> and former <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1815">section 1815 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, and repealed provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8253">section 8253 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of subtitle F to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe8ac7e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, and not as part of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe8ac7e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/b/82/A">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(82)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s401/1">section 401(1) of title 5</ref>,” for “section 11(2) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.),” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s415/f">section 415(f) of title 5</ref>” for “section 8E(f)(1) as established by section 8E(a)(2) of the Inspector General Act Amendments of 1988 (<ref href="/us/pl/100/504">Public Law 100–504</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/b/82/B">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(82)(B)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s402">section 402 of title 5</ref>” for “section 2 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe8ac7e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbe8ac7e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, <date date="2004-10-09">Oct. 9, 2004</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Government Operations of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Government Reform and Oversight of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>. Committee on Government Reform and Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>. Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Public Works and Transportation of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
