<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe8ac7e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g"><num value="8262g">§ 8262g.</num><heading> Procurement and identification of energy efficient products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8ac7e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Procurement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency, each shall undertake a program to include energy efficient products in carrying out their procurement and supply functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8ac7ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, each shall implement, in conjunction with carrying out their procurement and supply functions, a program to identify and designate those energy efficient products that offer significant potential savings, using, to the extent practicable, the life cycle cost methods and procedures developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8254">section 8254 of this title</ref>. The Secretary of Energy shall, to the extent necessary to carry out this section and after consultation with the aforementioned agency heads, provide estimates of the degree of relative energy efficiency of products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8ac7eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency, shall issue guidelines to encourage the acquisition and use by all Federal agencies of products identified pursuant to this section. The Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency shall consider, and place emphasis on, the acquisition of such products as part of the Agency’s ongoing review of military specifications.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe8ac7ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than December 31 of 1993 and thereafter as part of the report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8258/b">section 8258(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency, shall report on the progress, status, activities, and results of the programs under subsections (a), (b), and (c). The report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the types and functions of each product identified under subsection (b), and efforts undertaken by the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency to encourage the acquisition and use of such products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the actions taken by the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency to identify products under subsection (b), the barriers which inhibit implementation of identification of such products, and recommendations for legislative action, if necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> progress on the development and issuance of guidelines under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an indication of whether energy cost savings technologies identified by the Advanced Building Technology Council, under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701j–2/h">section 1701j–2(h) of title 12</ref>, have been used in the identification of products under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> an estimate of the potential cost savings to the Federal Government from acquiring products identified under subsection (b) with respect to which energy is a significant component of life cycle cost, based on the quantities of such products that could be utilized throughout the Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac7f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262g/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the actual quantities acquired of products described in paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe8ac7f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s161">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 161</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2858">106 Stat. 2858</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1052/c">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1052(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/718">109 Stat. 718</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe8ac7f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe8ac7f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe8ac7f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, and not as part of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe8ac7f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> substituted “thereafter as part of the report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8258/b">section 8258(b) of this title</ref>,” for “of each year thereafter,” in introductory provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe8ac7f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe8ac7f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which the 12th item on page 85 identifies a reporting provision which, as subsequently amended, is contained in subsec. (d) of this section), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbe8ac7fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbe8ac7fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 12845</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12845, <date date="1993-04-21">Apr. 21, 1993</date>, 58 F.R. 21887, which required Federal agencies to procure computer equipment that met EPA Energy Star requirements for energy efficiency, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13123, § 604, <date date="1999-06-03">June 3, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 30859, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8251">section 8251 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
