<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe8ac808-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262i"><num value="8262i">§ 8262i.</num><heading> United States Postal Service energy management report</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, and not later than January 1 of each year thereafter, the Postmaster General shall submit a report to the Committee on Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House of Representatives on the United States Postal Service’s building management program as it relates to energy efficiency. The report shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac809-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a description of actions taken to reduce energy consumption;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac80a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> future plans to reduce energy consumption;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac80b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an assessment of the success of the energy conservation program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac80c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a statement of energy costs incurred in operating and maintaining all United States Postal Service facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe8ac80d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8262i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the status of the energy efficient procurement program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8262h">section 8262h of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbe8ac80e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tI/s165">Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 165</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2861">106 Stat. 2861</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe8ac80f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe8ac810-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe8ac811-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, and not as part of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe8ac812-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbe8ac813-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, <date date="2004-10-09">Oct. 9, 2004</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe8ac814-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of House of Representatives abolished by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Fourth Congress, <date date="1995-01-04">Jan. 4, 1995</date>. References to Committee on Post Office and Civil Service treated as referring to Committee on Government Reform and Oversight of House of Representatives, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/b">section 1(b) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Government Reform and Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>. Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
