<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe91f361-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352"><num value="8352">§ 8352.</num><heading> Permanent exemptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f362-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption due to lack of alternate fuel supply, site limitations, or environmental requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f363-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A for a powerplant, the Secretary shall, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection for the use of natural gas or petroleum, if he finds that the petitioner has demonstrated that despite diligent good faith efforts—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f364-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> it is likely that an adequate and reliable supply of coal or other alternate fuels of the quality necessary to conform with design and operational requirements for use as a primary energy source will not be available to such powerplant at a cost (taking into account associated facilities for the transportation and use of such fuel) which, based upon the best practicable estimates, does not substantially exceed the cost, as determined by rule by the Secretary, of using imported petroleum as a primary energy source during the remaining useful life of the powerplant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f365-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> one or more site limitations exist which would not permit the operation of such a powerplant using coal or any other alternate fuel as a primary energy source; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f366-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the prohibitions of part A could not be satisfied without violating applicable environmental requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f367-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this subsection, a powerplant which has been granted an exemption under subsection (g) may not be granted an exemption under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f368-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption due to certain State or local requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A for a powerplant, the Secretary may, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection, if he finds that the petitioner has demonstrated that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f369-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> with respect to the site of the powerplant, the operation of such a facility using coal or any other alternate fuel is infeasible because of a State or local requirement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f36a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if such State or local requirement is under a building code or nuisance or zoning law, no other exemption under this part could be granted for such facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f36b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the granting of the exemption would be in the public interest and would be consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f36c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption for cogeneration</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A for a cogeneration facility, the Secretary may, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection, if he—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f36d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> finds that the petitioner has demonstrated that economic and other benefits of cogeneration are unobtainable unless petroleum or natural gas, or both, are used in such facility, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f36e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> includes in the final order a statement of the basis for such finding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f36f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption for certain fuel mixtures containing natural gas or petroleum</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f370-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A for a powerplant, the Secretary shall, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection, if he finds that the petitioner has demonstrated that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f371-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the powerplant uses, or proposes to use, a mixture of petroleum or natural gas and coal or another alternate fuel as a primary energy source; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f372-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of the petroleum or natural gas used in such mixture will not exceed the minimum percentage of the total Btu heat input of the primary energy sources of such powerplant needed to maintain reliability of operation of the unit consistent with maintaining a reasonable level of fuel efficiency, as determined in accordance with rules prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f373-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/12/A">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(12)(A)</ref>, <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/313">101 Stat. 313</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f374-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may authorize a higher percentage than that referred to in paragraph (1)(B) if he finds that the higher percentage of natural gas allowed would be mixed with synthetic fuels derived from municipal wastes or agricultural wastes and would encourage the use of alternate or new technologies which use renewable sources of energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f375-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption for emergency purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A for a powerplant, the Secretary shall, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection, if he finds that the petitioner has demonstrated that such powerplant will be maintained and operated only for emergency purposes (as defined by rule by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f376-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption for peakload powerplants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A for a powerplant, the Secretary shall, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection, if he finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f377-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the powerplant is operated solely as a peakload powerplant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f378-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a denial of such petition is likely to result in an impairment of reliability of service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f379-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f37a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> modification of the powerplant to permit compliance with such prohibitions is technically infeasible; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f37b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such modification would result in an unreasonable expense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f37c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption for intermediate load powerplants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f37d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A on the use of petroleum by a powerplant, the Secretary may, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection, if he finds that the petitioner has demonstrated that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f37e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (or the appropriate State air pollution control agency) certifies to the Secretary that the use by such powerplant of coal or any available alternate fuel as a primary energy source will cause or contribute to a concentration, in an air quality control region or any area within such region, of a pollutant for which any national ambient air quality standard is or would be exceeded for such area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f37f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> such powerplant is to be operated only to replace no more than the equivalent capacity of existing electric powerplants—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe91f380-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> which use natural gas or petroleum as a primary energy source,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe91f381-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> which are owned by the same person who is to operate such powerplant, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe91f382-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> which, if they used coal as a primary energy source, would cause or contribute to such a concentration in such region;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f383-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such powerplant is and shall continue to be operated solely as an intermediate load powerplant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f384-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the net fuel heat input rate for such powerplant will be maintained at or less than 9,500 Btu’s per kilowatt hour throughout the remaining useful life of the powerplant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f385-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the powerplant has the capability to use synthetic fuels derived from coal or other alternate fuel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f386-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall, from time to time, review each exemption granted to a powerplant under this subsection, and shall terminate such exemption if he finds that there is available a supply of synthetic fuel derived from coal or other alternate fuel suitable for use as a primary energy source by such powerplant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f387-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption for use of natural gas by certain powerplants with capacities of less than 250 million Btu’s per hour</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f388-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2), after consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from any prohibition of part A for the use of natural gas by a powerplant, the Secretary shall, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection for such use, if he finds that the petitioner has demonstrated that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f389-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such powerplant has a design capability of consuming fuel (or any mixture thereof) at a fuel heat input rate of less than 250 million Btu’s per hour;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f38a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such powerplant was a baseload powerplant on <date date="1977-04-20">April 20, 1977</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe91f38b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> such powerplant is not capable of consuming coal without—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe91f38c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> substantial physical modification of the unit; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe91f38d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> substantial reduction in the rated capacity of the unit (as determined by the Secretary).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe91f38e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An exemption under this subsection may only apply to the prohibitions under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8341">section 8341 of this title</ref> and prohibitions established by final rules or orders issued before <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe91f38f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8352/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent exemption for use of LNG by certain powerplants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consideration of a petition (and comments thereon) for an exemption from one or more of the prohibitions of part A for a powerplant, the Secretary shall, by order, grant a permanent exemption under this subsection for the use of liquefied natural gas if the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (or the appropriate State air pollution control agency) has certified to the Secretary that the use of coal by such powerplant as a primary energy source will cause or contribute to a concentration, in an air quality control region or any area within such region, of a pollutant for which any national ambient air quality standard is or would be exceeded for such region or area and the use of coal would not comply with applicable environmental requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe91f390-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/620/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 95–620, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3309">92 Stat. 3309</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/10">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(10)</ref>, (12), <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/313">101 Stat. 313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe91f391-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe91f392-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe91f393-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/620">Pub. L. 95–620</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3289">92 Stat. 3289</ref>, known as the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">section 8301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe91f394-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsecs. (a)(1), (b), (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/10">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(10)</ref>, struck out “or installation” after “powerplant” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/12/A">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(12)(A)</ref>, struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “In the case of an existing major fuel-burning installation, the percentage determined by the Secretary under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) shall not be less than 25 percent.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/12/B">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(12)(B)</ref>, substituted “The” for “In the case of an existing electric powerplant, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/10">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(10)</ref>, struck out “or installation” after “powerplant” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/12/C">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(12)(C)</ref>, struck out subsec. (j) which related to granting, by Secretary of Energy, of permanent exemptions for use of natural gas for installations served by international pipelines.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/12/C">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(12)(C)</ref>, struck out subsec. (k) which related to granting, by Secretary of Energy, of permanent exemptions for use of natural gas or petroleum for installations based upon product or process requirements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/12/C">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(12)(C)</ref>, struck out subsec. (<i>l</i>) which related to granting, by Secretary of Energy, of permanent exemptions for use of natural gas or petroleum for installations necessary to meet scheduled equipment outages.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe946395-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe946396-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exemption for Certain Electric Powerplants as Effective Prior to 180 Days After <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effectiveness of exemption for certain electric powerplants as prior to 180 days after <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/620/s902/a">section 902(a) of Pub. L. 95–620</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">section 8301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
