<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe9463b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373"><num value="8373">§ 8373.</num><heading> Conservation in Federal facilities, contracts, and financial assistance programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9463b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal facilities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9463b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each Federal agency owning or operating any electric powerplant shall comply with any prohibition, term, condition, or other substantial or procedural requirement under this chapter, to the same extent as would be the case if such powerplant were owned or operated by a nongovernmental person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9463b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The President may, by order, exempt from the application of paragraph (1) any powerplant owned or operated by any Federal agency, if the President determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9463b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> such use is in the paramount interest of the United States and that the powerplant involved is a component of or is used solely in connection with any weaponry, equipment, aircraft, vessels, vehicles or other classes or categories of property which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9463ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are owned or operated by the Armed Forces of the United States (including the Coast Guard) or by the National Guard of any State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9463bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> are uniquely military in nature; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9463bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> there is a lack of appropriation for such use but only if the President specifically requested such appropriations as a part of the budgetary process and the Congress failed to make available such requested appropriation.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such order shall not take effect until 60 days after a copy of such order has been transmitted to each House of the Congress. The President shall review each such determination every 2 years and submit a report to the Congress on the results of such review.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9463bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal contracts and financial assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9463be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In order to implement the purposes of this chapter, the President shall, not later than 30 days after the effective date of this chapter, issue an order—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9463bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> requiring each Federal agency which is authorized to extend Federal assistance by way of grant, loan, contract, or other form of financial assistance, to promptly effectuate the purposes of this chapter relating to the conservation of petroleum and natural gas, by rule, in such contracting or assistance activities within 180 days after issuance of such order, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9463c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> setting forth procedures, sanctions, penalties, and such other provisions as the President determines necessary to carry out such requirement effectively, including a requirement that each agency annually transmit to the President, and make available to the public, a report on the actions taken and to be taken to implement such order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9463c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The President may exempt by order any specific grant, loan, contract, or other form of financial assistance from all or part of the provisions of this subsection if he determines such exemption is in the national interest. The President shall notify the Congress in writing of such exemption at least 60 days before it is effective.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9463c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The President or any Federal agency may not use the authority granted under paragraph (1) to require compliance, including the use of coal, by any person or facility with any prohibition under other sections of this chapter if such person or facility has been specifically determined by the Secretary as subject to such prohibition or has been exempted from the application of such prohibition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe9463c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/620/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 95–620, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3317">92 Stat. 3317</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/14">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(14)</ref>, <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/313">101 Stat. 313</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXXX/s3011">Pub. L. 102–486, title XXX, § 3011</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3128">106 Stat. 3128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe9463c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe9463c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe9463c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (b)(1), (3), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/620">Pub. L. 95–620</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3289">92 Stat. 3289</ref>, known as the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">section 8301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is the effective date of <ref href="/us/pl/95/620">Pub. L. 95–620</ref>. See <ref href="/us/pl/95/620/s901">section 901 of Pub. L. 95–620</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">section 8301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe9463c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> struck out subsec. (c), which read as follows: “The President shall annually submit a detailed report to each House of the Congress on the actions taken by the President and each Federal agency to implement this section, including the progress and problems associated with implementation of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/14/A">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(14)(A)</ref>, struck out “, major fuel-burning installation, or other unit” after “electric powerplant” and “, installation, or unit” after “such powerplant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/14/B">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(14)(B)</ref>, (C), struck out “, installation, or other unit” after “powerplant” in introductory provisions, “, installation, or unit” after “powerplant” in subpar. (A), and last sentence which read as follows: “Any powerplant, installation, or other unit permitted to use natural gas or petroleum under an exemption under this paragraph shall establish and carry out effective fuel conservation measures, as determined by the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/14/D">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(14)(D)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “Any powerplant, installation, or unit owned or operated by any such Federal agency shall be entitled to any exemption by the Secretary to the same extent, in the same manner, and under the same terms and conditions as would apply if it were owned or operated by a nongovernmental person.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe9463c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe9463c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which the report under the last sentence of subsec. (a)(2) of this section is listed as the 16th item on page 19), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbe9463ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbe9463cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbe9463cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12185. Effectuation of Conservation of Petroleum and Natural Gas by Recipients of Federal Financial Assistance</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12185, <date date="1979-12-17">Dec. 17, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 75093, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President of the United States of America by Section 403(b) of the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/stat/92/3318">92 Stat. 3318</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/620">Public Law 95–620</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b">42 U.S.C. 8373(b)</ref>] and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">Section 301 of Title 3</ref> of the United States Code, in order to encourage additional conservation of petroleum and natural gas by recipients of Federal financial assistance, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–101. Each Federal agency, as that term is defined in Section 103(a)(25) of the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/stat/92/3297">92 Stat. 3297</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8302/a/25">42 U.S.C. 8302(a)(25)</ref>], shall effectuate through its financial assistance programs the purposes of that Act relating to the conservation of petroleum and natural gas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–102. Each Federal agency which extends financial assistance shall review those programs of financial assistance and identify those which are most likely to offer opportunities for significant conservation of petroleum and natural gas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–103. Within two months, and annually thereafter, each agency shall publish for comment a list of those programs which it has identified as likely to offer significant opportunity for conservation. The public shall be given 60 days to submit comments, including suggestions for rules which would effectuate the conservation purposes of the Act [see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">42 U.S.C. 8301</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–104. After receiving public comment and suggestions, and after consulting with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, each agency shall publish proposed rules designed to achieve conservation of petroleum and natural gas in connection with the receipt of financial assistance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proposed rules should be published within 30 days of the close of the comment period under Section 1–103.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–105. Final rules shall be adopted by each agency in accordance with the provisions of Sections 102(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301/b">42 U.S.C. 8301(b)</ref>], 403(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b">42 U.S.C. 8373(b)</ref>] and 701(a) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8411/a">42 U.S.C. 8411(a)</ref>] of the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978, and the provisions of this Order, not later than 180 days from the date of this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–106. No one shall be awarded any financial assistance unless that award complies with the provisions of the conservation rules adopted by the agency pursuant to this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–107. To the extent permitted by law and where not inconsistent with the financial assistance program, final rules may provide for the reduction or suspension of financial assistance under any award. Such reduction or suspension shall not be ordered until there has been an opportunity for a hearing on the record, and shall last for such time as the recipient fails to comply with the terms of the conservation rule.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–108. No conservation rule shall be adopted which is inconsistent with the statutory provisions establishing the financial assistance program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–109. No conservation rule shall be used to enforce compliance with any prohibition under the Act [see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">42 U.S.C. 8301</ref>] against any person or facility which has been specifically determined by the Secretary of Energy as subject to or exempt from a prohibition under the Act. The conservation rules shall be used to enforce other new ways of achieving the purposes of the Act related to the conservation of petroleum and natural gas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–110. In order to assess the effectiveness of this program, each agency shall annually prepare a report on its activities in accord with Section 403(b)(1)(B) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b">42 U.S.C. 8373(b)</ref>]. These reports shall be submitted to the President through the Secretary of Energy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–111. The Secretary of Energy shall prepare for the President’s consideration and transmittal to the Congress the report required by Section 403(c) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8373/c">42 U.S.C. 8373(c)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–112. The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may issue any rules, regulations, or orders he deems necessary to ensure the implementation of this Order. The Director may exercise any of the authority vested in the President by Section 403(b) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8373/b">42 U.S.C. 8373(b)</ref>], and may redelegate such of that authority as he deems appropriate to the head of any other agency.</p>
<signature>
<name>Jimmy Carter.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbe9463cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 12217</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12217, <date date="1980-06-18">June 18, 1980</date>, 45 F.R. 41623, which established the responsibilities and duties of Executive agencies for compliance with this chapter, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12437, <date date="1983-08-11">Aug. 11, 1983</date>, 48 F.R. 36801.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
