<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe94645e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411"><num value="8411">§ 8411.</num><heading> Administrative procedures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe94645f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rulemaking</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except to the extent otherwise provided in this section or other provisions of this chapter, rules prescribed under this chapter shall be made in accordance with the procedures set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe946460-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Notices of rules and orders imposing prohibitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Before the Secretary prescribes any rule or issues any order imposing a prohibition under this chapter, he shall publish such proposed rule or order in the Federal Register, together with a statement of the reasons for such rule or order and, in the case of a rule, a detailed statement of any special circumstances or characteristics required to be taken into account in prescribing such rule. A copy shall be transmitted to the person who operates any such powerplant required to be specifically identified in such rule or order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe946461-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Petitions for exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe946462-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any petition for an exemption from any prohibition under this chapter shall be filed at such time and shall be in such form as the Secretary shall by rule prescribe. The Secretary, upon receipt of such petition, shall publish a notice thereof in the Federal Register together with a statement of the reasons set forth in such a petition for requesting such exemption, and provide a period of public comment of at least 45 days for written comments thereon. Rules required under this paragraph shall be prescribed not later than 120 days after <date date="1978-11-09">November 9, 1978</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe946463-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary, upon receipt of such petition, shall notify the appropriate State agencies having primary authority to permit or regulate the construction or operation of the electric powerplant which is the subject of such petition, and, to the maximum extent practicable, consult with such agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe946464-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary, within 6 months after the period for public comment and hearing applicable to any petition for an exemption, shall issue a final order granting or denying the petition for such exemption, except that the Secretary may extend such period to a specified date if he publishes notice thereof in the Federal Register and includes with such notice a statement of the reasons for such extension.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe946465-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Public comment on prohibitions and exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe946466-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the case of any proposed rule or order by the Secretary imposing a prohibition or any petition for any order granting an exemption under this chapter, any interested person shall be afforded an opportunity to present oral data, views, and arguments at a public hearing. At such hearing any interested person shall have an opportunity to question—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe946467-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> other interested persons who make oral presentations,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe946468-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> employees and contractors of the United States who have made written or oral presentations or who have participated in the development of the proposed rule or order or in the consideration of such petition, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe96ad59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> experts and consultants who have provided information to any person who makes an oral presentation and which is contained in or referred to in such presentation,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">with respect to disputed issues of material fact, except that the Secretary may restrict questioning if he determines that such questioning is duplicative or is not likely to result in a timely and effective resolution of such issues. Any oral or documentary evidence may be received, but the Secretary as a matter of policy shall provide for the exclusion of irrelevant, immaterial, or unduly repetitious evidence.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96ad5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A rule or order subject to this section may not be issued except on consideration of the whole record or those parts thereof cited by a party and supported by and in accordance with the reliable, probative, and substantial evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ad5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Transcript</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A transcript shall be kept of any public hearing made in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ad5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Environmental Protection Agency comment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A copy of any proposed rule or order to be prescribed or issued by the Secretary which imposes a prohibition under this chapter (other than under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8374">section 8374 of this title</ref>), or a petition for an exemption (or permit) under this chapter (other than under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8374">section 8374 of this title</ref>), shall be transmitted by the Secretary to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary shall request such agency to comment thereon within the period provided to the public unless a longer period is provided under the Clean Air Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.]. In any such case, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall be afforded the same opportunity to comment and question as is provided other interested persons under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ad5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/E">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(E)</ref>, <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/313">101 Stat. 313</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ad5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with other provisions of law</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96ad5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in sections 8412(c)(4), 8433(d)(5), and 8434 of this title, title V of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7191">42 U.S.C. 7191</ref>, et seq.) shall not apply with respect to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96ad60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The preceding provisions of this section shall not apply with respect to any exercise of authority under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8374">section 8374 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96ad61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The procedures applicable under this chapter shall not—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe96ad62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be considered to be modified or affected by any other provision of law unless such other provision specifically amends this chapter (or provisions of law cited herein), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe96ad63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8411/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be considered to be superseded by any other provision of law unless such other provision does so in specific terms, referring to this chapter, and declaring that such provision supersedes, in whole or in part, the procedures of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe96ad64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/620/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 95–620, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3329">92 Stat. 3329</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)</ref>, <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/313">101 Stat. 313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe96ad65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe96ad66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe96ad67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) to (c)(1), (d)(1), (f), and (h)(1), (3), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/620">Pub. L. 95–620</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3289">92 Stat. 3289</ref>, known as the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">section 8301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clean Air Act, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/322">69 Stat. 322</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 85 (§ 7401 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Department of Energy Organization Act, referred to in subsec. (h)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/567">91 Stat. 567</ref>. Title V of the Department of Energy Organization Act is classified generally to subchapter V (§ 7191 et seq.) of chapter 84 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7101">section 7101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe96ad68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/A">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(A)</ref>, struck out “(other than under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8372">section 8372 of this title</ref>)” after “this chapter” and “or installation” after “powerplant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/B/i">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), struck out “or for any permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8375">section 8375 of this title</ref>” after “this chapter” and “or permit” after “such exemption”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/B/iii">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(B)(iii)</ref>, struck out “or, where appropriate, major fuel-burning installation” after “powerplant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/B/i">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(B)(i)</ref>, struck out “or permit” after “exemption” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/B/iv">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(B)(iv)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which read as follows: “Any order for the approval of a system compliance plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8391">section 8391 of this title</ref>, and any petition for such an order, shall be treated for purposes of this subchapter the same as an order (or petition) for an exemption.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/C">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(C)</ref>, struck out “(or permit)” after “an exemption” and “(other than under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8372">section 8372 of this title</ref>)” after “under this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/D">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(D)</ref>, struck out “8372 or” after “(other than under section” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/16/E">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(E)</ref>, struck out subsec. (g) which read as follows: “A copy of any proposed rule or order to be prescribed or issued by the Secretary which imposes a prohibition under this chapter (other than under section 8372 or 8374 of this title) with respect to a major fuel-burning installation or a boiler subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8371">section 8371 of this title</ref> or a petition by such installation or boiler for an exemption (or permit) under this chapter (other than under section 8372 or 8374 of this title), shall be transmitted by the Secretary to the Federal Trade Commission and the Secretary shall request such Commission to comment thereon within the period provided to the public. In any such case, the Federal Trade Commission shall be afforded the same opportunity to comment and question as is provided other interested persons under subsection (d).”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
