<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe96ada5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433"><num value="8433">§ 8433.</num><heading> Civil penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ada6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General civil penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who violates any provision of this chapter, or rule or order thereunder, shall be subject to a civil penalty, which shall be assessed by the Secretary, of not more than $25,000 for each violation. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ada7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalty for operation in excess of exemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any electric powerplant granted an exemption, any person who operates such powerplant during any 12-calendar-month period in excess of that authorized in such exemption, shall be liable for a civil penalty, which shall be assessed by the Secretary. The amount of such civil penalty may not exceed $10 per barrel of petroleum or $3 per Mcf of natural gas used in operation of such powerplant in excess of that authorized in such exemption.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ada8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/20/C">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(20)(C)</ref>, <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/314">101 Stat. 314</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe96ada9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Before issuing an order assessing a civil penalty against any person under this chapter, the Secretary shall provide to such person notice of the proposed penalty. Such notice shall inform such person of his opportunity to elect in writing within 30 days after the date of receipt of such notice to have the procedures of paragraph (3) (in lieu of those of paragraph (2)) apply with respect to such assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Unless an election is made within 30 calendar days after receipt of notice under paragraph (1) to have paragraph (3) apply with respect to such penalty, the Secretary shall assess the penalty, by order, after a determination of violation has been made on the record after an opportunity for an agency hearing pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref> before an administrative law judge appointed under section 3105 of such title 5. Such assessment order shall include the administrative law judge’s findings and the basis for such assessment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any person against whom a penalty is assessed under this paragraph may, within 60 calendar days after the date of the order of the Secretary assessing such penalty, institute an action in the United States court of appeals for the appropriate judicial circuit for judicial review of such order in accordance with chapter 7 of title 5. The court shall have jurisdiction to enter a judgment affirming, modifying, or setting aside in whole or in part, the order of the Secretary, or the court may remand the proceeding to the Secretary for such further action as the court may direct.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of any civil penalty with respect to which the procedures of this paragraph have been elected, the Secretary shall promptly assess such penalty, by order, after the date of the receipt of the notice under paragraph (1) of the proposed penalty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If the civil penalty has not been paid within 60 calendar days after the assessment order has been made under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall institute an action in the appropriate district court of the United States for an order affirming the assessment of the civil penalty. The court shall have authority to review de novo the law and the facts involved, and shall have jurisdiction to enter a judgment enforcing, modifying, and enforcing as so modified, or setting aside in whole or in part, such assessment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adb1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any election to have this paragraph apply may not be revoked except with the consent of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adb2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If any person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty after it has become a final and unappealable order under paragraph (2), or after the appropriate district court has entered final judgment in favor of the Secretary under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall institute an action to recover the amount of such penalty in any appropriate district court of the United States. In such action, the validity and appropriateness of such final assessment order or judgment shall not be subject to review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of title 28, or of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7192/c">section 7192(c) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall be represented by the general counsel of the Department of Energy (or any attorney or attorneys within the Department of Energy designated by the Secretary) who shall supervise, conduct, and argue any civil litigation to which paragraph (3) of this subsection applies (including any related collection action under paragraph (4)) in a court of the United States or in any other court, except the Supreme Court. However, the Secretary or the general counsel shall consult with the Attorney General concerning such litigation, and the Attorney General shall provide, on request, such assistance in the conduct of such litigation as may be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7192/c">section 7192(c) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall be represented by the Attorney General, or the Solicitor General, as appropriate, in actions under this subsection, except to the extent provided in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe96adb6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8433/d/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7172/d">Section 7172(d) of this title</ref> shall not apply with respect to the functions of the Secretary under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe96adb7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/620/tVII/s723">Pub. L. 95–620, title VII, § 723</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3333">92 Stat. 3333</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/20">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(20)</ref>, <date date="1987-05-21">May 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/313">101 Stat. 313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe96adb8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe96adb9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe96adba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (d)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/620">Pub. L. 95–620</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3289">92 Stat. 3289</ref>, known as the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8301">section 8301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe96adbb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/20/A">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(20)(A)</ref>, struck out “(other than <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8372">section 8372 of this title</ref>)” after “this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/20/B">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(20)(B)</ref>, (C), struck out “(1)” before “In the case of” and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “Any person operating a major fuel-burning installation granted an exemption which, for any 12-calendar-month period, uses petroleum or natural gas, or both, in excess of that use allowed by such exemption shall be liable for a civil penalty, which shall be assessed by the Secretary. The amount of such civil penalty may not exceed $10 per barrel of petroleum or $3 per Mcf of natural gas which was used in excess of that use allowed by such exemption.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/42/s1/c/20/C">Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(20)(C)</ref>, struck out subsec. (c) which set forth civil penalties for violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8372">section 8372 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
