<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe991feb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513"><num value="8513">§ 8513.</num><heading> Standby Federal conservation plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe991fec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of standby conservation plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991fed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 90 days after <date date="1979-11-05">November 5, 1979</date>, the Secretary, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7191">section 7191 of this title</ref>, shall establish a standby Federal emergency conservation plan. The Secretary may amend such plan at any time, and shall make such amendments public upon their adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991fee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The plan under this section shall be consistent with the attainment of the objectives of section 753(b)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003843">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003843"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 15, and shall provide for the emergency reduction in the public and private use of each energy source for which an emergency conservation target is in effect or may be in effect under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8511">section 8511 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe991fef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation of standby conservation plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991ff0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If the President finds—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe991ff1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> after a reasonable period of operation, but not less than 90 days, that a State emergency conservation plan approved and implemented under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8512">section 8512 of this title</ref> is not substantially meeting a conservation target established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8511/a">section 8511(a) of this title</ref> for such State and it is likely that such target will continue to be unmet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe991ff2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a shortage exists or is likely to exist in such State for the 60-day period beginning after such finding that is equal to or greater than 8 percent of the projected normal demand, as determined by the President, for an energy source for which such conservation target has been established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8511/a">section 8511(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the President shall, after consultation with the Governor of such State, make effective in such State all or any part of the standby Federal conservation plan established under subsection (a) for such period or periods as the President determines appropriate to achieve the target in that State.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991ff3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If the President finds after a reasonable period of time, that the conservation target established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8511/a">section 8511(a) of this title</ref> is not being substantially met and it is likely that such target will continue to be unmet in a State which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe991ff4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has no emergency conservation plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8512">section 8512 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe991ff5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the President finds has substantially failed to carry out the assurances regarding implementation set forth in the plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8512">section 8512 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the President shall, after consultation with the Governor of such State, make effective in such State all or any part of the standby Federal conservation plan established under subsection (a) for such period or periods as the President determines appropriate to achieve the target in that State.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe991ff6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis for findings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any finding under subsection (b) shall be accompanied by such information and analysis as is necessary to provide a basis therefor and shall be available to the Congress and the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe991ff7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of State emergency conservation plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991ff8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003844">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003844"><num>2</num> So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted.</note> The Governor of a State in which all or any portion of the standby Federal conservation plan is or will be in effect may submit at any time a State emergency conservation plan, and if it is approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8512/c">section 8512(c) of this title</ref>, all or such portion of the standby Federal conservation plan shall cease to be effective in that State. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect any action or pending proceedings, administrative or civil, not finally determined on such date, nor any administrative or civil action or proceeding, whether or not pending, based upon any act committed or liability incurred prior to such cessation of effectiveness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe991ff9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> State substitute emergency conservation measures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991ffa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> After the President makes all or any part of the standby Federal conservation plan effective in any State or political subdivision under subsection (b), the Secretary shall provide procedures whereby such State or any political subdivision thereof may submit to the Secretary for approval one or more measures under authority of State or local law to be implemented by such State or political subdivision and to be substituted for any Federal measure in the Federal plan. The measures may include provisions whereby persons affected by such Federal measure are permitted to use alternative means of conserving at least as much energy as would be conserved by such Federal measure. Such measures shall provide effective procedures, as determined by the Secretary, for the approval and enforcement of such alternative means by such State or by any political subdivision thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991ffb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may approve the measures under paragraph (1) if he finds—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe991ffc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that such measures when in effect will conserve at least as much energy as would be conserved by such Federal measure which would have otherwise been in effect in such State or political subdivision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe991ffd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such measures otherwise meet the requirements of this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe991ffe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such measures would be approved under section 8512(c)(1)(B), (C), and (D) of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe991fff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the Secretary approves measures under this subsection such Federal measure shall cease to be effective in that State or political subdivision. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect any action or pending proceedings, administrative or civil, not finally determined on the date the Federal measure ceases to be effective in that State or political subdivision, nor any administrative or civil action or proceeding, whether or not pending, based upon any act committed or liability incurred prior to such cessation of effectiveness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe992000-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the Secretary finds after a reasonable period of time that the requirements of this subsection are not being met under the measures in effect under this subsection he may reimpose the Federal measure referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe992001-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> State authority to administer plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the request of the Governor of any State, the President may provide that the administration and enforcement of all or a portion of the standby Federal conservation plan made effective in that State under subsection (b) be in accordance with section 8512(d)(1), (2), and (4) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe992002-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential authority not to be delegated</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than subsection (f)), the authority vested in the President under this section may not be delegated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe992003-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements of plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The plan established under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe992004-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> taken as a whole, be designed so that the plan, if implemented, would be likely to achieve the emergency conservation target under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8511">section 8511 of this title</ref> for which it would be implemented,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe992005-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> taken as a whole, be designed so as not to impose an unreasonably disproportionate share of the burden of restrictions on energy use on any specific class of industry, business, or commercial enterprise, or any individual segment thereof, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe992006-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> not contain any measure which the Secretary finds—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe992007-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is inconsistent with any otherwise applicable Federal law (including any rule or regulation under such law),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe992008-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is an undue burden on interstate commerce,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe992009-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is a tax, tariff, or user fee, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe99200a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/h/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> is a program for the assignment of rights for end-user purchases of gasoline or diesel fuel, as described in section 6263(a)(1)(A) and (B) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe99200b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan may not authorize weekend closings of retail gasoline stations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe99200c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the plan established under subsection (a) may not provide for the restriction of hours of sale of motor fuel at retail at any time between Friday noon and Sunday midnight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe99200d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) shall not preclude the restriction on such hours of sale if that restriction occurs in connection with a program for restricting hours of sale of motor fuel each day of the week on a rotating basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe99200e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe99200f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Whoever violates the requirements of such a plan implemented under subsection (b) shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $1,000 for each violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe992010-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any penalty under paragraph (1) may be assessed by the court in any action brought in any appropriate United States district court or any other court of competent jurisdiction. Except to the extent provided under paragraph (3), any such penalty collected shall be deposited into the general fund of the United States Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe992011-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8513/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may enter into an agreement with the Governor of any State under which amounts collected pursuant to this subsection may be collected and retained by the State to the extent necessary to cover costs incurred by that State in connection with the administration and enforcement of that portion of the standby Federal conservation plan for which authority is delegated to that State under subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe992012-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/102/tII/s213">Pub. L. 96–102, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1979-11-05">Nov. 5, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/762">93 Stat. 762</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe992013-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe992014-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe992015-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s753">Section 753 of title 15</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), was omitted from the Code pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s760g">section 760g of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, which provided for the expiration of the President’s authority under that section on <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6263">Section 6263 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (h)(3)(D), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/106/469/tI/s104/1">Pub. L. 106–469, title I, § 104(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2033">114 Stat. 2033</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
