<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe9b69a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623"><num value="8623">§ 8623.</num><heading> State allotments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9b69aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount; distribution, computation, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall, from that percentage of the amount appropriated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621/b">section 8621(b) of this title</ref> for each fiscal year which is remaining after reserving any amount permitted to be reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8628a">section 8628a of this title</ref> and after the amount of allotments for such fiscal year under subsection (b)(1) is determined by the Secretary, allot to each State an amount equal to such remaining percentage multiplied by the State’s allotment percentage.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> From the sums appropriated therefor after reserving any amount permitted to be reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8628a">section 8628a of this title</ref>, if for any period a State has a plan which is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1">section 8624(c)(1) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall pay to such State an amount equal to 100 percent of the expenditures of such State made during such period in carrying out such plan, including administrative costs (subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/9/B">section 8624(b)(9)(B) of this title</ref>), with respect to households described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2">section 8624(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), for fiscal year 1985 and thereafter, a State’s allotment percentage is the percentage which expenditures for home energy by low-income households in that State bears to such expenditures in all States, except that States which thereby receive the greatest proportional increase in allotments by reason of the application of this paragraph from the amount they received pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/98/139">Public Law 98–139</ref> shall have their allotments reduced to the extent necessary to ensure that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> no State for fiscal year 1985 shall receive less than the amount of funds the State received in fiscal year 1984; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> no State for fiscal year 1986 and thereafter shall receive less than the amount of funds the State would have received in fiscal year 1984 if the appropriations for this subchapter for fiscal year 1984 had been $1,975,000,000, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any State whose allotment percentage out of funds available to States from a total appropriation of $2,250,000,000 would be less than 1 percent, shall not, in any year when total appropriations equal or exceed $2,250,000,000, have its allotment percentage reduced from the percentage it would receive from a total appropriation of $2,140,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the sums appropriated for any fiscal year for making grants under this subchapter are not sufficient to pay in full the total amount allocated to a State under paragraph (1) for such fiscal year, the amount which all States will receive under this subchapter for such fiscal year shall be ratably reduced.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For the purpose of this section, the Secretary shall determine the expenditure for home energy by low-income households on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data available to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9b69b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Allotments to insular areas</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall apportion not less than one-tenth of 1 percent, and not more than one-half of 1 percent, of the amounts appropriated for each fiscal year to carry out this subchapter on the basis of need among the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. The Secretary shall determine the total amount to be apportioned under this paragraph for any fiscal year (which shall not exceed one-half of 1 percent) after evaluating the extent to which each jurisdiction specified in the preceding sentence requires assistance under this paragraph for the fiscal year involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each jurisdiction to which paragraph (1) applies may receive grants under this subchapter upon an application submitted to the Secretary containing provisions which describe the programs for which assistance is sought under this subchapter, and which are consistent with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8624">section 8624 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9b69b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Energy crisis intervention</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Of the funds available to each State under subsection (a), a reasonable amount based on data from prior years shall be reserved until March 15 of each program year by each State for energy crisis intervention. The program for which funds are reserved by this subsection shall be administered by public or nonprofit entities which have experience in administering energy crisis programs under the Low-Income Energy Assistance Act of 1980, or under this subchapter,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003847">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003847"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> experience in assisting low-income individuals in the area to be served, the capacity to undertake a timely and effective energy crisis intervention program, and the ability to carry out the program in local communities. The program for which funds are reserved under this subsection shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> not later than 48 hours after a household applies for energy crisis benefits, provide some form of assistance that will resolve the energy crisis if such household is eligible to receive such benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not later than 18 hours after a household applies for crisis benefits, provide some form of assistance that will resolve the energy crisis if such household is eligible to receive such benefits and is in a life-threatening situation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> require each entity that administers such program—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9b69bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to accept applications for energy crisis benefits at sites that are geographically accessible to all households in the area to be served by such entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9b69bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> to provide to low-income individuals who are physically infirm the means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9b69be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to submit applications for energy crisis benefits without leaving their residences; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9b69bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to travel to the sites at which such applications are accepted by such entity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The preceding sentence shall not apply to a program in a geographical area affected by a natural disaster in the United States designated by the Secretary, or by a major disaster or emergency designated by the President under the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 <sup>1</sup> [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.], for so long as such designation remains in effect, if the Secretary determines that such disaster or such emergency makes compliance with such sentence impracticable.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9b69c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Allotments to Indian tribes</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If, with respect to any State, the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> receives a request from the governing organization of an Indian tribe within the State that assistance under this subchapter be made directly to such organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> determines that the members of such tribe would be better served by means of grants made directly to provide benefits under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall reserve from amounts which would otherwise be payable to such State from amounts allotted to it under this subchapter for the fiscal year involved the amount determined under paragraph (2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount determined under this paragraph for a fiscal year is the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount which would (but for this subsection) be allotted to such State under this subchapter for such fiscal year (other than by reason of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8626/b/2">section 8626(b)(2) of this title</ref>) as the number of Indian households described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2">section 8624(b)(2) of this title</ref> and residing within the State on the reservation of the tribes or on trust lands adjacent to such reservation bears to the number of all households described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2">section 8624(b)(2) of this title</ref> in such State, or such greater amount as the Indian tribe and the State may agree upon. In cases where a tribe has no reservation, the Secretary, in consultation with the tribe and the State, shall define the number of Indian households for the determination under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The sums reserved by the Secretary on the basis of a determination under this subsection shall be granted to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the tribal organization serving the individuals for whom such a determination has been made; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9b69c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in any case where there is no tribal organization serving an individual for whom such a determination has been made, such other entity as the Secretary determines has the capacity to provide assistance pursuant to this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9b69c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In order for a tribal organization or other entity to be eligible for an amount under this subsection for a fiscal year, it shall submit to the Secretary a plan (in lieu of being under the State’s plan) for such fiscal year which meets such criteria as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9b69c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8623/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Allotment of emergency funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsections (a) through (d), the Secretary may allot amounts appropriated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621/e">section 8621(e) of this title</ref> to one or more than one State. In determining whether to make such an allotment to a State, the Secretary shall take into account the extent to which the State was affected by the natural disaster or other emergency involved, the availability to the State of other resources under the program carried out under this subchapter or any other program, and such other factors as the Secretary may find to be relevant. Not later than 30 days after making the determination, but prior to releasing an allotted amount to a State, the Secretary shall notify Congress of the allotments made pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe9b69ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVI/s2604">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVI, § 2604</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/894">95 Stat. 894</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/tVI">Pub. L. 98–558, title VI</ref>, §§ 603, 604, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2890">98 Stat. 2890</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/tV">Pub. L. 99–425, title V</ref>, §§ 502(a), 503, 505(b), <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/973-975">100 Stat. 973–975</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 101–501, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1258">104 Stat. 1258</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/tIII">Pub. L. 103–252, title III</ref>, §§ 304(c), 311(c)(3), <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/659">108 Stat. 659</ref>, 662; <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/tIII">Pub. L. 105–285, title III</ref>, §§ 304(b), 305, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2757">112 Stat. 2757</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe9b69cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe9b69cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe9b69cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/139">Public Law 98–139</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/98/139">Pub. L. 98–139</ref>, <date date="1983-10-31">Oct. 31, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/871">97 Stat. 871</ref>, known as the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriation Act, 1984. For complete classification of this Act to the Code see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Low-Income Energy Assistance Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (c), probably means the Home Energy Assistance Act of 1980, which is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/288">94 Stat. 288</ref>, and which was classified generally to subchapter I of this chapter prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVI/s2611">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVI, § 2611</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/902">95 Stat. 902</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this Act” which was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title XXVI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Disaster Relief Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/288">Pub. L. 93–288</ref>, <date date="1974-05-22">May 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/143">88 Stat. 143</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 68 (§ 5121 et seq.) of this title. The 1974 Act was renamed “The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act”, and was substantially revised by <ref href="/us/pl/100/707">Pub. L. 100–707</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4689">102 Stat. 4689</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/s102/b">Section 102(b) of Pub. L. 100–707</ref> provided that a reference in any other law to a provision of the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 shall be deemed to be a reference to such provision of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. The name of the Act was subsequently changed to the “Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act” by <ref href="/us/pl/106/390/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 106–390, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, 1<ref href="/us/stat/114/1572">114 Stat. 1572</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe9b69ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s305/1">Pub. L. 105–285, § 305(1)</ref>, substituted “and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.” for “the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s305/2">Pub. L. 105–285, § 305(2)</ref>, substituted “applications” for “application”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s305/5">Pub. L. 105–285, § 305(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s305/3">Pub. L. 105–285, § 305(3)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) relating to optional transfer of funds to block grants for community service programs, preventive health services, etc.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s305/5">Pub. L. 105–285, § 305(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/285">Pub. L. 105–285</ref>, §§ 304(b), 305(4), substituted “subsections (a) through (d)” for “subsections (a) through (f)” and “In determining whether to make such an allotment to a State, the Secretary shall take into account the extent to which the State was affected by the natural disaster or other emergency involved, the availability to the State of other resources under the program carried out under this subchapter or any other program, and such other factors as the Secretary may find to be relevant. Not later than 30 days after making the determination, but prior to releasing an allotted amount to a State, the Secretary shall notify Congress of the allotments made pursuant to this subsection.” for “In determining to which State or States additional funds may be allotted, the Secretary shall take into account the extent to which a State was affected by the emergency or disaster, the availability to an affected State of other resources under this or any other program, and such other factors as the Secretary determines relevant. The Secretary shall notify Congress of the allotment pursuant to this subsection prior to releasing the allotted funds.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s311/c/3">Pub. L. 103–252, § 311(c)(3)</ref>, inserted “of the United States” after “Virgin Islands”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s304/c">Pub. L. 103–252, § 304(c)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/501">Pub. L. 101–501</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1) to (3) as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, substituted “in accordance with paragraph (2) a percentage” for “up to 10 percent”, “or a combination” for “or any combination”, and “subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C)” for “paragraphs (1), (2), and (3)”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s505/b/1">Pub. L. 99–425, § 505(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “after reserving any amount permitted to be reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8628a">section 8628a of this title</ref> and” after “remaining”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s505/b/2">Pub. L. 99–425, § 505(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “after reserving any amount permitted to be reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8628a">section 8628a of this title</ref>” after “therefor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s502/a">Pub. L. 99–425, § 502(a)</ref>, substituted “the capacity” for “and the capacity”, inserted “, and the ability to carry out the program in local communities”, and inserted provisions relating to hourly time periods in which the program must respond, application for benefits, and nonapplicability of the program to areas affected by a natural disaster or major disaster.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s503">Pub. L. 99–425, § 503</ref>, substituted “and residing within the State on the reservation of the tribes or on trust lands adjacent to such reservation” for “in such State with respect to which a determination under this subsection is made”, inserted “, or such greater amount as the Indian tribe and the State may agree upon”, and inserted “In cases where a tribe has no reservation, the Secretary, in consultation with the tribe and the State, shall define the number of Indian households for the determination under this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s604/a">Pub. L. 98–558, § 604(a)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally, substituting provisions relating to State allotment computation for former provisions which also related to computation of State allotment formulas and adding subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s604/b">Pub. L. 98–558, § 604(b)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s603/a">Pub. L. 98–558, § 603(a)</ref>, inserted “until March 15 of each program year” after “reserved” and inserted “The program for which funds are reserved by this subsection shall be administered by public or nonprofit entities which have experience in administering energy crisis programs under the Low-Income Energy Assistance Act of 1980, or under this subchapter, experience in assisting low-income individuals in the area to be served, and the capacity to undertake a timely and effective energy crisis intervention program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s603/b">Pub. L. 98–558, § 603(b)</ref>, substituted “otherwise be payable” for “otherwise be paid” in provisions following subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s603/c">Pub. L. 98–558, § 603(c)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which related to direct payments to households and State options.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s603/d">Pub. L. 98–558, § 603(d)</ref>, substituted “the funds payable to it” for “its allotment”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe9dd9cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dd9d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/252">Pub. L. 103–252</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-01">Oct. 1, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s314">section 314 of Pub. L. 103–252</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dd9d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/501">Pub. L. 101–501</ref> effective <date date="1990-10-01">Oct. 1, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/s1001/a">section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 101–501</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dd9d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s502/a">section 502(a) of Pub. L. 99–425</ref> effective <date date="1986-12-01">Dec. 1, 1986</date>, and amendment by sections 503 and 505(b) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/425">Pub. L. 99–425</ref> effective <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s1001">section 1001 of Pub. L. 99–425</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dd9d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/558">Pub. L. 98–558</ref> effective <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s609/a">section 609(a) of Pub. L. 98–558</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe9dd9d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rules for Energy Crisis Intervention</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/425/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 99–425, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/973">100 Stat. 973</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/425/tV/s502/b">“Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue rules to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
