<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe9dd9d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624"><num value="8624">§ 8624.</num><heading> Applications and requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dd9d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Form; assurances; public hearings</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dd9d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each State desiring to receive an allotment for any fiscal year under this subchapter shall submit an application to the Secretary. Each such application shall be in such form as the Secretary shall require. Each such application shall contain assurances by the chief executive officer of the State that the State will meet the conditions enumerated in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dd9d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> After the expiration of the first fiscal year for which a State receives funds under this subchapter, no funds shall be allotted to such State for any fiscal year under this subchapter unless such State conducts public hearings with respect to the proposed use and distribution of funds to be provided under this subchapter for such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dd9d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Certifications required for covered activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As part of the annual application required by subsection (a), the chief executive officer of each State shall certify that the State agrees to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> use the funds available under this subchapter to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conduct outreach activities and provide assistance to low income households in meeting their home energy costs, particularly those with the lowest incomes that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy, consistent with paragraph (5);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> intervene in energy crisis situations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide low-cost residential weatherization and other cost-effective energy-related home repair; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> plan, develop, and administer the State’s program under this subchapter including leveraging programs,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">and the State agrees not to use such funds for any purposes other than those specified in this subchapter;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> make payments under this subchapter only with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> households in which 1 or more individuals are receiving—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9dd9e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> assistance under the State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s601">42 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9dd9e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> supplemental security income payments under title XVI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1381">42 U.S.C. 1381</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9dd9e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2011">7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9dd9e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> payments under section 1315, 1521, 1541, or 1542 of title 38, or under section 306 of the Veterans’ and Survivors’ Pension Improvement Act of 1978; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> households with incomes which do not exceed the greater of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9dd9e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an amount equal to 150 percent of the poverty level for such State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbe9dd9e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an amount equal to 60 percent of the State median income;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">except that a State may not exclude a household from eligibility in a fiscal year solely on the basis of household income if such income is less than 110 percent of the poverty level for such State, but the State may give priority to those households with the highest home energy costs or needs in relation to household income;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> conduct outreach activities designed to assure that eligible households, especially households with elderly individuals or disabled individuals, or both, and households with high home energy burdens, are made aware of the assistance available under this subchapter, and any similar energy-related assistance available under subtitle B of title VI (relating to community services block grant program) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">42 U.S.C. 9901</ref> et seq.] or under any other provision of law which carries out programs which were administered under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2701">42 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.] before <date date="1981-08-13">August 13, 1981</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> coordinate its activities under this subchapter with similar and related programs administered by the Federal Government and such State, particularly low-income energy-related programs under subtitle B of title VI (relating to community services block grant program) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">42 U.S.C. 9901</ref> et seq.], under the supplemental security income program, under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s601">42 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.], under title XX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397">42 U.S.C. 1397</ref> et seq.], under the low-income weatherization assistance program under title IV of the Energy Conservation and Production Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6851">42 U.S.C. 6851</ref> et seq.], or under any other provision of law which carries out programs which were administered under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2701">42 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.] before <date date="1981-08-13">August 13, 1981</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> provide, in a timely manner, that the highest level of assistance will be furnished to those households which have the lowest incomes and the highest energy costs or needs in relation to income, taking into account family size, except that the State may not differentiate in implementing this section between the households described in clause (2)(A) and (2)(B) of this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> to the extent it is necessary to designate local administrative agencies in order to carry out the purposes of this subchapter, give special consideration, in the designation of such agencies, to any local public or private nonprofit agency which was receiving Federal funds under any low-income energy assistance program or weatherization program under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2701">42 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.] or any other provision of law on <date date="1981-08-12">August 12, 1981</date>, except that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the State shall, before giving such special consideration, determine that the agency involved meets program and fiscal requirements established by the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if there is no such agency because of any change in the assistance furnished to programs for economically disadvantaged persons, then the State shall give special consideration in the designation of local administrative agencies to any successor agency which is operated in substantially the same manner as the predecessor agency which did receive funds for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the determination is made;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> if the State chooses to pay home energy suppliers directly, establish procedures to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> notify each participating household of the amount of assistance paid on its behalf;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assure that the home energy supplier will charge the eligible household, in the normal billing process, the difference between the actual cost of the home energy and the amount of the payment made by the State under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> assure that the home energy supplier will provide assurances that any agreement entered into with a home energy supplier under this paragraph will contain provisions to assure that no household receiving assistance under this subchapter will be treated adversely because of such assistance under applicable provisions of State law or public regulatory requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> ensure that the provision of vendored payments remains at the option of the State in consultation with local grantees and may be contingent on unregulated vendors taking appropriate measures to alleviate the energy burdens of eligible households, including providing for agreements between suppliers and individuals eligible for benefits under this subchapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003848">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003848"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> that seek to reduce home energy costs, minimize the risks of home energy crisis, and encourage regular payments by individuals receiving financial assistance for home energy costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> provide assurances that (A) the State will not exclude households described in clause (2)(B) of this subsection from receiving home energy assistance benefits under clause (2), and (B) the State will treat owners and renters equitably under the program assisted under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> provide that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the State may use for planning and administering the use of funds under this subchapter an amount not to exceed 10 percent of the funds payable to such State under this subchapter for a fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dd9f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the State will pay from non-Federal sources the remaining costs of planning and administering the program assisted under this subchapter and will not use Federal funds for such remaining costs (except for the costs of the activities described in paragraph (16));</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> provide that such fiscal control and fund accounting procedures will be established as may be necessary to assure the proper disbursal of and accounting for Federal funds paid to the State under this subchapter, including procedures for monitoring the assistance provided under this subchapter, and provide that the State will comply with the provisions of chapter 75 of title 31 (commonly known as the “Single Audit Act”);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> permit and cooperate with Federal investigations undertaken in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8627">section 8627 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> provide for timely and meaningful public participation in the development of the plan described in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> provide an opportunity for a fair administrative hearing to individuals whose claims for assistance under the plan described in subsection (c) are denied or are not acted upon with reasonable promptness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> cooperate with the Secretary with respect to data collecting and reporting under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8629">section 8629 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> beginning in fiscal year 1992, provide, in addition to such services as may be offered by State Departments of Public Welfare at the local level, outreach and intake functions for crisis situations and heating and cooling assistance that is administered by additional State and local governmental entities or community-based organizations (such as community action agencies, area agencies on aging, and not-for-profit neighborhood-based organizations), and in States where such organizations do not administer intake functions as of <date date="1991-09-30">September 30, 1991</date>, preference in awarding grants or contracts for intake services shall be provided to those agencies that administer the low-income weatherization or energy crisis intervention programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dd9fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> use up to 5 percent of such funds, at its option, to provide services that encourage and enable households to reduce their home energy needs and thereby the need for energy assistance, including needs assessments, counseling, and assistance with energy vendors, and report to the Secretary concerning the impact of such activities on the number of households served, the level of direct benefits provided to those households, and the number of households that remain unserved.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary may not prescribe the manner in which the States will comply with the provisions of this subsection. The Secretary shall issue regulations to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in the programs assisted by this subchapter.</continuation>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 18 months after <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, the Secretary shall develop model performance goals and measurements in consultation with State, territorial, tribal, and local grantees, that the States may use to assess the success of the States in achieving the purposes of this subchapter. The model performance goals and measurements shall be made available to States to be incorporated, at the option of the States, into the plans for fiscal year 1997. The Secretary may request data relevant to the development of model performance goals and measurements.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dd9fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State plan; revision; public inspection</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dd9ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> As part of the annual application required in subsection (a), the chief executive officer of each State shall prepare and furnish to the Secretary, in such format as the Secretary may require, a plan which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> describes the eligibility requirements to be used by the State for each type of assistance to be provided under this subchapter, including criteria for designating an emergency under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c">section 8623(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> describes the benefit levels to be used by the State for each type of assistance including assistance to be provided for emergency crisis intervention and for weatherization and other energy-related home repair;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> contains estimates of the amount of funds the State will use for each of the programs under such plan and describes the alternative use of funds reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c">section 8623(c) of this title</ref> in the event any portion of the amount so reserved is not expended for emergencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> describes weatherization and other energy-related home repair the State will provide under subsection (k), including any steps the State will take to address the weatherization and energy-related home repair needs of households that have high home energy burdens, and describes any rules promulgated by the Department of Energy for administration of its Low Income Weatherization Assistance Program which the State, to the extent permitted by the Secretary to increase consistency between federally assisted programs, will follow regarding the use of funds provided under this subchapter by the State for such weatherization and energy-related home repairs and improvements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> describes any steps that will be taken (in addition to those necessary to carry out the assurance contained in paragraph (5) of subsection (b)) to target assistance to households with high home energy burdens;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> describes how the State will carry out assurances in clauses (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), (10), (12), (13), and (15) of subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> states, with respect to the 12-month period specified by the Secretary, the number and income levels of households which apply and the number which are assisted with funds provided under this subchapter, and the number of households so assisted with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dda07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> one or more members who had attained 60 years of age;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dda08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> one or more members who were disabled; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbe9dda09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> one or more young children; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> contains any other information determined by the Secretary to be appropriate for purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The chief executive officer may revise any plan prepared under this paragraph and shall furnish the revised plan to the Secretary.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each plan prepared under paragraph (1) and each substantial revision thereof shall be made available for public inspection within the State involved in such a manner as will facilitate timely and meaningful review of, and comment upon, such plan or substantial revision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not later than April 1 of each fiscal year the Secretary shall make available to the States a model State plan format that may be used, at the option of each State, to prepare the plan required under paragraph (1) for the next fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Expending of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State shall expend funds in accordance with the State plan under this subchapter or in accordance with revisions applicable to such plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Conduct of audits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State shall, in carrying out the requirements of subsection (b)(10), obtain financial and compliance audits of any funds which the State receives under this subchapter. Such audits shall be made public within the State on a timely basis. The audits shall be conducted in accordance with chapter 75 of title 31.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments or assistance not to be deemed income or resources for any purpose under Federal or State law; determination of excess shelter expense deduction</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law unless enacted in express limitation of this paragraph, the amount of any home energy assistance payments or allowances provided directly to, or indirectly for the benefit of, an eligible household under this subchapter shall not be considered income or resources of such household (or any member thereof) for any purpose under any Federal or State law, including any law relating to taxation, supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits, public assistance, or welfare programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection and for purposes of determining any excess shelter expense deduction under section 5(e) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2014/e">7 U.S.C. 2014(e)</ref>)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the full amount of such payments or allowances shall be deemed to be expended by such household for heating or cooling expenses, without regard to whether such payments or allowances are provided directly to, or indirectly for the benefit of, such household, except that, for purposes of the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2011">7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.), such payments or allowances were greater than $20 annually, consistent with section 5(e)(6)(C)(iv)(I) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2014/e/6/C/iv/I">7 U.S.C. 2014(e)(6)(C)(iv)(I)</ref>), as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> no distinction may be made among households on the basis of whether such payments or allowances are provided directly to, or indirectly for the benefit of, any of such households.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Repayment of funds expended improperly; offset</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State shall repay to the United States amounts found not to have been expended in accordance with this subchapter or the Secretary may offset such amounts against any other amount to which the State is or may become entitled under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodic evaluation of expenditures by Comptroller General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Comptroller General of the United States shall, from time to time <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003849">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003849"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> evaluate the expenditures by States of grants under this subchapter in order to assure that expenditures are consistent with the provisions of this subchapter and to determine the effectiveness of the State in accomplishing the purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain recipients of supplemental security income ineligible for payments or assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A household which is described in subsection (b)(2)(A) solely by reason of clause (ii) thereof shall not be treated as a household described in subsection (b)(2) if the eligibility of the household is dependent upon—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an individual whose annual supplemental security income benefit rate is reduced pursuant to section 1611(e)(1) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382/e/1">42 U.S.C. 1382(e)(1)</ref>] by reason of being in an institution receiving payments under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] with respect to such individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an individual to whom the reduction specified in section 1612(a)(2)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382a/a/2/A/i">42 U.S.C. 1382a(a)(2)(A)(i)</ref>] applies; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a child described in section 1614(f)(2) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382c/f/2">42 U.S.C. 1382c(f)(2)</ref>] who is living together with a parent, or the spouse of a parent, of the child.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> State verification of income eligibility; policies and procedures applicable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In verifying income eligibility for purposes of subsection (b)(2)(B), the State may apply procedures and policies consistent with procedures and policies used by the State agency administering programs under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s601">42 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.], under title XX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397">42 U.S.C. 1397</ref> et seq.], under subtitle B of title VI of this Act (relating to community services block grant program) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">42 U.S.C. 9901</ref> et seq.], under any other provision of law which carries out programs which were administered under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2701">42 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.] before <date date="1981-08-13">August 13, 1981</date>, or under other income assistance or service programs (as determined by the State).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds; waiver</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), not more than 15 percent of the greater of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda1d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the funds allotted to a State under this subchapter for any fiscal year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda1e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the funds available to such State under this subchapter for such fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may be used by the State for low-cost residential weatherization or other energy-related home repair for low-income households, particularly those low-income households with the lowest incomes that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda1f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda20-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If a State receives a waiver granted under subparagraph (B) for a fiscal year, the State may use not more than the greater of 25 percent of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the funds allotted to a State under this subchapter for such fiscal year; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the funds available to such State under this subchapter for such fiscal year;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for residential weatherization or other energy-related home repair for low-income households, particularly those low-income households with the lowest incomes that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda23-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For purposes of subparagraph (A), the Secretary may grant a waiver to a State for a fiscal year if the State submits a written request to the Secretary after March 31 of such fiscal year and if the Secretary determines, after reviewing such request and any public comments, that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda24-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda25-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the number of households in the State that will receive benefits, other than weatherization and energy-related home repair, under this subchapter in such fiscal year will not be fewer than the number of households in the State that received benefits, other than weatherization and energy-related home repair, under this subchapter in the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the aggregate amounts of benefits that will be received under this subchapter by all households in the State in such fiscal year will not be less than the aggregate amount of such benefits that were received under this subchapter by all households in the State in the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda27-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> such weatherization activities have been demonstrated to produce measurable savings in energy expenditures by low-income households; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbe9dda28-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/k/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in accordance with rules issued by the Secretary, the State demonstrates good cause for failing to satisfy the requirements specified in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> State tax credits to energy suppliers who supply home energy at reduced rates to low-income households</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any State may use amounts provided under this subchapter for the purpose of providing credits against State tax to energy suppliers who supply home energy at reduced rates to low-income households.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any such credit provided by a State shall not exceed the amount of the loss of revenue to such supplier on account of such reduced rate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbe9dda2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8624/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any certification for such tax credits shall be made by the State, but such State may use Federal data available to such State with respect to recipients of supplemental security income benefits if timely delivery of benefits to households described in subsection (b) and suppliers will not be impeded by the use of such data.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe9dda2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVI/s2605">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVI, § 2605</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/896">95 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/tVI/s605">Pub. L. 98–558, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2891">98 Stat. 2891</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/tV/s504">Pub. L. 99–425, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/974">100 Stat. 974</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/tVII">Pub. L. 101–501, title VII</ref>, §§ 704, 705, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1259">104 Stat. 1259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/2">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/406">105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/tIII">Pub. L. 103–252, title III</ref>, §§ 305–309, 311(a)(1), (b), (c)(4), (5), <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/659-662">108 Stat. 659–662</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1072/c">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1072(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/721">109 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tI/s110/p">Pub. L. 104–193, title I, § 110(p)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2175">110 Stat. 2175</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 105–285, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2758">112 Stat. 2758</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tIV/s4002/b/1/B">Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (E), (2)(EE), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1096">122 Stat. 1096</ref>, 1097; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(B), (E), (2)(EE), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1859; <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/tIV/s4006/b">Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4006(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/787">128 Stat. 787</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe9dda2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe9dda2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe9dda30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2)(A)(i), (ii), (4), (i)(1), and (j), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Part A of title IV of the Social Security Act is classified generally to part A (§ 601 et seq.) of subchapter IV of chapter 7 of this title. Titles XVI, XIX, and XX of the Social Security Act are classified generally to subchapters XVI (§ 1381 et seq.), XIX (§ 1396 et seq.), and XX (§ 1397 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title, respectively. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2)(A)(iii) and (f)(2)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/525">Pub. L. 88–525</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/703">78 Stat. 703</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 51 (§ 2011 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2011">section 2011 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 306 of the Veterans’ and Survivors’ Pension Improvement Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(A)(iv), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/588/s306">section 306 of Pub. L. 95–588</ref>, title III, <date date="1978-11-04">Nov. 4, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2508">92 Stat. 2508</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s521">section 521 of Title 38</ref>, Veterans’ Benefits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subtitle B of title VI, referred to in subsecs. (b)(3), (4) and (j), is subtitle B of title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s671">Pub. L. 97–35, § 671</ref> et seq., <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/511">95 Stat. 511</ref>, known as the Community Services Block Grant Act, which is classified generally to chapter 106 (§ 9901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9901">section 9901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, referred to in subsecs. (b)(3), (4), (6) and (j), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/452">Pub. L. 88–452</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/508">78 Stat. 508</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 34 (§ 2701 et seq.) of this title prior to repeal, except for titles VIII and X, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s683/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 683(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/519">95 Stat. 519</ref>. Titles VIII and X of the Act are classified generally to subchapters VIII (§ 2991 et seq.) and X (§ 2996 et seq.) of chapter 34 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Energy Conservation and Production Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/385">Pub. L. 94–385</ref>, <date date="1976-08-14">Aug. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1142">90 Stat. 1142</ref>. Title IV of the Energy Conservation and Production Act is classified principally to subchapter III (§ 6851 et seq.) of chapter 81 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6801">section 6801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(7)(D), was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title XXVI of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, known as the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbe9dda31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b)(6), “<date date="1981-08-12">August 12, 1981</date>” substituted for “the day before the date of the enactment of this Act”, which date of enactment is <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbe9dda32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (f)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/79">Pub. L. 113–79</ref> inserted before semicolon “, except that, for purposes of the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2011">7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.), such payments or allowances were greater than $20 annually, consistent with section 5(e)(6)(C)(iv)(I) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2014/e/6/C/iv/I">7 U.S.C. 2014(e)(6)(C)(iv)(I)</ref>), as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(2)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4002/b/1/B">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4002(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (E), (2)(EE), substituted “supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits” for “food stamps” and “Food and Nutrition Act of 2008” for “Food Stamp Act of 1977”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4002/b/1/E">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4002(b)(1)(E)</ref>, (2)(EE), substituted “supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits” for “food stamps”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4002/b/1/B">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4002(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(EE), substituted “Food and Nutrition Act of 2008” for “Food Stamp Act of 1977” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s306/1/C">Pub. L. 105–285, § 306(1)(C)</ref>, (D), struck out “The Secretary may not prescribe the manner in which the States will comply with the provisions of this subsection.” in provisions after par. (14) and inserted identical language before “The Secretary shall issue” in concluding provisions after par. (16).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s306/1/A">Pub. L. 105–285, § 306(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “and not transferred pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8623/f">section 8623(f) of this title</ref> for use under another block grant” before the semicolon.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s306/1/B">Pub. L. 105–285, § 306(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s306/2/A">Pub. L. 105–285, § 306(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “State” for “States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(G)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s306/2/B">Pub. L. 105–285, § 306(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “had” for “has”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/s306/3">Pub. L. 105–285, § 306(3)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, particularly those low-income households with the lowest incomes that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(2)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> amended cl. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (i) read as follows: “aid to families with dependent children under the State’s plan approved under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (other than such aid in the form of foster care in accordance with section 408 of such Act);”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out “(but not less frequently than every three years),” after “from time to time”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s311/c/4">Pub. L. 103–252, § 311(c)(4)</ref>, transferred the sentence immediately preceding par. (15) to appear as a flush sentence immediately after par. (16).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s311/b">Pub. L. 103–252, § 311(b)</ref>, inserted at end “Not later than 18 months after <date date="1994-05-18">May 18, 1994</date>, the Secretary shall develop model performance goals and measurements in consultation with State, territorial, tribal, and local grantees, that the States may use to assess the success of the States in achieving the purposes of this subchapter. The model performance goals and measurements shall be made available to States to be incorporated, at the option of the States, into the plans for fiscal year 1997. The Secretary may request data relevant to the development of model performance goals and measurements.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s305/a">Pub. L. 103–252, § 305(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “use the funds available under this subchapter for the purposes described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621/a">section 8621(a) of this title</ref> and otherwise in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter, and agrees not to use such funds for any payments other than payments specified in this section;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s306/a">Pub. L. 103–252, § 306(a)</ref>, in concluding provisions substituted “except that a State may not exclude a household from eligibility in a fiscal year solely on the basis of household income if such income is less than 110 percent of the poverty level for such State, but the State may give priority to those households with the highest home energy costs or needs in relation to household income;” for “except that no household may be excluded from eligibility under this subclause for payments under this subchapter for fiscal year 1986 and thereafter if the household has an income which is less than 110 percent of the poverty level for such State for such fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252">Pub. L. 103–252</ref>, §§ 306(b), 311(c)(3), substituted “disabled” for “handicapped” and “and households with high home energy burdens, are made aware” for “are made aware”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s306/c">Pub. L. 103–252, § 306(c)</ref>, inserted “or needs” after “highest energy costs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s311/a/1">Pub. L. 103–252, § 311(a)(1)</ref>, amended subpar. (D) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (D) read as follows: “assure that any home energy supplier receiving direct payments agrees not to discriminate, either in the cost of the goods supplied or the services provided, against the eligible household on whose behalf payments are made;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s305/b/1">Pub. L. 103–252, § 305(b)(1)</ref>, inserted before semicolon at end “(except for the costs of the activities described in paragraph (16))”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s307/1">Pub. L. 103–252, § 307(1)</ref>, substituted “and provide that the State will comply with the provisions of chapter 75 of title 31 (commonly known as the ‘Single Audit Act’)” for “and provide that at least every two years the State shall prepare an audit of its expenditures of amounts received under this subchapter and amounts transferred to carry out the purposes of this subchapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s305/b/2">Pub. L. 103–252, § 305(b)(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (16).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s308">Pub. L. 103–252, § 308</ref>, inserted before semicolon at end “, including any steps the State will take to address the weatherization and energy-related home repair needs of households that have high home energy burdens, and describes any rules promulgated by the Department of Energy for administration of its Low Income Weatherization Assistance Program which the State, to the extent permitted by the Secretary to increase consistency between federally assisted programs, will follow regarding the use of funds provided under this subchapter by the State for such weatherization and energy-related home repairs and improvements”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s306/d/2">Pub. L. 103–252, § 306(d)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (E). Former subpar. (E) redesignated (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252">Pub. L. 103–252</ref>, §§ 306(d)(1), 309(1), redesignated subpar. (E) as (F), substituted “(13), and (15)” for “and (13)”, and struck out “and” at end. Former subpar. (F) redesignated (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s309/2">Pub. L. 103–252, § 309(2)</ref>, added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s306/d/1">Pub. L. 103–252, § 306(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (F) as (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s307/2">Pub. L. 103–252, § 307(2)</ref>, substituted “in accordance with chapter 75 of title 31” for “at least every two years by an organization or person independent of any agency administering activities under this subchapter. The audits shall be conducted in accordance with the Comptroller General’s standards for audit of governmental organizations, programs, activities, and functions. Within 30 days after completion of each audit, the chief executive officer of the State shall submit a copy of the audit to the legislature of the State and to the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b)(2)(A)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref> substituted “section 1315, 1521, 1541, or 1542 of title 38” for “section 415, 521, 541, or 542 of title 38”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/s704/a/1">Pub. L. 101–501, § 704(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “timely and meaningful” after “provide for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/s704/a/2">Pub. L. 101–501, § 704(a)(2)</ref>–(4), added par. (15) at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/s704/b">Pub. L. 101–501, § 704(b)</ref>, inserted “timely and meaningful” after “will facilitate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/s705">Pub. L. 101–501, § 705</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (2), not” for “Not”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s504/a">Pub. L. 99–425, § 504(a)</ref>, substituted “in a timely manner” for “in a manner consistent with the efficient and timely payment of benefits”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(14) to (17). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s504/b">Pub. L. 99–425, § 504(b)</ref>, redesignated cl. (17) as (14), and struck out former cls. (14) to (16) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(14) describe the procedures by which households in the State are identified as eligible to participate under this subchapter and the manner in which the State determines benefit levels;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(15) describe the amount that the State will reserve in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8623/c">section 8623(c) of this title</ref> in each fiscal year for energy crisis intervention activities together with the administrative procedures (A) for designating an emergency, (B) for determining the assistance to be provided in any such emergency, and (C) for the use of funds reserved under such section for the purposes under this subchapter in the event any portion of the amount so reserved is not expended for emergencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(16) describe energy usage and the average cost of home energy in the State, identified by type of fuel and by region of the State;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s504/c">Pub. L. 99–425, § 504(c)</ref>, revised provisions relating to requirements for State plans, restating as subpars. (A) to (F), provisions of former subpars. (A) to (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s504/d">Pub. L. 99–425, § 504(d)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s504/e">Pub. L. 99–425, § 504(e)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “provided directly to, or indirectly for the benefit of” for “provided to”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/9">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(9)</ref>, inserted at end “The Secretary shall issue regulations to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in the programs assisted by this subchapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/1">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “section” for “subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/2">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “except that no household may be excluded from eligibility under this subclause for payments under this subchapter for fiscal year 1986 and thereafter if the household has an income which is less than 110 percent of the poverty level for such State for such fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/3">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “, except that the State may not differentiate in implementing this section between the households described in clause (2)(A) and (2)(B) of this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/4">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “adversely” for “any differently”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/5">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(5)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (B) and added subpar. (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/6">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(6)</ref>, in amending subpar. (A) generally, struck out “in each fiscal year” before “the State may” and substituted “for a fiscal year and not transferred pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8623/f">section 8623(f) of this title</ref> for use under another block grant” for “for such fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/7">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(7)</ref>, substituted “every two years” for “every year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(14) to (17). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/a/8">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(a)(8)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (b) by adding pars. (14) to (17) at the end thereof, was executed by adding those pars. after par. (13) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/b/1">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(b)(1)</ref>, in amending par. (1) generally, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpars. (B) to (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/b/2">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “and each substantial revision thereof” and “or substantial revision” at the end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/c">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(c)</ref>, in amending subsec. (d) generally, substituted provisions that the State shall expend funds in accordance with the State plan or revisions thereto for former provisions which related to waiver of requirements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/d">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(d)</ref>, in amending subsec. (e) generally, inserted provisions requiring that the audits be made public and that they shall be conducted in accordance with the Comptroller General’s standards.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/e">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(e)</ref>, inserted “unless enacted in express limitation of this paragraph”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s605/f">Pub. L. 98–558, § 605(f)</ref>, inserted “(but not less frequently than every three years)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbe9dda33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dda34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/79">Pub. L. 113–79</ref> effective 30 days after <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date> and applicable with respect to certification periods that begin after that date, with State option to delay implementation for current recipients of standard utility allowance, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/s4006/c">section 4006(c) of Pub. L. 113–79</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2014">section 2014 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dda35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 4002(b)(1)(B), (E), (2)(EE) of <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-10-01">Oct. 1, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4407">section 4407 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1161">section 1161 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dda36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> effective <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, with transition rules relating to State options to accelerate such date, rules relating to claims, actions, and proceedings commenced before such date, rules relating to closing out of accounts for terminated or substantially modified programs and continuance in office of Assistant Secretary for Family Support, and provisions relating to termination of entitlement under AFDC program, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s116">section 116 of Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, as amended, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s601">section 601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dda37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/252">Pub. L. 103–252</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-01">Oct. 1, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/252/s314">section 314 of Pub. L. 103–252</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dda38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/501">Pub. L. 101–501</ref> effective <date date="1990-10-01">Oct. 1, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/s1001/a">section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 101–501</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dda39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 504(a)–(d) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/425">Pub. L. 99–425</ref> not applicable with respect to any fiscal year beginning in or before the 60-day period ending on <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, and amendment by section 504(e) effective <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/425/s1001">section 1001 of Pub. L. 99–425</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbe9dda3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/558">Pub. L. 98–558</ref> effective on first day of first fiscal year beginning after <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/558/s609/b">section 609(b) of Pub. L. 98–558</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbe9dda3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Clarification on Utility Allowances</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIX/s927">Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 927</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3885">106 Stat. 3885</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/185/s1">Pub. L. 103–185, § 1</ref>, <date date="1993-12-14">Dec. 14, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2244">107 Stat. 2244</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/185/s1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Tenants who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> are responsible for making out-of-pocket payments for utility bills; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> receive energy assistance through utility allowances that include energy costs under programs identified in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall not have their eligibility or benefits under other programs designed to assist low-income people with increases in energy costs since 1978 reduced or eliminated, except as provided in subsection (d).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Equal Treatment in Benefit Programs</inline>.—</heading><content>Tenants described in subsection (a) shall be treated identically with other households eligible for or receiving energy assistance, including in the determination of the home energy costs for which they are individually responsible and in the determination of their incomes for any program in which eligibility or benefits are based on need, except as provided in subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>This section applies to programs under the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">42 U.S.C. 1437</ref> et seq.], the National Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">12 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], section 101 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701s">12 U.S.C. 1701s</ref>], section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</ref>], and title V of the Housing Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1471">42 U.S.C. 1471</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program, tenants described in subsection (a)(2) who are responsible for paying some or all heating or cooling costs shall not have their eligibility automatically denied. A State may consider the amount of the heating or cooling component of utility allowances received by tenants described in subsection (a)(2) when setting benefit levels under the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program. The size of any reduction in Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program benefits must be reasonably related to the amount of the heating or cooling component of the utility allowance received and must ensure that the highest level of assistance will be furnished to those households with the lowest incomes and the highest energy costs in relation to income, taking into account family size, in compliance with section 2605(b)(5) of the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8624/b/5">42 U.S.C. 8624(b)(5)</ref>).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
