<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbe9dda3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8625"><num value="8625">§ 8625.</num><heading> Nondiscrimination provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8625/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall on the ground of race, color, national origin, or sex be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination under, any program or activity funded in whole or in part with funds made available under this subchapter. Any prohibition against discrimination on the basis of age under the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6101">42 U.S.C. 6101</ref> et seq.] or with respect to an otherwise qualified handicapped individual as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">section 794 of title 29</ref> also shall apply to any such program or activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8625/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures applicable to secure compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary determines that a State that has received a payment under this subchapter has failed to comply with subsection (a) or an applicable regulation, he shall notify the chief executive officer of the State and shall request him to secure compliance. If within a reasonable period of time, not to exceed 60 days, the chief executive officer fails or refuses to secure compliance, the Secretary is authorized to (1) refer the matter to the Attorney General with a recommendation that an appropriate civil action be instituted; (2) exercise the powers and functions provided by title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq.], the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6101">42 U.S.C. 6101</ref> et seq.], or <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">section 794 of title 29</ref>, as may be applicable; or (3) take such other action as may be provided by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbe9dda3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8625/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of civil actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When a matter is referred to the Attorney General pursuant to subsection (b), or whenever he has reason to believe that the State is engaged in a pattern or practice in violation of the provisions of this section, the Attorney General may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court for such relief as may be appropriate, including injunctive relief.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbe9dda40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVI/s2606">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVI, § 2606</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/900">95 Stat. 900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbe9dda41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbe9dda42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbe9dda43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Age Discrimination Act of 1975, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/94/135">Pub. L. 94–135</ref>, <date date="1975-11-28">Nov. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/728">78 Stat. 728</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 76 (§ 6101 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6101">section 6101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Civil Rights Act of 1964, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/352">Pub. L. 88–352</ref>, <date date="1964-07-02">July 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/241">78 Stat. 241</ref>. Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 is classified generally to subchapter V (§ 2000d et seq.) of chapter 21 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000a">section 2000a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
