<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbea294bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814"><num value="8814">§ 8814.</num><heading> Loan guarantees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary concerned</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to sections 8812 and 8817 of this title, the Secretary concerned may commit to guarantee, and guarantee, against loss of principal and interest, loans which are made to provide funds for the construction of biomass energy projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Estimated project construction costs as determinative of initial and revised amount of guarantee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea294bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any guarantee of a loan under this section may not exceed 90 per centum of the cost of the construction of the biomass energy project involved, as estimated by the Secretary on the date of the guarantee or commitment to guarantee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea294c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the event the construction costs of the project are thereafter estimated by the Secretary concerned to exceed the construction costs initially estimated by the Secretary, the Secretary may in addition, upon application therefor, guarantee, against loss of principal and interest, a loan for up to 60 per centum of the difference between the construction costs then estimated and the construction costs initially estimated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Debt obligation; ineligibility for purchase, etc., by Federal Financing Bank or any Federal agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of the Federal Financing Bank Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2281">12 U.S.C. 2281</ref> et seq.) or any other provision of law (except as may be specifically provided by reference to this subsection in any Act enacted after <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>), no debt obligation which is guaranteed or committed to be guaranteed by the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of Energy under this section shall be eligible for purchase by, or commitment to purchase by, or sale or issuance to, the Federal Financing Bank or any Federal agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The terms and conditions of loan guarantees under this section shall provide that, if the Secretary concerned makes a payment of principal or interest upon the default by a borrower, the Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the recipient of such payment (and such subrogation shall be expressly set forth in the loan guarantee or related agreements).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination, cancellation, or revocation, and conclusive nature of guarantee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any loan guarantee under this section shall not be terminated, canceled, or otherwise revoked, except in accordance with the terms thereof and shall be conclusive evidence that such guarantee complies fully with the provisions of this chapter and of the approval and legality of the principal amount, interest rate, and all other terms of the securities, obligations, or loans and of the guarantee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment to lender</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary concerned determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the borrower is unable to meet payments and is not in default,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> it is in the public interest to permit the borrower to continue with such project, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the probable net benefit to the United States in paying the principal and interest due under the loan will be greater than that which would result in the event of a default,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the Secretary may pay to the lender under a loan guarantee agreement an amount not greater than the principal and interest which the borrower is obligated to pay to such lender, if the borrower agrees to reimburse the Secretary for such payment on terms and conditions, including interest, which the Secretary determines are sufficient to protect the financial interests of the United States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Preconditions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea294c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A loan may not be guaranteed under this section unless the applicant for such loan has established to the satisfaction of the Secretary concerned that the lender is not willing without such a guarantee to extend credit to the applicant at reasonable rates and terms, taking into consideration prevailing rates and terms for loans for similar purposes and periods of time, to finance the construction of the biomass energy project for which such loan is sought.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea294ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8814/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary concerned shall ensure that the lender bears a reasonable degree of risk in the financing of such project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbea294cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tII">Pub. L. 96–294, title II</ref> § 214, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/690">94 Stat. 690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbea294cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbea294cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbea294ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Financing Bank Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/224">Pub. L. 93–224</ref>, <date date="1973-12-29">Dec. 29, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/937">87 Stat. 937</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 24 (§ 2281 et seq.) of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2281">section 2281 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (e), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/96/294">Pub. L. 96–294</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/683">94 Stat. 683</ref>, known as the Biomass Energy and Alcohol Fuels Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8801">section 8801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbea294cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbea294d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Defaulted Loans Under Department of Energy Alcohol Fuels Loan Guarantee Program; Sale of Assets; Unobligated Funds</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/121/tII">Pub. L. 101–121, title II</ref>, <date date="1989-10-23">Oct. 23, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/732">103 Stat. 732</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/121/tII">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">31 U.S.C. 3302</ref>, funds derived from the sale of assets as a result of defaulted loans made under the Department of Energy Alcohol Fuels Loan Guarantee program, or any other funds received in connection with this program, shall hereafter be credited to the Biomass Energy Development account, and shall be available solely for payment of the guaranteed portion of defaulted loans and associated costs of the Department of Energy Alcohol Fuels Loan Guarantee program for loans guaranteed prior to <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Unobligated balances available in the ‘Alternative fuels production’ account may hereafter be used for payment of the guaranteed portion of defaulted loans and associated costs of the Department of Energy Alcohol Fuels Loan Guarantee program, subject to the determination by the Secretary of Energy that such unobligated funds are not needed for carrying out the purposes of the Alternative Fuels Production program: <i>Provided</i>, That the use of these unobligated funds for payment of defaulted loans and associated costs shall be available only for loans guaranteed prior to <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>: <i>Provided further</i>, That such funds shall be used only after the unobligated balance in the Department of Energy Alcohol Fuel Loan Guarantee reserve has been exhausted.”</p>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
