<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbea294de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816"><num value="8816">§ 8816.</num><heading> Purchase agreements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary concerned; consultative requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to sections 8812 and 8817 of this title, the Secretary concerned may commit to make, and make, purchase agreements for all or part of the biomass energy production of any biomass energy project, if the Secretary determines—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that such biomass energy is of a type, quantity, and quality that can be used by Federal agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that the quantity of such biomass energy, if delivery is accepted, would not exceed the likely needs of Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each Secretary concerned shall consult with the other Secretary before making any determination under paragraph (2).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum sales price</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The sales price specified in a purchase agreement under this section may not exceed the estimated prevailing market price as of the date of delivery, as determined by the Secretary of Energy, unless the Secretary concerned determines that such sales price must exceed the estimated prevailing market price in order to ensure the production of biomass energy to achieve the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Assurances required</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary concerned in entering into, or committing to enter into, a purchase agreement under this section shall require—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assurances that the quality of the biomass energy purchased will meet standards for the use for which such energy is purchased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assurances that the ordered quantities of such energy will be delivered on a timely basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea294e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> such other assurances as may reasonably be required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Arrangements for delivery pursuant to agreement; charge to Federal agency receiving delivery</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary concerned may take delivery of biomass energy pursuant to a purchase agreement under this section if appropriate arrangements have been made for its distribution to and use by one or more Federal agencies. Any Federal agency receiving such energy shall be charged (in accordance with otherwise applicable law), from sums appropriated to such Federal agency, for the prevailing market price as of the date of delivery, as determined by the Secretary of Energy, for the product which the biomass energy is replacing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultative requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary concerned shall consult with the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of the General Services Administration in carrying out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each purchase agreement, and commitment to enter into a purchase agreement, under this section shall provide that the Secretary concerned retains the right to refuse delivery of the biomass energy involved upon such terms and conditions as shall be specified in the purchase agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum dollar amount of liability of United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each purchase agreement, or commitment to enter into a purchase agreement, which is made under this section shall specify the maximum dollar amount of liability of the United States under that agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea294eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Renegotiation of sales price and maximum liability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary concerned determines, in the discretion of the Secretary, that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea505ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a biomass energy project would not otherwise be satisfactorily completed or continued, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea505ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8816/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> completion or continuation of such project would be necessary to achieve the purposes of this chapter,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the sales price set forth in the purchase agreement, and maximum liability under such agreement, may be renegotiated.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbea505ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tII/s216">Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/692">94 Stat. 692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbea505ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbea505f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbea505f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b) and (h)(2), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/96/294">Pub. L. 96–294</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/683">94 Stat. 683</ref>, known as the Biomass Energy and Alcohol Fuels Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8801">section 8801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
