<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbea505f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817"><num value="8817">§ 8817.</num><heading> General requirements regarding financial assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea505f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Priorities, terms, availability, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea505f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Priority for financial assistance under this subchapter, and the most favorable financial terms available, shall be provided to a person for any biomass energy project that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea505f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> uses a primary fuel other than petroleum or natural gas in the production of biomass fuel, such as geothermal energy resources, solar energy resources, or waste heat; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea505f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> applies new technologies which expand the possible feedstocks, produces new forms of biomass energy, or produces biomass fuel using improved or new technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to exclude financial assistance for any project which does not use such a fuel or apply such a technology.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea505f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea505f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Financial assistance under this subchapter shall be available for a biomass energy project only if the Secretary concerned finds that the Btu content of the motor fuels to be used in the facility involved to produce the biomass fuel will not exceed the Btu content of the biomass fuel produced in the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea505f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In making the determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall take into account any displacement of motor fuel or other petroleum products which the applicant has demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Secretary would result from the use of the biomass fuel produced in the facility involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea505fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No financial assistance may be provided under this subchapter to any person for any biomass energy project if the Secretary concerned finds that the process to be used by the project will not extract the protein content of the feedstock for utilization as food or feed for readily available markets in any case in which to do so would be technically and economically practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea505fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Financial assistance may not be provided under this subchapter to any person unless the Secretary concerned—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea505fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> finds that necessary feedstocks are available and it is reasonable to expect they will continue to be available in the future, and, for biomass energy projects using wood or wood wastes or residues from the National Forest System, there shall be taken into account current levels of use by then existing facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea505fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has obtained assurance that the person receiving such financial assistance will bear a reasonable degree of risk in the construction and operation of the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea505fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has determined that the amount of financial assistance provided for the project is not greater than is necessary to achieve the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea505ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In providing financial assistance under this subchapter, the Secretary concerned shall give due consideration to promoting competition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea50600-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> In determining the amount of financial assistance for any biomass energy project which will yield byproducts in addition to biomass energy, the Secretary shall consider the potential value of such byproducts and the costs attributable to their production.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea50601-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms, conditions, maturity, etc., for insured loans, and loan guarantees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An insured loan may not be made, and a loan guarantee may not be issued, under this subchapter unless the Secretary concerned determines that the terms, conditions, maturity, security, and schedule and amounts of repayments with respect to such loan are reasonable and meet such standards as the Secretary determines are sufficient to protect the financial interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea50602-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea50603-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> No financial assistance may be provided to any person under this subchapter unless an application therefor—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea50604-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has been submitted to the Secretary concerned by that person in such form and under such procedures as the Secretary shall prescribe, consistent with the requirements of this subchapter, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea50605-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has been approved by the Secretary in accordance with such procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea50606-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Each such application shall include information regarding the construction costs of the biomass energy project involved, and estimates of operating costs and income relating to that project (including the sale of any byproducts from that project). In addition, each applicant shall provide—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea50607-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> access at reasonable times to such other information, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea50608-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such assurances,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">as the Secretary concerned may require.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea50609-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports and recordkeeping</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea5060a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Every recipient of financial assistance under this subchapter shall, as a condition precedent thereto, consent to such examinations and reports regarding the biomass energy project involved as the Secretary concerned may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea5060b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> With respect to each biomass energy project for which financial assistance is provided under this subchapter, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea5060c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> require from the recipient of financial assistance such reports and records relating to that project as the Secretary deems necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea5060d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> prescribe the manner in which such recipient shall keep such records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea5060e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> have access to such records at reasonable times for the purpose of ensuring compliance with the terms and conditions upon which financial assistance is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea5060f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts and instruments of Secretary concerned backed by full faith and credit of United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All contracts and instruments of the Secretary concerned to provide, or providing, for financial assistance shall be general obligations of the United States backed by its full faith and credit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea50610-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Contestability of contracts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the conditions of any contract for financial assistance, such contract shall be incontestable in the hands of the holder, except as to fraud or material misrepresentation on the part of the holder.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea50611-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Fees for loan guarantees, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea50612-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A fee or fees may be charged and collected by the Secretary concerned for any loan guarantee, price guarantee, or purchase agreement provided under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea50613-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount of such fee shall be based on the estimated administrative costs and risk of loss, except that such fee may not exceed 1 per centum of the amount of the financial assistance provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbea50614-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8817/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposit of amounts received by Secretary concerned</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All amounts received by the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of Energy as fees, interest, repayment of principal, and any other moneys received by either Secretary from activities under this subchapter shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts. The preceding sentence shall not apply to insured loans made under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8813">section 8813 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbea50615-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/294/tII/s217">Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 217</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/693">94 Stat. 693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbea50616-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbea50617-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbea50618-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(4)(C), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/96/294">Pub. L. 96–294</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/683">94 Stat. 683</ref>, known as the Biomass Energy and Alcohol Fuels Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8801">section 8801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
