<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbea9c03b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8906"><num value="8906">§ 8906.</num><heading> Updated data base on acid content in precipitation; new monitoring site not required</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea9c03c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8906/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea9c03d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8906/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The National Weather Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall maintain an updated data base describing the acid content in precipitation in the United States, using information from Federal acid precipitation monitoring sites.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea9c03e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8906/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such data shall be available to interested parties by Weather Service Forecast Offices in the National Weather Service, or through such other facilities or means as the Assistant Administrator for Weather Services, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall direct, for those areas of the United States where and at such time as such information is presently available, within 120 days after <date date="1988-11-17">November 17, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea9c03f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8906/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Where other Federal agencies collect such data in the course of carrying out their statutory missions, the heads of those agencies and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall arrange for the transfer of such data to the National Weather Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbea9c040-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s8906/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any Federal agency to establish any new acid precipitation monitoring site.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbea9c041-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/685/tIV/s414">Pub. L. 100–685, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="1988-11-17">Nov. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4101">102 Stat. 4101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbea9c042-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbea9c043-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbea9c044-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1989, and not as part of the Acid Precipitation Act of 1980 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
