<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb800e3ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902"><num value="902">§ 902.</num><heading> Commissioner; Deputy Commissioner; other officers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e3ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Commissioner of Social Security</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There shall be in the Administration a Commissioner of Social Security (in this subchapter referred to as the “Commissioner”) who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commissioner shall be compensated at the rate provided for level I of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Commissioner shall be appointed for a term of 6 years, except that the initial term of office for Commissioner shall terminate <date date="2001-01-19">January 19, 2001</date>. In any case in which a successor does not take office at the end of a Commissioner’s term of office, such Commissioner may continue in office until the entry upon office of such a successor. A Commissioner appointed to a term of office after the commencement of such term may serve under such appointment only for the remainder of such term. An individual serving in the office of Commissioner may be removed from office only pursuant to a finding by the President of neglect of duty or malfeasance in office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Commissioner shall be responsible for the exercise of all powers and the discharge of all duties of the Administration, and shall have authority and control over all personnel and activities thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Commissioner may prescribe such rules and regulations as the Commissioner determines necessary or appropriate to carry out the functions of the Administration. The regulations prescribed by the Commissioner shall be subject to the rulemaking procedures established under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Commissioner may establish, alter, consolidate, or discontinue such organizational units or components within the Administration as the Commissioner considers necessary or appropriate, except that this paragraph shall not apply with respect to any unit, component, or provision provided for by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The Commissioner may assign duties, and delegate, or authorize successive redelegations of, authority to act and to render decisions, to such officers and employees of the Administration as the Commissioner may find necessary. Within the limitations of such delegations, redelegations, or assignments, all official acts and decisions of such officers and employees shall have the same force and effect as though performed or rendered by the Commissioner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> The Commissioner and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall consult, on an ongoing basis, to ensure—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e3b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the coordination of the programs administered by the Commissioner, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>, with the programs administered by the Secretary under subchapters XVIII and XIX of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e3b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that adequate information concerning benefits under such subchapters XVIII and XIX is available to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e3b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Deputy Commissioner of Social Security</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There shall be in the Administration a Deputy Commissioner of Social Security (in this subchapter referred to as the “Deputy Commissioner”) who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Deputy Commissioner shall be appointed for a term of 6 years, except that the initial term of office for the Deputy Commissioner shall terminate <date date="2001-01-19">January 19, 2001</date>. In any case in which a successor does not take office at the end of a Deputy Commissioner’s term of office, such Deputy Commissioner may continue in office until the entry upon office of such a successor. A Deputy Commissioner appointed to a term of office after the commencement of such term may serve under such appointment only for the remainder of such term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Deputy Commissioner shall be compensated at the rate provided for level II of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Deputy Commissioner shall perform such duties and exercise such powers as the Commissioner shall from time to time assign or delegate. The Deputy Commissioner shall be Acting Commissioner of the Administration during the absence or disability of the Commissioner and, unless the President designates another officer of the Government as Acting Commissioner, in the event of a vacancy in the office of the Commissioner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e3be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Chief Actuary</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There shall be in the Administration a Chief Actuary, who shall be appointed by, and in direct line of authority to, the Commissioner. The Chief Actuary shall be appointed from individuals who have demonstrated, by their education and experience, superior expertise in the actuarial sciences. The Chief Actuary shall serve as the chief actuarial officer of the Administration, and shall exercise such duties as are appropriate for the office of the Chief Actuary and in accordance with professional standards of actuarial independence. The Chief Actuary may be removed only for cause.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e3c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Chief Actuary shall be compensated at the highest rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5382/b">section 5382(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e3c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Chief Financial Officer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be in the Administration a Chief Financial Officer appointed by the Commissioner in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s901/a/2">section 901(a)(2) of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e3c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s902/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspector General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be in the Administration an Inspector General appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s403/a">section 403(a) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb800e3c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title VII, § 702, <ref href="/us/stat/49/636">49 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-08-28/ch809">Aug. 28, 1950, ch. 809</ref>, title III, pt. 6, § 361(c), (d), <ref href="/us/stat/64/558">64 Stat. 558</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/j/2/C/i">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(j)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, (<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1170">98 Stat. 1170</ref>, 1171; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s102">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1465">108 Stat. 1465</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/121/tI/s103/e/1">Pub. L. 104–121, title I, § 103(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-03-29">Mar. 29, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/851">110 Stat. 851</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/b/76">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(76)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4351">136 Stat. 4351</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb800e3c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb800e3c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb800e3c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Levels I and II of the Executive Schedule, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (b)(3), are set out in sections 5312 and 5313, respectively, of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb800e3c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s403/a">section 403(a) of title 5</ref>.” for “section 3(a) of the Inspector General Act of 1978.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/121">Pub. L. 104–121</ref> added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsecs. (c) and (d) as (d) and (e), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “The Secretary shall perform the duties imposed upon him by this chapter and shall also have the duty of studying and making recommendations as to the most effective methods of providing economic security through social insurance, and as to legislation and matters of administrative policy concerning old-age pensions, unemployment compensation, accident compensation, and related subjects.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/j/2/C/i">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(j)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare”, could not be executed because “Health, Education, and Welfare” did not appear in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-08-28">Aug. 28, 1950</date>, substituted “Administrator” for “Board” and “him” for “it”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb800e3c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb800e3c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/121/tI/s103/e/2">Pub. L. 104–121, title I, § 103(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-03-29">Mar. 29, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/851">110 Stat. 851</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/121/tI/s103/e/2">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-03-29">Mar. 29, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb800e3ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb800e3cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Issuance by Commissioner of Social Security of Receipts To Acknowledge Submission of Reports of Changes in Work or Earnings Status of Disabled Beneficiaries</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/203/tII/s202">Pub. L. 108–203, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2004-03-02">Mar. 2, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/509">118 Stat. 509</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/203/tII/s202">“Effective as soon as possible, but not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-03-02">Mar. 2, 2004</date>], until such time as the Commissioner of Social Security implements a centralized computer file recording the date of the submission of information by a disabled beneficiary (or representative) regarding a change in the beneficiary’s work or earnings status, the Commissioner shall issue a receipt to the disabled beneficiary (or representative) each time he or she submits documentation, or otherwise reports to the Commissioner, on a change in such status.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Demonstration Projects Relating to Accountability for Telephone Service Center Communications</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5108">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5108</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-269">104 Stat. 1388–269</ref>, directed Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and carry out demonstration projects designed to implement certain accountability procedures in not fewer than 3 telephone service centers operated by the Social Security Administration, provided that such projects commence not later than 180 days after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, and remain in operation for not less than 1 year and not more than 3 years, and directed Secretary to submit to Congress a written report on the progress of the demonstration projects not later than 90 days after the termination of the project.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Telephone Access to Social Security Administration</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 103–296, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1518">108 Stat. 1518</ref>, directed Comptroller General of the United States to submit to Congress, not later than <date date="1996-01-31">Jan. 31, 1996</date>, report and study of telephone access to local offices of the Social Security Administration, based on independent assessment of Social Security Administration’s use of innovative technology (including attendant call and voice mail) to increase public telephone access to local offices of the Administration.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5110">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5110</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-272">104 Stat. 1388–272</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5110">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Minimum Level of Access to Local Offices</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition to such other access by telephone to offices of the Social Security Administration as the Secretary of Health and Human Services may consider appropriate, the Secretary shall maintain access by telephone to local offices of the Social Security Administration at the level of access generally available as of <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Telephone Listings</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall make such requests of local telephone utilities in the United States as are necessary to ensure that the listings subsequently maintained and published by such utilities for each locality include the address and telephone number for each local office of the Social Security Administration to which direct telephone access is maintained under subsection (a) in such locality. Such listing may also include information concerning the availability of a toll-free number which may be called for general information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report by Secretary</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> assesses the impact of the requirements established by this section on the Social Security Administration’s allocation of resources, workload levels, and service to the public, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> presents a plan for using new, innovative technologies to enhance access to the Social Security Administration, including access to local offices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">GAO Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall review the level of telephone access by the public to the local offices of the Social Security Administration. The Comptroller General shall file an interim report with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate describing such level of telephone access not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>] and shall file a final report with such Committees describing such level of access not later than 210 days after such date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall meet the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) as soon as possible after the date of the enactment of this Act but not later [than] 180 days after such date.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report Regarding Notices in Languages Other Than English</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tX/s10306/b">Pub. L. 101–239, title X, § 10306(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2484">103 Stat. 2484</ref>, directed Secretary of Health and Human Resources, not later than <date date="1991-01-01">Jan. 1, 1991</date>, to submit a report to Congress relating to procedures of Social Security Administration for issuing notices in languages other than English.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study Concerning Establishment of Social Security Administration as an Independent Agency</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/21/tIII/s338">Pub. L. 98–21, title III, § 338</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/132">97 Stat. 132</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2662/h/1">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2662(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1160">98 Stat. 1160</ref>, established, under authority of Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and Committee on Finance of the Senate, a Joint Study Panel on the Social Security Administration to undertake a study of removing Social Security Administration from Department of Health and Human Services and establishing it as an independent agency in the executive branch with its own independent administrative structure, including possibility of such a structure headed by a board appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and to submit, not later than <date date="1984-04-01">Apr. 1, 1984</date>, a report of the findings of the study, and provided that the Panel would expire 30 days after the date of the submission of the report.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Earnings Sharing Implementation Report</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/21/tIII/s343">Pub. L. 98–21, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/136">97 Stat. 136</ref>, directed Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop, in consultation with Committee on Finance of the Senate and Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, proposals for earnings sharing legislation (i.e., proposals that combined earnings of a husband and wife during period of their marriage be divided equally and shared between them for social security benefit purposes) and report such proposals to such committees not later than <date date="1984-07-01">July 1, 1984</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Universal Coverage of Social Security Programs; Study and Report to President and Congress Respecting Scope, Alternatives, etc.; Consultation by Secretary</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/216/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 95–216, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1531">91 Stat. 1531</ref>, as amended by 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>, directed Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare to undertake as soon as possible after <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, a thorough study with respect to extent of coverage under old-age, survivors, and disability insurance programs and under programs established by subchapter XVIII of this chapter and submit a report on findings of such study not later than 2 years after <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb800e3d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Proposals for Elimination of Dependency and Sex Discrimination Under Social Security Program; Study and Report to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/216/tIII/s341">Pub. L. 95–216, title III, § 341</ref>, <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1548">91 Stat. 1548</ref>, directed Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, in consultation with the Task Force on Sex Discrimination, to make a detailed study of proposals to eliminate dependency as a factor in the determination of entitlement to spouse’s benefits under the program established under subchapter II of this chapter and of proposals to bring about equal treatment for men and women in any and all respects under such program and submit a report to Congress within 6 months of <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
