<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb800e404-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904"><num value="904">§ 904.</num><heading> Administrative duties of Commissioner</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e405-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e406-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commissioner shall appoint such additional officers and employees as the Commissioner considers necessary to carry out the functions of the Administration under this chapter, and attorneys and experts may be appointed without regard to the civil service laws. Except as otherwise provided in the preceding sentence or in any other provision of law, such officers and employees shall be appointed, and their compensation shall be fixed, in accordance with title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e407-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commissioner may procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e408-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding any requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3133">section 3133 of title 5</ref>, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall authorize for the Administration a total number of Senior Executive Service positions which is substantially greater than the number of such positions authorized in the Social Security Administration in the Department of Health and Human Services as of immediately before <date date="1994-08-15">August 15, 1994</date>, to the extent that the greater number of such authorized positions is specified in the comprehensive work force plan as established and revised by the Commissioner under subsection (b)(2). The total number of such positions authorized for the Administration shall not at any time be less than the number of such authorized positions as of immediately before such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e409-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Budgetary matters</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e40a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e40b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Commissioner shall prepare an annual budget for the Administration, which shall be submitted by the President to the Congress without revision, together with the President’s annual budget for the Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e40c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Commissioner shall include in the annual budget prepared pursuant to subparagraph (A) an itemization of the amount of funds required by the Social Security Administration for the fiscal year covered by the budget to support efforts to combat fraud committed by applicants and beneficiaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e40d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e40e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Appropriations requests for staffing and personnel of the Administration shall be based upon a comprehensive work force plan, which shall be established and revised from time to time by the Commissioner.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e40f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Appropriations for administrative expenses of the Administration are authorized to be provided on a biennial basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e410-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For each fiscal year beginning with 2016 and ending with 2021, the Commissioner shall include in the annual budget prepared pursuant to subparagraph (A) a report describing the purposes for which amounts made available for purposes described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s901/b/2/B">section 901(b)(2)(B) of title 2</ref> for the fiscal year were expended by the Social Security Administration and the purposes for which the Commissioner plans for the Administration to expend such funds in the succeeding fiscal year, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e411-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the total such amount expended;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e412-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount expended on co-operative disability investigation units;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e413-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the number of cases of fraud prevented by co-operative disability investigation units and the amount expended on such cases (as reported to the Commissioner by the Inspector General of the Social Security Administration);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e414-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the number of felony cases prosecuted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s408">section 408 of this title</ref> (as reported to the Commissioner by the Inspector General) and the amount expended by the Social Security Administration in supporting the prosecution of such cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e415-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the amount of such felony cases successfully prosecuted (as reported to the Commissioner by the Inspector General) and the amount expended by the Social Security Administration in supporting the prosecution of such cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e416-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> the amount expended on and the number of completed—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb800e417-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> continuing disability reviews conducted by mail;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb800e418-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> redeterminations conducted by mail;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb800e419-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> medical continuing disability reviews conducted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s421/i">section 421(i) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb800e41a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> medical continuing disability reviews conducted pursuant to 1382c(a)(3)(H) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002655">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002655"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”.</note> of this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb800e41b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/F/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> redeterminations conducted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382/c">section 1382(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb800e41c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/F/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> work-related continuing disability reviews to determine whether earnings derived from services demonstrate an individual’s ability to engage in substantial gainful activity;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e41d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the number of cases of fraud identified for which benefits were terminated as a result of medical continuing disability reviews (as reported to the Commissioner by the Inspector General), work-related continuing disability reviews, and redeterminations, and the amount of resulting savings for each such type of review or redetermination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e41e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/b/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> the number of work-related continuing disability reviews in which a beneficiary improperly reported earnings derived from services for more than 3 consecutive months, and the amount of resulting savings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e41f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment restriction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The total number of positions in the Administration (other than positions established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>) which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e420-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> are held by noncareer appointees (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3132/a/7">section 3132(a)(7) of title 5</ref>) in the Senior Executive Service, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e421-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> have been determined by the President or the Office of Personnel Management to be of a confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character and have been excepted from the competitive service thereby,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may not exceed at any time the equivalent of 20 full-time positions.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e422-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Seal of office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner shall cause a seal of office to be made for the Administration of such design as the Commissioner shall approve. Judicial notice shall be taken of such seal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb800e423-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Data exchanges</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb800e424-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including subsections (b), (<i>o</i>), (p), (q), (r), and (u) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of title 5</ref>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb800e425-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary shall disclose to the Commissioner any record or information requested in writing by the Commissioner for the purpose of administering any program administered by the Commissioner, if records or information of such type were disclosed to the Commissioner of Social Security in the Department of Health and Human Services under applicable rules, regulations, and procedures in effect before <date date="1994-08-15">August 15, 1994</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Commissioner shall disclose to the Secretary or to any State any record or information requested in writing by the Secretary to be so disclosed for the purpose of administering any program administered by the Secretary, if records or information of such type were so disclosed under applicable rules, regulations, and procedures in effect before <date date="1994-08-15">August 15, 1994</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commissioner and the Secretary shall enter into an agreement under which the Commissioner provides the Secretary data concerning the quality of the services and information provided to beneficiaries of the programs under subchapters XVIII and XIX and the administrative services provided by the Social Security Administration in support of such programs. Such agreement shall stipulate the type of data to be provided and the terms and conditions under which the data are to be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Commissioner and the Secretary shall periodically review the need for exchanges of information not referred to in paragraph (1) or (2) and shall enter into such agreements as may be necessary and appropriate to provide information to each other or to States in order to meet the programmatic needs of the requesting agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any disclosure from a system of records (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a/a/5">section 552a(a)(5) of title 5</ref>) pursuant to this subsection shall be made as a routine use under subsection (b)(3) of section 552a of such title (unless otherwise authorized under such section 552a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any computerized comparison of records, including matching programs, between the Commissioner and the Secretary shall be conducted in accordance with subsections (<i>o</i>), (p), (q), (r), and (u) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Commissioner and the Secretary shall each ensure that timely action is taken to establish any necessary routine uses for disclosures required under paragraph (1) or agreed to pursuant to paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8032d1d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title VII, § 704, <ref href="/us/stat/49/636">49 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-08-28/ch809">Aug. 28, 1950, ch. 809</ref>, title IV, § 402(b), <ref href="/us/stat/64/558">64 Stat. 558</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/273/s33">Pub. L. 94–273, § 33</ref>, <date date="1976-04-21">Apr. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/380">90 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1171">98 Stat. 1171</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s104/a">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1470">108 Stat. 1470</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/169/tII/s211/a">Pub. L. 106–169, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-14">Dec. 14, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1842">113 Stat. 1842</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s845/a">Pub. L. 114–74, title VIII, § 845(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/618">129 Stat. 618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8032d1e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8032d1f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8032d20-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/74">Pub. L. 114–74</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/169">Pub. L. 106–169</ref> designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “The Secretary shall make a full report to Congress, within one hundred and twenty days after the beginning of each regular session, of the administration of the functions with which he is charged under this chapter. In addition to the number of copies of such report authorized by other law to be printed, there is hereby authorized to be printed not more than five thousand copies of such report for use by the Secretary for distribution to Members of Congress and to State and other public or private agencies or organizations participating in or concerned with the social security program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/273">Pub. L. 94–273</ref> substituted “within one hundred and twenty days after the beginning” for “at the beginning”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-08-28">Aug. 28, 1950</date>, substituted “Administrator” for “Board” in first sentence and added second sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8032d21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8032d22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/169/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 106–169, title II, § 211(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-14">Dec. 14, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1842">113 Stat. 1842</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/169/tII/s211/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to annual budgets prepared for fiscal years after fiscal year 1999.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8032d23-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s104/c">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 104(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1472">108 Stat. 1472</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s104/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 704(e)(4) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s904/e/4">42 U.S.C. 904(e)(4)</ref>] (as amended by subsection (a)) shall take effect <date date="1996-03-31">March 31, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition rule</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including subsections (b), (<i>o</i>), (p), (q), (r), and (u) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of title 5</ref>, United States Code), arrangements for disclosure of records or other information, and arrangements for computer matching of records, which were in effect immediately before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>] between the Social Security Administration in the Department of Health and Human Services and other components of such Department may continue between the Social Security Administration established under section 701 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s901">42 U.S.C. 901</ref>] (as amended by this Act) and such Department during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending <date date="1996-03-31">March 31, 1996</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s104/a">section 104(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8032d24-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8032d25-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expedited Examination of Administrative Law Judges</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s846">Pub. L. 114–74, title VIII, § 846</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/620">129 Stat. 620</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/74/tVIII/s846">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Office of Personnel Management shall, upon request of the Commissioner of Social Security, expeditiously administer a sufficient number of competitive examinations, as determined by the Commissioner, for the purpose of identifying an adequate number of candidates to be appointed as Administrative Law Judges under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3105">section 3105 of title 5</ref>, United States Code. The first such examination shall take place not later than <date date="2016-04-01">April 1, 2016</date> and other examinations shall take place at such time or times requested by the Commissioner, but not later than <date date="2022-12-31">December 31, 2022</date>. Such examinations shall proceed even if one or more individuals who took a prior examination have appealed an adverse determination and one or more of such appeals have not concluded, provided that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Commissioner of Social Security has made a determination that delaying the examination poses a significant risk that an adequate number of Administrative Law Judges will not be available to meet the need of the Social Security Administration to reduce or prevent a backlog of cases awaiting a hearing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> an individual whose appeal is pending is provided an option to continue their appeal or elects to take the new examination, in which case the appeal is considered vacated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an individual who decides to continue his or her appeal and who ultimately prevails in the appeal shall receive expeditious consideration for hire by the Office Personnel Management and the Commissioner of Social Security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment of Costs</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commissioner of Social Security shall pay the full cost associated with each examination conducted pursuant to subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8032d26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on SES Positions Under Comprehensive Work Force Plan</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s104/b">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1472">108 Stat. 1472</ref>, provided that within 60 days after establishment by Commissioner of Social Security of comprehensive work force plan required under subsec. (b)(2) of this section, Director of Office of Personnel Management was to transmit to Congress a report specifying total number of Senior Executive Services positions authorized for Social Security Administration in connection with such work force plan.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
