<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8032d2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906"><num value="906">§ 906.</num><heading> Training grants for public welfare personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to assist in increasing the effectiveness and efficiency of administration of public assistance programs by increasing the number of adequately trained public welfare personnel available for work in public assistance programs, there are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1963-06-30">June 30, 1963</date>, the sum of $3,500,000, and for each fiscal year thereafter the sum of $5,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation for carrying out direct grant programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such portion of the sums appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) for any fiscal year as the Secretary may determine, but not in excess of $1,000,000 in the case of the fiscal year ending <date date="1963-06-30">June 30, 1963</date>, and $2,000,000 in the case of any fiscal year thereafter, shall be available for carrying out subsection (f). From the remainder of the sums so appropriated for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall make allotments to the States on the basis of (1) population, (2) relative need for trained public welfare personnel, particularly for personnel to provide self-support and self-care services, and (3) financial need.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments to States for cost of grant programs to certain agencies and institutions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">From each State’s allotment under subsection (b), the Secretary shall from time to time pay to such State its costs of carrying out the purposes of this section through (1) grants to public or other nonprofit institutions of higher learning for training personnel employed or preparing for employment in public assistance programs, (2) special courses of study or seminars of short duration conducted for such personnel by experts hired on a temporary basis for the purpose, and (3) establishing and maintaining, directly or through grants to such institutions, fellowships or traineeships for such personnel at such institutions, with such stipends and allowances as may be permitted under regulations of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Advance payments to States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Payments pursuant to subsection (c) shall be made in advance on the basis of estimates by the Secretary and adjustments may be made in future payments under this section to take account of overpayments or underpayments in amounts previously paid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reallotments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amount of any allotment to a State under subsection (b) for any fiscal year which the State certifies to the Secretary will not be required for carrying out the purposes of this section in such State shall be available for reallotment from time to time, on such dates as the Secretary may fix, to other States which the Secretary determines have need in carrying out such purposes for sums in excess of those previously allotted to them under this section and will be able to use such excess amounts during such fiscal year; such reallotments to be made on the basis provided in subsection (b) for the initial allotments to the States. Any amount so reallotted to a State shall be deemed part of its allotment under such subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct grants to certain agencies and institutions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The portion of the sums appropriated for any fiscal year which is determined by the Secretary under the first sentence of subsection (b) to be available for carrying out this subsection shall be available to enable him to provide (A) directly or through grants to or contracts with public or nonprofit private institutions of higher learning, for training personnel who are employed or preparing for employment in the administration of public assistance programs, (B) directly or through grants to or contracts with public or nonprofit private agencies or institutions, for special courses of study or seminars of short duration (not in excess of one year) for training of such personnel, and (C) directly or through grants to or contracts with public or nonprofit private institutions of higher learning, for establishing and maintaining fellowships or traineeships for such personnel at such institutions, with such stipends and allowances as may be permitted by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Payments under paragraph (1) may be made in advance on the basis of estimates by the Secretary, or may be made by way of reimbursement, and adjustments may be made in future payments under this subsection to take account of overpayments or underpayments in amounts previously paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s906/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may, to the extent he finds such action to be necessary, prescribe requirements to assure that any individual will repay the amount of his fellowship or traineeship received under this subsection to the extent such individual fails to serve, for the period prescribed by the Secretary, with a State or political subdivision thereof, or with the Federal Government, in connection with administration of any State or local public assistance program. The Secretary may relieve any individual of his obligation to so repay, in whole or in part, whenever and to the extent that requirement of such repayment would, in his judgment, be inequitable or would be contrary to the purposes of any of the public welfare programs established by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8032d35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title VII, § 705, as added <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch836">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 836</ref>, title III, § 332, <ref href="/us/stat/70/851">70 Stat. 851</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/87/31/s3">Pub. L. 87–31, § 3</ref>, <date date="1961-05-08">May 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/77">75 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/543/tI/s123">Pub. L. 87–543, title I, § 123</ref> (a)–(c), <date date="1962-07-25">July 25, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/192">76 Stat. 192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8032d36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8032d37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8032d38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/87/543/s123/a">Pub. L. 87–543, § 123(a)</ref>, substituted “for the fiscal year ending <date date="1963-06-30">June 30, 1963</date>, the sum of $3,500,000, and for each fiscal year thereafter the sum of $5,000,000” for “for the fiscal year ending <date date="1958-06-30">June 30, 1958</date>, the sum of $5,000,000, and for each of the five succeeding fiscal years such sums as the Congress may determine”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/543/s123/b">Pub. L. 87–543, § 123(b)</ref>, required appropriated moneys to be made available for carrying out subsec. (f) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/87/543/s123/c">Pub. L. 87–543, § 123(c)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/87/31/s3/a">Pub. L. 87–31, § 3(a)</ref>, substituted “five” for “four”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/31/s3/b">Pub. L. 87–31, § 3(b)</ref>, substituted “its costs of carrying out the purposes of this section” for “80 per centum of the total of its expenditures in carrying out the purposes of this section”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8032d39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8032d3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/87/543/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 87–543, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-07-25">July 25, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/208">76 Stat. 208</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/87/543/tII/s202/b">“The amendments made by sections 102(c), 123, and 132(d) [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s727">section 727 of this title</ref>, amending this section and sections 722 and 726 of this title, and repealing credits to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1308">section 1308 of this title</ref> and provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1308">section 1308 of this title</ref>] shall be applicable in the case of fiscal years beginning after <date date="1962-06-30">June 30, 1962</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8032d3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1961 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/87/31/s3/b">Pub. L. 87–31, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-08">May 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/77">75 Stat. 77</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective with respect to payments from allotments from appropriations made for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
