<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8032d42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a"><num value="907a">§ 907a.</num><heading> National Commission on Social Security</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; membership; Chairman and Vice Chairman; quorum; terms of office; vacancies; per diem and expense reimbursement; meetings</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is established a commission to be known as the National Commission on Social Security (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Commission shall consist of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> five members to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, one of whom shall, at the time of appointment, be designated as Chairman of the Commission;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> two members to be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> two members to be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> At no time shall more than three of the members appointed by the President, one of the members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, or one of the members appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate be members of the same political party.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The membership of the Commission shall consist of individuals who are of recognized standing and distinction and who possess the demonstrated capacity to discharge the duties imposed on the Commission, and shall include representatives of the private insurance industry and of recipients and potential recipients of benefits under the programs involved as well as individuals whose capacity is based on a special knowledge or expertise in those programs. No individual who is otherwise an officer or full-time employee of the United States shall serve as a member of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Chairman of the Commission shall designate a member of the Commission to act as Vice Chairman of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may conduct hearings.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Members of the Commission shall be appointed for a term which shall end on <date date="1981-04-01">April 1, 1981</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> A vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner as that herein provided for the appointment of the member first appointed to the vacant position.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Members of the Commission shall receive $138 per diem while engaged in the actual performance of the duties vested in the Commission, plus reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of such duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairman, or at the call of a majority of the members of the Commission; but meetings of the Commission shall be held not less frequently than once in each calendar month which begins after a majority of the authorized membership of the Commission has first been appointed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuing study, investigation, and review of social security program; scope of study, etc., and public participation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> It shall be the duty and function of the Commission to conduct a continuing study, investigation, and review of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Federal old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established by subchapter II of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the health insurance programs established by subchapter XVIII of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Such study, investigation, and review of such programs shall include (but not be limited to)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the fiscal status of the trust funds established for the financing of such programs and the adequacy of such trust funds to meet the immediate and long-range financing needs of such programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the scope of coverage, the adequacy of benefits including the measurement of an adequate retirement income, and the conditions of qualification for benefits provided by such programs including the application of the retirement income test to unearned as well as earned income;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the impact of such programs on, and their relation to, public assistance programs, nongovernmental retirement and annuity programs, medical service delivery systems, and national employment practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any inequities (whether attributable to provisions of law relating to the establishment and operation of such programs, to rules and regulations promulgated in connection with the administration of such programs, or to administrative practices and procedures employed in the carrying out of such programs) which affect substantial numbers of individuals who are insured or otherwise eligible for benefits under such programs, including inequities and inequalities arising out of marital status, sex, or similar classifications or categories;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> possible alternatives to the current Federal programs or particular aspects thereof, including but not limited to (i) a phasing out of the payroll tax with the financing of such programs being accomplished in some other manner (including general revenue funding and the retirement bond), (ii) the establishment of a system providing for mandatory participation in any or all of the Federal programs, (iii) the integration of such current Federal programs with private retirement programs, and (iv) the establishment of a system permitting covered individuals a choice of public or private programs or both;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the need to develop a special Consumer Price Index for the elderly, including the financial impact that such an index would have on the costs of the programs established under this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8032d5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> methods for effectively implementing the recommendations of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In order to provide an effective opportunity for the general public to participate fully in the study, investigation, and review under this section, the Commission, in conducting such study, investigation, and review, shall hold public hearings in as many different geographical areas of the country as possible. The residents of each area where such a hearing is to be held shall be given reasonable advance notice of the hearing and an adequate opportunity to appear and express their views on the matters under consideration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Special, annual, and final reports to President and Congress concerning implementation, etc., of study, investigation, and review responsibilities; termination of Commission</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No later than four months after the date on which a majority of the authorized membership of the Commission is initially appointed, the Commission shall submit to the President and the Congress a special report describing the Commission’s plans for conducting the study, investigation, and review under subsection (b), with particular reference to the scope of such study, investigation, and review and the methods proposed to be used in conducting it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> At or before the close of each of the first two years after the date on which a majority of the authorized membership of the Commission is initially appointed, the Commission shall submit to the President and the Congress an annual report on the study, investigation, and review under subsection (b), together with its recommendations with respect to the programs involved. The second such report shall constitute the final report of the Commission on such study, investigation, and review, and shall include its final recommendations; and the Commission shall cease to exist on <date date="1981-04-01">April 1, 1981</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Executive Director and additional personnel; appointment and compensation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commission shall appoint an Executive Director of the Commission who shall be compensated at a rate fixed by the Commission, but which shall not exceed the rate established for level V of the Executive Schedule by title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8032d64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In addition to the Executive Director, the Commission shall have the power to appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as it deems advisable, in accordance with the provisions of title 5 governing appointments to the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out its duties under this section, the Commission, or any duly authorized committee thereof, is authorized to hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, and take such testimony, with respect to matters with respect to which it has a responsibility under this section, as the Commission or such committee may deem advisable. The Chairman of the Commission or any member authorized by him may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Commission or before any committee thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Data and information from other Federal departments and agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States such data and information as may be necessary to enable it to carry out its duties under this section. Upon request of the Chairman of the Commission, any such department or agency shall furnish any such data or information to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative support services from General Services Administration; reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The General Services Administration shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis such administrative support services as the Commission may request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8032d68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s907a/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8032d69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/216/tIII/s361">Pub. L. 95–216, title III, § 361</ref>, <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1556">91 Stat. 1556</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/tV/s502">Pub. L. 96–265, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1980-06-09">June 9, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/470">94 Stat. 470</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2349/b/3">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III, § 2349(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1097">98 Stat. 1097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8032d6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8032d6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb8032d6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Level V of the Executive Schedule, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), is set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5316">section 5316 of Title 5</ref>, Government Officers and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb8032d6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Social Security Amendments of 1977, and not as part of the Social Security Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8032d6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> struck out subsec. (i) which provided for notice of and attendance at meetings of the Health Insurance Benefits Advisory Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(2)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s502/a">Pub. L. 96–265, § 502(a)</ref>, substituted “a term which shall end on <date date="1981-04-01">April 1, 1981</date>” for “a term of two years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/s502/b">Pub. L. 96–265, § 502(b)</ref>, substituted “and the Commission shall cease to exist on <date date="1981-04-01">April 1, 1981</date>” for “and upon the submission of such final report the Commission shall cease to exist”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8032d6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8032d70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2349/c">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III, § 2349(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1097">98 Stat. 1097</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2349/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395z">section 1395z of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231f">section 231f of Title 45</ref>, Railroads, and repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd">section 1395dd of this title</ref>] shall become effective on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
