<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbea9c0d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102"><num value="9102">§ 9102.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires, the term—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “adjacent coastal State” means any coastal State which is required to be designated as such by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9115/a/1">section 9115(a)(1) of this title</ref> or is designated as such by the Administrator in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9115/a/2">section 9115(a)(2) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “antitrust laws” includes the Act of <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">15 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.], the Act of <date date="1914-10-15">October 15, 1914</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">15 U.S.C. 12</ref> et seq.], and sections 73 and 74 of the Act of <date date="1894-08-27">August 27, 1894</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">15 U.S.C. 8</ref> and 9];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> “application” means any application submitted under this chapter (A) for issuance of a license for the ownership, construction, and operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship; (B) for transfer or renewal of any such license; or (C) for any substantial change in any of the conditions and provisions of any such license;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “coastal State” means a State in, or bordering on, the Atlantic, Pacific, or Arctic Ocean, the Gulf of Mexico, Long Island Sound, or one or more of the Great Lakes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> “construction” means any activities conducted at sea to supervise, inspect, actually build, or perform other functions incidental to the building, repairing, or expanding of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or any of its components, including but not limited to, piledriving, emplacement of mooring devices, emplacement of cables and pipelines, and deployment of the cold water pipe, and alterations, modifications, or additions to an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> “facility” means an ocean thermal energy conversion facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> “Governor” means the Governor of a State or the person designated by law to exercise the powers granted to the Governor pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> “high seas” means that part of the oceans lying seaward of the territorial sea of the United States and outside the territorial sea, as recognized by the United States, of any other nation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> “licensee” means the holder of a valid license for the ownership, construction, and operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship that was issued, transferred, or renewed pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> “ocean thermal energy conversion facility” means any facility which is standing, fixed or moored in whole or in part seaward of the highwater mark and which is designed to use temperature differences in ocean water to produce electricity or another form of energy capable of being used directly to perform work, and includes any equipment installed on such facility to use such electricity or other form of energy to produce, process, refine, or manufacture a product, and any cable or pipeline used to deliver such electricity, fresh water, or product to shore, and all other associated equipment and appurtenances of such facility, to the extent they are located seaward of the highwater mark;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> “ocean thermal energy conversion plantship” means any vessel which is designed to use temperature differences in ocean water while floating unmoored or moving through such water, to produce electricity or another form of energy capable of being used directly to perform work, and includes any equipment installed on such vessel to use such electricity or other form of energy to produce, process, refine, or manufacture a product, and any equipment used to transfer such product to other vessels for transportation to users, and all other associated equipment and appurtenances of such vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> “plantship” means an ocean thermal energy conversion plantship;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> “person” means any individual (whether or not a citizen of the United States), any corporation, partnership, association, or other entity organized or existing under the laws of any nation, and any Federal, State, local or foreign government or any entity of any such government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and any other Commonwealth, territory, or possession over which the United States has jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> “test platform” means any floating or moored platform, barge, ship, or other vessel which is designed for limited-scale, at sea operation in order to test or evaluate the operation of components or all of an ocean thermal energy conversion system and which will not operate as an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship after the conclusion of such tests or evaluation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> “thermal plume” means the area of the ocean in which a significant difference in temperature, as defined in regulations by the Administrator, occurs as a result of the operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbea9c0ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9102/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> “United States citizen” means (A) any individual who is a citizen of the United States by law, birth, or naturalization; (B) any Federal, State, or local government in the United States, or any entity of any such government; or (C) any corporation, partnership, association, or other entity, organized or existing under the laws of the United States, or of any State, which has as its president or other executive officer and as its chairman of the board of directors, or holder of similar office, an individual who is a United States citizen and which has no more of its directors who are not United States citizens than constitute a minority of the number required for a quorum necessary to conduct the business of the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbea9c0eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/320/s3">Pub. L. 96–320, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-08-03">Aug. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/975">94 Stat. 975</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/623/tVI/s602/a/2">Pub. L. 98–623, title VI, § 602(a)(2)</ref>, (e)(7), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3410">98 Stat. 3410</ref>, 3412.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbea9c0ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbea9c0ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbea9c0ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in introductory provisions and pars. (4), (8), and (10), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/320">Pub. L. 96–320</ref>, <date date="1980-08-03">Aug. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/974">94 Stat. 974</ref>, known as the Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9101">section 9101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1890-07-02">July 2, 1890</date>, as amended, referred to in par. (3), is <ref href="/us/act/1890-07-02/ch647">act July 2, 1890, ch. 647</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/209">26 Stat. 209</ref>, known as the Sherman Act, which is classified to sections 1 to 7 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1">section 1 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1914-10-15">October 15, 1914</date>, as amended, referred to in par. (3), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-10-15/ch323">act Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/730">78 Stat. 730</ref>, known as the Clayton Act, which is classified generally to sections 12, 13, 14 to 19, 21, and 22 to 27 of Title 15, and sections 52 and 53 of Title 29, Labor. For further details and complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s12">section 12 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 73 and 74 of the Act of <date date="1894-08-27">August 27, 1894</date>, as amended, referred to in par. (3), are sections 73 and 74 of <ref href="/us/act/1894-08-27/ch349">act Aug. 27, 1894, ch. 349</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/570">28 Stat. 570</ref>. Sections 73 to 77 of such Act are known as the Wilson Tariff Act. Sections 73 to 76 enacted sections 8 to 11 of Title 15. Section 77 is not classified to the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8">section 8 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbeac31ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Par. (11). <ref href="/us/pl/98/623/s602/a/2">Pub. L. 98–623, § 602(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “standing, fixed or moored in whole or in part seaward of the highwater mark” for “standing or moored in or beyond the territorial sea of the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/623/s602/e/7">Pub. L. 98–623, § 602(e)(7)</ref>, substituted “fresh water” for “freshwater”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbeac31f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbeac31f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Territorial Sea of United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For extension of territorial sea of United States, see Proc. No. 5928, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">section 1331 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
