<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbeae7bd8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9151"><num value="9151">§ 9151.</num><heading> Prohibited acts</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person who is a United States citizen or national, or a foreign national in or on board an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or on board any vessel documented or numbered under the laws of the United States, or who is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States by an international agreement to which the United States is a party—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bd9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9151/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to violate any provision of this chapter; or any rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant to this chapter; or any term or condition of any license issued to such person pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bda-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9151/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to refuse to permit any Federal officer or employee authorized to monitor or enforce the provisions of sections 9120 and 9153 of this title to enter or board an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or any vessel documented or numbered under the laws of the United States, for purposes of conducting any search or inspection in connection with the monitoring or enforcement of this chapter or any rule, regulation, order, term, or condition referred to in paragraph (1) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bdb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9151/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to forcibly assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, or interfere with any such authorized officer or employee in the conduct of any search or inspection described in paragraph (2) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bdc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9151/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to resist a lawful arrest for any act prohibited by this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bdd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9151/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to interfere with, delay, or prevent, by any means, the apprehension or arrest of another person subject to this section knowing that the other person has committed any act prohibited by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbeae7bde-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/320/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 96–320, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1980-08-03">Aug. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/994">94 Stat. 994</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/623/tVI/s602/a/9">Pub. L. 98–623, title VI, § 602(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3411">98 Stat. 3411</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbeae7bdf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbeae7be0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbeae7be1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in pars. (1) and (2), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/320">Pub. L. 96–320</ref>, <date date="1980-08-03">Aug. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/974">94 Stat. 974</ref>, known as the Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9101">section 9101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbeae7be2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/623">Pub. L. 98–623</ref> substituted “in or on board an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or on board any vessel” for “on board an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or other vessel” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/623">Pub. L. 98–623</ref> substituted “to enter or board” for “to board”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
