<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbeae7bf9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153"><num value="9153">§ 9153.</num><heading> Enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbeae7bfa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement responsibility of Administrator of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; Coast Guard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except where a specific section of this chapter designates enforcement responsibility, the provisions of this chapter shall be enforced by the Administrator. The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall have exclusive responsibility for enforcement measures which affect the safety of life and property at sea, shall exercise such other enforcement responsibilities with respect to vessels subject to the provisions of this chapter as are authorized under other provisions of law, and may, upon the specific request of the Administrator, assist the Administrator in the enforcement of any provision of this chapter. The Administrator and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may, by agreement, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, utilize the personnel, services, equipment, including aircraft and vessels, and facilities of any other Federal agency or department, and may authorize officers or employees of other departments or agencies to provide assistance as necessary in carrying out subsection (b) of this section. The Administrator and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may issue regulations jointly or severally as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out their duties under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbeae7bfb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement activities of authorized officers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To enforce the provisions of this chapter in or on board any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or any vessel subject to the provisions of this chapter, any officer who is authorized by the Administrator or the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bfc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> enter or board, and inspect, any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or any vessel which is subject to the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bfd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> search the vessel if the officer has reasonable cause to believe that the vessel has been used or employed in the violation of any provision of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bfe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> arrest any person subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9151">section 9151 of this title</ref> if the officer has reasonable cause to believe that the person has committed a criminal act prohibited by sections 9151 and 9152(d) of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7bff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> seize the vessel together with its gear, furniture, appurtenances, stores, and cargo, used or employed in, or with respect to which it reasonably appears that such vessel was used or employed in, the violation of any provision of this chapter if such seizure is necessary to prevent evasion of the enforcement of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7c00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> seize any evidence related to any violation of any provision of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7c01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> execute any warrant or other process issued by any court of competent jurisdiction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeae7c02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> exercise any other lawful authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbeae7c03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction; venue</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9125">section 9125 of this title</ref>, the district courts of the United States shall have exclusive original jurisdiction over any case or controversy arising under the provisions of this chapter. Except as otherwise specified in this chapter, venue shall lie in any district wherein, or nearest to which, the cause of action arose, or wherein any defendant resides, may be found, or has his principal office. In the case of Guam, and any Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States in the Pacific Ocean, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of Guam, except that in the case of American Samoa, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of Hawaii. Any such court may, at any time—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeb0ed04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> enter restraining orders or prohibitions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeb0ed05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> issue warrants, process in rem, or other process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeb0ed06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> prescribe and accept satisfactory bonds or other security; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeb0ed07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> take such other actions as are in the interest of justice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbeb0ed08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9153/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “vessel” includes an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship, and the term “provisions of this chapter” or “provision of this chapter” includes any rule, regulation, or order issued pursuant to this chapter and any term or condition of any license issued pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbeb0ed09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/320/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 96–320, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1980-08-03">Aug. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/996">94 Stat. 996</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/623/tVI/s602/a/10">Pub. L. 98–623, title VI, § 602(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3411">98 Stat. 3411</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbeb0ed0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbeb0ed0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbeb0ed0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/320">Pub. L. 96–320</ref>, <date date="1980-08-03">Aug. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/974">94 Stat. 974</ref>, known as the Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9101">section 9101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbeb0ed0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/623">Pub. L. 98–623</ref> substituted “in or on board any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or any vessel” for “on board any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or other vessel” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/623">Pub. L. 98–623</ref> substituted “enter or board, and inspect, any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship or” for “board and inspect”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbeb0ed0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbeb0ed0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
