<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbec8ba45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9615"><num value="9615">§ 9615.</num><heading> Presidential delegation and assignment of duties or powers and promulgation of regulations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to delegate and assign any duties or powers imposed upon or assigned to him and to promulgate any regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbec8ba46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/tI/s115">Pub. L. 96–510, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2796">94 Stat. 2796</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbec8ba47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbec8ba48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbec8ba49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12580. Superfund Implementation</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12580, <date date="1987-01-23">Jan. 23, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 2923, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12777, § 1(a), <date date="1991-10-18">Oct. 18, 1991</date>, 56 F.R. 54757; Ex. Ord. No. 13016, <date date="1996-08-28">Aug. 28, 1996</date>, 61 F.R. 45871; Ex. Ord. No. 13286, § 43, <date date="2003-02-28">Feb. 28, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 10627; Ex. Ord. No. 13308, <date date="2003-06-20">June 20, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 37691, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President of the United States of America by Section 115 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9615">42 U.S.C. 9615</ref> <i>et seq</i>.) (“the Act”), and by <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">Section 301 of Title 3</ref> of the United States Code, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>National Contingency Plan</i>. (a)(1) The National Contingency Plan (“the NCP”), shall provide for a National Response Team (“the NRT”) composed of representatives of appropriate Federal departments and agencies for national planning and coordination of preparedness and response actions, and Regional Response Teams as the regional counterparts to the NRT for planning and coordination of regional preparedness and response actions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) The following agencies (in addition to other appropriate agencies) shall provide representatives to the National and Regional Response Teams to carry out their responsibilities under the NCP: Department of State, Department of Defense, Department of Justice, Department of the Interior, Department of Agriculture, Department of Commerce, Department of Labor, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of Transportation, Department of Energy, Department of Homeland Security, Environmental Protection Agency,, [sic] United States Coast Guard, and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Except for periods of activation because of response action, the representative of the Environmental Protection Agency (“EPA”) shall be the chairman, and the representative of the United States Coast Guard shall be the vice chairman, of the NRT and these agencies’ representatives shall be co-chairs of the Regional Response Teams (“the RRTs”). When the NRT or an RRT is activated for a response action, the EPA representative shall be the chairman when the release or threatened release or discharge or threatened discharge occurs in the inland zone, and the United States Coast Guard representative shall be the chairman when the release or threatened release or discharge or threatened discharge occurs in the coastal zone, unless otherwise agreed upon by the EPA and the United States Coast Guard representatives (inland and coastal zones are defined in the NCP).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) The RRTs may include representatives from State governments, local governments (as agreed upon by the States), and Indian tribal governments. Subject to the functions and authorities delegated to Executive departments and agencies in other sections of this order, the NRT shall provide policy and program direction to the RRTs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b)(1) The responsibility for the revision of the NCP and all the other functions vested in the President by Sections 105(a), (b), (c), (g) and (h), 125, and 301(f) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9605/a">42 U.S.C. 9605(a)</ref>, (b), (c), (g), (h), 9625, 9651(f)], by Section 311(d)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1321/d/1">33 U.S.C. 1321(d)(1)</ref>], and by Section 4201(c) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/380">Pub. L. 101–380</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1321">33 U.S.C. 1321</ref> note] is delegated to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (“the Administrator”).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) The function vested in the President by Section 118(p) of the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref>) (“SARA”) [<ref href="/us/stat/100/1662">100 Stat. 1662</ref>] is delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p>(c) In accord with Section 107(f)(2)(A) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607/f/2/A">42 U.S.C. 9607(f)(2)(A)</ref>], Section 311(f)(5) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1321/f/5">33 U.S.C. 1321(f)(5)</ref>), and Section 1006(b)(1) and (2) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2706/b/1">33 U.S.C. 2706(b)(1)</ref>, (2)], the following shall be among those designated in the NCP as Federal trustees for natural resources:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Secretary of Defense;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Secretary of the Interior;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Secretary of Agriculture;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) Secretary of Commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(5) Secretary of Energy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In the event of a spill, the above named Federal trustees for natural resources shall designate one trustee to act as Lead Administrative Trustee, the duties of which shall be defined in the regulations promulgated pursuant to Section 1006(e)(1) of OPA. If there are natural resource trustees other than those designated above which are acting in the event of a spill, those other trustees may join with the Federal trustees to name a Lead Administrative Trustee which shall exercise the duties defined in the regulations promulgated pursuant to Section 1006(e)(1) of OPA.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Revisions to the NCP shall be made in consultation with members of the NRT prior to publication for notice and comment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) All revisions to the NCP, whether in proposed or final form, shall be subject to review and approval by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (“OMB”).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Response and Related Authorities</i>. (a) The functions vested in the President by the first sentence of Section 104(b)(1) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b/1">42 U.S.C. 9604(b)(1)</ref>] relating to “illness, disease, or complaints thereof” are delegated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services who shall, in accord with Section 104(i) of the Act, perform those functions through the Public Health Service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The functions vested in the President by Sections 104(e)(7)(C), 113(k)(2), 119(c)(7), and 121(f)(1) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/e/7/C">42 U.S.C. 9604(e)(7)(C)</ref>, 9613(k)(2), 9619(c)(7), 9621(f)(1)], relating to promulgation of regulations and guidelines, are delegated to the Administrator, to be exercised in consultation with the NRT.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c)(1) The functions vested in the President by Sections 104(a) and the second sentence of 126(b) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/a">42 U.S.C. 9604(a)</ref>, 9626(b)], to the extent they require permanent relocation of residents, businesses, and community facilities or temporary evacuation and housing of threatened individuals not otherwise provided for, are delegated to the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to subsection (b) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 117(a) and (c), and 119 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9617/a">42 U.S.C. 9617(a)</ref>, (c), 9619], to the extent such authority is needed to carry out the functions delegated under paragraph (1) of this subsection, are delegated to the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Subject to subsections (a), (b) and (c) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 104(a), (b) and (c)(4), 113(k), 117(a) and (c), 119, and 121 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/a">42 U.S.C. 9604(a)</ref>, (b), (c)(4), 9613(k), 9617(a), (c), 9619, 9621] are delegated to the Secretaries of Defense and Energy, with respect to releases or threatened releases where either the release is on or the sole source of the release is from any facility or vessel under the jurisdiction, custody or control of their departments, respectively, including vessels bare-boat chartered and operated. These functions must be exercised consistent with the requirements of Section 120 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620">42 U.S.C. 9620</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e)(1) Subject to subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 104(a), (b), and (c)(4), and 121 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/a">42 U.S.C. 9604(a)</ref>, (b), (c)(4), 9621] are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies, with respect to remedial actions for releases or threatened releases which are not on the National Priorities List (“the NPL”) and removal actions other than emergencies, where either the release is on or the sole source of the release is from any facility or vessel under the jurisdiction, custody or control of those departments and agencies, including vessels bare-boat chartered and operated. The Administrator shall define the term “emergency”, solely for the purposes of this subsection, either by regulation or by a memorandum of understanding with the head of an Executive department or agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 104(b)(2), 113(k), 117(a) and (c), and 119 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b/2">42 U.S.C. 9604(b)(2)</ref>, 9613(k), 9617(a), (c), 9619] are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies, with respect to releases or threatened releases where either the release is on or the sole source of the release is from any facility or vessel under the jurisdiction, custody or control of those departments and agencies, including vessels bare-boat chartered and operated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) Subject to subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), and (e) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 104(a), (b) and (c)(4), 113(k), 117(a) and (c), 119, and 121 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/a">42 U.S.C. 9604(a)</ref>, (b), (c)(4), 9613(k), 9617(a), (c), 9619, 9621] are delegated to the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating (“the Coast Guard”), with respect to any release or threatened release involving the coastal zone, Great Lakes waters, ports, and harbors.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) Subject to subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 101(24), 104(a), (b), (c)(4) and (c)(9), 113(k), 117(a) and (c), 119, 121, and 126(b) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/24">42 U.S.C. 9601(24)</ref>, 9604(a), (b), (c)(4), (9), 9613(k), 9617(a), (c), 9619, 9621, 9626(b)] are delegated to the Administrator. The Administrator’s authority under Section 119 of the Act is retroactive to the date of enactment of SARA [<date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(h) The functions vested in the President by Section 104(c)(3) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/c/3">42 U.S.C. 9604(c)(3)</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator, with respect to providing assurances for Indian tribes, to be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) Subject to subsections (d), (e), (f), (g) and (h) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 104(c) and (d) of the Act are delegated to the Coast Guard, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and the Administrator in order to carry out the functions delegated to them by this Section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(j)(1) The functions vested in the President by Section 104(e)(5)(A) are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies, with respect to releases or threatened releases where either the release is on or the sole source of the release is from any facility or vessel under the jurisdiction, custody or control of those departments and agencies, to be exercised with the concurrence of the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to subsection (b) of this Section and paragraph (1) of this subsection, the functions vested in the President by Section 104(e) are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies in order to carry out their functions under this Order or the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(k) The functions vested in the President by Section 104(f), (g), (h), (i)(11), and (j) of the Act are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies in order to carry out the functions delegated to them by this Section. The exercise of authority under Section 104(h) of the Act shall be subject to the approval of the Administrator of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Cleanup Schedules</i>. (a) The functions vested in the President by Sections 116(a) and the first two sentences of 105(d) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9616/a">42 U.S.C. 9616(a)</ref>, 9605(d)] are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies with respect to facilities under the jurisdiction, custody or control of those departments and agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Subject to subsection (a) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 116 and 105(d) are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Enforcement</i>. (a) The functions vested in the President by Sections 109(d) and 122(e)(3)(A) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9609/d">42 U.S.C. 9609(d)</ref>, 9622(e)(3)(A)], relating to development of regulations and guidelines, are delegated to the Administrator, to be exercised in consultation with the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b)(1) Subject to subsection (a) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 122 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">42 U.S.C. 9622</ref>] (except subsection (b)(1)) are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies, with respect to releases or threatened releases not on the NPL where either the release is on or the sole source of the release is from any facility under the jurisdiction, custody or control of those Executive departments and agencies. These functions may be exercised only with the concurrence of the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to subsection (a) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 109 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9609">42 U.S.C. 9609</ref>], relating to violations of Section 122 of the Act, are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies, with respect to releases or threatened releases not on the NPL where either the release is on or the sole source of the release is from any facility under the jurisdiction, custody or control of those Executive departments and agencies. These functions may be exercised only with the concurrence of the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c)(1) Subject to subsection[s] (a) and (b)(1) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 106(a) and 122 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606/a">42 U.S.C. 9606(a)</ref>, 9622] are delegated to the Coast Guard with respect to any release or threatened release involving the coastal zone, Great Lakes waters, ports, and harbors.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to subsection[s] (a) and (b)(2) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 109 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9609">42 U.S.C. 9609</ref>], relating to violations of Sections 103(a) and (b), and 122 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9603/a">42 U.S.C. 9603(a)</ref>, (b), 9622], are delegated to the Coast Guard with respect to any release or threatened release involving the coastal zone, Great Lakes waters, ports, and harbors.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Subject to subsections (a) and (b)(1) of this section, the functions vested in the President by sections 106(a) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606/a">42 U.S.C. 9606(a)</ref>] and 122 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">42 U.S.C. 9622</ref>] (except subsection (b)(1)) of the Act are delegated to the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, to be exercised only with the concurrence of the Coast Guard, with respect to any release or threatened release in the coastal zone, Great Lakes waters, ports, and harbors, affecting (1) natural resources under their trusteeship, or (2) a vessel or facility subject to their custody, jurisdiction, or control. Such authority shall not be exercised at any vessel or facility at which the Coast Guard is the lead Federal agency for the conduct or oversight of a response action. Such authority shall not be construed to authorize or permit use of the Hazardous Substance Superfund to implement section 106 or to fund performance of any response action in lieu of the payment by a person who receives but does not comply with an order pursuant to section 106(a), where such order has been issued by the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary of Energy. This subsection shall not be construed to limit any authority delegated by any other section of this order. Authority granted under this subsection shall be exercised in a manner to ensure interagency coordination that enhances efficiency and effectiveness.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d)(1) Subject to subsections (a), (b)(1), and (c)(1) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Sections 106 and 122 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">42 U.S.C. 9606</ref>, 9622] are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to subsections (a), (b)(2), and (c)(2) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 109 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9609">42 U.S.C. 9609</ref>], relating to violations of Sections 103 and 122 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9603">42 U.S.C. 9603</ref>, 9622], are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Subject to subsections (a), (b)(1), and (c)(1) of this section, the functions vested in the President by sections 106(a) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606/a">42 U.S.C. 9606(a)</ref>] and 122 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">42 U.S.C. 9622</ref>] (except subsection (b)(1)) of the Act are delegated to the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, and the Department of Energy, to be exercised only with the concurrence of the Administrator, with respect to any release or threatened release affecting (1) natural resources under their trusteeship, or (2) a vessel or facility subject to their custody, jurisdiction, or control. Such authority shall not be exercised at any vessel or facility at which the Administrator is the lead Federal official for the conduct or oversight of a response action. Such authority shall not be construed to authorize or permit use of the Hazardous Substance Superfund to implement section 106 or to fund performance of any response action in lieu of the payment by a person who receives but does not comply with an order pursuant to section 106(a), where such order has been issued by the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary of Energy. This subsection shall not be construed to limit any authority delegated by any other section of this order. Authority granted under this subsection shall be exercised in a manner to ensure interagency coordination that enhances efficiency and effectiveness.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Notwithstanding any other provision of this Order, the authority under Sections 104(e)(5)(A) and 106(a) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/e/5/A">42 U.S.C. 9604(e)(5)(A)</ref>, 9606(a)] to seek information, entry, inspection, samples, or response actions from Executive departments and agencies may be exercised only with the concurrence of the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Liability</i>. (a) The function vested in the President by Section 107(c)(1)(C) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607/c/1/C">42 U.S.C. 9607(c)(1)(C)</ref>] is delegated to the Secretary of Transportation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The functions vested in the President by Section 107(c)(3) of the Act are delegated to the Coast Guard with respect to any release or threatened release involving the coastal zone, Great Lakes waters, ports and harbors.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Subject to subsection (b) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 107(c)(3) of the Act are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The functions vested in the President by Section 107(f)(1) of the Act are delegated to each of the Federal trustees for natural resources designated in the NCP for resources under their trusteeship.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The functions vested in the President by Section 107(f)(2)(B) of the Act, to receive notification of the state natural resource trustee designations, are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) The functions vested in the President by Section 107(<i>o</i>) and (p) of the Act are delegated to the heads of the Executive departments and agencies, to be exercised in consultation with the Administrator, with respect to releases or threatened releases where either the release is on or the sole source of the release is from any facility under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of those departments and agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) Subject to subsection (f) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 107(<i>o</i>) and (p) of the Act are delegated to the Administrator except that, with respect to determinations regarding natural resource restoration, the Administrator shall make such determinations in consultation with the appropriate Federal natural resource trustee.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>Litigation</i>. (a) Notwithstanding any other provision of this Order, any representation pursuant to or under this Order in any judicial proceedings shall be by or through the Attorney General. The conduct and control of all litigation arising under the Act shall be the responsibility of the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Notwithstanding any other provision of this Order, the authority under the Act to require the Attorney General to commence litigation is retained by the President.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The functions vested in the President by Section 113(g) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9613/g">42 U.S.C. 9613(g)</ref>], to receive notification of a natural resource trustee’s intent to file suit, are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies with respect to response actions for which they have been delegated authority under Section 2 of this Order. The Administrator shall promulgate procedural regulations for providing such notification.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The functions vested in the President by Sections [sic] 310(d) and (e) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9659/d">42 U.S.C. 9659(d)</ref>, (e)], relating to promulgation of regulations, are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 7. <i>Financial Responsibility</i>. (a) The functions vested in the President by Section 107(k)(4)(B) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607/k/4/B">42 U.S.C. 9607(k)(4)(B)</ref>] are delegated to the Secretary of the Treasury. The Administrator will provide the Secretary with such technical information and assistance as the Administrator may have available.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b)(1) The functions vested in the President by Section 108(a)(1) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9608/a/1">42 U.S.C. 9608(a)(1)</ref>] are delegated to the Coast Guard.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to Section 4(a) of this Order, the functions vested in the President by Section 109 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9609">42 U.S.C. 9609</ref>], relating to violations of Section 108(a)(1) of the Act, are delegated to the Coast Guard.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c)(1) The functions vested in the President by Section 108(b) of the Act are delegated to the Secretary of Transportation with respect to all transportation related facilities, including any pipeline, motor vehicle, rolling stock, or aircraft.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to Section 4(a) of this Order, the functions vested in the President by Section 109 of the Act, relating to violations of Section 108(a)(3) of the Act, are delegated to the Secretary of Transportation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Subject to Section 4(a) of this Order, the functions vested in the President by Section 109 of the Act, relating to violations of Section 108(b) of the Act, are delegated to the Secretary of Transportation with respect to all transportation related facilities, including any pipeline, motor vehicle, rolling stock, or aircraft.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d)(1) Subject to subsection (c)(1) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 108(a)(4) and (b) of the Act are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to Section 4(a) of this Order and subsection (c)(3) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 109 of the Act, relating to violations of Section 108(a)(4) and (b) of the Act, are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 8. <i>Employee Protection and Notice to Injured</i>. (a) The functions vested in the President by Section 110(e) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9610/e">42 U.S.C. 9610(e)</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The functions vested in the President by Section 111(g) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9611/g">42 U.S.C. 9611(g)</ref>] are delegated to the Secretaries of Defense and Energy with respect to releases from facilities or vessels under the jurisdiction, custody or control of their departments, respectively, including vessels bare-boat chartered and operated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Subject to subsection (b) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 111(g) of the Act are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 9. <i>Management of the Hazardous Substance Superfund and Claims</i>. (a) The functions vested in the President by Section 111(a) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9611/a">42 U.S.C. 9611(a)</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator, subject to the provisions of this Section and other applicable provisions of this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Administrator shall transfer to other agencies, from the Hazardous Substance Superfund out of sums appropriated, such amounts as the Administrator may determine necessary to carry out the purposes of the Act. These amounts shall be consistent with the President’s Budget, within the total approved by the Congress, unless a revised amount is approved by OMB. Funds appropriated specifically for the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry (“ATSDR”), shall be directly transferred to ATSDR, consistent with fiscally responsible investment of trust fund money.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Administrator shall chair a budget task force composed of representatives of Executive departments and agencies having responsibilities under this Order or the Act. The Administrator shall also, as part of the budget request for the Environmental Protection Agency, submit to OMB a budget for the Hazardous Substance Superfund which is based on recommended levels developed by the budget task force. The Administrator may prescribe reporting and other forms, procedures, and guidelines to be used by the agencies of the Task Force in preparing the budget request, consistent with budgetary reporting requirements issued by OMB. The Administrator shall prescribe forms to agency task force members for reporting the expenditure of funds on a site specific basis.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Administrator and each department and agency head to whom funds are provided pursuant to this Section, with respect to funds provided to them, are authorized in accordance with Section 111(f) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9611/f">42 U.S.C. 9611(f)</ref>] to designate Federal officials who may obligate such funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The functions vested in the President by Section 112 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9612">42 U.S.C. 9612</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator for all claims presented pursuant to Section 111 of the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) The functions vested in the President by Section 111(o) of the Act are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) The functions vested in the President by Section 117(e) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9617/e">42 U.S.C. 9617(e)</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator, to be exercised in consultation with the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(h) The functions vested in the President by Section 123 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9623">42 U.S.C. 9623</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) Funds from the Hazardous Substance Superfund may be used, at the discretion of the Administrator or the Coast Guard, to pay for removal actions for releases or threatened releases from facilities or vessels under the jurisdiction, custody or control of Executive departments and agencies but must be reimbursed to the Hazardous Substance Superfund by such Executive department or agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 10. <i>Federal Facilities</i>. (a) When necessary, prior to selection of a remedial action by the Administrator under Section 120(e)(4)(A) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620/e/4/A">42 U.S.C. 9620(e)(4)(A)</ref>], Executive agencies shall have the opportunity to present their views to the Administrator after using the procedures under Section 1–6 of Executive Order No. 12088 of <date date="1978-10-13">October 13, 1978</date> [set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of this title</ref>], or any other mutually acceptable process. Notwithstanding subsection 1–602 of Executive Order No. 12088, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall facilitate resolution of any issues.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Executive Order No. 12088 of <date date="1978-10-13">October 13, 1978</date>, is amended by renumbering the current Section 1–802 as Section 1–803 and inserting the following new Section 1–802.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“1–802. Nothing in this Order shall create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law by a party against the United States, its agencies, its officers, or any person.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 11. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) The function vested in the President by Section 101(37) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/37">42 U.S.C. 9601(37)</ref>] is delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b)(1) The function vested in the President by Section 105(f) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9605/f">42 U.S.C. 9605(f)</ref>], relating to reporting on minority participation in contracts, is delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to paragraph 1 of this subsection, the functions vested in the President by Section 105(f) of the Act are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies in order to carry out the functions delegated to them by this Order. Each Executive department and agency shall provide to the Administrator any requested information on minority contracting for inclusion in the Section 105(f) annual report.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The functions vested in the President by Section 126(c) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9626/c">42 U.S.C. 9626(c)</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator, to be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The functions vested in the President by Section 301(c) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9651/c">42 U.S.C. 9651(c)</ref>] are delegated to the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Each agency shall have authority to issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the functions delegated to them by this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) The performance of any function under this Order shall be done in consultation with interested Federal departments and agencies represented on the NRT, as well as with any other interested Federal agency.</p>
<p>(g) The following functions vested in the President by the Act which have been delegated or assigned by this Order may be redelegated to the head of any Executive department or agency with his consent: functions set forth in Sections 2 (except subsection (b)), 3, 4(b), 4(c), 4(d), 5(b), 5(c), and 8(c) of this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(h) Executive Order No. 12316 of <date date="1981-08-14">August 14, 1981</date>, is revoked.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 12. <i>Brownfields</i>. (a) The functions vested in the President by Sections 101(39) and (41) and 104(k) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/39">42 U.S.C. 9601(39)</ref>, (41), 9604(k)] are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The functions vested in the President by Section 128(b)(1)(B)(ii) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9628/b/1/B/ii">42 U.S.C. 9628(b)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>] are delegated to the heads of the Executive departments and agencies, to be exercised in consultation with the Administrator, with respect to property subject to their jurisdiction, custody, or control.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The functions vested in the President by Section 128(b)(1)(E) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9628/b/1/E">42 U.S.C. 9628(b)(1)(E)</ref>] are delegated to the heads of Executive departments and agencies in cases where they have acted under subsection (b) of this Section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this Section, the functions vested in the President by Section 128 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9628">42 U.S.C. 9628</ref>] are delegated to the Administrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 13. <i>Preservation of Authorities</i>. Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budget, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 14. <i>General Provision</i>. This order is intended only to improve the internal management of the Federal Government and is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or equity by a party against the United States, its departments, agencies, instrumentalities, or entities, its officers or employees, or any other person.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
