<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbecb2b6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619"><num value="9619">§ 9619.</num><heading> Response action contractors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability of response action contractors</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Response action contractors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person who is a response action contractor with respect to any release or threatened release of a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant from a vessel or facility shall not be liable under this subchapter or under any other Federal law to any person for injuries, costs, damages, expenses, or other liability (including but not limited to claims for indemnification or contribution and claims by third parties for death, personal injury, illness or loss of or damage to property or economic loss) which results from such release or threatened release.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Negligence, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of a release that is caused by conduct of the response action contractor which is negligent, grossly negligent, or which constitutes intentional misconduct.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on warranties; employer liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall affect the liability of any person under any warranty under Federal, State, or common law. Nothing in this subsection shall affect the liability of an employer who is a response action contractor to any employee of such employer under any provision of law, including any provision of any law relating to worker’s compensation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Governmental employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A state employee or an employee of a political subdivision who provides services relating to response action while acting within the scope of his authority as a governmental employee shall have the same exemption from liability (subject to the other provisions of this section) as is provided to the response action contractor under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings provisions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability of other persons</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The defense provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607/b/3">section 9607(b)(3) of this title</ref> shall not be available to any potentially responsible party with respect to any costs or damages caused by any act or omission of a response action contractor. Except as provided in subsection (a)(4) and the preceding sentence, nothing in this section shall affect the liability under this chapter or under any other Federal or State law of any person, other than a response action contractor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Burden of plaintiff</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall affect the plaintiff’s burden of establishing liability under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Indemnification</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may agree to hold harmless and indemnify any response action contractor meeting the requirements of this subsection against any liability (including the expenses of litigation or settlement) for negligence arising out of the contractor’s performance in carrying out response action activities under this subchapter, unless such liability was caused by conduct of the contractor which was grossly negligent or which constituted intentional misconduct.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection shall apply only with respect to a response action carried out under written agreement with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b77-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any Federal agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a State or political subdivision which has entered into a contract or cooperative agreement in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/d/1">section 9604(d)(1) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any potentially responsible party carrying out any agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">section 9622 of this title</ref> (relating to settlements) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref> (relating to abatement).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Source of funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection shall not be subject to section 1301 or 1341 of title 31 or section 6301(a) and (b) of title 41 or to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9662">section 9662 of this title</ref>. For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9611">section 9611 of this title</ref>, amounts expended pursuant to this subsection for indemnification of any response action contractor (except with respect to federally owned or operated facilities) shall be considered governmental response costs incurred pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">section 9604 of this title</ref>. If sufficient funds are unavailable in the Hazardous Substance Superfund established under subchapter A of chapter 98 of title 26 to make payments pursuant to such indemnification or if the Fund is repealed, there are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to make such payments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An indemnification agreement may be provided under this subsection only if the President determines that each of the following requirements are met:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The liability covered by the indemnification agreement exceeds or is not covered by insurance available, at a fair and reasonable price, to the contractor at the time the contractor enters into the contract to provide response action, and adequate insurance to cover such liability is not generally available at the time the response action contract is entered into.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The response action contractor has made diligent efforts to obtain insurance coverage from non-Federal sources to cover such liability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of a response action contract covering more than one facility, the response action contractor agrees to continue to make such diligent efforts each time the contractor begins work under the contract at a new facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability covered</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Indemnification under this subsection shall apply only to response action contractor liability which results from a release of any hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant if such release arises out of response action activities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Deductibles and limits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An indemnification agreement under this subsection shall include deductibles and shall place limits on the amount of indemnification to be made available.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts with potentially responsible parties</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Decision to indemnify</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In deciding whether to enter into an indemnification agreement with a response action contractor carrying out a written contract or agreement with any potentially responsible party, the President shall determine an amount which the potentially responsible party is able to indemnify the contractor. The President may enter into such an indemnification agreement only if the President determines that such amount of indemnification is inadequate to cover any reasonable potential liability of the contractor arising out of the contractor’s negligence in performing the contract or agreement with such party. The President shall make the determinations in the preceding sentences (with respect to the amount and the adequacy of the amount) taking into account the total net assets and resources of potentially responsible parties with respect to the facility at the time of such determinations.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The President may pay a claim under an indemnification agreement referred to in clause (i) for the amount determined under clause (i) only if the contractor has exhausted all administrative, judicial, and common law claims for indemnification against all potentially responsible parties participating in the clean-up of the facility with respect to the liability of the contractor arising out of the contractor’s negligence in performing the contract or agreement with such party. Such indemnification agreement shall require such contractor to pay any deductible established under subparagraph (B) before the contractor may recover any amount from the potentially responsible party or under the indemnification agreement.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> RCRA facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No owner or operator of a facility regulated under the Solid Waste Disposal Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.] may be indemnified under this subsection with respect to such facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/5/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons retained or hired</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A person retained or hired by a person described in subsection (e)(2)(B) shall be eligible for indemnification under this subsection only if the President specifically approves of the retaining or hiring of such person.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost recovery</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607">section 9607 of this title</ref>, amounts expended pursuant to this subsection for indemnification of any person who is a response action contractor with respect to any release or threatened release shall be considered a cost of response incurred by the United States Government with respect to such release.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President shall promulgate regulations for carrying out the provisions of this subsection. Before promulgation of the regulations, the President shall develop guidelines to carry out this section. Development of such guidelines shall include reasonable opportunity for public comment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Comptroller General shall conduct a study in the fiscal year ending <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, on the application of this subsection, including whether indemnification agreements under this subsection are being used, the number of claims that have been filed under such agreements, and the need for this subsection. The Comptroller General shall report the findings of the study to Congress no later than <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The exemption provided under subsection (a) and the authority of the President to offer indemnification under subsection (c) shall not apply to any person covered by the provisions of paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607/a">section 9607(a) of this title</ref> with respect to the release or threatened release concerned if such person would be covered by such provisions even if such person had not carried out any actions referred to in subsection (e) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Response action contract</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “response action contract” means any written contract or agreement entered into by a response action contractor (as defined in paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection) with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any Federal agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a State or political subdivision which has entered into a contract or cooperative agreement in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/d/1">section 9604(d)(1) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any potentially responsible party carrying out an agreement under section 9606 or 9622 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">to provide any remedial action under this chapter at a facility listed on the National Priorities List, or any removal under this chapter, with respect to any release or threatened release of a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant from the facility or to provide any evaluation, planning, engineering, surveying and mapping, design, construction, equipment, or any ancillary services thereto for such facility.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Response action contractor</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “response action contractor” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> any—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecb2b93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> person who enters into a response action contract with respect to any release or threatened release of a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant from a facility and is carrying out such contract; and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003874">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003874"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “and” probably should not appear.</note></content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecb2b94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> person, public or nonprofit private entity, conducting a field demonstration pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b">section 9660(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecb2b95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Recipients <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003875">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003875"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> of grants (including sub-grantees) under section 9660a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003876">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003876"><num>3</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title for the training and education of workers who are or may be engaged in activities related to hazardous waste removal, containment, or emergency response under this chapter; and <sup>1</sup></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any person who is retained or hired by a person described in subparagraph (A) to provide any services relating to a response action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecb2b97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any surety who after <date date="1990-10-16">October 16, 1990</date>, provides a bid, performance or payment bond to a response action contractor, and begins activities to meet its obligations under such bond, but only in connection with such activities or obligations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Insurance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “insurance” means liability insurance which is fair and reasonably priced, as determined by the President, and which is made available at the time the contractor enters into the response action contract to provide response action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Competition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Response action contractors and subcontractors for program management, construction management, architectural and engineering, surveying and mapping, and related services shall be selected in accordance with title IX of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949.<sup>3</sup> The Federal selection procedures shall apply to appropriate contracts negotiated by all Federal governmental agencies involved in carrying out this chapter. Such procedures shall be followed by response action contractors and subcontractors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecb2b9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Surety bonds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbecb2b9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If under sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract and are not waived pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3134">section 3134 of title 40</ref>, they shall be issued in accordance with sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbecb2b9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If under applicable Federal law surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract, no right of action shall accrue on the performance bond issued on such response action contract to or for the use of any person other than the obligee named in the bond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbecb2b9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If under applicable Federal law surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract, unless otherwise provided for by the procuring agency in the bond, in the event of a default, the surety’s liability on a performance bond shall be only for the cost of completion of the contract work in accordance with the plans and specifications less the balance of funds remaining to be paid under the contract, up to the penal sum of the bond. The surety shall in no event be liable on bonds to indemnify or compensate the obligee for loss or liability arising from personal injury or property damage whether or not caused by a breach of the bonded contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbecb2b9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as preempting, limiting, superseding, affecting, applying to, or modifying any State laws, regulations, requirements, rules, practices or procedures. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as affecting, applying to, modifying, limiting, superseding, or preempting any rights, authorities, liabilities, demands, actions, causes of action, losses, judgments, claims, statutes of limitation, or obligations under Federal or State law, which do not arise on or under the bond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbecb2b9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> This subsection shall not apply to bonds executed before <date date="1990-10-17">October 17, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbecb2ba0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/tI/s119">Pub. L. 96–510, title I, § 119</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tI/s119">Pub. L. 99–499, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1662">100 Stat. 1662</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/f/tII/s201">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(f) [title II, § 201]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-187">101 Stat. 1329–187</ref>, 1329–198; <ref href="/us/pl/101/584/s1">Pub. L. 101–584, § 1</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2872">104 Stat. 2872</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIII/s331/a">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 331(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2373">106 Stat. 2373</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tIII">Pub. L. 105–276, title III</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2497">112 Stat. 2497</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbecb2ba1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbecb2ba2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbecb2ba3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1), (e)(1), (2)(A)(iii), and (f), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/510">Pub. L. 96–510</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2767">94 Stat. 2767</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">section 9601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Solid Waste Disposal Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(5)(D), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/89/272">Pub. L. 89–272</ref>, <date date="1965-10-20">Oct. 20, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/997">79 Stat. 997</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2795">90 Stat. 2795</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 82 (§ 6901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">section 6901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9660a">Section 9660a of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(A)(iii), was in the original “section 126” probably meaning <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/s126">section 126 of Pub. L. 99–499</ref>, title I, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1690">100 Stat. 1690</ref>. Subsecs. (a) to (f) of section 126, which relate to worker protection standards, are set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s655">section 655 of Title 29</ref>, Labor. Subsec. (g) of section 126, which relates to grants for training and education of workers who are or may be engaged in activities related to hazardous waste removal, etc., is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9660a">section 9660a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-06-30/ch288">act June 30, 1949, ch. 288</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/377">63 Stat. 377</ref>. Title IX of the Act, which was classified generally to subchapter VI (§ 541 et seq.) of chapter 10 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, was repealed and reenacted by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217">Pub. L. 107–217</ref>, §§ 1, 6(b), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>, 1304, as chapter 11 (§ 1101 et seq.) of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works. For disposition of sections of former Title 40 to revised Title 40, see Table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s101">section 101 of Title 40</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbecb2ba4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (c)(3), “section 6301(a) and (b) of title 41” substituted for “section 3732 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s11">41 U.S.C. 11</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (g)(1), “sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40” substituted for “the Act of <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270a–270d">40 U.S.C. 270a–270d</ref>), commonly referred to as the ‘Miller Act’ ” and for “such Act of <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3134">section 3134 of title 40</ref>” substituted for “the Act of <date date="1941-04-29">April 29, 1941</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270e–270f">40 U.S.C. 270e–270f</ref>)”, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbecb2ba5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (e)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276">Pub. L. 105–276</ref> struck out “and before <date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>,” after “1990,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276">Pub. L. 105–276</ref> struck out “, or after <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (e)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s321/a/1/A">Pub. L. 102–484, § 321(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1996-01-01">January 1, 1996</date>,” for “<date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s331/a/2">Pub. L. 102–484, § 331(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “the Act of <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270a–270d">40 U.S.C. 270a–270d</ref>), commonly referred to as the ‘Miller Act’,” for “the Miller Act, 40 U.S.C. sections 270a–270f,”, inserted “and are not waived pursuant to the Act of <date date="1941-04-29">April 29, 1941</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270e–270f">40 U.S.C. 270e–270f</ref>)”, and substituted “in accordance with such Act of <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>.” for “in accordance with 40 U.S.C. sections 270a–270d.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s331/a/1/B">Pub. L. 102–484, § 331(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>” for “<date date="1992-12-31">December 31, 1992</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (e)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/584/s1/1">Pub. L. 101–584, § 1(1)</ref>, (2), added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/584/s1/3">Pub. L. 101–584, § 1(3)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (e)(2)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref> added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbecb2ba6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbecb2ba7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination of Titles I to IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Any provision of titles I to IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref>, imposing any tax, premium, or fee; establishing any trust fund; or authorizing expenditures from any trust fund, to have no force or effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/s531">section 531 of Pub. L. 99–499</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
