<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbecfe654-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622"><num value="9622">§ 9622.</num><heading> Settlements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe655-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to enter into agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President, in his discretion, may enter into an agreement with any person (including the owner or operator of the facility from which a release or substantial threat of release emanates, or any other potentially responsible person), to perform any response action (including any action described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref>) if the President determines that such action will be done properly by such person. Whenever practicable and in the public interest, as determined by the President, the President shall act to facilitate agreements under this section that are in the public interest and consistent with the National Contingency Plan in order to expedite effective remedial actions and minimize litigation. If the President decides not to use the procedures in this section, the President shall notify in writing potentially responsible parties at the facility of such decision and the reasons why use of the procedures is inappropriate. A decision of the President to use or not to use the procedures in this section is not subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe656-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements with potentially responsible parties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe657-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Mixed funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An agreement under this section may provide that the President will reimburse the parties to the agreement from the Fund, with interest, for certain costs of actions under the agreement that the parties have agreed to perform but which the President has agreed to finance. In any case in which the President provides such reimbursement, the President shall make all reasonable efforts to recover the amount of such reimbursement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607">section 9607 of this title</ref> or under other relevant authorities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe658-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reviewability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President’s decisions regarding the availability of fund financing under this subsection shall not be subject to judicial review under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe659-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, as part of any agreement, the President will be carrying out any action and the parties will be paying amounts to the President, the President may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, retain and use such amounts for purposes of carrying out the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe65a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Future obligation of Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a completed remedial action pursuant to an agreement described in paragraph (1), the Fund shall be subject to an obligation for subsequent remedial actions at the same facility but only to the extent that such subsequent actions are necessary by reason of the failure of the original remedial action. Such obligation shall be in a proportion equal to, but not exceeding, the proportion contributed by the Fund for the original remedial action. The Fund’s obligation for such future remedial action may be met through Fund expenditures or through payment, following settlement or enforcement action, by parties who were not signatories to the original agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe65b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of agreement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe65c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the President has entered into an agreement under this section, the liability to the United States under this chapter of each party to the agreement, including any future liability to the United States, arising from the release or threatened release that is the subject of the agreement shall be limited as provided in the agreement pursuant to a covenant not to sue in accordance with subsection (f). A covenant not to sue may provide that future liability to the United States of a settling potentially responsible party under the agreement may be limited to the same proportion as that established in the original settlement agreement. Nothing in this section shall limit or otherwise affect the authority of any court to review in the consent decree process under subsection (d) any covenant not to sue contained in an agreement under this section. In determining the extent to which the liability of parties to an agreement shall be limited pursuant to a covenant not to sue, the President shall be guided by the principle that a more complete covenant not to sue shall be provided for a more permanent remedy undertaken by such parties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe65d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions against other persons</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If an agreement has been entered into under this section, the President may take any action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref> against any person who is not a party to the agreement, once the period for submitting a proposal under subsection (e)(2)(B) has expired. Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect either of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe65e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The liability of any person under section 9606 or 9607 of this title with respect to any costs or damages which are not included in the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe65f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The authority of the President to maintain an action under this chapter against any person who is not a party to the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe660-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe661-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Cleanup agreements</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe662-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent decree</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Whenever the President enters into an agreement under this section with any potentially responsible party with respect to remedial action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref>, following approval of the agreement by the Attorney General, except as otherwise provided in the case of certain administrative settlements referred to in subsection (g), the agreement shall be entered in the appropriate United States district court as a consent decree. The President need not make any finding regarding an imminent and substantial endangerment to the public health or the environment in connection with any such agreement or consent decree.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe663-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The entry of any consent decree under this subsection shall not be construed to be an acknowledgment by the parties that the release or threatened release concerned constitutes an imminent and substantial endangerment to the public health or welfare or the environment. Except as otherwise provided in the Federal Rules of Evidence, the participation by any party in the process under this section shall not be considered an admission of liability for any purpose, and the fact of such participation shall not be admissible in any judicial or administrative proceeding, including a subsequent proceeding under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe664-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Structure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The President may fashion a consent decree so that the entering of such decree and compliance with such decree or with any determination or agreement made pursuant to this section shall not be considered an admission of liability for any purpose.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe665-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe666-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing of proposed judgment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">At least 30 days before a final judgment is entered under paragraph (1), the proposed judgment shall be filed with the court.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe667-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Opportunity for comment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Attorney General shall provide an opportunity to persons who are not named as parties to the action to comment on the proposed judgment before its entry by the court as a final judgment. The Attorney General shall consider, and file with the court, any written comments, views, or allegations relating to the proposed judgment. The Attorney General may withdraw or withhold its consent to the proposed judgment if the comments, views, and allegations concerning the judgment disclose facts or considerations which indicate that the proposed judgment is inappropriate, improper, or inadequate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe668-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> 9604(b) agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the President enters into an agreement under this section with any potentially responsible party with respect to action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref>, the President shall issue an order or enter into a decree setting forth the obligations of such party. The United States district court for the district in which the release or threatened release occurs may enforce such order or decree.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe669-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Special notice procedures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe66a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the President determines that a period of negotiation under this subsection would facilitate an agreement with potentially responsible parties for taking response action (including any action described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref>) and would expedite remedial action, the President shall so notify all such parties and shall provide them with information concerning each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe66b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The names and addresses of potentially responsible parties (including owners and operators and other persons referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607/a">section 9607(a) of this title</ref>), to the extent such information is available.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe66c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To the extent such information is available, the volume and nature of substances contributed by each potentially responsible party identified at the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe66d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A ranking by volume of the substances at the facility, to the extent such information is available.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The President shall make the information referred to in this paragraph available in advance of notice under this paragraph upon the request of a potentially responsible party in accordance with procedures provided by the President. The provisions of subsection (e) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">section 9604 of this title</ref> regarding protection of confidential information apply to information provided under this paragraph. Disclosure of information generated by the President under this section to persons other than the Congress, or any duly authorized Committee thereof, is subject to other privileges or protections provided by law, including (but not limited to) those applicable to attorney work product. Nothing contained in this paragraph or in other provisions of this chapter shall be construed, interpreted, or applied to diminish the required disclosure of information under other provisions of this or other Federal or State laws.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe66e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Negotiation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe66f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Moratorium</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in this subsection, the President may not commence action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/a">section 9604(a) of this title</ref> or take any action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref> for 120 days after providing notice and information under this subsection with respect to such action. Except as provided in this subsection, the President may not commence a remedial investigation and feasibility study under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref> for 90 days after providing notice and information under this subsection with respect to such action. The President may commence any additional studies or investigations authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref>, including remedial design, during the negotiation period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe670-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Proposals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Persons receiving notice and information under paragraph (1) of this subsection with respect to action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref> shall have 60 days from the date of receipt of such notice to make a proposal to the President for undertaking or financing the action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref>. Persons receiving notice and information under paragraph (1) of this subsection with respect to action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref> shall have 60 days from the date of receipt of such notice to make a proposal to the President for undertaking or financing the action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe671-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional parties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If an additional potentially responsible party is identified during the negotiation period or after an agreement has been entered into under this subsection concerning a release or threatened release, the President may bring the additional party into the negotiation or enter into a separate agreement with such party.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe672-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Preliminary allocation of responsibility</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe673-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The President shall develop guidelines for preparing nonbinding preliminary allocations of responsibility. In developing these guidelines the President may include such factors as the President considers relevant, such as: volume, toxicity, mobility, strength of evidence, ability to pay, litigative risks, public interest considerations, precedential value, and inequities and aggravating factors. When it would expedite settlements under this section and remedial action, the President may, after completion of the remedial investigation and feasibility study, provide a nonbinding preliminary allocation of responsibility which allocates percentages of the total cost of response among potentially responsible parties at the facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe674-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">To collect information necessary or appropriate for performing the allocation under subparagraph (A) or for otherwise implementing this section, the President may by subpoena require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of reports, papers, documents, answers to questions, and other information that the President deems necessary. Witnesses shall be paid the same fees and mileage that are paid witnesses in the courts of the United States. In the event of contumacy or failure or refusal of any person to obey any such subpoena, any district court of the United States in which venue is proper shall have jurisdiction to order any such person to comply with such subpoena. Any failure to obey such an order of the court is punishable by the court as a contempt thereof.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe675-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The nonbinding preliminary allocation of responsibility shall not be admissible as evidence in any proceeding, and no court shall have jurisdiction to review the nonbinding preliminary allocation of responsibility. The nonbinding preliminary allocation of responsibility shall not constitute an apportionment or other statement on the divisibility of harm or causation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe676-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The costs incurred by the President in producing the nonbinding preliminary allocation of responsibility shall be reimbursed by the potentially responsible parties whose offer is accepted by the President. Where an offer under this section is not accepted, such costs shall be considered costs of response.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe677-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/3/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Decision to reject offer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Where the President, in his discretion, has provided a nonbinding preliminary allocation of responsibility and the potentially responsible parties have made a substantial offer providing for response to the President which he rejects, the reasons for the rejection shall be provided in a written explanation. The President’s decision to reject such an offer shall not be subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe678-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to propose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the President determines that a good faith proposal for undertaking or financing action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref> has not been submitted within 60 days of the provision of notice pursuant to this subsection, the President may thereafter commence action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/a">section 9604(a) of this title</ref> or take an action against any person under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref>. If the President determines that a good faith proposal for undertaking or financing action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref> has not been submitted within 60 days after the provision of notice pursuant to this subsection, the President may thereafter commence action under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/b">section 9604(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe679-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Significant threats</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall limit the President’s authority to undertake response or enforcement action regarding a significant threat to public health or the environment within the negotiation period established by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe67a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Inconsistent response action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">When either the President, or a potentially responsible party pursuant to an administrative order or consent decree under this chapter, has initiated a remedial investigation and feasibility study for a particular facility under this chapter, no potentially responsible party may undertake any remedial action at the facility unless such remedial action has been authorized by the President.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe67b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Covenant not to sue</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe67c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Discretionary covenants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may, in his discretion, provide any person with a covenant not to sue concerning any liability to the United States under this chapter, including future liability, resulting from a release or threatened release of a hazardous substance addressed by a remedial action, whether that action is onsite or offsite, if each of the following conditions is met:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe67d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The covenant not to sue is in the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe67e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The covenant not to sue would expedite response action consistent with the National Contingency Plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9605">section 9605 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe67f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The person is in full compliance with a consent decree under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9606">section 9606 of this title</ref> (including a consent decree entered into in accordance with this section) for response to the release or threatened release concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe680-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The response action has been approved by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe681-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Special covenants not to sue</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any person to whom the President is authorized under paragraph (1) of this subsection to provide a covenant not to sue, for the portion of remedial action—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe682-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which involves the transport and secure disposition offsite of hazardous substances in a facility meeting the requirements of sections 6924(c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (m), (<i>o</i>), (p), (u), and (v) and 6925(c) of this title, where the President has rejected a proposed remedial action that is consistent with the National Contingency Plan that does not include such offsite disposition and has thereafter required offsite disposition; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe683-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which involves the treatment of hazardous substances so as to destroy, eliminate, or permanently immobilize the hazardous constituents of such substances, such that, in the judgment of the President, the substances no longer present any current or currently foreseeable future significant risk to public health, welfare or the environment, no byproduct of the treatment or destruction process presents any significant hazard to public health, welfare or the environment, and all byproducts are themselves treated, destroyed, or contained in a manner which assures that such byproducts do not present any current or currently foreseeable future significant risk to public health, welfare or the environment,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the President shall provide such person with a covenant not to sue with respect to future liability to the United States under this chapter for a future release or threatened release of hazardous substances from such facility, and a person provided such covenant not to sue shall not be liable to the United States under section 9606 or 9607 of this title with respect to such release or threatened release at a future time.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe684-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement that remedial action be completed</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A covenant not to sue concerning future liability to the United States shall not take effect until the President certifies that remedial action has been completed in accordance with the requirements of this chapter at the facility that is the subject of such covenant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe685-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In assessing the appropriateness of a covenant not to sue under paragraph (1) and any condition to be included in a covenant not to sue under paragraph (1) or (2), the President shall consider whether the covenant or condition is in the public interest on the basis of such factors as the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe686-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The effectiveness and reliability of the remedy, in light of the other alternative remedies considered for the facility concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe687-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The nature of the risks remaining at the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe688-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The extent to which performance standards are included in the order or decree.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe689-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The extent to which the response action provides a complete remedy for the facility, including a reduction in the hazardous nature of the substances at the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe68a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The extent to which the technology used in the response action is demonstrated to be effective.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe68b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Whether the Fund or other sources of funding would be available for any additional remedial actions that might eventually be necessary at the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe68c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/4/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Whether the remedial action will be carried out, in whole or in significant part, by the responsible parties themselves.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe68d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Satisfactory performance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any covenant not to sue under this subsection shall be subject to the satisfactory performance by such party of its obligations under the agreement concerned.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe68e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional condition for future liability</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbecfe68f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except for the portion of the remedial action which is subject to a covenant not to sue under paragraph (2) or under subsection (g) (relating to de minimis settlements), a covenant not to sue a person concerning future liability to the United States shall include an exception to the covenant that allows the President to sue such person concerning future liability resulting from the release or threatened release that is the subject of the covenant where such liability arises out of conditions which are unknown at the time the President certifies under paragraph (3) that remedial action has been completed at the facility concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbecfe690-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In extraordinary circumstances, the President may determine, after assessment of relevant factors such as those referred to in paragraph (4) and volume, toxicity, mobility, strength of evidence, ability to pay, litigative risks, public interest considerations, precedential value, and inequities and aggravating factors, not to include the exception referred to in subparagraph (A) if other terms, conditions, or requirements of the agreement containing the covenant not to sue are sufficient to provide all reasonable assurances that public health and the environment will be protected from any future releases at or from the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbecfe691-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/f/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The President is authorized to include any provisions allowing future enforcement action under section 9606 or 9607 of this title that in the discretion of the President are necessary and appropriate to assure protection of public health, welfare, and the environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe692-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> De minimis settlements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe693-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited final settlement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever practicable and in the public interest, as determined by the President, the President shall as promptly as possible reach a final settlement with a potentially responsible party in an administrative or civil action under section 9606 or 9607 of this title if such settlement involves only a minor portion of the response costs at the facility concerned and, in the judgment of the President, the conditions in either of the following subparagraph (A) or (B) are met:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe694-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Both of the following are minimal in comparison to other hazardous substances at the facility:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecfe695-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The amount of the hazardous substances contributed by that party to the facility.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecfe696-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The toxic or other hazardous effects of the substances contributed by that party to the facility.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbecfe697-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The potentially responsible party—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecfe698-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is the owner of the real property on or in which the facility is located;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecfe699-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> did not conduct or permit the generation, transportation, storage, treatment, or disposal of any hazardous substance at the facility; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbecfe69a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> did not contribute to the release or threat of release of a hazardous substance at the facility through any action or omission.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">This subparagraph (B) does not apply if the potentially responsible party purchased the real property with actual or constructive knowledge that the property was used for the generation, transportation, storage, treatment, or disposal of any hazardous substance.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe69b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Covenant not to sue</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may provide a covenant not to sue with respect to the facility concerned to any party who has entered into a settlement under this subsection unless such a covenant would be inconsistent with the public interest as determined under subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe69c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President shall reach any such settlement or grant any such covenant not to sue as soon as possible after the President has available the information necessary to reach such a settlement or grant such a covenant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe69d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent decree or administrative order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A settlement under this subsection shall be entered as a consent decree or embodied in an administrative order setting forth the terms of the settlement. In the case of any facility where the total response costs exceed $500,000 (excluding interest), if the settlement is embodied as an administrative order, the order may be issued only with the prior written approval of the Attorney General. If the Attorney General or his designee has not approved or disapproved the order within 30 days of this referral, the order shall be deemed to be approved unless the Attorney General and the Administrator have agreed to extend the time. The district court for the district in which the release or threatened release occurs may enforce any such administrative order.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe69e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A party who has resolved its liability to the United States under this subsection shall not be liable for claims for contribution regarding matters addressed in the settlement. Such settlement does not discharge any of the other potentially responsible parties unless its terms so provide, but it reduces the potential liability of the others by the amount of the settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe69f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Settlements with other potentially responsible parties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the authority of the President to reach settlements with other potentially responsible parties under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe6a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction in settlement amount based on limited ability to pay</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbecfe6a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The condition for settlement under this paragraph is that the potentially responsible party is a person who demonstrates to the President an inability or a limited ability to pay response costs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In determining whether or not a demonstration is made under subparagraph (A) by a person, the President shall take into consideration the ability of the person to pay response costs and still maintain its basic business operations, including consideration of the overall financial condition of the person and demonstrable constraints on the ability of the person to raise revenues.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A person requesting settlement under this paragraph shall promptly provide the President with all relevant information needed to determine the ability of the person to pay response costs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative payment methods</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the President determines that a person is unable to pay its total settlement amount at the time of settlement, the President shall consider such alternative payment methods as may be necessary or appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional conditions for expedited settlements</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver of claims</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The President shall require, as a condition for settlement under this subsection, that a potentially responsible party waive all of the claims (including a claim for contribution under this chapter) that the party may have against other potentially responsible parties for response costs incurred with respect to the facility, unless the President determines that requiring a waiver would be unjust.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to comply</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The President may decline to offer a settlement to a potentially responsible party under this subsection if the President determines that the potentially responsible party has failed to comply with any request for access or information or an administrative subpoena issued by the President under this chapter or has impeded or is impeding, through action or inaction, the performance of a response action with respect to the facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/8/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibility to provide information and access</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A potentially responsible party that enters into a settlement under this subsection shall not be relieved of the responsibility to provide any information or access requested in accordance with subsection (e)(3)(B) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/e">section 9604(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis of determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the President determines that a potentially responsible party is not eligible for settlement under this subsection, the President shall provide the reasons for the determination in writing to the potentially responsible party that requested a settlement under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">As soon as practicable after receipt of sufficient information to make a determination, the President shall notify any person that the President determines is eligible under paragraph (1) of the person’s eligibility for an expedited settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> No judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A determination by the President under paragraph (7), (8), (9), or (10) shall not be subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/g/12"><num value="12" class="bold">(12)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of settlement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After a settlement under this subsection becomes final with respect to a facility, the President shall promptly notify potentially responsible parties at the facility that have not resolved their liability to the United States of the settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost recovery settlement authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to settle</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The head of any department or agency with authority to undertake a response action under this chapter pursuant to the national contingency plan may consider, compromise, and settle a claim under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607">section 9607 of this title</ref> for costs incurred by the United States Government if the claim has not been referred to the Department of Justice for further action. In the case of any facility where the total response costs exceed $500,000 (excluding interest), any claim referred to in the preceding sentence may be compromised and settled only with the prior written approval of the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of arbitration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Arbitration in accordance with regulations promulgated under this subsection may be used as a method of settling claims of the United States where the total response costs for the facility concerned do not exceed $500,000 (excluding interest). After consultation with the Attorney General, the department or agency head may establish and publish regulations for the use of arbitration or settlement under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Recovery of claims</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If any person fails to pay a claim that has been settled under this subsection, the department or agency head shall request the Attorney General to bring a civil action in an appropriate district court to recover the amount of such claim, plus costs, attorneys’ fees, and interest from the date of the settlement. In such an action, the terms of the settlement shall not be subject to review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Claims for contribution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person who has resolved its liability to the United States under this subsection shall not be liable for claims for contribution regarding matters addressed in the settlement. Such settlement shall not discharge any of the other potentially liable persons unless its terms so provide, but it reduces the potential liability of the others by the amount of the settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Settlement procedures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At least 30 days before any settlement (including any settlement arrived at through arbitration) may become final under subsection (h), or under subsection (g) in the case of a settlement embodied in an administrative order, the head of the department or agency which has jurisdiction over the proposed settlement shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the proposed settlement. The notice shall identify the facility concerned and the parties to the proposed settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Comment period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For a 30-day period beginning on the date of publication of notice under paragraph (1) of a proposed settlement, the head of the department or agency which has jurisdiction over the proposed settlement shall provide an opportunity for persons who are not parties to the proposed settlement to file written comments relating to the proposed settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of comments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The head of the department or agency shall consider any comments filed under paragraph (2) in determining whether or not to consent to the proposed settlement and may withdraw or withhold consent to the proposed settlement if such comments disclose facts or considerations which indicate the proposed settlement is inappropriate, improper, or inadequate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Natural resources</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of trustee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Where a release or threatened release of any hazardous substance that is the subject of negotiations under this section may have resulted in damages to natural resources under the trusteeship of the United States, the President shall notify the Federal natural resource trustee of the negotiations and shall encourage the participation of such trustee in the negotiations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Covenant not to sue</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An agreement under this section may contain a covenant not to sue under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607/a/4/C">section 9607(a)(4)(C) of this title</ref> for damages to natural resources under the trusteeship of the United States resulting from the release or threatened release of hazardous substances that is the subject of the agreement, but only if the Federal natural resource trustee has agreed in writing to such covenant. The Federal natural resource trustee may agree to such covenant if the potentially responsible party agrees to undertake appropriate actions necessary to protect and restore the natural resources damaged by such release or threatened release of hazardous substances.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Section not applicable to vessels</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not apply to releases from a vessel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A potentially responsible party which is a party to an administrative order or consent decree entered pursuant to an agreement under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620">section 9620 of this title</ref> (relating to Federal facilities) or which is a party to an agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620">section 9620 of this title</ref> and which fails or refuses to comply with any term or condition of the order, decree or agreement shall be subject to a civil penalty in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9609">section 9609 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed257bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9622/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of general principles of law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of consent decrees and other settlements under this section (including covenants not to sue), no provision of this chapter shall be construed to preclude or otherwise affect the applicability of general principles of law regarding the setting aside or modification of consent decrees or other settlements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbed257bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/tI/s122">Pub. L. 96–510, title I, § 122</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tI/s122/a">Pub. L. 99–499, title I, § 122(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1678">100 Stat. 1678</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/118/tI/s102/b">Pub. L. 107–118, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-11">Jan. 11, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2359">115 Stat. 2359</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbed257bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbed257be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbed257bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/510">Pub. L. 96–510</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2767">94 Stat. 2767</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">section 9601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Evidence, referred to in subsec. (d)(1)(B), are set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbed257c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (g)(7) to (12). <ref href="/us/pl/107/118">Pub. L. 107–118</ref> added pars. (7) to (12).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbed257c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed257c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect on Concluded Actions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/118">Pub. L. 107–118</ref> not to apply to or in any way affect any settlement lodged in, or judgment issued by, a United States District Court, or any administrative settlement or order entered into or issued by the United States or any State, before <date date="2002-01-11">Jan. 11, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/118/s103">section 103 of Pub. L. 107–118</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9607">section 9607 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed257c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application to Section</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/74/dC/tII">Pub. L. 119–74, div. C, title II</ref>, <date date="2026-01-23">Jan. 23, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/128">140 Stat. 128</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/74/dC/tII">“That section 122(b)(3) of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622/b/3">42 U.S.C. 9622(b)(3)</ref>) shall be applied in this fiscal year by inserting before the period: ‘, including for the hire, maintenance, and operation of aircraft”</quotedContent>
’.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed257c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination of Titles I to IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Any provision of titles I to IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref>, imposing any tax, premium, or fee; establishing any trust fund; or authorizing expenditures from any trust fund, to have no force or effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/s531">section 531 of Pub. L. 99–499</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
