<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbed4a1b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652"><num value="9652">§ 9652.</num><heading> Effective dates; savings provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbed4a1b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Unless otherwise provided, all provisions of this chapter shall be effective on <date date="1980-12-11">December 11, 1980</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbed4a1b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any regulation issued pursuant to any provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1321">section 1321 of title 33</ref> which is repealed or superseded by this chapter and which is in effect on the date immediately preceding the effective date of this chapter shall be deemed to be a regulation issued pursuant to the authority of this chapter and shall remain in full force and effect unless or until superseded by new regulations issued thereunder.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbed4a1ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> Any regulation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbed4a1bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> respecting financial responsibility,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbed4a1bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> issued pursuant to any provision of law repealed or superseded by this chapter, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbed4a1bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in effect on the date immediately preceding the effective date of this chapter shall be deemed to be a regulation issued pursuant to the authority of this chapter and shall remain in full force and effect unless or until superseded by new regulations issued thereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbed4a1be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9652/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Nothing in this chapter shall affect or modify in any way the obligations or liabilities of any person under other Federal or State law, including common law, with respect to releases of hazardous substances or other pollutants or contaminants. The provisions of this chapter shall not be considered, interpreted, or construed in any way as reflecting a determination, in part or whole, of policy regarding the inapplicability of strict liability, or strict liability doctrines, to activities relating to hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants or other such activities.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbed4a1bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 96–510, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2808">94 Stat. 2808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbed4a1c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbed4a1c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbed4a1c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), (c)(2), (3), and (d), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/510">Pub. L. 96–510</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2767">94 Stat. 2767</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">section 9601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
