<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbed4a1e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9657"><num value="9657">§ 9657.</num><heading> Separability; contribution</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter, or the application of any provision of this chapter to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances and the remainder of this chapter shall not be affected thereby. If an administrative settlement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">section 9622 of this title</ref> has the effect of limiting any person’s right to obtain contribution from any party to such settlement, and if the effect of such limitation would constitute a taking without just compensation in violation of the fifth amendment of the Constitution of the United States, such person shall not be entitled, under other laws of the United States, to recover compensation from the United States for such taking, but in any such case, such limitation on the right to obtain contribution shall be treated as having no force and effect.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbed4a1e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/tIII/s308">Pub. L. 96–510, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2811">94 Stat. 2811</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tI/s122/b">Pub. L. 99–499, title I, § 122(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1688">100 Stat. 1688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbed4a1e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbed4a1e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbed4a1e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/510">Pub. L. 96–510</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2767">94 Stat. 2767</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, which enacted this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6911a">section 6911a of this title</ref>, and sections 4611, 4612, 4661, 4662, 4681, and 4682 of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code, amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6911">section 6911 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1364">section 1364 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters, and <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s11901">section 11901 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and enacted provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6911">section 6911 of this title</ref> and sections 1 and 4611 of Title 26. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">section 9601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbed4a1e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref> inserted sentence at end relating to administrative settlements under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">section 9622 of this title</ref> which have effect of limiting any person’s right to obtain contribution from any party to such settlement.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
