<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbed4a212-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660"><num value="9660">§ 9660.</num><heading> Research, development, and demonstration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed4a213-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Hazardous substance research and training</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed4a214-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorities of Secretary</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the Secretary), in consultation with the Administrator, shall establish and support a basic research and training program (through grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts) consisting of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed4a215-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Basic research (including epidemiologic and ecologic studies) which may include each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed4a216-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Advanced techniques for the detection, assessment, and evaluation of the effects on human health of hazardous substances.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed4a217-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Methods to assess the risks to human health presented by hazardous substances.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed71218-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Methods and technologies to detect hazardous substances in the environment and basic biological, chemical, and physical methods to reduce the amount and toxicity of hazardous substances.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71219-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Training, which may include each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed7121a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Short courses and continuing education for State and local health and environment agency personnel and other personnel engaged in the handling of hazardous substances, in the management of facilities at which hazardous substances are located, and in the evaluation of the hazards to human health presented by such facilities.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed7121b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Graduate or advanced training in environmental and occupational health and safety and in the public health and engineering aspects of hazardous waste control.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed7121c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Graduate training in the geosciences, including hydrogeology, geological engineering, geophysics, geochemistry, and related fields necessary to meet professional personnel needs in the public and private sectors and to effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7121d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Director of NIEHS</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director of the National Institute for Environmental Health Sciences shall cooperate fully with the relevant Federal agencies referred to in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (5) in carrying out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7121e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Recipients of grants, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A grant, cooperative agreement, or contract may be made or entered into under paragraph (1) with an accredited institution of higher education. The institution may carry out the research or training under the grant, cooperative agreement, or contract through contracts, including contracts with any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed7121f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Generators of hazardous wastes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71220-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Persons involved in the detection, assessment, evaluation, and treatment of hazardous substances.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71221-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Owners and operators of facilities at which hazardous substances are located.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71222-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> State and local governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71223-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In making grants and entering into cooperative agreements and contracts under this subsection, the Secretary shall act through the Director of the National Institute for Environmental Health Sciences. In considering the allocation of funds for training purposes, the Director shall ensure that at least one grant, cooperative agreement, or contract shall be awarded for training described in each of clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of paragraph (1)(B). Where applicable, the Director may choose to operate training activities in cooperation with the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health. The procedures applicable to grants and contracts under title IV of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">42 U.S.C. 281</ref> et seq.] shall be followed under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71224-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory council</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To assist in the implementation of this subsection and to aid in the coordination of research and demonstration and training activities funded from the Fund under this section, the Secretary shall appoint an advisory council (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “Advisory Council”) which shall consist of representatives of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71225-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The relevant Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71226-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The chemical industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71227-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The toxic waste management industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71228-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Institutions of higher education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71229-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> State and local health and environmental agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed7122a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/5/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The general public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7122b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Planning</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within nine months after <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institute for Environmental Health Sciences, shall issue a plan for the implementation of paragraph (1). The plan shall include priorities for actions under paragraph (1) and include research and training relevant to scientific and technological issues resulting from site specific hazardous substance response experience. The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, take appropriate steps to coordinate program activities under this plan with the activities of other Federal agencies in order to avoid duplication of effort. The plan shall be consistent with the need for the development of new technologies for meeting the goals of response actions in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The Advisory Council shall be provided an opportunity to review and comment on the plan and priorities and assist appropriate coordination among the relevant Federal agencies referred to in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7122c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative or innovative treatment technology research and demonstration program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7122d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator is authorized and directed to carry out a program of research, evaluation, testing, development, and demonstration of alternative or innovative treatment technologies (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “program”) which may be utilized in response actions to achieve more permanent protection of human health and welfare and the environment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7122e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The program shall be administered by the Administrator, acting through an office of technology demonstration and shall be coordinated with programs carried out by the Office of Solid Waste and Emergency Response and the Office of Research and Development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7122f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts and grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the program, the Administrator is authorized to enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, and make grants to, persons, public entities, and nonprofit private entities which are exempt from tax under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/3">section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref>. The Administrator shall, to the maximum extent possible, enter into appropriate cost sharing arrangements under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71230-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of sites</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the program, the Administrator may arrange for the use of sites at which a response may be undertaken under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">section 9604 of this title</ref> for the purposes of carrying out research, testing, evaluation, development, and demonstration projects. Each such project shall be carried out under such terms and conditions as the Administrator shall require to assure the protection of human health and the environment and to assure adequate control by the Administrator of the research, testing, evaluation, development, and demonstration activities at the site.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71231-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstration assistance</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71232-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Program components</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The demonstration assistance program shall include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed71233-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The publication of a solicitation and the evaluation of applications for demonstration projects utilizing alternative or innovative technologies.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed71234-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The selection of sites which are suitable for the testing and evaluation of innovative technologies.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed71235-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The development of detailed plans for innovative technology demonstration projects.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed71236-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The supervision of such demonstration projects and the providing of quality assurance for data obtained.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbed71237-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The evaluation of the results of alternative innovative technology demonstration projects and the determination of whether or not the technologies used are effective and feasible.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71238-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Solicitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 90 days after <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>, and no less often than once every 12 months thereafter, the Administrator shall publish a solicitation for innovative or alternative technologies at a stage of development suitable for full-scale demonstrations at sites at which a response action may be undertaken under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">section 9604 of this title</ref>. The purpose of any such project shall be to demonstrate the use of an alternative or innovative treatment technology with respect to hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants which are located at the site or which are to be removed from the site. The solicitation notice shall prescribe information to be included in the application, including technical and economic data derived from the applicant’s own research and development efforts, and other information sufficient to permit the Administrator to assess the technology’s potential and the types of remedial action to which it may be applicable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71239-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any person and any public or private nonprofit entity may submit an application to the Administrator in response to the solicitation. The application shall contain a proposed demonstration plan setting forth how and when the project is to be carried out and such other information as the Administrator may require.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7123a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Project selection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In selecting technologies to be demonstrated, the Administrator shall fully review the applications submitted and shall consider at least the criteria specified in paragraph (7). The Administrator shall select or refuse to select a project for demonstration under this subsection within 90 days of receiving the completed application for such project. In the case of a refusal to select the project, the Administrator shall notify the applicant within such 90-day period of the reasons for his refusal.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7123b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Site selection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator shall propose 10 sites at which a response may be undertaken under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">section 9604 of this title</ref> to be the location of any demonstration project under this subsection within 60 days after the close of the public comment period. After an opportunity for notice and public comment, the Administrator shall select such sites and projects. In selecting any such site, the Administrator shall take into account the applicant’s technical data and preferences either for onsite operation or for utilizing the site as a source of hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants to be treated offsite.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7123c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstration plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 60 days after the selection of the site under this paragraph to be the location of a demonstration project, the Administrator shall establish a final demonstration plan for the project, based upon the demonstration plan contained in the application for the project. Such plan shall clearly set forth how and when the demonstration project will be carried out.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7123d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Supervision and testing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each demonstration project under this subsection shall be performed by the applicant, or by a person satisfactory to the applicant, under the supervision of the Administrator. The Administrator shall enter into a written agreement with each applicant granting the Administrator the responsibility and authority for testing procedures, quality control, monitoring, and other measurements necessary to determine and evaluate the results of the demonstration project. The Administrator may pay the costs of testing, monitoring, quality control, and other measurements required by the Administrator to determine and evaluate the results of the demonstration project, and the limitations established by subparagraph (J) shall not apply to such costs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7123e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/H"><num value="H" class="bold">(H)</num><heading class="bold"> Project completion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each demonstration project under this subsection shall be completed within such time as is established in the demonstration plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7123f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Extensions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator may extend any deadline established under this paragraph by mutual agreement with the applicant concerned.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71240-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/5/J"><num value="J" class="bold">(J)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding restrictions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator shall not provide any Federal assistance for any part of a full-scale field demonstration project under this subsection to any applicant unless such applicant can demonstrate that it cannot obtain appropriate private financing on reasonable terms and conditions sufficient to carry out such demonstration project without such Federal assistance. The total Federal funds for any full-scale field demonstration project under this subsection shall not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of such project estimated at the time of the award of such assistance. The Administrator shall not expend more than $10,000,000 for assistance under the program in any fiscal year and shall not expend more than $3,000,000 for any single project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71241-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Field demonstrations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the program, the Administrator shall initiate or cause to be initiated at least 10 field demonstration projects of alternative or innovative treatment technologies at sites at which a response may be undertaken under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604">section 9604 of this title</ref>, in fiscal year 1987 and each of the succeeding three fiscal years. If the Administrator determines that 10 field demonstration projects under this subsection cannot be initiated consistent with the criteria set forth in paragraph (7) in any of such fiscal years, the Administrator shall transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report explaining the reasons for his inability to conduct such demonstration projects.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71242-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In selecting technologies to be demonstrated under this subsection, the Administrator shall, consistent with the protection of human health and the environment, consider each of the following criteria:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71243-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The potential for contributing to solutions to those waste problems which pose the greatest threat to human health, which cannot be adequately controlled under present technologies, or which otherwise pose significant management difficulties.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71244-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The availability of technologies which have been sufficiently developed for field demonstration and which are likely to be cost-effective and reliable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71245-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The availability and suitability of sites for demonstrating such technologies, taking into account the physical, biological, chemical, and geological characteristics of the sites, the extent and type of contamination found at the site, and the capability to conduct demonstration projects in such a manner as to assure the protection of human health and the environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71246-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The likelihood that the data to be generated from the demonstration project at the site will be applicable to other sites.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71247-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Technology transfer</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the program, the Administrator shall conduct a technology transfer program including the development, collection, evaluation, coordination, and dissemination of information relating to the utilization of alternative or innovative treatment technologies for response actions. The Administrator shall establish and maintain a central reference library for such information. The information maintained by the Administrator shall be made available to the public, subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref>, and to other Government agencies in a manner that will facilitate its dissemination; except, that upon a showing satisfactory to the Administrator by any person that any information or portion thereof obtained under this subsection by the Administrator directly or indirectly from such person, would, if made public, divulge—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71248-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> trade secrets; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71249-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> other proprietary information of such person,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the Administrator shall not disclose such information and disclosure thereof shall be punishable under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref>. This subsection is not authority to withhold information from Congress or any committee of Congress upon the request of the chairman of such committee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7124a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Training</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator is authorized and directed to carry out, through the Office of Technology Demonstration, a program of training and an evaluation of training needs for each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed7124b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Training in the procedures for the handling and removal of hazardous substances for employees who handle hazardous substances.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed7124c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Training in the management of facilities at which hazardous substances are located and in the evaluation of the hazards to human health presented by such facilities for State and local health and environment agency personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7124d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/b/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “alternative or innovative treatment technologies” means those technologies, including proprietary or patented methods, which permanently alter the composition of hazardous waste through chemical, biological, or physical means so as to significantly reduce the toxicity, mobility, or volume (or any combination thereof) of the hazardous waste or contaminated materials being treated. The term also includes technologies that characterize or assess the extent of contamination, the chemical and physical character of the contaminants, and the stresses imposed by the contaminants on complex ecosystems at sites.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7124e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Hazardous substance research</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may conduct and support, through grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts, research with respect to the detection, assessment, and evaluation of the effects on and risks to human health of hazardous substances and detection of hazardous substances in the environment. The Administrator shall coordinate such research with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the advisory council established under this section, in order to avoid duplication of effort.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7124f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> University hazardous substance research centers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71250-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall make grants to institutions of higher learning to establish and operate not fewer than 5 hazardous substance research centers in the United States. In carrying out the program under this subsection, the Administrator should seek to have established and operated 10 hazardous substance research centers in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71251-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of centers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The responsibilities of each hazardous substance research center established under this subsection shall include, but not be limited to, the conduct of research and training relating to the manufacture, use, transportation, disposal, and management of hazardous substances and publication and dissemination of the results of such research.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71252-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any institution of higher learning interested in receiving a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Administrator an application in such form and containing such information as the Administrator may require by regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71253-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall select recipients of grants under this subsection on the basis of the following criteria:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71254-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The hazardous substance research center shall be located in a State which is representative of the needs of the region in which such State is located for improved hazardous waste management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71255-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The grant recipient shall be located in an area which has experienced problems with hazardous substance management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71256-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> There is available to the grant recipient for carrying out this subsection demonstrated research resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71257-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The capability of the grant recipient to provide leadership in making national and regional contributions to the solution of both long-range and immediate hazardous substance management problems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71258-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The grant recipient shall make a commitment to support ongoing hazardous substance research programs with budgeted institutional funds of at least $100,000 per year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed71259-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The grant recipient shall have an interdisciplinary staff with demonstrated expertise in hazardous substance management and research.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed7125a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> The grant recipient shall have a demonstrated ability to disseminate results of hazardous substance research and educational programs through an interdisciplinary continuing education program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed7125b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/4/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> The projects which the grant recipient proposes to carry out under the grant are necessary and appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7125c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No grant may be made under this subsection in any fiscal year unless the recipient of such grant enters into such agreements with the Administrator as the Administrator may require to ensure that such recipient will maintain its aggregate expenditures from all other sources for establishing and operating a regional hazardous substance research center and related research activities at or above the average level of such expenditures in its 2 fiscal years preceding <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7125d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Federal share of a grant under this subsection shall not exceed 80 percent of the costs of establishing and operating the regional hazardous substance research center and related research activities carried out by the grant recipient.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7125e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No funds made available to carry out this subsection shall be used for acquisition of real property (including buildings) or construction of any building.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7125f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration through the Office of the Administrator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Administrative responsibility for carrying out this subsection shall be in the Office of the Administrator.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71260-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Equitable distribution of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall allocate funds made available to carry out this subsection equitably among the regions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71261-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Technology transfer activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not less than five percent of the funds made available to carry out this subsection for any fiscal year shall be available to carry out technology transfer activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71262-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the time of the submission of the annual budget request to Congress, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate and to the advisory council established under subsection (a), a report on the progress of the research, development, and demonstration program authorized by subsection (b), including an evaluation of each demonstration project completed in the preceding fiscal year, findings with respect to the efficacy of such demonstrated technologies in achieving permanent and significant reductions in risk from hazardous wastes, the costs of such demonstration projects, and the potential applicability of, and projected costs for, such technologies at other hazardous substance sites.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71263-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Saving provision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the provisions of the Solid Waste Disposal Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71264-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9660/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Small business participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, an adequate opportunity for small business participation in the program established by subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbed71265-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 96–510, title III, § 311</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s209/b">Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 209(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1708">100 Stat. 1708</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbed71266-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbed71267-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbed71268-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B)(iii), (6), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/510">Pub. L. 96–510</ref>, <date date="1980-12-11">Dec. 11, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2767">94 Stat. 2767</ref>, known as the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">section 9601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>. Title IV of the Public Health Service Act is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 281 et seq.) of chapter 6A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Solid Waste Disposal Act, referred to in subsec. (f), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/89/272">Pub. L. 89–272</ref>, <date date="1965-10-20">Oct. 20, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/997">79 Stat. 997</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/94/580/s2">Pub. L. 94–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2795">90 Stat. 2795</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 82 (§ 6901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">section 6901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbed71269-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbed7126a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed7126b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Methamphetamine Remediation Research</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/143">Pub. L. 110–143</ref>, <date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1809">121 Stat. 1809</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/143">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Methamphetamine Remediation Research Act of 2007’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Methamphetamine use and production is growing rapidly throughout the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Materials and residues remaining from the production of methamphetamine pose novel environmental problems in locations where methamphetamine laboratories have been closed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> There has been little standardization of measures for determining when the site of a closed methamphetamine laboratory has been successfully remediated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Initial cleanup actions are generally limited to removal of hazardous substances and contaminated materials that pose an immediate threat to public health or the environment. It is not uncommon for significant levels of contamination to be found throughout residential structures after a methamphetamine laboratory has closed, partially because of a lack of knowledge of how to achieve an effective cleanup.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Data on methamphetamine laboratory-related contaminants of concern are very limited, and cleanup standards do not currently exist. In addition, procedures for sampling and analysis of contaminants need to be researched and developed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Many States are struggling with establishing remediation guidelines and programs to address the rapidly expanding number of methamphetamine laboratories being closed each year.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> VOLUNTARY GUIDELINES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Voluntary Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>], the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (in this Act referred to as the ‘Administrator’), in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall establish voluntary guidelines, based on the best currently available scientific knowledge, for the remediation of former methamphetamine laboratories, including guidelines regarding preliminary site assessment and the remediation of residual contaminants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing the voluntary guidelines under subsection (a), the Administrator shall consider, at a minimum—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> relevant standards, guidelines, and requirements found in Federal, State, and local laws and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the varying types and locations of former methamphetamine laboratories; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the expected cost of carrying out any proposed guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">States</inline>.—</heading><content>The voluntary guidelines should be designed to assist State and local governments in the development and the implementation of legislation and other policies to apply state-of-the-art knowledge and research results to the remediation of former methamphetamine laboratories. The Administrator shall work with State and local governments and other relevant non-Federal agencies and organizations, including through the conference described in section 5, to promote and encourage the appropriate adoption of the voluntary guidelines.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updating the Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall periodically update the voluntary guidelines as the Administrator, in consultation with States and other interested parties, determines to be necessary and appropriate to incorporate research findings and other new knowledge.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> RESEARCH PROGRAM.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Administrator shall establish a program of research to support the development and revision of the voluntary guidelines described in section 3. Such research shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> identify methamphetamine laboratory-related chemicals of concern;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> assess the types and levels of exposure to chemicals of concern identified under paragraph (1), including routine and accidental exposures, that may present a significant risk of adverse biological effects, and the research necessary to better address biological effects and to minimize adverse human exposures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> evaluate the performance of various methamphetamine laboratory cleanup and remediation techniques; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> support other research priorities identified by the Administrator in consultation with States and other interested parties.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> TECHNOLOGY TRANSFER CONFERENCE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conference</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>], and at least every third year thereafter, the Administrator shall convene a conference of appropriate State agencies, as well as individuals or organizations involved in research and other activities directly related to the environmental, or biological impacts of former methamphetamine laboratories. The conference should be a forum for the Administrator to provide information on the guidelines developed under section 3 and on the latest findings from the research program described in section 4, and for the non-Federal participants to provide information on the problems and needs of States and localities and their experience with guidelines developed under section 3.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 3 months after each conference, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Congress that summarizes the proceedings of the conference, including a summary of any recommendations or concerns raised by the non-Federal participants and how the Administrator intends to respond to them. The report shall also be made widely available to the general public.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6">“SEC. 6.</num><heading> RESIDUAL EFFECTS STUDY.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>], the Administrator shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences for a study of the status and quality of research on the residual effects of methamphetamine laboratories. The study shall identify research gaps and recommend an agenda for the research program described in section 4. The study shall pay particular attention to the need for research on the impacts of methamphetamine laboratories on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the residents of buildings where such laboratories are, or were, located, with particular emphasis given to biological impacts on children; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> first responders.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 3 months after the completion of the study, the Administrator shall transmit to Congress a report on how the Administrator will use the results of the study to carry out the activities described in sections 3 and 4.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7">“SEC. 7.</num><heading> METHAMPHETAMINE DETECTION RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Director of National Institute of Standards and Technology, in consultation with the Administrator, shall support a research program to develop—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> new methamphetamine detection technologies, with emphasis on field test kits and site detection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> appropriate standard reference materials and validation procedures for methamphetamine detection testing.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8">“SEC. 8.</num><heading> SAVINGS CLAUSE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect or limit the application of, or any obligation to comply with, any State or Federal environmental law or regulation, including the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.) and the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6901">42 U.S.C. 6901</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="9">“SEC. 9.</num><heading> AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental Protection Agency</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out this Act $1,750,000 for each of the fiscal years 2007 and 2008.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Institute of Standards and Technology</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Standards and Technology to carry out this Act $750,000 for each of the fiscal years 2007 and 2008.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed7126c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Gulf Coast Hazardous Substance Research, Development, and Demonstration Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tI/s118">Pub. L. 99–499, title I, § 118</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1660">100 Stat. 1660</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/stat/100/1660">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of hazardous substance research, development, and demonstration center</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall establish a hazardous substance research, development, and demonstration center (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the ‘Center’) for the purpose of conducting research to aid in more effective hazardous substance response and waste management throughout the Gulf Coast.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes of the center</inline>.—</heading><content>The Center shall carry out a program of research, evaluation, testing, development, and demonstration of alternative or innovative technologies which may be utilized in response actions or in normal handling of hazardous wastes to achieve better protection of human health and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Operation of center</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> For purposes of operating the Center, the Administrator is authorized to enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, and make grants to, a university related institute involved with the improvement of waste management. Such institute shall be located in Jefferson County, Texas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Center shall be authorized to make grants, accept contributions, and enter into agreements with universities located in the States of Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Florida in order to carry out the purposes of the Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator for purposes of carrying out this subsection for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, not more than $5,000,000.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed7126d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pacific Northwest Hazardous Substance Research, Development, and Demonstration Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tI/s118">Pub. L. 99–499, title I, § 118</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1661">100 Stat. 1661</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/stat/100/1661">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall establish a hazardous substance research, development, and demonstration center (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the ‘Center’) for the purpose of conducting research to aid in more effective hazardous substance response in the Pacific Northwest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes of center</inline>.—</heading><content>The Center shall carry out a program of research, evaluation, testing, development, and demonstration of alternative or innovative technologies which may be utilized in response actions to achieve more permanent protection of human health and welfare and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Operation of center.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonprofit entity</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of operating the Center, the Administrator is authorized to enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, and make grants to, a nonprofit private entity as defined in section 201(i) of Public Law 96-517 [probably means <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s201/i">section 201(i) of Title 35</ref>, Patents, which was enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/96/517/s6/a">section 6(a) of Pub. L. 96–517</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3020">94 Stat. 3020</ref>] which entity shall agree to provide the basic technical and management personnel. Such nonprofit private entity shall also agree to provide at least two permanent research facilities, one of which shall be located in Benton County, Washington, and one of which shall be located in Clallam County, Washington.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Center shall be authorized to make grants, accept contributions, and enter into agreements with universities located in the States of Washington, Oregon, Idaho, and Montana in order to carry out the purposes of the Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hazardous waste research at the hanford site.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interagency agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator and the Secretary of Energy are authorized to enter into interagency agreements with one another for the purpose of providing for research, evaluation, testing, development, and demonstration into alternative or innovative technologies to characterize and assess the nature and extent of hazardous waste (including radioactive mixed waste) contamination at the Hanford site, in the State of Washington.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy for purposes of carrying out this paragraph for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, not more than $5,000,000. All sums appropriated under this subparagraph shall be provided to the Administrator by the Secretary of Energy, pursuant to the interagency agreement entered into under subparagraph (A), for the purpose of the Administrator entering into contracts and cooperative agreements with, and making grants to, the Center in order to carry out the research, evaluation, testing, development, and demonstration described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator for purposes of carrying out this subsection (other than paragraph (4)) for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, not more than $5,000,000.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed7126e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Statement of Purpose</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s209/a">Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1708">100 Stat. 1708</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s209/a">
<inline>“The purposes of this section [enacting this section] are as follows:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> To establish a comprehensive and coordinated Federal program of research, development, demonstration, and training for the purpose of promoting the development of alternative and innovative treatment technologies that can be used in response actions under the CERCLA program, to provide incentives for the development and use of such technologies, and to improve the scientific capability to assess, detect and evaluate the effects on and risks to human health from hazardous substances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> To establish a basic university research and education program within the Department of Health and Human Services and a research, demonstration, and training program within the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> To reserve certain funds from the Hazardous Substance Trust Fund to support a basic research program within the Department of Health and Human Services, and an applied and developmental research program within the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> To enhance the Environmental Protection Agency’s internal research capabilities related to CERCLA activities, including site assessment and technology evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> To provide incentives for the development of alternative and innovative treatment technologies in a manner that supplements or coordinates with, but does not compete with or duplicate, private sector development of such technologies.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed7126f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Councils</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory councils established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
