<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbed71278-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661"><num value="9661">§ 9661.</num><heading> Love Canal property acquisition</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71279-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of property in Emergency Declaration Area</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (hereinafter referred to as the “Administrator”) may make grants not to exceed $2,500,000 to the State of New York (or to any duly constituted public agency or authority thereof) for purposes of acquisition of private property in the Love Canal Emergency Declaration Area. Such acquisition shall include (but shall not be limited to) all private property within the Emergency Declaration Area, including non-owner occupied residential properties, commercial, industrial, public, religious, non-profit, and vacant properties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7127a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for acquisition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No property shall be acquired pursuant to this section unless the property owner voluntarily agrees to such acquisition. Compensation for any property acquired pursuant to this section shall be based upon the fair market value of the property as it existed prior to the emergency declaration. Valuation procedures for property acquired with funds provided under this section shall be in accordance with those set forth in the agreement entered into between the New York State Disaster Preparedness Commission and the Love Canal Revitalization Agency on <date date="1980-10-09">October 9, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7127b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State ownership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall not provide any funds under this section for the acquisition of any properties pursuant to this section unless a public agency or authority of the State of New York first enters into a cooperative agreement with the Administrator providing assurances deemed adequate by the Administrator that the State or an agency created under the laws of the State shall take title to the properties to be so acquired.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7127c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall enter into a cooperative agreement with an appropriate public agency or authority of the State of New York under which the Administrator shall maintain or arrange for the maintenance of all properties within the Emergency Declaration Area that have been acquired by any public agency or authority of the State. Ninety (90) percent of the costs of such maintenance shall be paid by the Administrator. The remaining portion of such costs shall be paid by the State (unless a credit is available under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9604/c">section 9604(c) of this title</ref>). The Administrator is authorized, in his discretion, to provide technical assistance to any public agency or authority of the State of New York in order to implement the recommendations of the habitability and land-use study in order to put the land within the Emergency Declaration Area to its best use.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed7127d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Habitability and land use study</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall conduct or cause to be conducted a habitability and land-use study. The study shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbed7127e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assess the risks associated with inhabiting of the Love Canal Emergency Declaration Area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbed7127f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> compare the level of hazardous waste contamination in that Area to that present in other comparable communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbed71280-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assess the potential uses of the land within the Emergency Declaration Area, including but not limited to residential, industrial, commercial and recreational, and the risks associated with such potential uses.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Administrator shall publish the findings of such study and shall work with the State of New York to develop recommendations based upon the results of such study.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed71281-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9611">section 9611 of this title</ref> [and 9631(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003880">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003880"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title], the expenditures authorized by this section shall be treated as a cost specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9611/c">section 9611(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed98382-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Response</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not affect the implementation of other response actions within the Emergency Declaration Area that the Administrator has determined (before <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>) to be necessary to protect the public health or welfare or the environment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbed98383-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed98384-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency Declaration Area</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The terms “Emergency Declaration Area” and “Love Canal Emergency Declaration Area” mean the Emergency Declaration Area as defined in section 950, paragraph (2) of the General Municipal Law of the State of New York, Chapter 259, Laws of 1980, as in effect on <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbed98385-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Private property</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">As used in subsection (a), the term “private property” means all property which is not owned by a department, agency, or instrumentality of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed98386-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbed98387-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9661/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the State of New York (or any public agency or authority thereof).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbed98388-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/510/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 96–510, title III, § 312</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s213/b">Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 213(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1727">100 Stat. 1727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbed98389-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbed9838a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbed9838b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9631">Section 9631 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (f), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tV/s517/c/1">Pub. L. 99–499, title V, § 517(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1774">100 Stat. 1774</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbed9838c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed9838d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Love Canal Property Acquisition; Congressional Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s213/a">Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 213(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1726">100 Stat. 1726</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s213/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The area known as Love Canal located in the city of Niagara Falls and the town of Wheatfield, New York, was the first toxic waste site to receive national attention. As a result of that attention Congress investigated the problems associated with toxic waste sites and enacted CERCLA [Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.)] to deal with these problems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Because Love Canal came to the Nation’s attention prior to the passage of CERCLA and because the fund under CERCLA was not available to compensate for all of the hardships endured by the citizens in the area, Congress has determined that special provisions are required. These provisions do not affect the lawfulness, implementation, or selection of any other response actions at Love Canal or at any other facilities.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbed9838e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination of Titles I to IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Any provision of titles I to IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref>, imposing any tax, premium, or fee; establishing any trust fund; or authorizing expenditures from any trust fund, to have no force or effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/s531">section 531 of Pub. L. 99–499</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
