<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbedbcd47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804"><num value="9804">§ 9804.</num><heading> Advisory Community Investment Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbedbcd48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> National Community Investment Board; functions, composition, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbedbcd49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President is authorized to establish a National Advisory Community Investment Board (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Investment Board”). Such Investment Board shall be composed of 15 members appointed, for staggered terms and without regard to the civil service laws, by the President, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”). Such members shall be representative of the investment and business communities and appropriate fields of endeavor related to this subchapter. The Investment Board shall meet at the call of the chairperson, but not less often than 3 times each year. The Secretary and the administrator of community economic development programs shall be ex officio members of the Investment Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbedbcd4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall carry out the provisions of this subchapter through an appropriate office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbedbcd4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Function</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Investment Board shall promote cooperation between private investors and businesses and community development corporation projects through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbedbcd4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> advising the Secretary and the community development corporations on ways to facilitate private investment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbedbcd4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> advising businesses and other investors of opportunities in community development corporation projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbedbcd4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> advising the Secretary, community development corporations, and private investors and businesses of ways in which they might engage in mutually beneficial efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbedbcd4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Local advisory community investment boards; establishment, composition, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The governing body of each Community Development Corporation may establish an advisory community investment board composed of not to exceed 15 members who shall be appointed by the governing body after consultation with appropriate local officials. Each such board shall promote cooperation between private investors and businesses and the governing body of the Community Development Corporation through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbedbcd50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> advising the governing body on ways to facilitate private investors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbedbcd51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> advising businesses and other investors of opportunities in Community Development Corporation projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbedbcd52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9804/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> advising the governing body, private investors, and businesses of ways in which they might engage in mutually beneficial efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbedbcd53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s615">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 615</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/489">95 Stat. 489</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/tII/s202/b/2">Pub. L. 105–285, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2755">112 Stat. 2755</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbedbcd54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbedbcd55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbedbcd56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/285">Pub. L. 105–285</ref> substituted “through an appropriate office” for “through the Office of Community Services established in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9905/a">section 9905(a) of this title</ref>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbedbcd57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbedbcd58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Boards</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory boards established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a board established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such board is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a board established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
