<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbede3df9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9831"><num value="9831">§ 9831.</num><heading> Statement of purpose</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter to promote the school readiness of low-income children by enhancing their cognitive, social, and emotional development—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbede3dfa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9831/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in a learning environment that supports children’s growth in language, literacy, mathematics, science, social and emotional functioning, creative arts, physical skills, and approaches to learning; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbede3dfb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9831/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> through the provision to low-income children and their families of health, educational, nutritional, social, and other services that are determined, based on family needs assessments, to be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbede3dfc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s636">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 636</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/499">95 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/tI/s102">Pub. L. 101–501, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1224">104 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/tI/s102">Pub. L. 105–285, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2703">112 Stat. 2703</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/134/s2">Pub. L. 110–134, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-12-12">Dec. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1363">121 Stat. 1363</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbede3dfd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbede3dfe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbede3dff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—<ref href="/us/pl/110/134">Pub. L. 110–134</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “It is the purpose of this subchapter to promote school readiness by enhancing the social and cognitive development of low-income children through the provision, to low-income children and their families, of health, educational, nutritional, social, and other services that are determined, based on family needs assessments, to be necessary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/285">Pub. L. 105–285</ref> amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) In recognition of the role which Project Head Start has played in the effective delivery of comprehensive health, educational, nutritional, social, and other services to economically disadvantaged children and their families, it is the purpose of this subchapter to extend the authority for the appropriation of funds for such program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) In carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall continue the administrative arrangement responsible for meeting the needs of migrant, non-English language background, and Indian children and shall assure that appropriate funding is provided to meet such needs.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/501">Pub. L. 101–501</ref> inserted “, non-English language background,” after “migrant”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbede3e00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbede3e01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/501">Pub. L. 101–501</ref> effective <date date="1990-10-01">Oct. 1, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/501/s1001/a">section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 101–501</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8621">section 8621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idbede3e02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of this subchapter as the “Head Start Act”, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s635">section 635 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9801">section 9801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbede3e03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Preschool Development Grants</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIX/s9212">Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9212</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2152">129 Stat. 2152</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/95/tIX/s9212">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of this section are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> to assist States to develop, update, or implement a strategic plan that facilitates collaboration and coordination among existing programs of early childhood care and education in a mixed delivery system across the State designed to prepare low-income and disadvantaged children to enter kindergarten and to improve transitions from such system into the local educational agency or elementary school that enrolls such children, by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> more efficiently using existing Federal, State, local, and non-governmental resources to align and strengthen the delivery of existing programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> coordinating the delivery models and funding streams existing in the State’s mixed delivery system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> developing recommendations to better use existing resources in order to improve—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the overall participation of children in a mixed delivery system of Federal, State, and local early childhood education programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> program quality while maintaining availability of services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> parental choice among existing programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> school readiness for children from low-income and disadvantaged families, including during such children’s transition into elementary school;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to encourage partnerships among Head Start providers, State and local governments, Indian tribes and tribal organizations, private entities (including faith- and community-based entities), and local educational agencies, to improve coordination, program quality, and delivery of services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to maximize parental choice among a mixed delivery system of early childhood education program providers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">ESEA definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘elementary school’, ‘local educational agency’, and ‘State’ have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Center of excellence in early childhood</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Center of Excellence in Early Childhood’ means a Center of Excellence in Early Childhood designated under section 657B(b) of the Head Start Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9852b/b">42 U.S.C. 9852b(b)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Early childhood education program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘early childhood education program’ has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Existing program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘existing program’ means a Federal, State, local, or privately-funded early childhood education program that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> was operating in the State on the day before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>]; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> began operating in the State at any time on or after the date of enactment of this Act through funds that were not provided by a grant under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Mixed delivery system</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘mixed delivery system’ means a system—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> of early childhood education services that are delivered through a combination of programs, providers, and settings (such as Head Start, licensed family and center-based child care programs, public schools, and community-based organizations); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> that is supported with a combination of public funds and private funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State advisory council</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State Advisory Council’ means a State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care designated or established under section 642B(b)(1)(A) of the Head Start Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9837b/b/1/A">42 U.S.C. 9837b(b)(1)(A)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grants Authorized.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>From amounts made available under subsection (k), the Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Education, shall award grants to States to enable the States to carry out the activities described in subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Award basis</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Grants under this subsection shall be awarded—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> on a competitive basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with priority for States that meet the requirements of subsection (e)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration of grants</inline>.—</heading><content>A grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of not more than 1 year and may be renewed by the Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Education, under subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matching requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Each State that receives a grant under this section shall provide funds from non-Federal sources (which may be provided in cash or in kind) to carry out the activities supported by the grant, in an amount equal to not less than 30 percent of the amount of such grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial Application</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State desiring a grant under subsection (c)(1) shall submit an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require. The application shall contain—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an identification of the State entity that the Governor of the State has appointed to be responsible for duties under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> a description of how such State entity proposes to accomplish the activities described in subsection (f) and meet the purposes of this section described in subsection (a), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a timeline for strategic planning activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a description of how the strategic planning activities and the proposed activities described in subsection (f) will increase participation of children from low-income and disadvantaged families in high-quality early childhood education and preschool programs as a result of the grant;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> a description of the Federal, State, and local existing programs in the State for which such State entity proposes to facilitate activities described in subsection (f), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> programs carried out under the Head Start Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9801">42 U.S.C. 9801</ref> et seq.) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9831">42 U.S.C. 9831</ref> et seq.], including the Early Head Start programs carried out under such Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> child care programs carried out under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9858">42 U.S.C. 9858</ref> et seq.) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9857">42 U.S.C. 9857</ref> et seq.] or section 418 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s618">42 U.S.C. 618</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> other Federal, State, and local programs of early learning and development, early childhood education, and child care, operating in the State (including programs operated by Indian tribes and tribal organizations and private entities, including faith- and community-based entities), as of the date of the application for the grant;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> a description of how the State entity, in collaboration with Centers of Excellence in Early Childhood, if appropriate, will provide technical assistance and disseminate best practices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> a description of how the State plans to sustain the activities described in, and carried out in accordance with, subsection (f) with non-Federal sources after grant funds under this section are no longer available, if the State plans to continue such activities after such time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> a description of how the State entity will work with the State Advisory Council and Head Start collaboration offices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review Process</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall review the applications submitted under subsection (d) to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> determine which applications satisfy the requirements of such subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> confirm that each State submitting an application has, as of the date of the application, a mixed delivery system in place; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> determine if a priority is merited in accordance with subsection (c)(2)(B) because the State has never received—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a grant under subsection (c); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a preschool development grant for development or expansion under such program as it existed on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State, acting through the State entity appointed under subsection (d)(1), that receives a grant under subsection (c)(1) shall use the grant funds for all of the following activities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Conducting a periodic statewide needs assessment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the availability and quality of existing programs in the State, including such programs serving the most vulnerable or underserved populations and children in rural areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to the extent practicable, the unduplicated number of children being served in existing programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to the extent practicable, the unduplicated number of children awaiting service in such programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Developing a strategic plan that recommends collaboration, coordination, and quality improvement activities (including activities to improve children’s transition from early childhood education programs into elementary schools) among existing programs in the State and local educational agencies. Such plan shall include information that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> identifies opportunities for, and barriers to, collaboration and coordination among existing programs in the State, including among State, local, and tribal (if applicable) agencies responsible for administering such programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> recommends partnership opportunities among Head Start providers, local educational agencies, State and local governments, Indian tribes and tribal organizations, and private entities (including faith- and community-based entities) that would improve coordination, program quality, and delivery of services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> builds on existing plans and goals with respect to early childhood education programs, including improving coordination and collaboration among such programs, of the State Advisory Council while incorporating new or updated Federal, State, and local statutory requirements, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the requirements of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9858">42 U.S.C. 9858</ref> et seq.) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9857">42 U.S.C. 9857</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> when appropriate, information found in the report required under section 13 of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 2014 (<ref href="/us/pl/113/186">Public Law 113–186</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/128/2002">128 Stat. 2002</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> describes how accomplishing the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) will better serve children and families in existing programs and how such activities will increase the overall participation of children in the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> Maximizing parental choice and knowledge about the State’s mixed delivery system of existing programs and providers by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> ensuring that parents are provided information about the variety of early childhood education programs for children from birth to kindergarten entry in the State’s mixed delivery system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> promoting and increasing involvement by parents and family members, including families of low-income and disadvantaged children, in the development of their children and the transition of such children from an early childhood education program into an elementary school.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Sharing best practices among early childhood education program providers in the State to increase collaboration and efficiency of services, including to improve transitions from such programs to elementary school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> After activities described in paragraphs (1) and (2) have been completed, improving the overall quality of early childhood education programs in the State, including by developing and implementing evidence-based practices that meet the requirements of section 8101(21)(A)(i) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801/21/A/i">20 U.S.C. 7801(21)(A)(i)</ref>], to improve professional development for early childhood education providers and educational opportunities for children.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Renewal Grants.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Education, may use funds available under subsection (k) to award renewal grants to States described in paragraph (2) to enable such States to continue activities described in subsection (f) and to carry out additional activities described in paragraph (6).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible states</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State shall be eligible for a grant under paragraph (1) if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the State has received a grant under subsection (c)(1) and the grant period has concluded; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the State has received a preschool development grant for development or expansion under such program as it existed on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, and the grant period for such grant has concluded; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the Secretary allows such State to apply directly for a renewal grant under this subsection, rather than an initial grant under subsection (c)(1), and the State submits with its application the needs assessment completed under the preschool development grant (updated as necessary to reflect the needs of the State as of the time of the application) in place of the activity described in subsection (f)(1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration of grants</inline>.—</heading><content>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be for a period of not more than 3 years and shall not be renewed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matching requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Each State that receives a grant under this subsection shall provide funds from non-Federal sources (which may be provided in cash or in kind) to carry out the activities supported by the grant, in an amount equal to not less than 30 percent of the amount of the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State described in paragraph (2) that desires a grant under this subsection shall submit an application for renewal at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require. The application shall contain—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> applicable information required in the application described in subsection (d), and in the case of a State described in paragraph (2)(A), updated as the State determines necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in the case of a State described in paragraph (2)(A), a description of how funds were used for the activities described in subsection (f) in the initial grant period and the extent to which such activities will continue to be supported in the renewal period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> in the case of a State described in paragraph (2)(B), how a needs assessment completed prior to the date of the application, such as the needs assessment completed under the preschool development grant program (as such program existed prior to the date of enactment of this Act), and updated as necessary in accordance with paragraph (2)(B)(ii), will be sufficient information to inform the use of funds under this subsection, and a copy of such needs assessment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a description of how funds will be used for the activities described in paragraph (6) during the renewal grant period, if the State proposes to use grant funds for such activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> in the case of a State that proposes to carry out activities described in paragraph (6) and to continue such activities after grant funds under this subsection are no longer available, a description of how such activities will be sustained with non-Federal sources after such time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional activities.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each State that receives a grant under this subsection may use grant funds to award subgrants to programs in a mixed delivery system across the State designed to benefit low-income and disadvantaged children prior to entering kindergarten, to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> enable programs to implement activities addressing areas in need of improvement as determined by the State, through the use of funds for the activities described in paragraph (5)(C) or subsection (f), as applicable; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> as determined through the activities described in paragraph (5)(C) or subsection (f), as applicable, expand access to such existing programs; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> develop new programs to address the needs of children and families eligible for, but not served by, such programs, if the State ensures that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> the distribution of subgrants under this subparagraph supports a mixed delivery system; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> funds made available under this subparagraph will be used to supplement, and not supplant, any other Federal, State, or local funds that would otherwise be available to carry out the activities assisted under this section.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading><content>In awarding subgrants under subparagraph (A), a State shall prioritize activities to improve areas in which there are State-identified needs that would improve services for low-income and disadvantaged children living in rural areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State receiving a renewal grant under this subsection that elects to award subgrants under subparagraph (A) shall not—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> for the first year of the renewal grant, use more than 60 percent of the grant funds available for such year to award such subgrants; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> for each of the second and third years of the renewal grant, use more than 75 percent of the grant funds available for such year to award such subgrants.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State Reporting.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial grants</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State that receives an initial grant under subsection (c)(1) shall submit a final report to the Secretary not later than 6 months after the end of the grant period. The report shall include a description of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> how, and to what extent, the grant funds were utilized for activities described in subsection (f), and any other activities through which funds were used to meet the purposes of this section, as described in subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> strategies undertaken at the State level and, if applicable, local or program level, to implement recommendations in the strategic plan developed under subsection (f)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any new partnerships among Head Start providers, State and local governments, Indian tribes and tribal organizations, and private entities (including faith- and community-based entities); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> how these partnerships improve coordination and delivery of services;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> if applicable, the degree to which the State used information from the report required under section 13 of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 2014 to inform activities under this section, and how this information was useful in coordinating, and collaborating among, programs and funding sources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the extent to which activities funded by the initial grant led to the blending or braiding of other public and private funding;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> how information about available existing programs for children from birth to kindergarten entry was disseminated to parents and families, and how involvement by parents and family was improved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> other State-determined and voluntarily provided information to share best practices regarding early childhood education programs and the coordination of such programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Renewal grants</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State receiving a renewal grant under subsection (g) shall submit a follow-up report to the Secretary not later than 6 months after the end of the grant period that includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> information described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) of paragraph (1), as applicable and updated for the period covered by the renewal grant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> if applicable, information on how the State was better able to serve children through the distribution of funds in accordance with subsection (g)(5), through—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a description of the activities conducted through the use of subgrant funds, including, where appropriate, measurable areas of program improvement and better use of existing resources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> best practices from the use of subgrant funds, including how to better serve the most vulnerable, underserved, and rural populations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rules of Construction.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on federal interference</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary or the Secretary of Education to establish any criterion for grants made under this section that specifies, defines, or prescribes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> early learning and development guidelines, standards, or specific assessments, including the standards or measures that States use to develop, implement, or improve such guidelines, standards, or assessments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> specific measures or indicators of quality early learning and care, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the systems that States use to assess the quality of early childhood education programs and providers, school readiness, and achievement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the term ‘high-quality’ as it relates to early learning, development, or care;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> early learning or preschool curriculum, programs of instruction, or instructional content;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> teacher and staff qualifications and salaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> class sizes and ratios of children to instructional staff;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> any new requirement that an early childhood education program is required to meet that is not explicitly authorized in this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> the scope of programs, including length of program day and length of program year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> any aspect or parameter of a teacher, principal, other school leader, or staff evaluation system within a State, local educational agency, or early childhood education program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on governmental requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary, Secretary of Education, the State, or any other governmental agency to alter requirements for existing programs for which coordination and alignment activities are recommended under this section, or to force programs to adhere to any recommendations developed through this program. The Secretary, Secretary of Education, State, or other governmental agency may only take an action described in the preceding sentence as otherwise authorized under Federal, State, or local law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary of education</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary of Education to have sole decision-making or regulatory authority in carrying out the program authorized under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Planning and Transition.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The recipient of an award for a preschool development grant for development or expansion under such program as it existed on the day before the date of enactment of this Act may continue to receive funds in accordance with the terms of such existing award.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Education, shall take such steps as are necessary to ensure an orderly transition to, and implementation of, the program under this section from the preschool development grants for development or expansion program as such program was operating prior to the date of enactment of this Act, in accordance with subsection (k).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out this section $250,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2020.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbede3e04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Federal Early Childhood Education Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIX/s9213">Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9213</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2160">129 Stat. 2160</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/95/tIX/s9213">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the heads of all Federal agencies that administer Federal early childhood education programs, shall conduct an interdepartmental review of all early childhood education programs for children less than 6 years of age in order to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> develop a plan for the elimination of overlapping programs, as identified by the Government Accountability Office’s 2012 annual report (GAO–12–342SP);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> determine if the activities conducted by States using grant funds from preschool development grants under section 9212 [set out above] have led to better utilization of resources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> make recommendations to Congress for streamlining all such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report and Updates</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the heads of all Federal agencies that administer Federal early childhood education programs, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>], prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives a detailed report that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> outlines the efficiencies that can be achieved by, and specific recommendations for, eliminating overlap and fragmentation among all Federal early childhood education programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> explains how the use by States of preschool development grant funds under section 9212 has led to the better utilization of resources; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> builds upon the review of Federal early learning and care programs required under section 13 of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 2014 (<ref href="/us/pl/113/186">Public Law 113–186</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/128/2002">128 Stat. 2002</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> annually prepare and submit to such Committees a detailed update of the report described in paragraph (1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
