<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbef15142-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9842"><num value="9842">§ 9842.</num><heading> Records and audits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbef15143-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9842/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Each recipient of financial assistance under this subchapter shall keep such records as the Secretary shall prescribe, including rec­ords which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such financial assistance, the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which such financial assistance is given or used, the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbef15144-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9842/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipients that are pertinent to the financial assistance received under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbef15145-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9842/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> Each recipient of financial assistance under this subchapter shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbef15146-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9842/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> maintain, and annually submit to the Secretary, a complete accounting of the recipient’s administrative expenses (including a detailed statement identifying the amount of financial assistance provided under this subchapter used to pay expenses for salaries and compensation and the amount (if any) of other funds used to pay such expenses);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbef15147-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9842/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not later than 30 days after the date of completion of an audit conducted in the manner and to the extent provided in chapter 75 of title 31 (commonly known as the “Single Audit Act of 1984”), submit to the Secretary a copy of the audit management letter and of any audit findings as they relate to the Head Start program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbef15148-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9842/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide such additional documentation as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbef15149-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s647">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 647</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/505">95 Stat. 505</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/134/s17">Pub. L. 110–134, § 17</ref>, <date date="2007-12-12">Dec. 12, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1422">121 Stat. 1422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbef1514a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbef1514b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbef1514c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/110/134">Pub. L. 110–134</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
