<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbeffa8ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g"><num value="9858g">§ 9858g.</num><heading> Administration and enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeffa8bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> coordinate all activities of the Department of Health and Human Services relating to child care, and, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate such activities with similar activities of other Federal entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeffa8bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> collect, publish, and make available to the public a listing of State child care standards at least once every 3 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeffa8be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide technical assistance, such as business technical assistance, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9858c/c/2/V">section 9858c(c)(2)(V) of this title</ref>, to States (which may include providing assistance on a reimbursable basis) which shall be provided by qualified experts on practices grounded in scientifically valid research, where appropriate, to carry out this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeffa8bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> disseminate, for voluntary informational purposes, information on practices that scientifically valid research indicates are most successful in improving the quality of programs that receive assistance with this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbeffa8c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> after consultation with the heads of any other Federal agencies involved, issue guidance and disseminate information on best practices regarding the use of funding combined by States as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9858c/c/2/O/ii">section 9858c(c)(2)(O)(ii) of this title</ref>, consistent with laws other than this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of compliance with State plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall review and monitor State compliance with this subchapter and the plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9858c/c">section 9858c(c) of this title</ref> for the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Noncompliance</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary, after reasonable notice to a State and opportunity for a hearing, finds that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbeffa8c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> there has been a failure by the State to comply substantially with any provision or requirement set forth in the plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9858c/c">section 9858c(c) of this title</ref> for the State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbeffa8c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the operation of any program for which assistance is provided under this subchapter there is a failure by the State to comply substantially with any provision of this subchapter;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall notify the State of the finding and shall require that the State reimburse the Secretary for any funds that were improperly expended for purposes prohibited or not authorized by this subchapter, that the Secretary deduct from the administrative portion of the State allotment for the following fiscal year an amount that is less than or equal to any improperly expended funds, or a combination of such options.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional sanctions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a finding of noncompliance made pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Secretary may, in addition to imposing the sanctions described in such subparagraph, impose other appropriate sanctions, including recoupment of money improperly expended for purposes prohibited or not authorized by this subchapter, and disqualification from the receipt of financial assistance under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The notice required under subparagraph (A) shall include a specific identification of any additional sanction being imposed under subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of rules</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish by rule procedures for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> receiving, processing, and determining the validity of complaints concerning any failure of a State to comply with the State plan or any requirement of this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> imposing sanctions under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Request for relief</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may waive for a period of not more than three years any provision under this subchapter or sanctions imposed upon a State in accordance with subsection (b)(2) upon the State’s request for such a waiver if the Secretary finds that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the request describes one or more conflicting or duplicative requirements preventing the effective delivery of child care services to justify a waiver, extraordinary circumstances, such as natural disaster or financial crisis, or an extended period of time for a State legislature to enact legislation to implement the provisions of this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such circumstances included in the request prevent the State from complying with any statutory or regulatory requirements of this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the waiver will, by itself, contribute to or enhance the State’s ability to carry out the purposes of this subchapter; and,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003908">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003908"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the waiver will not contribute to inconsistency with the objectives of this law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Such request shall be provided to the Secretary in writing and will—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> detail each sanction or provision within this subchapter that the State seeks relief from;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> describe how a waiver from that sanction or provision of this subchapter will, by itself, improve delivery of child care services for children in the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbeffa8d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> certify that the health, safety, and well-being of children served through assistance received under this subchapter will not be compromised as a result of the waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 90 days after the receipt of a State’s request under this subsection, the Secretary shall inform the State of approval or disapproval of the request. If the plan is disapproved, the Secretary shall, at this time, inform the State, the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate of the reasons for the disapproval and give the State the opportunity to amend the request. In the case of approval, the Secretary shall, within 30 days of granting such waiver, notify and submit a report to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate on the circumstances of the waiver including each specific sanction or provision waived, the reason as given by the State of the need for a waiver, and the expected impact of the waiver on children served under this program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> External conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall not require or impose any new or additional requirements in exchange for receipt of a waiver if such requirements are not specified in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may approve a request under this subsection for a period not to exceed three years, unless a renewal is granted under paragraph (7).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall terminate approval of a request for a waiver authorized under this subsection if the Secretary determines, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that the performance of a State granted relief under this subsection has been inadequate, or if such relief is no longer necessary to achieve its original purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Renewal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may approve or disapprove a request from a State for renewal of an existing waiver under this subchapter for a period no longer than one year. A State seeking to renew their waiver approval must inform the Secretary of this intent no later than 30 days prior to the expiration date of the waiver. The State shall re-certify in its extension request the provisions in paragraph (2) of this subchapter, and shall also explain the need for additional time of relief from such sanction(s) or provisions approved under this law as provided in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbeffa8db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9858g/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as providing the Secretary the authority to permit States to alter the eligibility requirements for eligible children, including work requirements, job training, or educational program participation, that apply to the parents of eligible children under this subchapter. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to allow the Secretary to waive anything related to his or her authority under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbeffa8dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s658I">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 658I</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5082/2">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5082(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-242">104 Stat. 1388–242</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/401/s3/a">Pub. L. 102–401, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-07">Oct. 7, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1959">106 Stat. 1959</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/586/s8/c/1">Pub. L. 102–586, § 8(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/5036">106 Stat. 5036</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVI/s609">Pub. L. 104–193, title VI, § 609</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2284">110 Stat. 2284</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/186/s8/a">Pub. L. 113–186, § 8(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2014-11-19">Nov. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1994">128 Stat. 1994</ref>, 1995.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbeffa8dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbeffa8de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbeffa8df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/186/s8/a/1">Pub. L. 113–186, § 8(a)(1)</ref>, inserted a comma after “publish” and struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/113/186/s8/a/2">Pub. L. 113–186, § 8(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “provide technical assistance to assist States to carry out this subchapter, including assistance on a reimbursable basis.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/113/186/s8/a/3">Pub. L. 113–186, § 8(a)(3)</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/113/186/s8/b">Pub. L. 113–186, § 8(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s609/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 609(1)</ref>, struck out “, and shall have the power to terminate payments to the State in accordance with paragraph (2)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s609/2">Pub. L. 104–193, § 609(2)</ref>, in closing provisions, substituted before period at end “finding and shall require that the State reimburse the Secretary for any funds that were improperly expended for purposes prohibited or not authorized by this subchapter, that the Secretary deduct from the administrative portion of the State allotment for the following fiscal year an amount that is less than or equal to any improperly expended funds, or a combination of such options” for “finding and that no further payments may be made to such State under this subchapter (or, in the case of noncompliance in the operation of a program or activity, that no further payments to the State will be made with respect to such program or activity) until the Secretary is satisfied that there is no longer any such failure to comply or that the noncompliance will be promptly corrected”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/401">Pub. L. 102–401</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/102/586">Pub. L. 102–586</ref> made identical technical corrections to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s5082/2">Pub. L. 101–508, § 5082(2)</ref>, which added this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbeffa8e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbeffa8e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s615">section 615 of Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9858">section 9858 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
