<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf091ebf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915"><num value="9915">§ 9915.</num><heading> Corrective action; termination and reduction of funding</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ec0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the State determines, on the basis of a final decision in a review pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9914">section 9914 of this title</ref>, that an eligible entity fails to comply with the terms of an agreement, or the State plan, to provide services under this chapter or to meet appropriate standards, goals, and other requirements established by the State (including performance objectives), the State shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> inform the entity of the deficiency to be corrected;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> require the entity to correct the deficiency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> offer training and technical assistance, if appropriate, to help correct the deficiency, and prepare and submit to the Secretary a report describing the training and technical assistance offered; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the State determines that such training and technical assistance are not appropriate, prepare and submit to the Secretary a report stating the reasons for the determination;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> at the discretion of the State (taking into account the seriousness of the deficiency and the time reasonably required to correct the deficiency), allow the entity to develop and implement, within 60 days after being informed of the deficiency, a quality improvement plan to correct such deficiency within a reasonable period of time, as determined by the State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not later than 30 days after receiving from an eligible entity a proposed quality improvement plan pursuant to subparagraph (A), either approve such proposed plan or specify the reasons why the proposed plan cannot be approved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf091ec9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> after providing adequate notice and an opportunity for a hearing, initiate proceedings to terminate the designation of or reduce the funding under this chapter of the eligible entity unless the entity corrects the deficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091eca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A determination to terminate the designation or reduce the funding of an eligible entity is reviewable by the Secretary. The Secretary shall, upon request, review such a determination. The review shall be completed not later than 90 days after the Secretary receives from the State all necessary documentation relating to the determination to terminate the designation or reduce the funding. If the review is not completed within 90 days, the determination of the State shall become final at the end of the 90th day.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ecb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9915/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a State violates the assurances contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9908/b/8">section 9908(b)(8) of this title</ref> and terminates or reduces the funding of an eligible entity prior to the completion of the State hearing described in that section and the Secretary’s review as required in subsection (b), the Secretary is authorized to provide financial assistance under this chapter to the eligible entity affected until the violation is corrected. In such a case, the grant or allotment for the State under section 9905 or 9906 of this title for the earliest appropriate fiscal year shall be reduced by an amount equal to the funds provided under this subsection to such eligible entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf091ecc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s678C">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 678C</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/tII/s201">Pub. L. 105–285, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2743">112 Stat. 2743</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
