<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf091ef3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918"><num value="9918">§ 9918.</num><heading> Limitations on use of funds</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ef4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction of facilities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ef5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), grants made under this chapter (other than amounts reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9903/b/3">section 9903(b)(3) of this title</ref>) may not be used by the State, or by any other person with which the State makes arrangements to carry out the purposes of this chapter, for the purchase or improvement of land, or the purchase, construction, or permanent improvement (other than low-cost residential weatherization or other energy-related home repairs) of any building or other facility.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ef6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may waive the limitation contained in paragraph (1) upon a State request for such a waiver, if the Secretary finds that the request describes extraordinary circumstances to justify the purchase of land or the construction of facilities (or the making of permanent improvements) and that permitting the waiver will contribute to the ability of the State to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ef7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Political activities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ef8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment as a State or local agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of chapter 15 of title 5, any entity that assumes responsibility for planning, developing, and coordinating activities under this chapter and receives assistance under this chapter shall be deemed to be a State or local agency. For purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 1502(a) of such title, any entity receiving assistance under this chapter shall be deemed to be a State or local agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091ef9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Programs assisted under this chapter shall not be carried on in a manner involving the use of program funds, the provision of services, or the employment or assignment of personnel, in a manner supporting or resulting in the identification of such programs with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf091efa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any partisan or nonpartisan political activity or any political activity associated with a candidate, or contending faction or group, in an election for public or party office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf091efb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any activity to provide voters or prospective voters with transportation to the polls or similar assistance in connection with any such election; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf091efc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any voter registration activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091efd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, after consultation with the Office of Personnel Management, shall issue rules and regulations to provide for the enforcement of this subsection, which shall include provisions for summary suspension of assistance or other action necessary to permit enforcement on an emergency basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091efe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Nondiscrimination</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091eff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No person shall, on the basis of race, color, national origin, or sex be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination under, any program or activity funded in whole or in part with funds made available under this chapter. Any prohibition against discrimination on the basis of age under the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6101">42 U.S.C. 6101</ref> et seq.) or with respect to an otherwise qualified individual with a disability as provided in section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">29 U.S.C. 794</ref>), or title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12131">42 U.S.C. 12131</ref> et seq.) shall also apply to any such program or activity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091f00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Action of Secretary</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the Secretary determines that a State that has received a payment under this chapter has failed to comply with paragraph (1) or an applicable regulation, the Secretary shall notify the chief executive officer of the State and shall request that the officer secure compliance. If within a reasonable period of time, not to exceed 60 days, the chief executive officer fails or refuses to secure compliance, the Secretary is authorized to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf091f01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> refer the matter to the Attorney General with a recommendation that an appropriate civil action be instituted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf091f02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> exercise the powers and functions provided by title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</ref> et seq.), the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6101">42 U.S.C. 6101</ref> et seq.), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">29 U.S.C. 794</ref>), or title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12131">42 U.S.C. 12131</ref> et seq.), as may be applicable; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf091f03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> take such other action as may be provided by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf091f04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s9918/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Action of Attorney General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">When a matter is referred to the Attorney General pursuant to paragraph (2), or whenever the Attorney General has reason to believe that the State is engaged in a pattern or practice of discrimination in violation of the provisions of this subsection, the Attorney General may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court for such relief as may be appropriate, including injunctive relief.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf091f05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVI/s678F">Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 678F</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/285/tII/s201">Pub. L. 105–285, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2747">112 Stat. 2747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf091f06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf091f07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf091f08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Age Discrimination Act of 1975, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), (2)(B), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/94/135">Pub. L. 94–135</ref>, <date date="1975-11-28">Nov. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/728">89 Stat. 728</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 76 (§ 6101 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6101">section 6101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), (2)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/327">104 Stat. 327</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 12131 et seq.) of chapter 126 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">section 12101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Civil Rights Act of 1964, referred to in subsec. (c)(2)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/88/352">Pub. L. 88–352</ref>, <date date="1964-07-02">July 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/241">78 Stat. 241</ref>. Title VI of the Act is classified generally to subchapter V (§ 2000d et seq.) of chapter 21 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000a">section 2000a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
