<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56ab1f38-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133"><num value="1133">§ 1133.</num><heading> Preliminary development and demonstration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56ab1f39-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Commandant shall ensure that developmental test and evaluation, operational test and evaluation, life-cycle cost estimates, and the development and demonstration requirements applied by this chapter to acquisition projects and programs are met to confirm that the projects or programs meet the requirements identified in the mission-analysis and affordability assessment prepared under section 1131(a)(2), the operational requirements developed under section 1132(a)(1) and the following development and demonstration objectives:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f3a-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To demonstrate that the design, manufacturing, and production solution is based upon a stable, producible, and cost-effective product design.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f3b-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To ensure that the product capabilities meet contract specifications, acceptable operational performance requirements, and system security requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f3c-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To ensure that the product design is mature enough to commit to full production and deployment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56ab1f3d-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tests and Evaluations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f3e-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall ensure that the Coast Guard conducts developmental tests and evaluations and operational tests and evaluations of a capability or asset and the subsystems of the capability or asset in accordance with the master plan prepared for the capability or asset under section 1132(d)(1).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002023"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f3f-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of third parties</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall ensure that the Coast Guard uses independent third parties with expertise in testing and evaluating the capabilities or assets and the subsystems of the capabilities or assets being acquired to conduct developmental tests and evaluations and operational tests and evaluations whenever the Coast Guard lacks the capability to conduct the tests and evaluations required by a master plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f40-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Communication of safety concerns</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall ensure that independent third parties and Government employees that identify safety concerns during developmental or operational tests and evaluations or through independent or Government-conducted design assessments of capabilities or assets and subsystems of capabilities or assets to be acquired by the Coast Guard communicate such concerns as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the completion of the test or assessment event or activity that identified the safety concern, to the program manager for the capability or asset and the subsystems concerned and to the Chief Acquisition Officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f41-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting of safety concerns</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall ensure that any safety concerns that have been communicated under paragraph (3) for an acquisition program or project are reported to the appropriate congressional committees at least 90 days before the award of any contract or issuance of any delivery order or task order for low, initial, or full-rate production of the capability or asset concerned if they will remain uncorrected or unmitigated at the time such a contract is awarded or delivery order or task order is issued. The report shall include a justification for the approval of that level of production of the capability or asset before the safety concerns are corrected or mitigated. The report shall also include an explanation of the actions that will be taken to correct or mitigate the safety concerns, the date by which those actions will be taken, and the adequacy of current funding to correct or mitigate the safety concerns.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f42-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Asset already in low, initial, or full-rate production</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Commandant shall ensure that if an independent third party or a Government employee identifies a safety concern with a capability or asset or any subsystems of a capability or asset not previously identified during operational test and evaluation of a capability or asset already in low, initial, or full-rate production—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id56ab1f43-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Commandant, through the Assistant Commandant for Capability, shall notify the program manager and the Chief Acquisition Officer of the safety concern as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the completion of the test and evaluation event or activity that identified the safety concern; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id56ab1f44-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the Deputy Commandant for Mission Support shall notify the Commandant and the Deputy Commandant for Operations of the safety concern within 50 days after the notification required under subparagraph (A), and include in such notification—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id56ab1f45-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an explanation of the actions that will be taken to correct or mitigate the safety concern in all capabilities or assets and subsystems of the capabilities or assets yet to be produced, and the date by which those actions will be taken;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id56ab1f46-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an explanation of the actions that will be taken to correct or mitigate the safety concern in previously produced capabilities or assets and subsystems of the capabilities or assets, and the date by which those actions will be taken; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id56ab1f47-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/b/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an assessment of the adequacy of current funding to correct or mitigate the safety concern in capabilities or assets and subsystems of the capabilities or assets and in previously produced capabilities or assets and subsystems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56ab1f48-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Technical Certification.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f49-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall ensure that any Level 1 or Level 2 acquisition project or program is certified by the technical authority of the Coast Guard after review by an independent third party with capabilities in the mission area, asset, or particular asset component.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f4a-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">TEMPEST testing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Commandant shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id56ab1f4b-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> cause all electronics on all aircraft, surface, and shore capabilities and assets that require TEMPEST certification to be tested in accordance with TEMPEST standards and communications security (comsec) standards by an independent third party that is authorized by the Federal Government to perform such testing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id56ab1f4c-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> certify that the assets meet all applicable TEMPEST requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f4d-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cutter classification.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id56ab1f4e-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall cause each cutter, other than a National Security Cutter, acquired by the Coast Guard and delivered after the date of enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2010 to be classed by the American Bureau of Shipping before final acceptance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" status="repealed" id="id56ab1f4f-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/3/B"><num value="B">[(B)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/112/213/tII/s210/c/2/B">Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 210(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1551">126 Stat. 1551</ref>.]</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f50-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other vessels</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall cause the design and construction of each National Security Cutter, other than National Security Cutters 1, 2, and 3, to be assessed by an independent third party with expertise in vessel design and construction certification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56ab1f51-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s1133/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Aircraft airworthiness</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall cause all aircraft and aircraft engines acquired by the Coast Guard to be assessed for airworthiness by an independent third party with expertise in aircraft and aircraft engine certification before final acceptance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id56ab1f52-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2944">124 Stat. 2944</ref>, § 573; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/213/tII/s210/c/2/B">Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 210(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1551">126 Stat. 1551</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dC/tXXXV/s3522">Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3522</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2314">132 Stat. 2314</ref>; renumbered § 1133 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI">Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 108(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4208">132 Stat. 4208</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56ab1f53-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56ab1f54-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id56ab1f55-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1132(d)(1), referred to in subsec. (b)(1), was, prior to amendment of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/115/282">Pub. L. 115–282</ref>, a reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s572/d/1">section 572(d)(1) of this title</ref>, which was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s572/f/1">section 572(f)(1) of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/114/120/tII/s204/a/1">Pub. L. 114–120, title II, § 204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/34">130 Stat. 34</ref>. <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s572">Section 572 of this title</ref> was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s1132">section 1132 of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI/s108/b/2">Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 108(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4208">132 Stat. 4208</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2010, referred to in subsec. (c)(3)(A), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/111/281">Pub. L. 111–281</ref>, which was approved <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56ab1f56-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s108/b">Pub. L. 115–282, § 108(b)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s573">section 573 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/2">Pub. L. 115–282, § 123(b)(2)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “section 1131(a)(2)” for “section 571(a)(2)” and “section 1132(a)(1)” for “section 572(a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/2">Pub. L. 115–282, § 123(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 1132(d)(1)” for “section 572(d)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3522/1">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3522(1)</ref>, substituted “ensure that independent third parties and Government employees that identify safety concerns” for “require that safety concerns identified” and “Coast Guard communicate such concerns as” for “Coast Guard shall be communicated as”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3522/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3522(2)</ref>, substituted “The Commandant shall ensure that any safety concerns that have been communicated under paragraph (3) for an acquisition program or project are reported” for “Any safety concerns that have been reported to the Chief Acquisition Officer for an acquisition program or project shall be reported by the Commandant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3522/3/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3522(3)(A)</ref>, added introductory provisions and struck out former introductory provisions which read as follows: “If operational test and evaluation of a capability or asset already in low, initial, or full-rate production identifies a safety concern with the capability or asset or any subsystems of the capability or asset not previously identified during developmental or operational test and evaluation, the Commandant shall—”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3522/3/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3522(3)(B)</ref>, inserted “the Commandant, through the Assistant Commandant for Capability, shall” before “notify”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3522/3/C">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3522(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “the Deputy Commandant for Mission Support shall notify the Commandant and the Deputy Commandant for Operations of the safety concern within 50 days after the notification required under subparagraph (A), and include in such notification” for “notify the Chief Acquisition Officer and include in such notification” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3522/4/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3522(4)(A)</ref>, struck out “and that are delivered after the date of enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2010” after “TEMPEST certification”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3522/4/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3522(4)(B)</ref>, struck out “and delivered after the date of enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2010” after “acquired by the Coast Guard”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (c)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/213">Pub. L. 112–213</ref> struck out subpar. (B). Text read as follows: “Not later than <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>, and biennially thereafter, the Commandant shall provide a report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate identifying which, if any, Coast Guard cutters that have been issued a certificate of classification by the American Bureau of Shipping have not been maintained in class and detailing the reasons why they have not been maintained in class.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id56ab1f57-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id56ab1f58-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Security Cutters</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tIII/s311/f">Pub. L. 115–282, title III, § 311(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4249">132 Stat. 4249</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/282/tIII/s311/f">“The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating is authorized to enter into a multiyear contract for the procurement of a tenth, eleventh, and twelfth National Security Cutter and associated government-furnished equipment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tVIII/s818/a">Pub. L. 115–282, title VIII, § 818(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4307">132 Stat. 4307</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/282/tVIII/s818/a">
<inline>“The Commandant of the Coast Guard may not certify an eighth National Security Cutter as Ready for Operations before the date on which the Commandant provides to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a notification of a new standard method for tracking operational employment of Coast Guard major cutters that does not include time during which such a cutter is away from its homeport for maintenance or repair; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> a report analyzing cost and performance for different approaches to achieving varied levels of operational employment using the standard method required by paragraph (1) that, at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> compares over a 30-year period the average annualized baseline cost and performances for a certified National Security Cutter that operated for 185 days away from homeport or an equivalent alternative measure of operational tempo—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> against the cost of a 15 percent increase in days away from homeport or an equivalent alternative measure of operational tempo for a National Security Cutter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> against the cost of the acquisition and operation of an additional National Security Cutter; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> examines the optimal level of operational employment of National Security Cutters to balance National Security Cutter cost and mission performance.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
