<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56b95065-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125"><num value="2125">§ 2125.</num><heading> Wartime temporary service promotions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b95066-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In time of war, or of national emergency declared by the President or Congress, the President may suspend any section of this chapter relating to the selection, promotion, or involuntary separation of officers. Such a suspension may not continue beyond six months after the termination of the war or national emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b95067-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> When the preceding sections of this chapter relating to selection and promotion of officers are suspended in accordance with subsection (a), and the needs of the service require, the President may, under regulations prescribed by him, promote to a higher grade any officer serving on active duty in the grade of ensign or above in the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b95068-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> In time of war, or of national emergency declared by the President or Congress, the President may, under regulations to be prescribed by him, promote to the next higher warrant officer grade any warrant officer serving on active duty in a grade below chief warrant officer, W–4.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" status="repealed" id="id56b95069-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/d"><num value="d">[(d)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/417/s2/6">Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(6)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2085">96 Stat. 2085</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b9506a-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> A promotion under this section to a grade above lieutenant may be made only upon the recommendation of a board of officers convened for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b9506b-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> A promotion under this section shall be made by an appointment for temporary service. Original appointments under this section in the grades of lieutenant commander and above shall be made by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Original appointments under this section in the grades of ensign through lieutenant shall be made by the President alone. Any other appointments under this section shall be made by the President alone.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b9506c-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> An appointment under this section, unless expressly declined, is regarded as accepted on the date specified by the Secretary as the date of the appointment, and the officer so promoted is entitled to pay and allowances of the grade to which appointed from that date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b9506d-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> An appointment under this section does not terminate any appointments held by an officer concerned under any other provisions of this title. The President may terminate temporary appointments made under this section at any time. An appointment under this section is effective for such period as the President determines. However, an appointment may not be effective later than six months after the end of the war or national emergency. When his temporary appointment under this section is terminated or expires, the officer shall revert to his former grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56b9506e-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2125/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Not later than six months after the end of the war or national emergency the President shall, under such regulations as he may prescribe, reestablish the active duty promotion list with adjustments and additions appropriate to the conditions of original appointment and wartime service of all officers to be included thereon. The President may, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, appoint officers on the reestablished active duty promotion list to fill vacancies in the authorized active duty strength of each grade. Such appointments shall be considered to have been made under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2121">section 2121 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id56b9506f-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/88/130/s1/10/C">Pub. L. 88–130, § 1(10)(C)</ref>, <date date="1963-09-24">Sept. 24, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/182">77 Stat. 182</ref>, § 275; amended <ref href="/us/pl/92/129/tVI/s605">Pub. L. 92–129, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1971-09-28">Sept. 28, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/362">85 Stat. 362</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/417/s2/6">Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(6)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2085">96 Stat. 2085</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/241/tII/s217/b">Pub. L. 109–241, title II, § 217(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/526">120 Stat. 526</ref>; renumbered § 2125 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI">Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 112(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4216">132 Stat. 4216</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56b95070-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56b95071-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56b95072-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s112/b">Pub. L. 115–282, § 112(b)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s275">section 275 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/2">Pub. L. 115–282, § 123(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 2121” for “section 271”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/241">Pub. L. 109–241</ref> substituted “Original appointments under this section in the grades of lieutenant commander and above shall be made by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Original appointments under this section in the grades of ensign through lieutenant shall be made by the President alone.” for “An appointment under this section to a grade above captain shall be made by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. An appointment under this section to grade above lieutenant commander of an officer in the Coast Guard Reserve shall be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/417">Pub. L. 97–417</ref> repealed subsec. (d) which had established the grade of commodore in the Coast Guard for the purposes of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/92/129">Pub. L. 92–129</ref> inserted provision covering appointments of officers in the Coast Guard Reserve to grades above lieutenant commander.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id56b95073-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id56b95074-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authority of President under this section, during a time of war or national emergency, to suspend the operation of any law relating to the selection, promotion, or involuntary separation of officers of the Coast Guard, and to temporarily promote officers serving on active duty and chief warrant officers serving on active duty, delegated to Secretary of Homeland Security without the approval, ratification, or other action by the President by Ex. Ord. No. 14106, § 2(a), <date date="2023-08-14">Aug. 14, 2023</date>, 88 F.R. 55905, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authority of President under subsec. (a) of this section, as invoked by section 2 of Ex. Ord. No. 13223, <date date="2001-09-14">Sept. 14, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 48201, delegated to Secretary of Homeland Security by section 5 of Ex. Ord. No. 13223, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12302">section 12302 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
