<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56bbc108-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145"><num value="2145">§ 2145.</num><heading> Regular lieutenant commanders and commanders; retirement for failure of selection for promotion</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56bbc109-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Each officer of the Regular Coast Guard serving in the grade of lieutenant commander or commander, who has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of commander or captain, respectively, for the second time shall:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56bbc10a-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if he has completed at least 20 years of active service or is eligible for retirement under any law on June 30 of the promotion year in which his second failure of selection occurs, be retired on that date; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56bbc10b-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if ineligible for retirement on the date specified in clause (1) be retained on active duty and retired on the last day of the month in which he completes twenty years of active service, unless earlier removed under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56bbc10c-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A lieutenant commander or commander of the Regular Coast Guard subject to discharge or retirement under subsection (a) may be continued on active duty when the Secretary directs a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2106">section 2106 of this title</ref> to continue up to a specified number of lieutenant commanders or commanders on active duty. When so directed, the selection board shall recommend those officers who in the opinion of the board are best qualified to advance the needs and efficiency of the Coast Guard. When the recommendations of the board are approved by the Secretary, the officers recommended for continuation shall be notified that they have been recommended for continuation and offered an additional term of service that fulfills the needs of the Coast Guard.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56bbc10d-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56bbc10e-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An officer who holds the grade of lieutenant commander of the Regular Coast Guard may not be continued on active duty under subsection (b) for a period that extends beyond 24 years of active commissioned service unless promoted to the grade of commander of the Regular Coast Guard. An officer who holds the grade of commander of the Regular Coast Guard may not be continued on active duty under subsection (b) for a period that extends beyond 26 years of active commissioned service unless promoted to the grade of captain of the Regular Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56bbc10f-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2145/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Unless retired or discharged under another provision of law, each officer who is continued on active duty under subsection (b) but is not subsequently promoted or continued on active duty, and is not on a list of officers recommended for continuation or for promotion to the next higher grade, shall, if eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retired under that law on the first day of the first month following the month in which the period of continued service is completed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id56bbc110-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/88/130/s1/10/C">Pub. L. 88–130, § 1(10)(C)</ref>, <date date="1963-09-24">Sept. 24, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/185">77 Stat. 185</ref>, § 285; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/283/s1/7">Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(7)</ref>, <date date="1974-05-14">May 14, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/140">88 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/546/s1/24">Pub. L. 94–546, § 1(24)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-18">Oct. 18, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2521">90 Stat. 2521</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/tIV/s412">Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2118">116 Stat. 2118</ref>; renumbered § 2145 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI">Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 112(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4216">132 Stat. 4216</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56bbc111-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56bbc112-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56bbc113-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s112/b">Pub. L. 115–282, § 112(b)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s285">section 285 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/2">Pub. L. 115–282, § 123(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 2106” for “section 251”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—<ref href="/us/pl/107/295">Pub. L. 107–295</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/546">Pub. L. 94–546</ref> substituted “promotion year” for “fiscal year” in cl. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/283">Pub. L. 93–283</ref> substituted “if he has completed at least 20 years of active service or is eligible” for “if eligible” in cl. (1).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id56bbc114-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id56bbc115-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Retired Pay on or Prior to <date date="1963-09-24">September 24, 1963</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Savings provisions in <ref href="/us/pl/88/130/s5/g">section 5(g) of Pub. L. 88–130</ref> providing that <ref href="/us/pl/88/130">Pub. L. 88–130</ref> does not affect the retired pay of anyone retired on or prior to <date date="1963-09-24">Sept. 24, 1963</date>, are set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id56bbc116-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effectiveness of Election, Change, or Revocation of Election of Annuity</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Savings provisions in <ref href="/us/pl/88/130/s5/h">section 5(h) of Pub. L. 88–130</ref> providing that notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1431">section 1431 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, an election, change or revocation thereof affecting an annuity, by an officer retired under this section, is effective if made prior to the first day of the third month following September 1963, are set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
