<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56c07b52-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s2313"><num value="2313">§ 2313.</num><heading> Retention beyond term of enlistment in case of disability</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any enlisted member of the Coast Guard in the active service whose term of enlistment expires while he is suffering disease or injury incident to service and not due to misconduct, and who is in need of medical care or hospitalization, may, with his consent, be retained in such service beyond the expiration of his term of enlistment. Any such enlisted member shall be entitled to receive at Government expense medical care or hospitalization and his pay and allowances, including credit for longevity, until he shall have recovered to such extent as would enable him to meet the physical requirements for reenlistment, or until it shall have been ascertained by competent authority of the Coast Guard that the disease or injury is of a character that recovery to such an extent would be impossible. Any enlisted member whose enlistment is so extended shall be subject to forfeitures in the same manner and to the same extent as if his term of enlistment had not expired. Nothing contained in this section shall prevent any enlisted member from being held in the service without his consent under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2314">section 2314 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id56c07b53-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-08-04/ch393">Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/523">63 Stat. 523</ref>, § 366; <ref href="/us/pl/98/557/s15/a/3/A">Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2865">98 Stat. 2865</ref>; renumbered § 2313 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI">Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 113(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4221">132 Stat. 4221</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56c07b54-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id56c07b55-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 35b (<ref href="/us/act/1941-12-12/ch566">Dec. 12, 1941, ch. 566</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/797">55 Stat. 797</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The parenthetical part, which has no application insofar as the Coast Guard is concerned, has been eliminated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Inasmuch as the act cited above applies equally to the Army, Navy, and Marine Corps, as well as the Coast Guard, it is not scheduled for repeal but is being amended by section 14 of this act to eliminate reference to the Coast Guard.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology. 81st Congress, House Report No. 557.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56c07b56-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56c07b57-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/2">Pub. L. 115–282, § 123(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 2314” for “section 367”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s113/b">Pub. L. 115–282, § 113(b)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s366">section 366 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/557">Pub. L. 98–557</ref> substituted reference to enlisted member for reference to enlisted man in four places.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
