<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56d5ff1b-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s3706"><num value="3706">§ 3706.</num><heading> Temporary members of the Reserve; eligibility and compensation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A citizen of the United States, its territories, or possessions who is a member of the Auxiliary, an officer or member of the crew of a motorboat or yacht placed at the disposal of the Coast Guard, or an individual (including a Government employee without pay other than the compensation of that individual’s civilian position) who by reason of special training and experience is considered by the Commandant to be qualified for duty, may be enrolled by the Commandant as a temporary member of the Reserve, for duty under conditions the Commandant may prescribe, including part-time and intermittent active duty with or without pay, without regard to age. The Commandant is authorized to define the powers and duties of temporary members of the Reserve, and to confer upon them, appropriate to their qualifications and experience, the same grades and ratings as provided for members of the Reserve. When performing active duty with pay as authorized by this section, temporary members of the Reserve are entitled to receive the pay and allowances of their rank, grade, or rating.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id56d5ff1c-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/322/s1">Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1004">94 Stat. 1004</ref>, § 706; renumbered § 3706, <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI/s118/b">Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 118(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4233">132 Stat. 4233</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dG/tLVXXXV">Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8505(a)(50), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4750">134 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56d5ff1d-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56d5ff1e-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id56d5ff1f-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s756">section 756 of this title</ref> prior to the complete revision of former chapter 21 of this title by <ref href="/us/pl/96/322">Pub. L. 96–322</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56d5ff20-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “an individual” for “a person” and “individual’s” for “person’s”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282">Pub. L. 115–282</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s706">section 706 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
