<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56d5ffb0-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s3735"><num value="3735">§ 3735.</num><heading> Authorized number of officers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56d5ffb1-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s3735/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The authorized number of officers in the Reserve in an active status is 5,000. Reserve officers on an active-duty list shall not be counted as part of the authorized number of officers in the Reserve. The actual number of Reserve officers in an active status at any time shall not exceed the authorized number unless the Secretary determines that a greater number is necessary for planned mobilization requirements, or unless the excess results directly from the operation of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56d5ffb2-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s3735/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56d5ffb3-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s3735/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall make, at least once each year, a computation to determine the number of Reserve officers in an active status authorized to be serving in each grade. The number in each grade shall be computed by applying the applicable percentage to the total number of such officers serving in an active status on the date the computation is made. The number of Reserve officers in an active status below the grade of rear admiral (lower half) shall be distributed by pay grade so as not to exceed percentages of commissioned officers authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2103/b">section 2103(b) of this title</ref>. When the actual number of Reserve officers in an active status in a particular pay grade is less than the maximum percentage authorized, the difference may be applied to the number in the next lower grade. A Reserve officer may not be reduced in rank or grade solely because of a reduction in an authorized number as provided for in this subsection, or because an excess results directly from the operation of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56d5ffb4-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s3735/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The authorized number of Reserve Officers in an active status not on active duty in the grades of rear admiral (lower half) and rear admiral is a total of two. However, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may authorize an additional number of Reserve officers not on active duty in the grades of rear admiral (lower half) and rear admiral as necessary in order to meet planned mobilization requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56d5ffb5-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s3735/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deferral of Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>If at the end of any fiscal year there is in effect a declaration of war or national emergency, the President may defer the effectiveness of any end-strength limitation with respect to that fiscal year prescribed by law for any military or civilian component of the Coast Guard Reserve, for a period not to exceed 6 months after the end of the war or termination of the national emergency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id56d5ffb6-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/322/s1">Pub. L. 96–322, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1007">94 Stat. 1007</ref>, § 724; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/417/s2/12">Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(12)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2086">96 Stat. 2086</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/557/s25/a/4">Pub. L. 98–557, § 25(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2872">98 Stat. 2872</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tV/s514/c/1">Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/629">99 Stat. 629</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 107–295, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2085">116 Stat. 2085</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/241/tII/s207">Pub. L. 109–241, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/521">120 Stat. 521</ref>; renumbered § 3735 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI">Pub. L. 115–282, title I</ref>, §§ 118(b), 123(b)(2), <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4233">132 Stat. 4233</ref>, 4240.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56d5ffb7-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56d5ffb8-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id56d5ffb9-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s772">section 772 of this title</ref> prior to the complete revision of former chapter 21 of this title by <ref href="/us/pl/96/322">Pub. L. 96–322</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56d5ffba-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s118/b">Pub. L. 115–282, § 118(b)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s724">section 724 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/2">Pub. L. 115–282, § 123(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 2103(b)” for “section 42(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/241/s207/1">Pub. L. 109–241, § 207(1)</ref>, inserted “Reserve officers on an active-duty list shall not be counted as part of the authorized number of officers in the Reserve.” after “5,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/241/s207/2">Pub. L. 109–241, § 207(2)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “The authorized number of Reserve officers in an active status below the grade of rear admiral (lower half) shall be distributed in grade in the following percentages, respectively: captain, 1.5; commander, 7.0; lieutenant commander, 22.0; lieutenant, 37.0; and the combined grades of lieutenant (junior grade) and ensign, 32.5. When the actual number of Reserve officers in an active status in a grade is less than the number authorized, the difference may be applied to increase the authorized number in a lower grade. A Reserve officer may not be reduced in rank or grade solely because of a reduction in an authorized number as provided for in this subsection, or because an excess results directly from the operation of law.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/295">Pub. L. 107–295</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/145">Pub. L. 99–145</ref> substituted “rear admiral (lower half)” for “commodore” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/557">Pub. L. 98–557</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), struck out provisions authorizing number of Reserve officers in an active status not on active duty in the combined grades of commodore and rear admiral as two, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/417">Pub. L. 97–417</ref> substituted “commodore” for “rear admiral” and “combined grades of commodore and real admiral” for “grade of rear admiral”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
