<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56959a5f-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s505"><num value="505">§ 505.</num><heading> Functions and powers vested in the Commandant</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All powers and functions conferred upon the Coast Guard, or the Commandant, by or pursuant to this title or any other law shall, unless otherwise specifically stated, be executed by the Commandant subject to the general supervision of the Secretary. In order to execute the powers and functions vested in him, the Commandant may assign personnel of the Coast Guard to duty in the District of Columbia, elsewhere in the United States, in any territory of the United States, and in any foreign country, but such personnel shall not be assigned to duties in any foreign country without the consent of the government of that country; assign to such personnel such duties and authority as he deems necessary; and issue rules, orders, and instructions, not inconsistent with law, relating to the organization, internal administration, and personnel of the Coast Guard.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id56959a60-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-08-04/ch393">Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/545">63 Stat. 545</ref>, § 632; renumbered § 505, <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4200">132 Stat. 4200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56959a61-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id56959a62-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 5, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 41, and on title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed. §§ 22, 58, 91, 99, 103 (R.S. 2749; <ref href="/us/act/1878-06-18/ch265">June 18, 1878, ch. 265</ref>, §§ 7, 8, <ref href="/us/stat/22/164">22 Stat. 164</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1882-05-04/ch117/s5">May 4, 1882, ch. 117, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/22/57">22 Stat. 57</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1907-03-04/ch2918">Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2918</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/1309">34 Stat. 1309</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1915-01-28/ch20/s1">Jan. 28, 1915, ch. 20, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/800">38 Stat. 800</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-29/ch417">Aug. 29, 1916, ch. 417</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/601">39 Stat. 601</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1921-06-10/ch18/s304">June 10, 1921, ch. 18, § 304</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/23">42 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1926-07-03/ch742/s9">July 3, 1926, ch. 742, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/817">44 Stat. 817</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Said section 91 has been divided. That part dealing with investigation of plans and inventions is covered in <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s93/d">section 93(d) of this title</ref>. The remainder is covered in general terms. It has been rewritten in broad terms, making clear that the Commandant is granted the necessary authority to administer the Coast Guard under the Secretary, including authority to issue rules, orders, and instructions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section is primarily a consolidation of existing functions rather than a codification of existing laws. It does not, for the most part, grant new authority to the Coast Guard as an organization. It merely clarifies the method by which Coast Guard functions shall be administered. Under existing statutes, functions relating to the Coast Guard have been conferred upon the President, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Commandant, and sometimes upon the Secretary of the Treasury in times of peace and the Secretary of the Navy in times of war. This revision confers some functions directly upon the Coast Guard, and this section provides for the execution of those functions by the Commandant, the military head of the organization, thereby making for consistency and uniformity. The functions are to be executed “subject to the general supervision of the Secretary”. Title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 91 now grants authority to the Commandant to prescribe regulations; this is changed to the issuance of rules, orders, and instructions as the promulgation of regulations in a military organization is properly a function of the Secretary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology. 81st Congress, House Report No. 557.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56959a63-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id56959a64-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 505 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2734">section 2734 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 505, <ref href="/us/act/1949-08-04/ch393">act Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/537">63 Stat. 537</ref>, related to escorts to the place of burial for the bodies of deceased Coast Guard personnel, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1954-07-15/ch507/s14/c/5">act July 15, 1954, ch. 507, § 14(c)(5)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/481">68 Stat. 481</ref>. For provisions relating to recovery, care, and disposition of the remains of deceased personnel of the uniformed services and deceased civilian personnel, see <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481">section 1481 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56959a65-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282">Pub. L. 115–282</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s632">section 632 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
