<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id56959ab6-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510"><num value="510">§ 510.</num><heading> Conveyance of Coast Guard vessels for public purposes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56980bb7-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>On request by the Commandant, the Administrator of the General Services Administration may transfer ownership of a Coast Guard vessel or aircraft to an eligible entity for educational, cultural, historical, charitable, recreational, or other public purposes if such transfer is authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56980bb8-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions of Conveyance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The General Services Administration may not convey a vessel or aircraft to an eligible entity as authorized by law unless the eligible entity agrees—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56980bb9-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to provide the documentation needed by the General Services Administration to process a request for aircraft or vessels as if the request were being processed under section 102.37.225 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56980bba-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to comply with the special terms, conditions, and restrictions imposed on aircraft and vessels under section 102.37.460 of such title, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56980bbb-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to make the vessel available to the United States Government if it is needed for use by the Commandant in time of war or a national emergency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id56980bbc-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to hold the United States Government harmless for any claims arising from exposure to hazardous materials, including asbestos and polychlorinated biphenyls, that occurs after conveyance of the vessel, except for claims arising from use of the vessel by the United States Government under paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56980bbd-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Obligations Unaffected</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section amends or affects any obligation of the Coast Guard or any other person under the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2601">15 U.S.C. 2601</ref> et seq.) or any other law regarding use or disposal of hazardous materials including asbestos and polychlorinated biphenyls.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id56980bbe-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s510/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Entity Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “eligible entity” means a State or local government, nonprofit corporation, educational agency, community development organization, or other entity that agrees to comply with the conditions established under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id56980bbf-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXII/s11258/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11258(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4057">136 Stat. 4057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id56980bc0-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id56980bc1-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id56980bc2-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), (2), is the date of enactment of div. K of <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, which was approved <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Toxic Substances Control Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/469">Pub. L. 94–469</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2003">90 Stat. 2003</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 53 (§ 2601 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2601">section 2601 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id56980bc3-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tIX/s914">Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 914</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3018">124 Stat. 3018</ref>, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s501">section 501 of this title</ref>, was redesignated as this section, transferred to appear after <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s509">section 509 of this title</ref>, and amended so that the enumerator, section catchline, typeface, and typestyle conformed to those appearing in other sections of this title by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s11258/a">Pub. L. 117–263, § 11258(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id56980bc4-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 510 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2762">section 2762 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id56980bc5-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s11258/c/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 11258(c)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Whenever the transfer of ownership of a Coast Guard vessel or aircraft to an eligible entity for use for educational, cultural, historical, charitable, recreational, or other public purposes is authorized by law or declared excess by the Commandant, the Coast Guard shall transfer the vessel or aircraft to the General Services Administration for conveyance to the eligible entity.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s11258/c/2/A">Pub. L. 117–263, § 11258(c)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “as if the request were being processed” after “vessels” and “, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022” after “Code of Federal Regulations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s11258/c/2/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 11258(c)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022” after “such title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s11258/c/2/C">Pub. L. 117–263, § 11258(c)(2)(C)</ref>, struck out “of the Coast Guard” after “Commandant”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
