<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id569f1087-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02" identifier="/us/usc/t14/s711"><num value="711">§ 711.</num><heading> Coast Guard officers as attachés to missions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Commissioned officers may, with the consent of the Secretary of State, be regularly and officially attached to the diplomatic missions of the United States in those nations with which the United States is extensively engaged in maritime commerce. Expenses for the maintenance of such Coast Guard attachés abroad, including office rental and pay of employees and allowances for living quarters, including heat, fuel, and light, may be defrayed by the Coast Guard.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id569f1088-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-08-04/ch393">Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/507">63 Stat. 507</ref>, § 150; renumbered § 711, <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI/s106/b">Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 106(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4203">132 Stat. 4203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id569f1089-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id569f108a-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Experience since the war has indicated the necessity for making provision for the assignment of Coast Guard officers to diplomatic missions in those foreign countries which are extensively engaged in maritime commerce with the United States. This is largely the result of duties in connection with inspection of merchant vessels.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section authorizes the designation, with the consent of the State Department, of Coast Guard officers to be officially attached to diplomatic missions of the United States. Although Coast Guard advice on Coast Guard matters is always available to our diplomatic missions, in those locations where such advice and information are frequently sought, it is felt that the most effective utilization of Coast Guard services would be achieved by having Coast Guard officers attached to such missions. Provision for customs officers to be attached to diplomatic missions is contained in the act of <date date="1923-03-04">March 4, 1923</date>, as amended, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1453">42 Stat. 1453</ref> (title 19, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 6). Before the transfer in 1939 of the Foreign Agriculture Service to the State Department, representatives of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the Department of Agriculture stationed abroad were agricultural attachés. Act of <date date="1930-06-05">June 5, 1930</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/498">46 Stat. 498</ref> (title 7, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 542(a)). 81st Congress, House Report No. 557.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id569f108b-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id569f108c-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 711 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s3712">section 3712 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id569f108d-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/282">Pub. L. 115–282</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s150">section 150 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id569f108e-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id569f108f-2930-11f1-a4c1-c531e6569a02"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Official Representation Items in Support of the Coast Guard Attaché Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 113–126, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1399">128 Stat. 1399</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/126/tIII/s312">“Notwithstanding any other limitation on the amount of funds that may be used for official representation items, the Secretary of Homeland Security may use funds made available to the Secretary through the National Intelligence Program for necessary expenses for intelligence analysis and operations coordination activities for official representation items in support of the Coast Guard Attaché Program.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
