<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b0454a4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s11"><num value="11">§ 11.</num><heading> Authority for compact between Middle Northwest States as to jurisdiction of offenses committed on boundary waters</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The consent of the Congress is given to the States of North Dakota, South Dakota, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Iowa, and Nebraska, or any two or more of them, by such agreement or compact as they may deem desirable or necessary, or as may be evidenced by legislative acts enacted by any two or more of said States, not in conflict with the Constitution of the United States or any law thereof, to determine and settle the jurisdiction to be exercised by said States, respectively, over offenses arising out of the violation of the laws of any of said States upon any of the waters forming the boundary lines between any two or more of said States, or waters through which such boundary line extends, and that the consent of the Congress be, and the same is, given to the concurrent jurisdiction agreed to by the States of Minnesota and South Dakota, as evidenced by the act of the Legislature of the State of Minnesota approved <date date="1917-04-20">April 20, 1917</date>, and the act of the Legislature of the State of South Dakota approved <date date="1917-02-13">February 13, 1917</date>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b0454a5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1921-03-04/ch176">Mar. 4, 1921, ch. 176</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1447">41 Stat. 1447</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b0454a6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b0454a7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b0454a8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section is from a resolution entitled a “Joint Resolution giving consent of the Congress of the United States to the States of North Dakota, South Dakota, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Iowa, and Nebraska, or any two or more of said States, to agree upon the jurisdiction to be exercised by said States over boundary waters between any two or more of said States”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
