<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b9104e7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103"><num value="1103">§ 1103.</num><heading> Executive responsibilities; utilization of staff, interagency, and non-Government advisory arrangements; consultation with agencies; solicitation of views of non-Federal agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b9104e8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> In conformity with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>, it shall be the duty of the President with the advice and assistance of the Council to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b9104e9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> survey all significant marine science activities, including the policies, plans, programs, and accomplishments of all departments and agencies of the United States engaged in such activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b9104ea-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> develop a comprehensive program of marine science activities, including, but not limited to, exploration, description and prediction of the marine environment, exploitation and conservation of the resources of the marine environment, marine engineering, studies of air-sea interaction, transmission of energy, and communications, to be conducted by departments and agencies of the United States, independently or in cooperation with such non-Federal organizations as States, institutions and industry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b9104eb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> designate and fix responsibility for the conduct of the foregoing marine science activities by departments and agencies of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b9104ec-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> insure cooperation and resolve differences arising among departments and agencies of the United States with respect to marine science activities under this subchapter, including differences as to whether a particular project is a marine science activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b9104ed-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> undertake a comprehensive study, by contract or otherwise, of the legal problems arising out of the management, use, development, recovery, and control of the resources of the marine environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b9104ee-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> establish long-range studies of the potential benefits to the United States economy, security, health, and welfare to be gained from marine resources, engineering, and science, and the costs involved in obtaining such benefits; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b9104ef-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> review annually all marine science activities conducted by departments and agencies of the United States in light of the policies, plans, programs, and priorities developed pursuant to this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b9104f0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1103/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In the planning and conduct of a coordinated Federal program the President and the Council shall utilize such staff, interagency, and non-Government advisory arrangements as they may find necessary and appropriate and shall consult with departments and agencies concerned with marine science activities and solicit the views of non-Federal organizations and individuals with capabilities in marine sciences.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b9104f1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/454/tI/s4">Pub. L. 89–454, title I, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-06-17">June 17, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/205">80 Stat. 205</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/688/s2/b">Pub. L. 89–688, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1001">80 Stat. 1001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b9104f2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b9104f3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6b9104f4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(7), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/454">Pub. L. 89–454</ref>, <date date="1966-06-17">June 17, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/203">80 Stat. 203</ref>, which, at the time this section was enacted, consisted only of sections 1 to 9, which are classified generally to this subchapter. <ref href="/us/pl/89/688/s2">Pub. L. 89–688, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1001">80 Stat. 1001</ref>, redesignated the Act as title I and made conforming amendments, substituting references to title I for previous references to the Act as a whole, but not in subsec. (a)(7) of this section. <ref href="/us/pl/89/454">Pub. L. 89–454</ref> was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/89/688">Pub. L. 89–688</ref> by adding title II, which is classified generally to subchapter II of this chapter, and later by <ref href="/us/pl/92/583">Pub. L. 92–583</ref> by adding title III, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1451 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b9104f5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/688">Pub. L. 89–688</ref>, in par. (4), substituted “this title” for “this Act”, which, for purposes of codification has been changed to “this subchapter”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b9104f6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b9104f7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Council</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">National Council on Marine Resources and Engineering, established under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1102">section 1102 of this title</ref>, terminated <date date="1971-04-30">Apr. 30, 1971</date>, for lack of funds. See Codification note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1102">section 1102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
