<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b937551-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123"><num value="1123">§ 1123.</num><heading> National sea grant college program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b937552-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Program maintenance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain within the Administration a program to be known as the national sea grant college program. The national sea grant college program shall be administered by a national sea grant office within the Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b937553-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Program elements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The national sea grant college program shall consist of the financial assistance for research, education, extension, training, technology transfer, and public service and other activities authorized in this subchapter, and shall provide support for the following elements—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937554-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> sea grant programs that comprise a national sea grant college program network, including international projects conducted within such programs and regional and national projects conducted among such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937555-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> administration of the national sea grant college program and this subchapter by the national sea grant office and the Administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937556-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the fellowship program under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1127">section 1127 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937557-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any regional or national strategic investments in fields relating to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources developed in consultation with the Board and with the approval of the sea grant colleges and the sea grant institutes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b937558-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of Secretary</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b937559-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, in consultation with the Board, sea grant colleges, and sea grant institutes, shall develop at least every 4 years a strategic plan that establishes priorities for the national sea grant college program, provides an appropriately balanced response to local, regional, and national needs, and is reflective of integration with the relevant portions of the strategic plans of the Department of Commerce and of the Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b93755a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary, in consultation with the Board, sea grant colleges, and sea grant institutes, shall establish guidelines related to the activities and responsibilities of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes. Such guidelines shall include requirements for the conduct of merit review by the sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes of proposals for grants and contracts to be awarded under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1124">section 1124 of this title</ref>, providing, at a minimum, for standardized documentation of such proposals and peer review of all research projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b93755b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe the qualifications required for designation of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1126">section 1126 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b93755c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> To carry out the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b93755d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> appoint, assign the duties, transfer, and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary, in accordance with civil service laws;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b93755e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> make appointments with respect to temporary and intermittent services to the extent authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b93755f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> publish or arrange for the publication of, and otherwise disseminate, in cooperation with other offices and programs in the Administration and without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">section 501 of title 44</ref>, any information of research, educational, training or other value in fields related to ocean, coastal, or Great Lakes resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937560-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> enter into contracts, cooperative agreements, and other transactions without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937561-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> accept donations of money and, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1342">section 1342 of title 31</ref>, of voluntary and uncompensated services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937562-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> accept funds from other Federal departments and agencies, including agencies within the Administration, to pay for and add to grants made and contracts entered into by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937563-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary and appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b937564-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Director of National Sea Grant College Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b937565-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall appoint, as the Director of the National Sea Grant College Program, a qualified individual who has appropriate administrative experience and knowledge or expertise in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources. The Director shall be appointed and compensated, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, at a rate payable under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b937566-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Subject to the supervision of the Secretary, the Director shall administer the national sea grant college program and oversee the operation of the national sea grant office. In addition to any other duty prescribed by law or assigned by the Secretary, the Director shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937567-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> facilitate and coordinate the development of a strategic plan under subsection (c)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937568-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> advise the Secretary with respect to the expertise and capabilities which are available within or through the national sea grant college program and encourage the use of such expertise and capabilities, on a cooperative or other basis, by other offices and activities within the Administration, and other Federal departments and agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937569-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> advise the Secretary on the designation of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes, and, if appropriate, on the termination or suspension of any such designation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b93756a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> encourage the establishment and growth of sea grant programs, and cooperation and coordination with other Federal activities in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b93756b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> With respect to sea grant colleges, sea grant institutes, sea grant programs, and sea grant projects, the Director shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b93756c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> evaluate and assess the performance of the programs of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes, using the priorities, guidelines, and qualifications established by the Secretary under subsection (c), and determine which of the programs are the best managed and carry out the highest quality research, education, extension, and training activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b93756d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> subject to the availability of appropriations, allocate funding among sea grant colleges, sea grant institutes, sea grant programs, and sea grant projects so as to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b93756e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> promote healthy competition among sea grant colleges and institutes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b93756f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> encourage collaborations among sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes to address regional and national priorities established under subsection (c)(1);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b937570-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> ensure successful implementation of sea grant programs;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b937571-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> to the maximum extent consistent with other provisions of this subchapter, provide a stable base of funding for sea grant colleges and institutes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b937572-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> encourage and promote coordination and cooperation between the research, education, and outreach programs of the Administration and those of academic institutions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b937573-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> encourage cooperation with Minority Serving Institutions to enhance collaborative research opportunities and increase the number of such students graduating in NOAA science areas; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b937574-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1123/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> ensure compliance with the guidelines for merit review under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b937575-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/454/tII/s204">Pub. L. 89–454, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/89/688/s1">Pub. L. 89–688, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/999">80 Stat. 999</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/477/s1/2">Pub. L. 90–477, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-11">Aug. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/704">82 Stat. 704</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/2">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(2)</ref>–(7), <date date="1973-07-10">July 10, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/170">87 Stat. 170</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/461/s2">Pub. L. 94–461, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-08">Oct. 8, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1963">90 Stat. 1963</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/428">Pub. L. 95–428</ref>, §§ 2(b), 3(1), <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/999">92 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/289/s1/2">Pub. L. 96–289, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/605">94 Stat. 605</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/tIII">Pub. L. 100–220, title III</ref>, §§ 3104(b)(1)(D), (2), (c), 3105(b), <date date="1987-12-29">Dec. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1470">101 Stat. 1470</ref>, 1471; <ref href="/us/pl/102/186">Pub. L. 102–186</ref>, §§ 2, 4(b)(1)(A), <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1282">105 Stat. 1282</ref>, 1283; <ref href="/us/pl/105/160/s5">Pub. L. 105–160, § 5</ref>, <date date="1998-03-06">Mar. 6, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/22">112 Stat. 22</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/299/s3/a">Pub. L. 107–299, § 3(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (c), <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2345">116 Stat. 2345</ref>, 2346; <ref href="/us/pl/110/394">Pub. L. 110–394</ref>, §§ 5, 9(a)(4)(C)(i), <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4206">122 Stat. 4206</ref>, 4208; <ref href="/us/pl/116/221">Pub. L. 116–221</ref>, §§ 4(a), 6, 9(c)(1), 11(1), <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1058">134 Stat. 1058</ref>, 1059, 1061.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b937576-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b937577-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6b937578-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), are classified generally to section 3301 et seq. of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (d)(3)(B)(iv), was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this title” meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/89/454">Pub. L. 89–454</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b937579-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (c)(4)(D), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">section 5 of title 41</ref>, United States Code” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b93757a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/221/s6">Pub. L. 116–221, § 6</ref>, inserted “for research, education, extension, training, technology transfer, and public service” after “financial assistance” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/116/221/s4/a">Pub. L. 116–221, § 4(a)</ref>, amended subpar. (E) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (E) read as follows: “notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1342">section 1342 of title 31</ref>, accept donations and voluntary and uncompensated services;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/221/s9/c/1/A">Pub. L. 116–221, § 9(c)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “With respect to sea grant colleges, sea grant institutes, sea grant programs, and sea grant projects” for “With respect to sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/221/s9/c/1/B">Pub. L. 116–221, § 9(c)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “funding among sea grant colleges, sea grant institutes, sea grant programs, and sea grant projects” for “funding among sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/116/221/s11/1">Pub. L. 116–221, § 11(1)</ref>, realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/a/1">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(a)(1)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “sea grant programs which comprise a national sea grant college program network, including international projects conducted within such programs;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/a/2">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(a)(2)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “administration of the national sea grant college program and this subchapter by the national sea grant office, the Administration, and the panel;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/a/3">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(a)(3)</ref>, amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows: “any national strategic investments in fields relating to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources developed with the approval of the panel, the sea grant colleges, and the sea grant institutes.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s9/a/4/C/i">Pub. L. 110–394, § 9(a)(4)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “Board” for “panel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394">Pub. L. 110–394</ref>, §§ 5(b), 9(a)(4)(C)(i), substituted “The” for “Within 6 months of <date date="1998-03-06">March 6, 1998</date>, the” and “Board” for “panel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, which directed the striking out of “long range”, was executed by striking out “long-range” before “strategic plan” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/c/2">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “evaluate and assess” for “evaluate” and “activities;” for “activities; and”, struck out cl. (i) designation before “evaluate”, and struck out cl. (ii) which read as follows: “rate the programs according to their relative performance (as determined under clause (i)) into no less than 5 categories, with each of the 2 best-performing categories containing no more than 25 percent of the programs;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/c/3/A">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(c)(3)(A)</ref>, added cl. (ii). Former cl. (ii) redesignated (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/c/3/A">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(c)(3)(A)</ref>, (B), redesignated cl. (ii) as (iii) and substituted “ensure” for “encourage”. Former cl. (iii) redesignated (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(iv), (v). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/c/3/A">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(c)(3)(A)</ref>, redesignated cls. (iii) and (iv) as (iv) and (v), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/110/394/s5/c/3/C">Pub. L. 110–394, § 5(c)(3)(C)</ref>, (D), added cl. (vi).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/299/s3/a">Pub. L. 107–299, § 3(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The Secretary, in consultation with the panel, sea grant colleges, and sea grant institutes, shall develop a long-range strategic plan which establishes priorities for the national sea grant college program and which provides an appropriately balanced response to local, regional, and national needs.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/299/s3/b/1">Pub. L. 107–299, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “evaluate the programs of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes, using the priorities, guidelines, and qualifications established by the Secretary;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/107/299/s3/c">Pub. L. 107–299, § 3(c)</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/160">Pub. L. 105–160</ref> amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment text consisted of subsecs. (a) to (d) relating to maintenance within the Administration of the National Sea Grant College Program, appointment and compensation of a Director of the program, duties of the Director, and powers of the Secretary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/186/s2/a">Pub. L. 102–186, § 2(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The Secretary shall maintain, within the Administration, a program to be known as the national sea grant college program. The national sea grant college program shall consist of the financial assistance and other activities provided for in this subchapter. The Secretary shall establish long-range planning guidelines and priorities for, and adequately evaluate, this program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/186/s4/b/1/A">Pub. L. 102–186, § 4(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “section 1124” for “sections 1124 and 1125”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/102/186/s2/b">Pub. L. 102–186, § 2(b)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/102/186/s2/c">Pub. L. 102–186, § 2(c)</ref>, inserted “and add” after “to pay for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s3104/b/1/D">Pub. L. 100–220, § 3104(b)(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources” for “ocean and coastal resources”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s3104/c">Pub. L. 100–220, § 3104(c)</ref>, substituted “Under Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing in introductory provisions and par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s3104/b/2">Pub. L. 100–220, § 3104(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources” for “ocean and coastal resource”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s3104/b/1/D">Pub. L. 100–220, § 3104(b)(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources” for “ocean and coastal resources” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s3105/b">Pub. L. 100–220, § 3105(b)</ref>, struck out “under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1124/a">section 1124(a) of this title</ref>” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c)(5) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/96/289">Pub. L. 96–289</ref> added par. (5) and redesignated former pars. (5) and (6) as (6) and (7), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (a) to (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/428/s2/b">Pub. L. 95–428, § 2(b)</ref>, substituted “national sea grant college program” for “national sea grant program” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/95/428/s3/1/B">Pub. L. 95–428, § 3(1)(B)</ref>, (C), added par. (6) and redesignated former par. (6) as (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/461">Pub. L. 94–461</ref> substituted provisions covering the establishment and administration of the national sea grant program for provisions covering the marine resource development programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/2">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(2)</ref>, (5), deleted item (1) designation for provision respecting consultation with experts and Federal agencies, deleted item (2) provision for seeking advice and counsel from the National Council on Marine Resources and Engineering Development, and substituted “Secretary” for “Foundation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/5">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(5)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Foundation” and “his authority” for “its authority”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/3">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(3)</ref>, (5), authorized Federal contributions exceeding percentage limitation to programs limited to one percent of appropriations for the fiscal year when reducing or eliminating matching payments by a participant when Secretary determines it would be inequitable relevant to the benefits derived by the participant from the program to require the participant to make a one-third payment of the cost, and substituted “Secretary” for “Foundation” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/4">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(4)</ref>, (5), made prohibitions of paragraph inapplicable to non-self-propelled habitats, buoys, platforms, or other similar devices or structures, used principally for research purposes and substituted “Secretary” for “foundation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d)(3), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/5">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(5)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Foundation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/5">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(5)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Foundation” and “his functions” for “its functions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/6">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(6)</ref>, substituted provisions for exercise of powers and authority under this subchapter by the Secretary rather than the Foundation under the powers and authority of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950, as amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/5">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(5)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Foundation” and “his functions” for “its functions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/7">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(7)</ref>, inserted “and which is so designated by the Secretary” after “marine resources”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4)(A) to (C). <ref href="/us/pl/93/73/s1/5">Pub. L. 93–73, § 1(5)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Foundation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/90/477">Pub. L. 90–477</ref> struck out “in any fiscal year” after “The total amount of payments” and “by any participants”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b95e67b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b95e67c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/221/s4/d">Pub. L. 116–221, § 4(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1058">134 Stat. 1058</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/221/s4/d">
<inline>“Nothing in this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as a note below] shall be construed to limit or otherwise affect any other amounts available for marine policy fellowships under section 208(b) of the National Sea Grant College Program Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1127/b">33 U.S.C. 1127(b)</ref>), including amounts—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> accepted under section 204(c)(4)(F) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/F">33 U.S.C. 1123(c)(4)(F)</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under section 212 of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1131">33 U.S.C. 1131</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b95e67d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Priorities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/221/s4/b">Pub. L. 116–221, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-18">Dec. 18, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1058">134 Stat. 1058</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/221/s4/b">“The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, shall establish priorities for the use of donations accepted under section 204(c)(4)(E) of the National Sea Grant College Program Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1123/c/4/E">33 U.S.C. 1123(c)(4)(E)</ref>), and shall consider among those priorities the possibility of expanding the Dean John A. Knauss Marine Policy Fellowship’s placement of additional fellows in relevant legislative offices under section 208(b) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1127/b">33 U.S.C. 1127(b)</ref>), in accordance with the recommendations under subsection (c) of this section [<ref href="/us/stat/134/1058">134 Stat. 1058</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b95e67e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Evaluation and Rating Process</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/299/s3/b/2">Pub. L. 107–299, § 3(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2346">116 Stat. 2346</ref>, provided that after 3 years after <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, was to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review the effectiveness of the evaluation and rating system under this section in determining the relative performance of programs of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes and provided that the National Academy of Sciences would submit a report to the Congress on the findings and recommendations of the panel not later than 4 years after <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b95e67f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notice of Reorganization</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/160/s9/d">Pub. L. 105–160, § 9(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-03-06">Mar. 6, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/27">112 Stat. 27</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/160/s9/d">“The Secretary of Commerce shall provide notice to the Committees on Science [now Science, Space, and Technology], Resources [now Natural Resources], and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Appropriations of the Senate, not later than 45 days before any major reorganization of any program, project, or activity of the National Sea Grant College Program.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
