<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6ba1cd06-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1252a"><num value="1252a">§ 1252a.</num><heading> Reservoir projects, water storage; modification; storage for other than for water quality, opinion of Federal agency, committee resolutions of approval; provisions inapplicable to projects with certain prescribed water quality benefits in relation to total project benefits</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any reservoir project authorized for construction by the Corps of Engineers, Bureau of Reclamation, or other Federal agency when the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency determines pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1252/b">section 1252(b) of this title</ref> that any storage in such project for regulation of streamflow for water quality is not needed, or is needed in a different amount, such project may be modified accordingly by the head of the appropriate agency, and any storage no longer required for water quality may be utilized for other authorized purposes of the project when, in the opinion of the head of such agency, such use is justified. Any such modification of a project where the benefits attributable to water quality are 15 per centum or more but not greater than 25 per centum of the total project benefits shall take effect only upon the adoption of resolutions approving such modification by the appropriate committees of the Senate and House of Representatives. The provisions of the section shall not apply to any project where the benefits attributable to water quality exceed 25 per centum of the total project benefits.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6ba1cd07-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/251/tI/s65">Pub. L. 93–251, title I, § 65</ref>, <date date="1974-03-07">Mar. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/30">88 Stat. 30</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6ba1cd08-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6ba1cd09-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6ba1cd0a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
