<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6ba4175c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255"><num value="1255">§ 1255.</num><heading> Grants for research and development</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba4175d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstration projects covering storm waters, advanced waste treatment and water purification methods, and joint treatment systems for municipal and industrial wastes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to conduct in the Environmental Protection Agency, and to make grants to any State, municipality, or intermunicipal or interstate agency for the purpose of assisting in the development of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba4175e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any project which will demonstrate a new or improved method of preventing, reducing, and eliminating the discharge into any waters of pollutants from sewers which carry storm water or both storm water and pollutants; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba4175f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any project which will demonstrate advanced waste treatment and water purification methods (including the temporary use of new or improved chemical additives which provide substantial immediate improvements to existing treatment processes), or new or improved methods of joint treatment systems for municipal and industrial wastes;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and to include in such grants such amounts as are necessary for the purpose of reports, plans, and specifications in connection therewith.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba41760-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstration projects for advanced treatment and environmental enhancement techniques to control pollution in river basins</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to make grants to any State or States or interstate agency to demonstrate, in river basins or portions thereof, advanced treatment and environmental enhancement techniques to control pollution from all sources, within such basins or portions thereof, including nonpoint sources, together with in stream <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002050">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002050"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> water quality improvement techniques.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba41761-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and demonstration projects for prevention of water pollution by industry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to carry out the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1311">section 1311 of this title</ref>, the Administrator is authorized to (1) conduct in the Environmental Protection Agency, (2) make grants to persons, and (3) enter into contracts with persons, for research and demonstration projects for prevention of pollution of any waters by industry including, but not limited to, the prevention, reduction, and elimination of the discharge of pollutants. No grant shall be made for any project under this subsection unless the Administrator determines that such project will develop or demonstrate a new or improved method of treating industrial wastes or otherwise prevent pollution by industry, which method shall have industrywide application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba41762-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Accelerated and priority development of waste management and waste treatment methods and identification and measurement methods</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Administrator shall conduct, on a priority basis, an accelerated effort to develop, refine, and achieve practical application of:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba68863-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> waste management methods applicable to point and nonpoint sources of pollutants to eliminate the discharge of pollutants, including, but not limited to, elimination of runoff of pollutants and the effects of pollutants from inplace or accumulated sources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba68864-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> advanced waste treatment methods applicable to point and nonpoint sources, including inplace or accumulated sources of pollutants, and methods for reclaiming and recycling water and confining pollutants so they will not migrate to cause water or other environmental pollution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba68865-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> improved methods and procedures to identify and measure the effects of pollutants on the chemical, physical, and biological integrity of water, including those pollutants created by new technological developments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba68866-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and demonstration projects covering agricultural pollution and pollution from sewage in rural areas; dissemination of information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6ba68867-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Administrator is authorized to (A) make, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, grants to persons for research and demonstration projects with respect to new and improved methods of preventing, reducing, and eliminating pollution from agriculture, and (B) disseminate, in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture, such information obtained under this subsection, <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1254/p">section 1254(p) of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1314">section 1314 of this title</ref> as will encourage and enable the adoption of such methods in the agricultural industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6ba68868-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator is authorized, (A) in consultation with other interested Federal agencies, to make grants for demonstration proj­ects with respect to new and improved methods of preventing, reducing, storing, collecting, treating, or otherwise eliminating pollution from sewage in rural and other areas where collection of sewage in conventional, community-wide sewage collection systems is impractical, uneconomical, or otherwise infeasible, or where soil conditions or other factors preclude the use of septic tank and drainage field systems, and (B) in cooperation with other interested Federal and State agencies, to disseminate such information obtained under this subsection as will encourage and enable the adoption of new and improved methods developed pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba68869-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Federal grants under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to the following limitations:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba6886a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No grant shall be made for any project unless such project shall have been approved by the appropriate State water pollution control agency or agencies and by the Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba6886b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No grant shall be made for any project in an amount exceeding 75 per centum of cost thereof as determined by the Administrator; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6ba6886c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No grant shall be made for any project unless the Administrator determines that such project will serve as a useful demonstration for the purpose set forth in clause (1) or (2) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba6886d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Federal grants under subsections (c) and (d) of this section shall not exceed 75 per centum of the cost of the project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba6886e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this section there is authorized to be appropriated $75,000,000 per fiscal year for the fiscal year ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, the fiscal year ending <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, and the fiscal year ending <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>, and from such appropriations at least 10 per centum of the funds actually appropriated in each fiscal year shall be available only for the purposes of subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba6886f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance for research and demonstration projects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to make grants to a municipality to assist in the costs of operating and maintaining a project which received a grant under this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1254">section 1254 of this title</ref>, or <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1263">section 1263 of this title</ref> prior to <date date="1977-12-27">December 27, 1977</date>, so as to reduce the operation and maintenance costs borne by the recipients of services from such project to costs comparable to those for projects assisted under subchapter II of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6ba68870-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1255/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance for recycle, reuse, and land treatment projects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to make a grant to any grantee who received an increased grant pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1282/a/2">section 1282(a)(2) of this title</ref>. Such grant may pay up to 100 per centum of the costs of technical evaluation of the operation of the treatment works, costs of training of persons (other than employees of the grantee), and costs of disseminating technical information on the operation of the treatment works.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6ba68871-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, title I, § 105, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/500/s2">Pub. L. 92–500, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/825">86 Stat. 825</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/592/s2">Pub. L. 93–592, § 2</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1925">88 Stat. 1925</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/217">Pub. L. 95–217</ref>, §§ 8, 9, <date date="1977-12-27">Dec. 27, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1568">91 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6ba68872-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6ba68873-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6ba68874-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/95/217">Pub. L. 95–217</ref> added subsecs. (i) and (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/93/592">Pub. L. 93–592</ref> substituted “the fiscal year ending <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, and the fiscal year ending <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>,” for “and the fiscal year ending <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6ba68875-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6ba68876-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enforcement functions of Secretary or other official in Department of Agriculture, insofar as they involve lands and programs under jurisdiction of that Department, related to compliance with this chapter with respect to pre-construction, construction, and initial operation of transportation system for Canadian and Alaskan natural gas were transferred to the Federal Inspector, Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, until the first anniversary of date of initial operation of the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System, see Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1979, §§ 102(f), 203(a), 44 F.R. 33663, 33666, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1373">93 Stat. 1373</ref>, 1376, effective <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Office of Federal Inspector for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System abolished and functions and authority vested in Inspector transferred to Secretary of Energy by <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s3012/b">section 3012(b) of Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, set out as an Abolition of Office of Federal Inspector note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s719e">section 719e of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade. Functions and authority vested in Secretary of Energy subsequently transferred to Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s720d/f">section 720d(f) of Title 15</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
