<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6bab436c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268"><num value="1268">§ 1268.</num><heading> Great Lakes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab436d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings, purpose, and definitions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab436e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Congress finds that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab436f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Great Lakes are a valuable national resource, continuously serving the people of the United States and other nations as an important source of food, fresh water, recreation, beauty, and enjoyment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4370-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the United States should seek to attain the goals embodied in the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement of 1978, as amended by the Water Quality Agreement of 1987 and any other agreements and amendments, with particular emphasis on goals related to toxic pollutants; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4371-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Environmental Protection Agency should take the lead in the effort to meet those goals, working with other Federal agencies and State and local authorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab4372-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It is the purpose of this section to achieve the goals embodied in the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement of 1978, as amended by the Water Quality Agreement of 1987 and any other agreements and amendments, through improved organization and definition of mission on the part of the Agency, funding of State grants for pollution control in the Great Lakes area, and improved accountability for implementation of such agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab4373-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4374-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Agency” means the Environmental Protection Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4375-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Great Lakes” means Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron (including Lake St. Clair), Lake Michigan, and Lake Superior, and the connecting channels (Saint Mary’s River, Saint Clair River, Detroit River, Niagara River, and Saint Lawrence River to the Canadian Border);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4376-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> “Great Lakes System” means all the streams, rivers, lakes, and other bodies of water within the drainage basin of the Great Lakes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4377-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> “Program Office” means the Great Lakes National Program Office established by this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4378-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> “Research Office” means the Great Lakes Research Office established by subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4379-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> “area of concern” means a geographic area located within the Great Lakes, in which beneficial uses are impaired and which has been officially designated as such under Annex 2 of the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab437a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> “Great Lakes States” means the States of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, and Wisconsin;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab437b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> “Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement” means the bilateral agreement, between the United States and Canada which was signed in 1978 and amended by the Protocol of 1987;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab437c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> “Lakewide Management Plan” means a written document which embodies a systematic and comprehensive ecosystem approach to restoring and protecting the beneficial uses of the open waters of each of the Great Lakes, in accordance with article VI and Annex 2 of the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab437d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> “Remedial Action Plan” means a written document which embodies a systematic and comprehensive ecosystem approach to restoring and protecting the beneficial uses of areas of concern, in accordance with article VI and Annex 2 of the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab437e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> “site characterization” means a process for monitoring and evaluating the nature and extent of sediment contamination in accordance with the Environmental Protection Agency’s guidance for the assessment of contaminated sediment in an area of concern located wholly or partially within the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab437f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> “potentially responsible party” means an individual or entity that may be liable under any Federal or State authority that is being used or may be used to facilitate the cleanup and protection of the Great Lakes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab4380-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Great Lakes National Program Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Great Lakes National Program Office (previously established by the Administrator) is hereby established within the Agency. The Program Office shall be headed by a Director who, by reason of management experience and technical expertise relating to the Great Lakes, is highly qualified to direct the development of programs and plans on a variety of Great Lakes issues. The Great Lakes National Program Office shall be located in a Great Lakes State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab4381-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Great Lakes management</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab4382-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Program Office shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4383-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in cooperation with appropriate Federal, State, tribal, and international agencies, and in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1251/e">section 1251(e) of this title</ref>, develop and implement specific action plans to carry out the responsibilities of the United States under the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement of 1978, as amended by the Water Quality Agreement of 1987 and any other agreements and amendments,; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002052">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002052"><num>1</num> So in original.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4384-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> establish a Great Lakes system-wide surveillance network to monitor the water quality of the Great Lakes, with specific emphasis on the monitoring of toxic pollutants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4385-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> serve as the liaison with, and provide information to, the Canadian members of the International Joint Commission and the Canadian counterpart to the Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4386-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> coordinate actions of the Agency (including actions by headquarters and regional offices thereof) aimed at improving Great Lakes water quality; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4387-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> coordinate actions of the Agency with the actions of other Federal agencies and State and local authorities, so as to ensure the input of those agencies and authorities in developing water quality strategies and obtain the support of those agencies and authorities in achieving the objectives of such agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab4388-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Great Lakes water quality guidance</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab4389-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> By <date date="1991-06-30">June 30, 1991</date>, the Administrator, after consultation with the Program Office, shall publish in the Federal Register for public notice and comment proposed water quality guidance for the Great Lakes System. Such guidance shall conform with the objectives and provisions of the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement, shall be no less restrictive than the provisions of this chapter and national water quality criteria and guidance, shall specify numerical limits on pollutants in ambient Great Lakes waters to protect human health, aquatic life, and wildlife, and shall provide guidance to the Great Lakes States on minimum water quality standards, antidegradation policies, and implementation procedures for the Great Lakes System.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab438a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> By <date date="1992-06-30">June 30, 1992</date>, the Administrator, in consultation with the Program Office, shall publish in the Federal Register, pursuant to this section and the Administrator’s authority under this chapter, final water quality guidance for the Great Lakes System.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab438b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Within two years after such Great Lakes guidance is published, the Great Lakes States shall adopt water quality standards, antidegradation policies, and implementation procedures for waters within the Great Lakes System which are consistent with such guidance. If a Great Lakes State fails to adopt such standards, policies, and procedures, the Administrator shall promulgate them not later than the end of such two-year period. When reviewing any Great Lakes State’s water quality plan, the agency shall consider the extent to which the State has complied with the Great Lakes guidance issued pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab438c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Remedial Action Plans</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab438d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> For each area of concern for which the United States has agreed to draft a Remedial Action Plan, the Program Office shall ensure that the Great Lakes State in which such area of concern is located—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab438e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> submits a Remedial Action Plan to the Program Office by <date date="1991-06-30">June 30, 1991</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab438f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> submits such Remedial Action Plan to the International Joint Commission by <date date="1992-01-01">January 1, 1992</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4390-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> includes such Remedial Action Plans within the State’s water quality plan by <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab4391-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For each area of concern for which Canada has agreed to draft a Remedial Action Plan, the Program Office shall, pursuant to subparagraph (c)(1)(C) of this section, work with Canada to assure the submission of such Remedial Action Plans to the International Joint Commission by <date date="1991-06-30">June 30, 1991</date>, and to finalize such Remedial Action Plans by <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab4392-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For any area of concern designated as such subsequent to <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Program Office shall (i) if the United States has agreed to draft the Remedial Action Plan, ensure that the Great Lakes State in which such area of concern is located submits such Plan to the Program Office within two years of the area’s designation, submits it to the International Joint Commission no later than six months after submitting it to the Program Office, and includes such Plan in the State’s water quality plan no later than one year after submitting it to the Commission; and (ii) if Canada has agreed to draft the Remedial Action Plan, work with Canada, pursuant to subparagraph (c)(1)(C) of this section, to ensure the submission of such Plan to the International Joint Commission within two years of the area’s designation and the finalization of such Plan no later than eighteen months after submitting it to such Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab4393-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Program Office shall compile formal comments on individual Remedial Action Plans made by the International Joint Commission pursuant to section 4(d) of Annex 2 of the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement and, upon request by a member of the public, shall make such comments available for inspection and copying. The Program Office shall also make available, upon request, formal comments made by the Environmental Protection Agency on individual Remedial Action Plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bab4394-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after <date date="2002-11-27">November 27, 2002</date>, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on such actions, time periods, and resources as are necessary to fulfill the duties of the Agency relating to oversight of Remedial Action Plans under—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4395-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4396-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab4397-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Lakewide Management Plans</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator, in consultation with the Program Office shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4398-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> by <date date="1992-01-01">January 1, 1992</date>, publish in the Federal Register a proposed Lakewide Management Plan for Lake Michigan and solicit public comments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab4399-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> by <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>, submit a proposed Lakewide Management Plan for Lake Michigan to the International Joint Commission for review; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bab439a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> by <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>, publish in the Federal Register a final Lakewide Management Plan for Lake Michigan and begin implementation.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Nothing in this subparagraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002053">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002053"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraph”.</note> shall preclude the simultaneous development of Lakewide Management Plans for the other Great Lakes.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bab439b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Spills of oil and hazardous materials</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Program Office, in consultation with the Coast Guard, shall identify areas within the Great Lakes which are likely to experience numerous or voluminous spills of oil or other hazardous materials from land based facilities, vessels, or other sources and, in consultation with the Great Lakes States, shall identify weaknesses in Federal and State programs and systems to prevent and respond to such spills. This information shall be included on at least a biennial basis in the report required by this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb39c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> 5-year plan and program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Program Office shall develop, in consultation with the States, a five-year plan and program for reducing the amount of nutrients introduced into the Great Lakes. Such program shall incorporate any management program for reducing nutrient runoff from nonpoint sources established under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1329">section 1329 of this title</ref> and shall include a program for monitoring nutrient runoff into, and ambient levels in, the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb39d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Great Lakes Restoration Initiative</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb39e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">There is established in the Agency a Great Lakes Restoration Initiative (referred to in this paragraph as the “Initiative”) to carry out programs and projects for Great Lakes protection and restoration.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb39f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Focus areas</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out the Initiative, the Administrator shall prioritize programs and projects, to be carried out in coordination with non-Federal partners, that address the priority areas described in the Initiative Action Plan, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3a0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the remediation of toxic substances and areas of concern;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3a1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the prevention and control of invasive species and the impacts of invasive species;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3a2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the protection and restoration of nearshore health and the prevention and mitigation of nonpoint source pollution;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3a3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> habitat and wildlife protection and restoration, including wetlands restoration and preservation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3a4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> accountability, monitoring, evaluation, communication, and partnership activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3a5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Projects</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3a6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In carrying out the Initiative, the Administrator shall collaborate with other Federal partners, including the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force established by Executive Order No. 13340 (69 Fed. Reg. 29043), to select the best combination of programs and projects for Great Lakes protection and restoration using appropriate principles and criteria, including whether a program or project provides—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3a7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the ability to achieve strategic and measurable environmental outcomes that implement the Initiative Action Plan and the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3a8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> the feasibility of—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id6badb3a9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/i/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> prompt implementation;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id6badb3aa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/i/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> timely achievement of results; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id6badb3ab-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/i/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> resource leveraging; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3ac-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the opportunity to improve interagency, intergovernmental, and interorganizational coordination and collaboration to reduce duplication and streamline efforts.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3ad-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In selecting the best combination of programs and projects for Great Lakes protection and restoration under clause (i), the Administrator shall consult with the Great Lakes States and Indian tribes and solicit input from other non-Federal stakeholders.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3ae-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Harmful algal bloom coordinator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Administrator shall designate a point person from an appropriate Federal partner to coordinate, with Federal partners and Great Lakes States, Indian tribes, and other non-Federal stakeholders, projects and activities under the Initiative involving harmful algal blooms in the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3af-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation of projects</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3b0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Subject to subparagraph (J)(ii), funds made available to carry out the Initiative shall be used to strategically implement—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3b1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Federal projects;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3b2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> projects carried out in coordination with States, Indian tribes, municipalities, institutions of higher education, and other organizations; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3b3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> operations and activities of the Program Office, including remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3b4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">With amounts made available for the Initiative each fiscal year, the Administrator may—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3b5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> transfer not more than the total amount appropriated under subparagraph (J)(i) for the fiscal year to the head of any Federal department or agency, with the concurrence of the department or agency head, to carry out activities to support the Initiative and the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3b6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> enter into an interagency agreement with the head of any Federal department or agency to carry out activities described in subclause (I).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3b7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements with non-Federal entities</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3b8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Administrator, or the head of any other Federal department or agency receiving funds under clause (ii)(I), may make a grant to, or otherwise enter into an agreement with, a qualified non-Federal entity, as determined by the Administrator or the applicable head of the other Federal department or agency receiving funds, for planning, research, monitoring, outreach, or implementation of a project selected under subparagraph (C), to support the Initiative Action Plan or the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3b9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/D/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified non-Federal entity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">For purposes of this clause, a qualified non-Federal entity may include a governmental entity, nonprofit organization, institution, or individual.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3ba-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3bb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Projects may be carried out under the Initiative on multiple levels, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3bc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> locally;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3bd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Great Lakes-wide; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3be-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Great Lakes basin-wide.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3bf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">No funds made available to carry out the Initiative may be used for any water infrastructure activity (other than a green infrastructure project that improves habitat and other ecosystem functions in the Great Lakes) for which financial assistance is received—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3c0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> from a State water pollution control revolving fund established under subchapter VI;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3c1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> from a State drinking water revolving loan fund established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300j–12">section 300j–12 of title 42</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3c2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/E/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> pursuant to the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s3901">33 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3c3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities by other Federal agencies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each relevant Federal department or agency shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3c4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> maintain the base level of funding for the Great Lakes activities of that department or agency without regard to funding under the Initiative; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3c5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> identify new activities and projects to support the environmental goals of the Initiative.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3c6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Revision of Initiative Action Plan</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3c7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/G/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not less often than once every 5 years, the Administrator, in conjunction with the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force, shall review, and revise as appropriate, the Initiative Action Plan to guide the activities of the Initiative in addressing the restoration and protection of the Great Lakes system.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3c8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/G/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In reviewing and revising the Initiative Action Plan under clause (i), the Administrator shall consult with the Great Lakes States and Indian tribes and solicit input from other non-Federal stakeholders.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3c9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/H"><num value="H" class="bold">(H)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring and reporting</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3ca-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> establish and maintain a process for monitoring and periodically reporting to the public on the progress made in implementing the Initiative Action Plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3cb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> make information about each project carried out under the Initiative Action Plan available on a public website; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3cc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/H/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a yearly detailed description of the progress of the Initiative and amounts transferred to participating Federal departments and agencies under subparagraph (D)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3cd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Initiative Action Plan defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “Initiative Action Plan” means the comprehensive, multiyear action plan for the restoration of the Great Lakes, first developed pursuant to the Joint Explanatory Statement of the Conference Report accompanying the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010 (<ref href="/us/pl/111/88">Public Law 111–88</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3ce-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J"><num value="J" class="bold">(J)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3cf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> $300,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> $375,000,000 for fiscal year 2022;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> $400,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> $425,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> $450,000,000 for fiscal year 2025; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/i/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> $475,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3d6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Nothing in this paragraph creates, expands, or amends the authority of the Administrator to implement programs or projects under—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> this section;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the Initiative Action Plan; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb3d9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/7/J/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3da-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrator’s responsibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall ensure that the Program Office enters into agreements with the various organizational elements of the Agency involved in Great Lakes activities and the appropriate State agencies specifically delineating—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb3db-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the duties and responsibilities of each such element in the Agency with respect to the Great Lakes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb3dc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the time periods for carrying out such duties and responsibilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb3dd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the resources to be committed to such duties and responsibilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3de-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget item</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall, in the Agency’s annual budget submission to Congress, include a funding request for the Program Office as a separate budget line item.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3df-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Confined disposal facilities</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb3e0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, shall develop and implement, within one year of <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, management plans for every Great Lakes confined disposal facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb3e1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The plan shall provide for monitoring of such facilities, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb3e2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> water quality at the site and in the area of the site;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb3e3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> sediment quality at the site and in the area of the site;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb3e4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the diversity, productivity, and stability of aquatic organisms at the site and in the area of the site; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb3e5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> such other conditions as the Administrator deems appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb3e6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The plan shall identify the anticipated use and management of the site over the following twenty-year period including the expected termination of dumping at the site, the anticipated need for site management, including pollution control, following the termination of the use of the site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb3e7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/10/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The plan shall identify a schedule for review and revision of the plan which shall not be less frequent than five years after adoption of the plan and every five years thereafter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3e8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3e9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In accordance with this paragraph, the Administrator, acting through the Program Office, may carry out projects that meet the requirements of subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3ea-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible projects</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A project meets the requirements of this subparagraph if the project is to be carried out in an area of concern located wholly or partially in the United States and the project—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3eb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> monitors or evaluates contaminated sediment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3ec-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subject to subparagraph (D), implements a plan to remediate contaminated sediment, including activities to restore aquatic habitat that are carried out in conjunction with a project for the remediation of contaminated sediment; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3ed-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> prevents further or renewed contamination of sediment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3ee-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In selecting projects to carry out under this paragraph, the Administrator shall give priority to a project that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3ef-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> constitutes remedial action for contaminated sediment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> has been identified in a Remedial Action Plan submitted under paragraph (3); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> is ready to be implemented;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> will use an innovative approach, technology, or technique that may provide greater environmental benefits, or equivalent environmental benefits at a reduced cost; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> includes remediation to be commenced not later than 1 year after the date of receipt of funds for the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3f5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator may not carry out a project under this paragraph for remediation of contaminated sediments located in an area of concern—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> if an evaluation of remedial alternatives for the area of concern has not been conducted, including a review of the short-term and long-term effects of the alternatives on human health and the environment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the Administrator determines that the area of concern is likely to suffer significant further or renewed contamination from existing sources of pollutants causing sediment contamination following completion of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> unless each non-Federal sponsor for the project has entered into a written project agreement with the Administrator under which the party agrees to carry out its responsibilities and requirements for the project; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6badb3f9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> unless the Administrator provides assurance that the Agency has conducted a reasonable inquiry to identify potentially responsible parties connected with the site.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3fa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3fb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The non-Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under this paragraph shall be at least 35 percent.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3fc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> In-kind contributions</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3fd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The non-Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under this paragraph may include the value of an in-kind contribution provided by a non-Federal sponsor.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3fe-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">A project agreement described in subparagraph (D)(iii) may provide, with respect to a project, that the Administrator shall credit toward the non-Federal share of the cost of the project the value of an in-kind contribution made by the non-Federal sponsor, if the Administrator determines that the material or service provided as the in-kind contribution is integral to the project.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb3ff-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Work performed before project agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In any case in which a non-Federal sponsor is to receive credit under subclause (II) for the cost of work carried out by the non-Federal sponsor and such work has not been carried out by the non-Federal sponsor as of <date date="2008-10-08">October 8, 2008</date>, the Administrator and the non-Federal sponsor shall enter into an agreement under which the non-Federal sponsor shall carry out such work, and only work carried out following the execution of the agreement shall be eligible for credit.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb400-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii/IV"><num value="IV" class="bold">(IV)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Credit authorized under this clause for a project carried out under this paragraph—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id6badb401-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> shall not exceed the non-Federal share of the cost of the project; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id6badb402-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> shall not exceed the actual and reasonable costs of the materials and services provided by the non-Federal sponsor, as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb403-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/ii/V"><num value="V" class="bold">(V)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion of certain contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In this subparagraph, the term “in-kind contribution” may include the costs of planning (including data collection), design, construction, and materials that are provided by the non-Federal sponsor for implementation of a project under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb404-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of credit between projects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Any credit provided under this subparagraph towards the non-Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under this paragraph may be applied towards the non-Federal share of the cost of any other project carried out under this paragraph by the same non-Federal sponsor for a site within the same area of concern.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb405-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The non-Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under this paragraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb406-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> may include monies paid pursuant to, or the value of any in-kind contribution performed under, an administrative order on consent or judicial consent decree; but</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6badb407-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> may not include any funds paid pursuant to, or the value of any in-kind contribution performed under, a unilateral administrative order or court order.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb408-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/E/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Operation and maintenance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The non-Federal share of the cost of the operation and maintenance of a project carried out under this paragraph shall be 100 percent.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb409-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Site characterization</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb40a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/F/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Administrator, in consultation with any affected State or unit of local government, shall carry out at Federal expense the site characterization of a project under this paragraph for the remediation of contaminated sediment.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb40b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/F/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), the Administrator may carry out one site assessment per discrete site within a project at Federal expense.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb40c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out projects under this paragraph, the Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary of the Army, and with the Governors of States in which the projects are located, to ensure that Federal and State assistance for remediation in areas of concern is used as efficiently as practicable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb40d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/H"><num value="H" class="bold">(H)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb40e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/H/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In addition to other amounts authorized under this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2010.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb40f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/H/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Funds made available under clause (i) shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb410-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11/H/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not more than 20 percent of the funds appropriated pursuant to clause (i) for a fiscal year may be used to carry out subparagraph (F).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb411-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/12"><num value="12" class="bold">(12)</num><heading class="bold"> Public information program</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb412-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/12/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator, acting through the Program Office and in coordination with States, Indian tribes, local governments, and other entities, may carry out a public information program to provide information relating to the remediation of contaminated sediment to the public in areas of concern that are located wholly or partially in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb413-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/12/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2010.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb414-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Great Lakes research</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb415-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of Research Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is established within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration the Great Lakes Research Office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb416-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of issues</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Research Office shall identify issues relating to the Great Lakes resources on which research is needed. The Research Office shall submit a report to Congress on such issues before the end of each fiscal year which shall identify any changes in the Great Lakes system <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002054">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002054"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be capitalized.</note> with respect to such issues.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb417-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Inventory</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Research Office shall identify and inventory Federal, State, university, and tribal environmental research programs (and, to the extent feasible, those of private organizations and other nations) relating to the Great Lakes system,<sup>3</sup> and shall update that inventory every four years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb418-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Research exchange</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Research Office shall establish a Great Lakes research exchange for the purpose of facilitating the rapid identification, acquisition, retrieval, dissemination, and use of information concerning research projects which are ongoing or completed and which affect the Great Lakes System.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb419-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Research program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Research Office shall develop, in cooperation with the Coordination Office, a comprehensive environmental research program and data base for the Great Lakes system.<sup>3</sup> The data base shall include, but not be limited to, data relating to water quality, fisheries, and biota.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb41a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Research Office shall conduct, through the Great Lakes Environmental Research Laboratory, the National Sea Grant College program, other Federal laboratories, and the private sector, appropriate research and monitoring activities which address priority issues and current needs relating to the Great Lakes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb41b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/d/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Location</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Research Office shall be located in a Great Lakes State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb41c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and management coordination</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb41d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Joint plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before October 1 of each year, the Program Office and the Research Office shall prepare a joint research plan for the fiscal year which begins in the following calendar year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb41e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each plan prepared under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb41f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identify all proposed research dedicated to activities conducted under the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement of 1978, as amended by the Water Quality Agreement of 1987 and any other agreements and amendments,; <sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb420-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> include the Agency’s assessment of priorities for research needed to fulfill the terms of such Agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6badb421-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> identify all proposed research that may be used to develop a comprehensive environmental data base for the Great Lakes System and establish priorities for development of such data base.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb422-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Health research report</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb423-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>, the Program Office, in consultation with the Research Office, the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, and Great Lakes States shall submit to the Congress a report assessing the adverse effects of water pollutants in the Great Lakes System on the health of persons in Great Lakes States and the health of fish, shellfish, and wildlife in the Great Lakes System. In conducting research in support of this report, the Administrator may, where appropriate, provide for research to be conducted under cooperative agreements with Great Lakes States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb424-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section not to exceed $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1992, 1993, and 1994.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb425-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency cooperation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The head of each department, agency, or other instrumentality of the Federal Government which is engaged in, is concerned with, or has authority over programs relating to research, monitoring, and planning to maintain, enhance, preserve, or rehabilitate the environmental quality and natural resources of the Great Lakes, including the Chief of Engineers of the Army, the Chief of the Soil Conservation Service, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall submit an annual report to the Administrator with respect to the activities of that agency or office affecting compliance with the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement of 1978, as amended by the Water Quality Agreement of 1987 and any other agreements and amendments,.<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb426-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to existing Federal and State laws and international treaties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb427-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to affect the jurisdiction, powers, or prerogatives of any department, agency, or officer of the Federal Government or of any State government, or of any tribe, nor any powers, jurisdiction, or prerogatives of any international body created by treaty with authority relating to the Great Lakes; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb428-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to affect any other Federal or State authority that is being used or may be used to facilitate the cleanup and protection of the Great Lakes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6badb429-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorizations of Great Lakes appropriations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section not to exceed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb42a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> $11,000,000 per fiscal year for the fiscal years 1987, 1988, 1989, and 1990, and $25,000,000 for fiscal year 1991;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb42b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 1992 through 2003; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6badb42c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1268/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2008.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6badb42d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, title I, § 118, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/tI/s104">Pub. L. 100–4, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1987-02-04">Feb. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/11">101 Stat. 11</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/688/tI/s1008">Pub. L. 100–688, title I, § 1008</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4151">102 Stat. 4151</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/596/tI">Pub. L. 101–596, title I</ref>, §§ 101–106, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3000-3004">104 Stat. 3000–3004</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/303/tI">Pub. L. 107–303, title I</ref>, §§ 102–105, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2355-2358">116 Stat. 2355–2358</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/365">Pub. L. 110–365</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4021">122 Stat. 4021</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/188/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 113–188, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2019">128 Stat. 2019</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dG/tIV/s426">Pub. L. 114–113, div. G, title IV, § 426</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2581">129 Stat. 2581</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/tIV/s5005">Pub. L. 114–322, title IV, § 5005</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1889">130 Stat. 1889</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/294/s2">Pub. L. 116–294, § 2</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4899">134 Stat. 4899</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6badb42e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6badb42f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6badb430-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13340, referred to in subsec. (c)(7)(C)(i), is Ex. Ord. No. 13340, <date date="2004-05-18">May 18, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 29043, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1268">section 1268 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014, referred to in subsec. (c)(7)(E)(ii)(III), is subtitle C (§§ 5021–5035) of title V of <ref href="/us/pl/113/121">Pub. L. 113–121</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1332">128 Stat. 1332</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 52 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010, referred to in subsec. (c)(7)(I), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/88/dA">Pub. L. 111–88, div. A</ref>, <date date="2009-10-30">Oct. 30, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2904">123 Stat. 2904</ref>. The Conference Report accompanying the Act (H.R. 2996) is H. Rept. No. 111–316, 111th Cong., 1st Sess.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6badb431-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, referred to in subsec. (c)(3)(C), was in the original “the enactment of this Act”, and “the date of the enactment of this title” which were translated as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/101/596/tI">Pub. L. 101–596, title I</ref> of which enacted subsec. (c)(3), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6badb432-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (c)(7)(J)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/294">Pub. L. 116–294</ref> substituted “are authorized” for “is authorized”, inserted dash after “this paragraph” and subcl. (I) designation before “$300,000,000”, and added subcls. (II) to (VI).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (c)(7)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/s5005/1">Pub. L. 114–322, § 5005(1)</ref>, added subpars. (B) and (C) and struck out former subpars. (B) and (C) which related to focus areas in which the Initiative should prioritize programs and projects, and the selection of programs and projects for Great Lakes protection and restoration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7)(D)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/s5005/2/A">Pub. L. 114–322, § 5005(2)(A)</ref>, added cl. (i) and struck out former cl. (i). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Subject to subparagraph (G)(ii), funds made available to carry out the Initiative shall be used to strategically implement—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) Federal projects; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) projects carried out in coordination with States, Indian tribes, municipalities, institutions of higher education, and other organizations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7)(D)(ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/s5005/2/B">Pub. L. 114–322, § 5005(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “(J)(i)” for “(G)(i)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7)(D)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/s5005/2/C">Pub. L. 114–322, § 5005(2)(C)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7)(E) to (J). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/s5005/3">Pub. L. 114–322, § 5005(3)</ref>, added subpars. (E) to (J) and struck out former subpars. (E) to (G) which related to scope of projects, activities by other Federal agencies, and funding for fiscal year 2016.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref> added par. (7) and struck out former par. (7), which required a five-year study and demonstration projects relating to the control and removal of toxic pollutants in the Great Lakes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(10) to (13). <ref href="/us/pl/113/188">Pub. L. 113–188</ref> redesignated pars. (11) to (13) as (10) to (12), respectively, and struck out former par. (10) which required submission of annual comprehensive reports.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(3)(K), (L). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s2">Pub. L. 110–365, § 2</ref>, added subpars. (K) and (L).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/a">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(a)</ref>, substituted “sediment, including activities to restore aquatic habitat that are carried out in conjunction with a project for the remediation of contaminated sediment” for “sediment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/b/1">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Limitations” for “Limitation” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(D)(iii), (iv). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/b/2">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(b)(2)</ref>–(4), added cls. (iii) and (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(E)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/c">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(c)</ref>, amended cl. (ii) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The non-Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under this paragraph may include the value of in-kind services contributed by a non-Federal sponsor.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(E)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/d/2">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(d)(2)</ref>, added cl. (iii). Former cl. (iii) redesignated (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(E)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/d/1">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(d)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated cl. (iii) as (iv) and substituted “contribution” for “service” in two places. Former cl. (iv) redesignated (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(E)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/d/1">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated cl. (iv) as (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/e">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(e)</ref>, amended subpar. (F) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Administrator may not carry out a project under this paragraph unless the non-Federal sponsor enters into such agreements with the Administrator as the Administrator may require to ensure that the non-Federal sponsor will maintain its aggregate expenditures from all other sources for remediation programs in the area of concern in which the project is located at or above the average level of such expenditures in the 2 fiscal years preceding the date on which the project is initiated.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(H)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/f/1">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(f)(1)</ref>, added cl. (i) and struck out former cl. (i). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In addition to other amounts authorized under this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2008.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12)(H)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/f/2">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(f)(2)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(13)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/365/s3/g">Pub. L. 110–365, § 3(g)</ref>, substituted “2010” for “2008”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c)(3)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/107/303/s102">Pub. L. 107–303, § 102</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12), (13). <ref href="/us/pl/107/303/s103">Pub. L. 107–303, § 103</ref>, added pars. (12) and (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/303/s104">Pub. L. 107–303, § 104</ref>, substituted “construed—” for “construed to affect”, inserted “(1) to affect” before “the jurisdiction”, substituted “Lakes; or” for “Lakes.”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/107/303/s105">Pub. L. 107–303, § 105</ref>, substituted “not to exceed—” for “not to exceed $11,000,000”, inserted “(1) $11,000,000” before “per fiscal year for”, substituted “1991;” for “1991.”, added pars. (2) and (3), and struck out former last sentence which read as follows: “Of the amounts appropriated each fiscal year—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) 40 percent shall be used by the Great Lakes National Program Office on demonstration projects on the feasibility of controlling and removing toxic pollutants;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) 7 percent shall be used by the Great Lakes National Program Office for the program of nutrient monitoring; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) 30 percent or $3,300,000, whichever is the lesser, shall be transferred to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for use by the Great Lakes Research Office.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(3)(F) to (J). <ref href="/us/pl/101/596/s103">Pub. L. 101–596, § 103</ref>, added subpars. (F) to (J).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/101/596">Pub. L. 101–596</ref>, §§ 101, 102, 104, added pars. (2) to (5) after par. (1) and renumbered existing paragraphs accordingly, which was executed by renumbering pars. (2) to (6) as (6) to (10), respectively, redesignated existing provisions of par. (7) as subpar. (A) and added subpars. (B) and (C), and added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/596/s106">Pub. L. 101–596, § 106</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/596/s105">Pub. L. 101–596, § 105</ref>, substituted “and 1990, and $25,000,000 for fiscal year 1991” for “1990, and 1991” in introductory provisions and inserted “or $3,300,000, whichever is the lesser,” after “30 percent” in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsecs. (a)(1)(B), (2), (c)(1)(A), (6)(A), (D), (e)(2)(A), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/688">Pub. L. 100–688</ref> inserted “, as amended by the Water Quality Agreement of 1987 and any other agreements and amendments,” after “the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement of 1978”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6badb433-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6badb434-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6badb435-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notification Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dG/tIV/s425">Pub. L. 114–113, div. G, title IV, § 425</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2580">129 Stat. 2580</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/113/dG/tIV/s425">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Administrator’ means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Affected state</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘affected State’ means any of the Great Lakes States (as defined in section 118(a)(3) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3">33 U.S.C. 1268(a)(3)</ref>)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discharge</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘discharge’ means a discharge as defined in section 502 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Great lakes</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Great Lakes’ means any of the waters as defined in section 118(a)(3) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1268/a/3">33 U.S.C. 1268(a)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment works</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘treatment works’ has the meaning given the term in section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall work with affected States having publicly owned treatment works that discharge to the Great Lakes to create public notice requirements for a combined sewer overflow discharge to the Great Lakes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The notice requirements referred to in paragraph (1) shall provide for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the method of the notice;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the contents of the notice, in accordance with paragraph (3); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> requirements for public availability of the notice.</content>
</clause>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum requirements.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The contents of the notice under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the dates and times of the applicable discharge;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the volume of the discharge; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> a description of any public access areas impacted by the discharge.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consistency</inline>.—</heading><content>The minimum requirements under this paragraph shall be consistent for all affected States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator shall work with the affected States to include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> follow-up notice requirements that provide a description of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> each applicable discharge;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the cause of the discharge; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> plans to prevent a reoccurrence of a combined sewer overflow discharge to the Great Lakes consistent with section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</ref>) or an administrative order or consent decree under such Act; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> annual publication requirements that list each treatment works from which the Administrator or the affected State receive a follow-up notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The notice and publication requirements described in this subsection shall be implemented by not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Administrator of the EPA may extend the implementation deadline for individual communities if the Administrator determines the community needs additional time to comply in order to avoid undue economic hardship.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State action</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection prohibits an affected State from establishing a State notice requirement in the event of a discharge that is more stringent than the requirements described in this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6badb436-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Funds Contributed by a Non-Federal Sponsor</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dI/tIII">Pub. L. 108–447, div. I, title III</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3332">118 Stat. 3332</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/447/dI/tIII">“The Administrator [of the Environmental Protection Agency] may hereafter receive and use funds contributed by a non-Federal sponsor as its share of the cost of a project to carry out a project under paragraph (c)(12) [now (c)(11)] of section 118 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1268/c/11">33 U.S.C. 1268(c)(11)</ref>], as amended.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6badb437-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Great Lakes Remedial Action Plans and Sediment Remediation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/640/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 101–640, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4644">104 Stat. 4644</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/303/tV/s515">Pub. L. 104–303, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3763">110 Stat. 3763</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/53/tV/s505">Pub. L. 106–53, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/338">113 Stat. 338</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/541/tIII/s344">Pub. L. 106–541, title III, § 344</ref>, <date date="2000-12-11">Dec. 11, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2613">114 Stat. 2613</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/114/tV/s5012">Pub. L. 110–114, title V, § 5012</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1195">121 Stat. 1195</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/114/tV/s5012">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Great Lakes Remedial Action Plans.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may provide technical, planning, and engineering assistance to State and local governments and nongovernmental entities designated by a State or local government in the development and implementation of remedial action plans for Areas of Concern in the Great Lakes identified under the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement of 1978.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-federal share.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Non-Federal interests shall contribute, in cash or by providing in-kind contributions, 35 percent of costs of activities for which assistance is provided under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contributions by entities</inline>.—</heading><content>Nonprofit public or private entities may contribute all or a portion of the non-Federal share.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sediment Remediation Projects.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (acting through the Great Lakes National Program Office), may conduct pilot- and full-scale projects of promising technologies to remediate contaminated sediments in freshwater coastal regions in the Great Lakes basin. The Secretary shall conduct not fewer than 3 full-scale projects under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Site selection for projects</inline>.—</heading><content>In selecting the sites for the technology projects, the Secretary shall give priority consideration to Saginaw Bay, Michigan, Sheboygan Harbor, Wisconsin, Grand Calumet River, Indiana, Ashtabula River, Ohio, Buffalo River, New York, and Duluth-Superior Harbor, Minnesota and Wisconsin.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-federal share</inline>.—</heading><content>Non-Federal interests shall contribute 35 percent of costs of projects under this subsection. Such costs may be paid in cash or by providing in-kind contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2001 through 2012.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6bb02538-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id6bb02539-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13340. Establishment of Great Lakes Interagency Task Force and Promotion of a Regional Collaboration of National Significance for the Great Lakes</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13340, <date date="2004-05-18">May 18, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 29043, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and to help establish a regional collaboration of national significance for the Great Lakes, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Policy</i>. The Great Lakes are a national treasure constituting the largest freshwater system in the world. The United States and Canada have made great progress addressing past and current environmental impacts to the Great Lakes ecology. The Federal Government is committed to making progress on the many significant challenges that remain. Along with numerous State, tribal, and local programs, over 140 Federal programs help fund and implement environmental restoration and management activities throughout the Great Lakes system. A number of intergovernmental bodies are providing leadership in the region to address environmental and resource management issues in the Great Lakes system. These activities would benefit substantially from more systematic collaboration and better integration of effort. It is the policy of the Federal Government to support local and regional efforts to address environmental challenges and to encourage local citizen and community stewardship. To this end, the Federal Government will partner with the Great Lakes States, tribal and local governments, communities, and other interests to establish a regional collaboration to address nationally significant environmental and natural resource issues involving the Great Lakes. It is the further policy of the Federal Government that its executive departments and agencies will ensure that their programs are funding effective, coordinated, and environmentally sound activities in the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Definitions</i>. For purposes of this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) “Great Lakes” means Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron (including Lake Saint Clair), Lake Michigan, and Lake Superior, and the connecting channels (Saint Marys River, Saint Clair River, Detroit River, Niagara River, and Saint Lawrence River to the Canadian Border).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) “Great Lakes system” means all the streams, rivers, lakes, and other bodies of water within the drainage basin of the Great Lakes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Great Lakes Interagency Task Force</i>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Task Force Purpose. To further the policy described in section 1 of this order, there is established, within the Environmental Protection Agency for administrative purposes, the “Great Lakes Interagency Task Force” (Task Force) to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) Help convene and establish a process for collaboration among the members of the Task Force and the members of the Working Group that is established in paragraph b(ii) of this section, with the Great Lakes States, local communities, tribes, regional bodies, and other interests in the Great Lakes region regarding policies, strategies, plans, programs, projects, activities, and priorities for the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) Collaborate with Canada and its provinces and with bi-national bodies involved in the Great Lakes region regarding policies, strategies, projects, and priorities for the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iii) Coordinate the development of consistent Federal policies, strategies, projects, and priorities for addressing the restoration and protection of the Great Lakes system and assisting in the appropriate management of the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iv) Develop outcome-based goals for the Great Lakes system relying upon, among other things, existing data and science-based indicators of water quality and related environmental factors. These goals shall focus on outcomes such as cleaner water, sustainable fisheries, and biodiversity of the Great Lakes system and ensure that Federal policies, strategies, projects, and priorities support measurable results.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(v) Exchange information regarding policies, strategies, projects, and activities of the agencies represented on the Task Force related to the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(vi) Work to coordinate government action associated with the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(vii) Ensure coordinated Federal scientific and other research associated with the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(viii) Ensure coordinated government development and implementation of the Great Lakes portion of the Global Earth Observation System of Systems.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ix) Provide assistance and support to agencies represented on the Task Force in their activities related to the Great Lakes system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(x) Submit a report to the President by <date date="2005-05-31">May 31, 2005</date>, and thereafter as appropriate, that summarizes the activities of the Task Force and provides any recommendations that would, in the judgment of the Task Force, advance the policy set forth in section 1 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Membership and Operation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) The Task Force shall consist exclusively of the following officers of the United States: the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (who shall chair the Task Force), the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the Army, and the Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality. A member of the Task Force may designate, to perform the Task Force functions of the member, any person who is part of the member’s department, agency, or office and who is either an officer of the United States appointed by the President or a full-time employee serving in a position with pay equal to or greater than the minimum rate payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule. The Task Force shall report to the President through the Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) The Task Force shall establish a “Great Lakes Regional Working Group” (Working Group) composed of the appropriate regional administrator or director with programmatic responsibility for the Great Lakes system for each agency represented on the Task Force including: the Great Lakes National Program Office of the Environmental Protection Agency; the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, National Park Service, and United States Geological Survey within the Department of the Interior; the Natural Resources Conservation Service and the Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture; the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of the Department of Commerce; the Department of Housing and Urban Development; the Department of Transportation; the Coast Guard within the Department of Homeland Security; and the Army Corps of Engineers within the Department of the Army. The Working Group will coordinate and make recommendations on how to implement the policies, strategies, projects, and priorities of the Task Force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Management Principles for Regional Collaboration of National Significance. To further the policy described in section 1, the Task Force shall recognize and apply key principles and foster conditions to ensure successful collaboration. To that end, the Environmental Protection Agency will coordinate the development of a set of principles of successful collaboration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Great Lakes National Program Office</i>. The Great Lakes National Program Office of the Environmental Protection Agency shall assist the Task Force and the Working Group in the performance of their functions. The Great Lakes National Program Manager shall serve as chair of the Working Group.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Preservation of Authority</i>. Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budget, administrative, regulatory, and legislative proposals. Nothing in this order shall be construed to affect the statutory authority or obligations of any Federal agency or any bi-national agreement with Canada.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>Judicial Review</i>. This order is intended only to improve the internal management of the Federal Government and is not intended to, and does not, create any right, benefit, or trust responsibility, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by a party against the United States, its departments, agencies, instrumentalities or entities, its officers or employees, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
