<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6bb99b5a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282"><num value="1282">§ 1282.</num><heading> Federal share</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bb99b5b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of grants for treatment works</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bb99b5c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The amount of any grant for treatment works made under this chapter from funds authorized for any fiscal year beginning after <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, and ending before <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, shall be 75 per centum of the cost of construction thereof (as approved by the Administrator), and for any fiscal year beginning on or after <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, shall be 55 per centum of the cost of construction thereof (as approved by the Administrator), unless modified to a lower percentage rate uniform throughout a State by the Governor of that State with the concurrence of the Administrator. Within ninety days after <date date="1980-10-21">October 21, 1980</date>, the Administrator shall issue guidelines for concurrence in any such modification, which shall provide for the consideration of the unobligated balance of sums allocated to the State under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1285">section 1285 of this title</ref>, the need for assistance under this subchapter in such State, and the availability of State grant assistance to replace the Federal share reduced by such modification. The payment of any such reduced Federal share shall not constitute an obligation on the part of the United States or a claim on the part of any State or grantee to reimbursement for the portion of the Federal share reduced in any such State. Any grant (other than for reimbursement) made prior to <date date="1972-10-18">October 18, 1972</date>, from any funds authorized for any fiscal year beginning after <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, shall, upon the request of the applicant, be increased to the applicable percentage under this section. Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph, in any case where a primary, secondary, or advanced waste treatment facility or its related interceptors or a project for infiltration-in-flow correction has received a grant for erection, building, acquisition, alteration, remodeling, improvement, extension, or correction before <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, all segments and phases of such facility, interceptors, and project for infiltration-in-flow correction shall be eligible for grants at 75 per centum of the cost of construction thereof for any grant made pursuant to a State obligation which obligation occurred before <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>. Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph, in the case of a project for which an application for a grant under this subchapter has been made to the Administrator before <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, and which project is under judicial injunction on such date prohibiting its construction, such project shall be eligible for grants at 75 percent of the cost of construction thereof. Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph, in the case of the Wyoming Valley Sanitary Authority project mandated by judicial order under a proceeding begun prior to <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, and a project for wastewater treatment for Altoona, Pennsylvania, such projects shall be eligible for grants at 75 percent of the cost of construction thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bb99b5d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount of any grant made after <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, and before <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, for any eligible treatment works or significant portion thereof utilizing innovative or alternative wastewater treatment processes and techniques referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1281/g/5">section 1281(g)(5) of this title</ref> shall be 85 per centum of the cost of construction thereof, unless modified by the Governor of the State with the concurrence of the Administrator to a percentage rate no less than 15 per centum greater than the modified uniform percentage rate in which the Administrator has concurred pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection. The amount of any grant made after <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, for any eligible treatment works or unit processes and techniques thereof utilizing innovative or alternative wastewater treatment processes and techniques referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1281/g/5">section 1281(g)(5) of this title</ref> shall be a percentage of the cost of construction thereof equal to 20 per centum greater than the percentage in effect under paragraph (1) of this subsection for such works or unit processes and techniques, but in no event greater than 85 per centum of the cost of construction thereof. No grant shall be made under this paragraph for construction of a treatment works in any State unless the proportion of the State contribution to the non-Federal share of construction costs for all treatment works in such State receiving a grant under this paragraph is the same as or greater than the proportion of the State contribution (if any) to the non-Federal share of construction costs for all treatment works receiving grants in such State under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bb99b5e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In addition to any grant made pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administrator is authorized to make a grant to fund all of the costs of the modification or replacement of any facilities constructed with a grant made pursuant to paragraph (2) if the Administrator finds that such facilities have not met design performance specifications unless such failure is attributable to negligence on the part of any person and if such failure has significantly increased capital or operating and maintenance expenditures. In addition, the Administrator is authorized to make a grant to fund all of the costs of the modification or replacement of biodisc equipment (rotating biological contactors) in any publicly owned treatment works if the Administrator finds that such equipment has failed to meet design performance specifications, unless such failure is attributable to negligence on the part of any person, and if such failure has significantly increased capital or operating and maintenance expenditures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bb99b5f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For the purposes of this section, the term “eligible treatment works” means those treatment works in each State which meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1281/g/5">section 1281(g)(5) of this title</ref> and which can be fully funded from funds available for such purpose in such State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bb99b60-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of grants for construction of treatment works not commenced prior to <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date></heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amount of the grant for any project approved by the Administrator after <date date="1971-01-01">January 1, 1971</date>, and before <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, for the construction of treatment works, the actual erection, building or acquisition of which was not commenced prior to <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, shall, upon the request of the applicant, be increased to the applicable percentage under subsection (a) of this section for grants for treatment works from funds for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, with respect to the cost of such actual erection, building, or acquisition. Such increased amount shall be paid from any funds allocated to the State in which the treatment works is located without regard to the fiscal year for which such funds were authorized. Such increased amount shall be paid for such project only if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bb99b61-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a sewage collection system that is a part of the same total waste treatment system as the treatment works for which such grant was approved is under construction or is to be constructed for use in conjunction with such treatment works, and if the cost of such sewage collection system exceeds the cost of such treatment works, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bb99b62-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the State water pollution control agency or other appropriate State authority certifies that the quantity of available ground water will be insufficient, inadequate, or unsuitable for public use, including the ecological preservation and recreational use of surface water bodies, unless effluents from publicly-owned treatment works after adequate treatment are returned to the ground water consistent with acceptable technological standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bb99b63-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1282/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of sums allotted to Puerto Rico</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, sums allotted to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1285">section 1285 of this title</ref> for fiscal year 1981 shall remain available for obligation for the fiscal year for which authorized and for the period of the next succeeding twenty-four months. Such sums and any unobligated funds available to Puerto Rico from allotments for fiscal years ending prior to <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, shall be available for obligation by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency only to fund the following systems: Aguadilla, Arecibo, Mayaguez, Carolina, and Camuy Hatillo. These funds may be used by the commonwealth of Puerto Rico to fund the non-Federal share of the costs of such projects. To the extent that these funds are used to pay the non-Federal share, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall repay to the Environmental Protection Agency such amounts on terms and conditions developed and approved by the Administrator in consultation with the Governor of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico. Agreement on such terms and conditions, including the payment of interest to be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be reached prior to the use of these funds for the Commonwealth’s non-Federal share. No Federal funds awarded under this provision shall be used to replace local governments funds previously expended on these projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6bb99b64-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, title II, § 202, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/500/s2">Pub. L. 92–500, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/834">86 Stat. 834</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/217/s17">Pub. L. 95–217, § 17</ref>, <date date="1977-12-27">Dec. 27, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1571">91 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/483/s9">Pub. L. 96–483, § 9</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2362">94 Stat. 2362</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/117">Pub. L. 97–117</ref>, §§ 7, 8(a), (b), <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1625">95 Stat. 1625</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/357/tV/s501">Pub. L. 97–357, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1982-10-19">Oct. 19, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1712">96 Stat. 1712</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 100–4, title II, § 202(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="1987-02-04">Feb. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/15">101 Stat. 15</ref>, 16.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6bb99b65-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6bb99b66-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6bb99b67-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s202/a">Pub. L. 100–4, § 202(a)</ref>, inserted “for any grant made pursuant to a State obligation which obligation occurred before <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>” before period at end of last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s202/b">Pub. L. 100–4, § 202(b)</ref>, inserted at end “Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph, in the case of a project for which an application for a grant under this subchapter has been made to the Administrator before <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, and which project is under judicial injunction on such date prohibiting its construction, such project shall be eligible for grants at 75 percent of the cost of construction thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s202/c">Pub. L. 100–4, § 202(c)</ref>, inserted at end “Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph, in the case of the Wyoming Valley Sanitary Authority project mandated by judicial order under a proceeding begun prior to <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, and a project for wastewater treatment for Altoona, Pennsylvania, such projects shall be eligible for grants at 75 percent of the cost of construction thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s202/d">Pub. L. 100–4, § 202(d)</ref>, inserted at end “In addition, the Administrator is authorized to make a grant to fund all of the costs of the modification or replacement of biodisc equipment (rotating biological contactors) in any publicly owned treatment works if the Administrator finds that such equipment has failed to meet design performance specifications, unless such failure is attributable to negligence on the part of any person, and if such failure has significantly increased capital or operating and maintenance expenditures.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/357">Pub. L. 97–357</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/117/s7">Pub. L. 97–117, § 7</ref>, inserted “and ending before <date date="1984-10-30">October 30, 1984</date>,” after “<date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>,” and “and for any fiscal year beginning on or after <date date="1984-10-01">October 1, 1984</date>, shall be 55 per centum of the cost of construction thereof (as approved by the Administrator),” after “(as approved by the Administrator),” and provision that notwithstanding first sentence of this paragraph, in any case where primary, secondary, or advanced waste treatment facility or its related interceptors or a proj­ect for infiltration-in-flow correction has received a grant for building, acquisition, etc., before <date date="1984-10-01">Oct. 1, 1984</date>, all segments and phases be eligible for grants at 75 per centum of the cost of construction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/117/s8/a">Pub. L. 97–117, § 8(a)</ref>, inserted provision that the amount of any grant made after <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>, for any eligible treatment works or unit processes or techniques, utilizing innovative or alternative wastewater treatment processes or techniques referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1281/g/5">section 1281(g)(5) of this title</ref> be a percentage of the cost of construction equal to 20 per centum greater than the percentage in effect under par. (1) of this subsection, but in no event greater than 85 per centum of the cost of construction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/117/s8/b">Pub. L. 97–117, § 8(b)</ref>, struck out “in the fiscal years ending <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, and <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>” after “purpose in such State” and provision that excluded from term “eligible treatment works” collector sewers, interceptors, storm or sanitary sewers or the separation thereof, or major sewer rehabilitation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/483/s9/a">Pub. L. 96–483, § 9(a)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to modification to a lower percentage rate by the Governor of the State and issuance of guidelines by the Administrator for the concurrence in any such modification.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/483/s9/b">Pub. L. 96–483, § 9(b)</ref>, inserted provision relating to the modification by the Governor of the State to a percentage rate no less than 15 per centum greater than the modified uniform rate in which the Administrator has concurred.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/217">Pub. L. 95–217</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added pars. (2) to (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6bbc0c68-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6bbc0c69-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Promulgation of Federal Shares</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-07-09/ch518/s4">Act July 9, 1956, ch. 518, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/507">70 Stat. 507</ref>, authorized the Surgeon General to promulgate Federal shares under the Federal Water Pollution Control Grant Program as soon as possible after <date date="1956-07-09">July 9, 1956</date>, in the manner specified in the Water Pollution Control Act, <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">act June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1155">62 Stat. 1155</ref>, and provided that such shares were to be conclusive for the purposes of section 5 of act <date date="1948-06-30">June 30, 1948</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
