<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6bccae79-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1313a"><num value="1313a">§ 1313a.</num><heading> Revised water quality standards</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The review, revision, and adoption or promulgation of revised or new water quality standards pursuant to section 303(c) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1313/c">33 U.S.C. 1313(c)</ref>] shall be completed by the date three years after <date date="1981-12-29">December 29, 1981</date>. No grant shall be made under title II of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1281">33 U.S.C. 1281</ref> et seq.] after such date until water quality standards are reviewed and revised pursuant to section 303(c), except where the State has in good faith submitted such revised water quality standards and the Administrator has not acted to approve or disapprove such submission within one hundred and twenty days of receipt.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6bccae7a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/117/s24">Pub. L. 97–117, § 24</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1632">95 Stat. 1632</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6bccae7b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6bccae7c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6bccae7d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Water Pollution Control Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">act June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/92/500/s2">Pub. L. 92–500, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/816">86 Stat. 816</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1281 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1251">section 1251 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6bccae7e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Municipal Wastewater Treatment Construction Grant Amendments of 1981, and not as part of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
