<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6bd1690c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318"><num value="1318">§ 1318.</num><heading> Records and reports; inspections</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bd1690d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance; monitoring equipment; entry; access to information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever required to carry out the objective of this chapter, including but not limited to (1) developing or assisting in the development of any effluent limitation, or other limitation, prohibition, or effluent standard, pretreatment standard, or standard of performance under this chapter; (2) determining whether any person is in violation of any such effluent limitation, or other limitation, prohibition or effluent standard, pretreatment standard, or standard of performance; (3) any requirement established under this section; or (4) carrying out sections 1315, 1321, 1342, 1344 (relating to State permit programs), 1345, and 1364 of this title—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bd1690e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/a/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Administrator shall require the owner or operator of any point source to (i) establish and maintain such records, (ii) make such reports, (iii) install, use, and maintain such monitoring equipment or methods (including where appropriate, biological monitoring methods), (iv) sample such effluents (in accordance with such methods, at such locations, at such intervals, and in such manner as the Administrator shall prescribe), and (v) provide such other information as he may reasonably require; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bd1690f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/a/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the Administrator or his authorized representative (including an authorized contractor acting as a representative of the Administrator), upon presentation of his credentials—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bd16910-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/a/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall have a right of entry to, upon, or through any premises in which an effluent source is located or in which any records required to be maintained under clause (A) of this subsection are located, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bd16911-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/a/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may at reasonable times have access to and copy any records, inspect any monitoring equipment or method required under clause (A), and sample any effluents which the owner or operator of such source is required to sample under such clause.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bd16912-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability to public; trade secrets exception; penalty for disclosure of confidential information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any records, reports, or information obtained under this section (1) shall, in the case of effluent data, be related to any applicable effluent limitations, toxic, pretreatment, or new source performance standards, and (2) shall be available to the public, except that upon a showing satisfactory to the Administrator by any person that records, reports, or information, or particular part thereof (other than effluent data), to which the Administrator has access under this section, if made public would divulge methods or processes entitled to protection as trade secrets of such person, the Administrator shall consider such record, report, or information, or particular portion thereof confidential in accordance with the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1905">section 1905 of title 18</ref>. Any authorized representative of the Administrator (including an authorized contractor acting as a representative of the Administrator) who knowingly or willfully publishes, divulges, discloses, or makes known in any manner or to any extent not authorized by law any information which is required to be considered confidential under this subsection shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit the Administrator or an authorized representative of the Administrator (including any authorized contractor acting as a representative of the Administrator) from disclosing records, reports, or information to other officers, employees, or authorized representatives of the United States concerned with carrying out this chapter or when relevant in any proceeding under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bd16913-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of State law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State may develop and submit to the Administrator procedures under State law for inspection, monitoring, and entry with respect to point sources located in such State. If the Administrator finds that the procedures and the law of any State relating to inspection, monitoring, and entry are applicable to at least the same extent as those required by this section, such State is authorized to apply and enforce its procedures for inspection, monitoring, and entry with respect to point sources located in such State (except with respect to point sources owned or operated by the United States).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bd16914-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1318/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Access by Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any limitation contained in this section or any other provision of law, all information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Administrator (or any representative of the Administrator) under this chapter shall be made available, upon written request of any duly authorized committee of Congress, to such committee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6bd16915-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, title III, § 308, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/500/s2">Pub. L. 92–500, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/858">86 Stat. 858</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/217/s67/c/1">Pub. L. 95–217, § 67(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-12-27">Dec. 27, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1606">91 Stat. 1606</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/tIII/s310">Pub. L. 100–4, title III, § 310</ref>, title IV, § 406(d)(1), <date date="1987-02-04">Feb. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/41">101 Stat. 41</ref>, 73.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6bd16916-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6bd16917-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6bd16918-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s406/d/1">Pub. L. 100–4, § 406(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “1345, and 1364” for “and 1364” in cl. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s310/a/2">Pub. L. 100–4, § 310(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “(including an authorized contractor acting as a representative of the Administrator)” after “representative”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s310/a/1">Pub. L. 100–4, § 310(a)(1)</ref>, substituted a period and “Any authorized representative of the Administrator (including an authorized contractor acting as a representative of the Administrator) who knowingly or willfully publishes, divulges, discloses, or makes known in any manner or to any extent not authorized by law any information which is required to be considered confidential under this subsection shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit the Administrator or an authorized representative of the Administrator (including any authorized contractor acting as a representative of the Administrator) from disclosing records, reports, or information to other officers, employees, or authorized representatives of the United States concerned with carrying out this chapter or when relevant in any proceeding under this chapter.” for “, except that such record, report, or information may be disclosed to other officers, employees, or authorized representatives of the United States concerned with carrying out this chapter or when relevant in any proceeding under this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/s310/b">Pub. L. 100–4, § 310(b)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/95/217">Pub. L. 95–217</ref> inserted “1344 (relating to State permit programs),” after “sections 1315, 1321, 1342,” in provisions preceding subpar. (A).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
