<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6bf2d3fa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330"><num value="1330">§ 1330.</num><heading> National estuary program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d3fb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Management conference</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d3fc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Nomination of estuaries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Governor of any State may nominate to the Administrator an estuary lying in whole or in part within the State as an estuary of national significance and request a management conference to develop a comprehensive management plan for the estuary. The nomination shall document the need for the conference, the likelihood of success, and information relating to the factors in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d3fd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Convening of conference</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d3fe-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In any case where the Administrator determines, on his own initiative or upon nomination of a State under paragraph (1), that the attainment or maintenance of that water quality in an estuary which assures protection of public water supplies and the protection and propagation of a balanced, indigenous population of shellfish, fish, and wildlife, and allows recreational activities, in and on the water, requires the control of point and nonpoint sources of pollution to supplement existing controls of pollution in more than one State, the Administrator shall select such estuary and convene a management conference.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d3ff-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority consideration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator shall give priority consideration under this section to Long Island Sound, New York and Connecticut; Narragansett Bay, Rhode Island; Buzzards Bay, Massachusetts; Massachusetts Bay, Massachusetts (including Cape Cod Bay and Boston Harbor); Puget Sound, Washington; New York-New Jersey Harbor, New York and New Jersey; Delaware Bay, Delaware and New Jersey; Delaware Inland Bays, Delaware; Albemarle Sound, North Carolina; Sarasota Bay, Florida; San Francisco Bay, California; Santa Monica Bay, California; Galveston Bay, Texas; Barataria-Terrebonne Bay estuary complex, Louisiana; Indian River Lagoon, Florida; Lake Pontchartrain Basin, Louisiana and Mississippi; Peconic Bay, New York; Casco Bay, Maine; Tampa Bay, Florida; Coastal Bend, Texas; San Juan Bay, Puerto Rico; Tillamook Bay, Oregon; Piscataqua Region, New Hampshire; Barnegat Bay, New Jersey; Maryland Coastal Bays, Maryland; Charlotte Harbor, Florida; Mobile Bay, Alabama; Morro Bay, California; Lower Columbia River, Oregon and Washington; and Pensacola and Perdido Bays, Florida.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d400-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Boundary dispute exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any case in which a boundary between two States passes through an estuary and such boundary is disputed and is the subject of an action in any court, the Administrator shall not convene a management conference with respect to such estuary before a final adjudication has been made of such dispute.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d401-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes of conference</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of any management conference convened with respect to an estuary under this subsection shall be to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d402-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assess trends in water quality, natural resources, and uses of the estuary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d403-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> collect, characterize, and assess data on toxics, nutrients, and natural resources within the estuarine zone to identify the causes of environmental problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d404-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> develop the relationship between the inplace loads and point and nonpoint loadings of pollutants to the estuarine zone and the potential uses of the zone, water quality, and natural resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d405-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> develop a comprehensive conservation and management plan that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d406-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> recommends priority corrective actions and compliance schedules addressing point and nonpoint sources of pollution to restore and maintain the chemical, physical, and biological integrity of the estuary, including restoration and maintenance of water quality, a balanced indigenous population of shellfish, fish and wildlife, and recreational activities in the estuary, and assure that the designated uses of the estuary are protected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d407-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> addresses the effects of recurring extreme weather events on the estuary, including the identification and assessment of vulnerabilities in the estuary and the development and implementation of adaptation strategies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d408-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> increases public education and awareness of the ecological health and water quality conditions of the estuary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d409-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> develop plans for the coordinated implementation of the plan by the States as well as Federal and local agencies participating in the conference;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d40a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> monitor the effectiveness of actions taken pursuant to the plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d40b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> review all Federal financial assistance programs and Federal development projects in accordance with the requirements of Executive Order 12372, as in effect on <date date="1983-09-17">September 17, 1983</date>, to determine whether such assistance program or project would be consistent with and further the purposes and objectives of the plan prepared under this section.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (7), such programs and projects shall not be limited to the assistance programs and development projects subject to Executive Order 12372, but may include any programs listed in the most recent Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance which may have an effect on the purposes and objectives of the plan developed under this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d40c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Members of conference</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The members of a management conference convened under this section shall include, at a minimum, the Administrator and representatives of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d40d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> each State and foreign nation located in whole or in part in the estuarine zone of the estuary for which the conference is convened;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d40e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> international, interstate, or regional agencies or entities having jurisdiction over all or a significant part of the estuary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d40f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> each interested Federal agency, as determined appropriate by the Administrator;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d410-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> local governments having jurisdiction over any land or water within the estuarine zone, as determined appropriate by the Administrator; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6bf2d411-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> affected industries, public and private educational institutions, nonprofit organizations, and the general public, as determined appropriate by the Administrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d412-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of existing data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing a conservation and management plan under this section, the management conference shall survey and utilize existing reports, data, and studies relating to the estuary that have been developed by or made available to Federal, interstate, State, and local agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d413-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Period of conference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A management conference convened under this section shall be convened for a period not to exceed 5 years. Such conference may be extended by the Administrator, and if terminated after the initial period, may be reconvened by the Administrator at any time thereafter, as may be necessary to meet the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d414-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval and implementation of plans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d415-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after the completion of a conservation and management plan and after providing for public review and comment, the Administrator shall approve such plan if the plan meets the requirements of this section and the affected Governor or Governors concur.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d416-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon approval of a conservation and management plan under this section, such plan shall be implemented. Funds authorized to be appropriated under subchapters II and VI of this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1329">section 1329 of this title</ref> may be used in accordance with the applicable requirements of this chapter to assist States with the implementation of such plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d417-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d418-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Recipients</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator is authorized to make grants to State, interstate, and regional water pollution control agencies and entities, State coastal zone management agencies, interstate agencies, other public or nonprofit private agencies, institutions, organizations, and individuals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d419-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Grants under this subsection shall be made to pay for activities necessary for the development and implementation of a comprehensive conservation and management plan under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d41a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Federal share of a grant to any person (including a State, interstate, or regional agency or entity) under this subsection for a fiscal year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d41b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> shall not exceed—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d41c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 75 percent of the annual aggregate costs of the development of a comprehensive conservation and management plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d41d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 50 percent of the annual aggregate costs of the implementation of the plan; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d41e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall be made on condition that the non-Federal share of the costs are provided from non-Federal sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d41f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Competitive awards</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d420-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Using the amounts made available under subsection (i)(2)(B), the Administrator shall make competitive awards under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d421-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Application for awards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator shall solicit applications for awards under this paragraph from State, interstate, and regional water pollution control agencies and entities, State coastal zone management agencies, interstate agencies, other public or nonprofit private agencies, institutions, organizations, and individuals.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d422-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of recipients</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In selecting award recipients under this paragraph, the Administrator shall select recipients that are best able to address urgent, emerging, and challenging issues that threaten the ecological and economic well-being of the estuaries selected by the Administrator under subsection (a)(2), or that relate to the coastal resiliency of such estuaries. Such issues shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d423-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> extensive seagrass habitat losses resulting in significant impacts on fisheries and water quality;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d424-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> recurring harmful algae blooms;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d425-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> unusual marine mammal mortalities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d426-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> invasive exotic species that may threaten wastewater systems and cause other damage;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d427-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> jellyfish proliferation limiting community access to water during peak tourism seasons;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d428-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> stormwater runoff;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d429-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> accelerated land loss;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d42a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> flooding that may be related to sea level rise, extreme weather, or wetland degradation or loss; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6bf2d42b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/g/4/C/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> low dissolved oxygen conditions in estuarine waters and related nutrient management.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d42c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person (including a State, interstate, or regional agency or entity) that receives a grant under subsection (g) shall report to the Administrator not later than 18 months after receipt of such grant and biennially thereafter on the progress being made under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d42d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d42e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $26,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021, and $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d42f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> expenses relating to the administration of grants or awards by the Administrator under this section, including the award and oversight of grants and awards, except that such expenses may not exceed 5 percent of the amount appropriated under this subsection for a fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d430-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> making grants and awards under subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d431-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d432-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/i/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Conservation and management plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not less than 80 percent of the amount made available under this subsection for a fiscal year shall be used by the Administrator to provide grant assistance for the development, implementation, and monitoring of each of the conservation and management plans eligible for grant assistance under subsection (g)(2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d433-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/i/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Competitive awards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not less than 15 percent of the amount made available under this subsection for a fiscal year shall be used by the Administrator for making competitive awards described in subsection (g)(4).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d434-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Research</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d435-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order to determine the need to convene a management conference under this section or at the request of such a management conference, the Administrator shall coordinate and implement, through the National Marine Pollution Program Office and the National Marine Fisheries Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, as appropriate, for one or more estuarine zones—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d436-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a long-term program of trend assessment monitoring measuring variations in pollutant concentrations, marine ecology, and other physical or biological environmental parameters which may affect estuarine zones, to provide the Administrator the capacity to determine the potential and actual effects of alternative management strategies and measures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d437-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a program of ecosystem assessment assisting in the development of (i) baseline studies which determine the state of estuarine zones and the effects of natural and anthropogenic changes, and (ii) predictive models capable of translating information on specific discharges or general pollutant loadings within estuarine zones into a set of probable effects on such zones;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d438-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a comprehensive water quality sampling program for the continuous monitoring of nutrients, chlorine, acid precipitation dissolved oxygen, and potentially toxic pollutants (including organic chemicals and metals) in estuarine zones, after consultation with interested State, local, interstate, or international agencies and review and analysis of all environmental sampling data presently collected from estuarine zones; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d439-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a program of research to identify the movements of nutrients, sediments and pollutants through estuarine zones and the impact of nutrients, sediments, and pollutants on water quality, the ecosystem, and designated or potential uses of the estuarine zones.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d43a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator, in cooperation with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall submit to the Congress no less often than biennially a comprehensive report on the activities authorized under this subsection including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d43b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a listing of priority monitoring and research needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d43c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an assessment of the state and health of the Nation’s estuarine zones, to the extent evaluated under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d43d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a discussion of pollution problems and trends in pollutant concentrations with a direct or indirect effect on water quality, the ecosystem, and designated or potential uses of each estuarine zone, to the extent evaluated under this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6bf2d43e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/j/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an evaluation of pollution abatement activities and management measures so far implemented to determine the degree of improvement toward the objectives expressed in subsection (b)(4) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bf2d43f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1330/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the terms “estuary” and “estuarine zone” have the meanings such terms have in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1254/n/4">section 1254(n)(4) of this title</ref>, except that the term “estuarine zone” shall also include associated aquatic ecosystems and those portions of tributaries draining into the estuary up to the historic height of migration of anadromous fish or the historic head of tidal influence, whichever is higher.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6bf2d440-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, title III, § 320, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/4/tIII/s317/b">Pub. L. 100–4, title III, § 317(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-02-04">Feb. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/61">101 Stat. 61</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/f/tII/s201">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(f) [title II, 201]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-187">101 Stat. 1329–187</ref>, 1329–197; <ref href="/us/pl/100/653/tX/s1004">Pub. L. 100–653, title X, § 1004</ref>, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3836">102 Stat. 3836</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/688/tII/s2001">Pub. L. 100–688, title II, § 2001</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4151">102 Stat. 4151</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tV/s501/a/2">Pub. L. 105–362, title V, § 501(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3283">112 Stat. 3283</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/457/tIII">Pub. L. 106–457, title III</ref>, §§ 301—303, <date date="2000-11-07">Nov. 7, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1972">114 Stat. 1972</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/303/tIII/s302/b/1">Pub. L. 107–303, title III, § 302(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2361">116 Stat. 2361</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/399/s1">Pub. L. 108–399, § 1</ref>, <date date="2004-10-30">Oct. 30, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2253">118 Stat. 2253</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/162">Pub. L. 114–162</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="2016-05-20">May 20, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/409">130 Stat. 409</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/337">Pub. L. 116–337</ref>, §§ 2–6, <date date="2021-01-13">Jan. 13, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/5120">134 Stat. 5120</ref>, 5121; <ref href="/us/pl/118/152/s2">Pub. L. 118–152, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-12-17">Dec. 17, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1686">138 Stat. 1686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6bf2d441-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6bf2d442-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6bf2d443-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12372, referred to in subsec. (b), is Ex. Ord. No. 12372, <date date="1982-07-14">July 14, 1982</date>, 47 F.R. 30959, as amended, which is set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s6506">section 6506 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6bf2d444-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/118/152">Pub. L. 118–152</ref> substituted “Lower Columbia River, Oregon and Washington; and Pensacola and Perdido Bays, Florida” for “and Lower Columbia River, Oregon and Washington”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s2">Pub. L. 116–337, § 2</ref>, substituted “Peconic Bay, New York; Casco Bay, Maine; Tampa Bay, Florida; Coastal Bend, Texas; San Juan Bay, Puerto Rico; Tillamook Bay, Oregon; Piscataqua Region, New Hampshire; Barnegat Bay, New Jersey; Maryland Coastal Bays, Maryland; Charlotte Harbor, Florida; Mobile Bay, Alabama; Morro Bay, California; and Lower Columbia River, Oregon and Washington” for “and Peconic Bay, New York”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s3">Pub. L. 116–337, § 3</ref>, inserted dash after “management plan that” and subpar. (A) designation before “recommends” and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s4">Pub. L. 116–337, § 4</ref>, inserted “nonprofit organizations,” after “educational institutions,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s5/1">Pub. L. 116–337, § 5(1)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted “, emerging,” after “urgent” and substituted “the estuaries selected by the Administrator under subsection (a)(2), or that relate to the coastal resiliency of such estuaries” for “coastal areas”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4)(C)(vi), (vii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s5/2">Pub. L. 116–337, § 5(2)</ref>, added cls. (vi) and (vii). Former cls. (vi) and (vii) redesignated (viii) and (ix), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4)(C)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s5/2">Pub. L. 116–337, § 5(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated cl. (vi) as (viii) and inserted “, extreme weather,” after “sea level rise”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4)(C)(ix). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s5/2">Pub. L. 116–337, § 5(2)</ref>, redesignated cl. (vii) as (ix).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/337/s6">Pub. L. 116–337, § 6</ref>, inserted “, and $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026,” after “2021”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (g)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/162/s1">Pub. L. 114–162, § 1</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/162/s2">Pub. L. 114–162, § 2</ref>, added subsec. (i) and struck out former subsec. (i) which related to authorization of appropriations for fiscal years 2001 through 2010.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/399">Pub. L. 108–399</ref> substituted “2010” for “2005” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/107/303">Pub. L. 107–303</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/s501/a/2">Pub. L. 105–362, § 501(a)(2)</ref>. See 1998 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/106/457/s301">Pub. L. 106–457, § 301</ref>, inserted “Lake Pontchartrain Basin, Louisiana and Mississippi;” before “and Peconic Bay, New York.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/457/s302">Pub. L. 106–457, § 302</ref>, added pars. (2) and (3) and struck out former pars. (2) and (3) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—Grants under this subsection shall be made to pay for assisting research, surveys, studies, and modeling and other technical work necessary for the development of a conservation and management plan under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) <inline class="small-caps">Federal share</inline>.—The amount of grants to any person (including a State, interstate, or regional agency or entity) under this subsection for a fiscal year shall not exceed 75 percent of the costs of such research, survey, studies, and work and shall be made on condition that the non-Federal share of such costs are provided from non-Federal sources.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/457/s303">Pub. L. 106–457, § 303</ref>, substituted “$35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2001 through 2005” for “$12,000,000 per fiscal year for each of fiscal years 1987, 1988, 1989, 1990, and 1991”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/s501/a/2">Pub. L. 105–362, § 501(a)(2)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “section 1254(n)(3)” for “section 1254(n)(4)”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/107/303">Pub. L. 107–303</ref>. See Effective Date of 2002 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/653/s1004">Pub. L. 100–653, § 1004</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/100/688/s2001/1">Pub. L. 100–688, § 2001(1)</ref>, made identical amendments, inserting “Massachusetts Bay, Massachusetts (including Cape Cod Bay and Boston Harbor);” after “Buzzards Bay, Massachusetts;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/688/s2001/2">Pub. L. 100–688, § 2001(2)</ref>, substituted “California; Galveston” for “California; and Galveston”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/688/s2001/3">Pub. L. 100–688, § 2001(3)</ref>, which directed insertion of “; Barataria-Terrebonne Bay estuary complex, Louisiana; Indian River Lagoon, Florida; and Peconic Bay, New York” after “Galveston Bay, Texas;” was executed by making insertion after “Galveston Bay, Texas” as probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref> inserted “Santa Monica Bay, California;”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6bf54445-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6bf54446-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/303">Pub. L. 107–303</ref> effective <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, and Federal Water Pollution Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1251">33 U.S.C. 1251</ref> et seq.) to be applied and administered on and after <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, as if amendments made by section 501(a)–(d) of <ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> had not been enacted, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/303/s302/b">section 302(b) of Pub. L. 107–303</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1254">section 1254 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6bf54447-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Massachusetts Bay Protection; Definition; Findings and Purpose; Funding Sources</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/653/tX">Pub. L. 100–653, title X</ref>, §§ 1002, 1003, 1005, <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3835">102 Stat. 3835</ref>, 3836, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/653/tX">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1002">“SEC. 1002.</num><heading> DEFINITION.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“For purposes of this title [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1330">section 1330 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 1251 and 1330 of this title], the term ‘Massachusetts Bay’ includes Massachusetts Bay, Cape Cod Bay, and Boston Harbor, consisting of an area extending from Cape Ann, Massachusetts south to the northern reach of Cape Cod, Massachusetts.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1003">“SEC. 1003.</num><heading> FINDINGS AND PURPOSE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Massachusetts Bay comprises a single major estuarine and oceanographic system extending from Cape Ann, Massachusetts south to the northern reaches of Cape Cod, encompassing Boston Harbor, Massachusetts Bay, and Cape Cod Bay;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> several major riverine systems, including the Charles, Neponset, and Mystic Rivers, drain the watersheds of eastern Massachusetts into the Bay;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the shorelines of Massachusetts Bay, first occupied in the middle 1600’s, are home to over 4 million people and support a thriving industrial and recreational economy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Massachusetts Bay supports important commercial fisheries, including lobsters, finfish, and shellfisheries, and is home to or frequented by several endangered species and marine mammals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Massachusetts Bay also constitutes an important recreational resource, providing fishing, swimming, and boating opportunities to the region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> rapidly expanding coastal populations and pollution pose increasing threats to the long-term health and integrity of Massachusetts Bay;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> while the cleanup of Boston Harbor will contribute significantly to improving the overall environmental quality of Massachusetts Bay, expanded efforts encompassing the entire ecosystem will be necessary to ensure its long-term health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> the concerted efforts of all levels of Government, the private sector, and the public at large will be necessary to protect and enhance the environmental integrity of Massachusetts Bay; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> the designation of Massachusetts Bay as an Estuary of National Significance and the development of a comprehensive plan for protecting and restoring the Bay may contribute significantly to its long-term health and environmental integrity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>The purpose of this title is to protect and enhance the environmental quality of Massachusetts Bay by providing for its designation as an Estuary of National Significance and by providing for the preparation of a comprehensive restoration plan for the Bay.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1005">“SEC. 1005.</num><heading> FUNDING SOURCES.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Within one year of enactment [<date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>], the Administrator of the United States Environmental Protection Agency and the Governor of Massachusetts shall undertake to identify and make available sources of funding to support activities pertaining to Massachusetts Bay undertaken pursuant to or authorized by section 320 of the Clean Water Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1330">33 U.S.C. 1330</ref>], and shall make every effort to coordinate existing research, monitoring or control efforts with such activities.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6bf54448-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Purposes and Policies of National Estuary Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/4/tIII/s317/a">Pub. L. 100–4, title III, § 317(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-02-04">Feb. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/61">101 Stat. 61</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/4/tIII/s317/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Nation’s estuaries are of great importance for fish and wildlife resources and recreation and economic opportunity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> maintaining the health and ecological integrity of these estuaries is in the national interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> increasing coastal population, development, and other direct and indirect uses of these estuaries threaten their health and ecological integrity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> long-term planning and management will contribute to the continued productivity of these areas, and will maximize their utility to the Nation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> better coordination among Federal and State programs affecting estuaries will increase the effectiveness and efficiency of the national effort to protect, preserve, and restore these areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of this section [enacting this section] are to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> identify nationally significant estuaries that are threatened by pollution, development, or overuse;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> promote comprehensive planning for, and conservation and management of, nationally significant estuaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> encourage the preparation of management plans for estuaries of national significance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> enhance the coordination of estuarine research.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
