<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6bfebad1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363"><num value="1363">§ 1363.</num><heading> Water Pollution Control Advisory Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bfebad2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; composition; terms of office</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bfebad3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is hereby established in the Environmental Protection Agency a Water Pollution Control Advisory Board, composed of the Administrator or his designee, who shall be Chairman, and nine members appointed by the President, none of whom shall be Federal officers or employees. The appointed members, having due regard for the purposes of this chapter, shall be selected from among representatives of various State, interstate, and local governmental agencies, of public or private interests contributing to, affected by, or concerned with pollution, and of other public and private agencies, organizations, or groups demonstrating an active interest in the field of pollution prevention and control, as well as other individuals who are expert in this field.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bfebad4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bfebad5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Each member appointed by the President shall hold office for a term of three years, except that (i) any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term, and (ii) the terms of office of the members first taking office after <date date="1956-06-30">June 30, 1956</date>, shall expire as follows: three at the end of one year after such date, three at the end of two years after such date, and three at the end of three years after such date, as designated by the President at the time of appointment, and (iii) the term of any member under the preceding provisions shall be extended until the date on which his successor’s appointment is effective. None of the members appointed by the President shall be eligible for reappointment within one year after the end of his preceding term.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6bfebad6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The members of the Board who are not officers or employees of the United States, while attending conferences or meetings of the Board or while serving at the request of the Administrator, shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the Administrator, but not exceeding $100 per diem, including travel-time, and while away from their homes or regular places of business they may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by law for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bfebad7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board shall advise, consult with, and make recommendations to the Administrator on matters of policy relating to the activities and functions of the Administrator under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6bfebad8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1363/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Clerical and technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such clerical and technical assistance as may be necessary to discharge the duties of the Board shall be provided from the personnel of the Environmental Protection Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6bfebad9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, title V, § 503, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/500/s2">Pub. L. 92–500, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/887">86 Stat. 887</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6bfebada-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6bfebadb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6bfebadc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence as authorized by law, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(B), probably means the allowances authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6bfebadd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6bfebade-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continuation of Term of Office</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/87/88/s6/c">Pub. L. 87–88, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1961-07-20">July 20, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/207">75 Stat. 207</ref>, provided that members of the Water Pollution Control Advisory Board holding office immediately preceding <date date="1961-07-20">July 20, 1961</date> were to remain in office as members of the Board as established by <ref href="/us/pl/87/88/s6/a">section 6(a) of Pub. L. 87–88</ref> until the expiration of the terms of office for which they were originally appointed.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6bfebadf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Terms of Office of Members of Water Pollution Control Advisory Board</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-07-09/ch518/s3">Act July 9, 1956, ch. 518, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/507">70 Stat. 507</ref>, provided that the terms of office of members of the Water Pollution Control Advisory Board, holding office on <date date="1956-07-09">July 9, 1956</date>, were to terminate at the close of business on that date.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6bfebae0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Boards</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory boards in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a board established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such board is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a board established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
