<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c012b31-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371"><num value="1371">§ 1371.</num><heading> Authority under other laws and regulations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c012b32-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Impairment of authority or functions of officials and agencies; treaty provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This chapter shall not be construed as (1) limiting the authority or functions of any officer or agency of the United States under any other law or regulation not inconsistent with this chapter; (2) affecting or impairing the authority of the Secretary of the Army (A) to maintain navigation or (B) under the Act of <date date="1899-03-03">March 3, 1899</date>, (<ref href="/us/stat/30/1112">30 Stat. 1112</ref>); except that any permit issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref> shall be conclusive as to the effect on water quality of any discharge resulting from any activity subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s403">section 403 of this title</ref>, or (3) affecting or impairing the provisions of any treaty of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c012b33-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Discharges of pollutants into navigable waters</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Discharges of pollutants into the navigable waters subject to the Rivers and Harbors Act of 1910 (<ref href="/us/stat/36/593">36 Stat. 593</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s421">33 U.S.C. 421</ref>) and the Supervisory Harbors Act of 1888 (<ref href="/us/stat/25/209">25 Stat. 209</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s441–451b">33 U.S.C. 441–451b</ref>) shall be regulated pursuant to this chapter, and not subject to such Act of 1910 and the Act of 1888 except as to effect on navigation and anchorage.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c012b34-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Action of the Administrator deemed major Federal action; construction of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c012b35-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except for the provision of Federal financial assistance for the purpose of assisting the construction of publicly owned treatment works as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1281">section 1281 of this title</ref>, and the issuance of a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342">section 1342 of this title</ref> for the discharge of any pollutant by a new source as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1316">section 1316 of this title</ref>, no action of the Administrator taken pursuant to this chapter shall be deemed a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment within the meaning of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c012b36-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Nothing in the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>) shall be deemed to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c012b37-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> authorize any Federal agency authorized to license or permit the conduct of any activity which may result in the discharge of a pollutant into the navigable waters to review any effluent limitation or other requirement established pursuant to this chapter or the adequacy of any certification under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1341">section 1341 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c012b38-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> authorize any such agency to impose, as a condition precedent to the issuance of any license or permit, any effluent limitation other than any such limitation established pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c012b39-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1371/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of international water pollution control agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding this chapter or any other provision of law, the Administrator (1) shall not require any State to consider in the development of the ranking in order of priority of needs for the construction of treatment works (as defined in subchapter II of this chapter), any water pollution control agreement which may have been entered into between the United States and any other nation, and (2) shall not consider any such agreement in the approval of any such priority ranking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c012b3a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch758">June 30, 1948, ch. 758</ref>, title V, § 511, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/500/s2">Pub. L. 92–500, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-10-18">Oct. 18, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/893">86 Stat. 893</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/243/s3">Pub. L. 93–243, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-01-02">Jan. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/1069">87 Stat. 1069</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c012b3b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c012b3c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6c012b3d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1899-03-03">March 3, 1899</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1899-03-03/ch425">act Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/1121">30 Stat. 1121</ref>, which enacted sections 401, 403, 404, 406, 407, 408, 409, 411 to 416, 418, 502, 549, and 687 of this title and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s686">section 686 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rivers and Harbors Act of 1910, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means <ref href="/us/act/1910-06-23/ch359">act June 23, 1910, ch. 359</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/593">36 Stat. 593</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Supervisory Harbors Act of 1888, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means <ref href="/us/act/1888-06-29/ch496">act June 29, 1888, ch. 496</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/25/209">25 Stat. 209</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 441 et seq.) of chapter 9 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c012b3e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/243">Pub. L. 93–243</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
