<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c0857a3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412"><num value="1412">§ 1412.</num><heading> Dumping permit program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857a4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Environmental Protection Agency permits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except in relation to dredged material, as provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413">section 1413 of this title</ref>, and in relation to radiological, chemical, and biological warfare agents, high-level radioactive waste, and medical waste, for which no permit may be issued, the Administrator may issue permits, after notice and opportunity for public hearings, for the transportation from the United States or, in the case of an agency or instrumentality of the United States, or in the case of a vessel or aircraft registered in the United States or flying the United States flag, for the transportation from a location outside the United States, of material for the purpose of dumping it into ocean waters, or for the dumping of material into the waters described in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1411/b">section 1411(b) of this title</ref>, where the Administrator determines that such dumping will not unreasonably degrade or endanger human health, welfare, or amenities, or the marine environment, ecological systems, or economic potentialities. The Administrator shall establish and apply criteria for reviewing and evaluating such permit applications, and, in establishing or revising such criteria, shall consider, but not be limited in his consideration to, the following :</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857a5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The need for the proposed dumping.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857a6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The effect of such dumping on human health and welfare, including economic, esthetic, and recreational values.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857a7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The effect of such dumping on fisheries resources, plankton, fish, shellfish, wildlife, shore lines and beaches.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857a8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> The effect of such dumping on marine ecosystems, particularly with respect to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857a9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the transfer, concentration, and dispersion of such material and its byproducts through biological, physical, and chemical processes.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857aa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> potential changes in marine ecosystem diversity, productivity, and stability, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857ab-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> species and community population dynamics.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857ac-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The persistence and permanence of the effects of the dumping.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857ad-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The effect of dumping particular volumes and concentrations of such materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857ae-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Appropriate locations and methods of disposal or recycling, including land-based alternatives and the probable impact of requiring use of such alternate locations or methods upon considerations affecting the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857af-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> The effect on alternate uses of oceans, such as scientific study, fishing, and other living resource exploitation, and non-living resource exploitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0857b0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> In designating recommended sites, the Administrator shall utilize wherever feasible locations beyond the edge of the Continental Shelf.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In establishing or revising such criteria, the Administrator shall consult with Federal, State, and local officials, and interested members of the general public, as may appear appropriate to the Administrator. With respect to such criteria as may affect the civil works program of the Department of the Army, the Administrator shall also consult with the Secretary. In reviewing applications for permits, the Administrator shall make such provision for consultation with interested Federal and State agencies as he deems useful or necessary. No permit shall be issued for a dumping of material which will violate applicable water quality standards. To the extent that he may do so without relaxing the requirements of this subchapter, the Administrator, in establishing or revising such criteria, shall apply the standards and criteria binding upon the United States under the Convention, including its Annexes.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857b1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit categories</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may establish and issue various categories of permits, including the general permits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1414/c">section 1414(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857b2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation of sites</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857b3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall, in a manner consistent with the criteria established pursuant to subsection (a), designate sites or time periods for dumping. The Administrator shall designate sites or time periods for dumping that will mitigate adverse impact on the environment to the greatest extent practicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857b4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibitions regarding site or time period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any case where the Administrator determines that, with respect to certain materials, it is necessary to prohibit dumping at a site or during a time period, the Administrator shall prohibit the dumping of such materials in such site or during such time period. This prohibition shall apply to any dumping at the site or during such time period. This prohibition shall apply to any dumping at the site or during the time period, including any dumping under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413/e">section 1413(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857b5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Dredged material disposal sites</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of dredged material disposal sites, the Administrator, in conjunction with the Secretary, shall develop a site management plan for each site designated pursuant to this section. In developing such plans, the Administrator and the Secretary shall provide opportunity for public comment. Such plans shall include, but not be limited to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857b6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a baseline assessment of conditions at the site;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857b7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a program for monitoring the site;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857b8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> special management conditions or practices to be implemented at each site that are necessary for protection of the environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857b9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> consideration of the quantity of the material to be disposed of at the site, and the presence, nature, and bioavailability of the contaminants in the material;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857ba-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> consideration of the anticipated use of the site over the long term, including the anticipated closure date for the site, if applicable, and any need for management of the site after the closure of the site; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0857bb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> a schedule for review and revision of the plan (which shall not be reviewed and revised less frequently than 10 years after adoption of the plan, and every 10 years thereafter).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857bc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> General site management plan requirement; prohibitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, no site shall receive a final designation unless a management plan has been developed pursuant to this section. Beginning on <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, no permit for dumping pursuant to this Act or authorization for dumping under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413/e">section 1413(e) of this title</ref> shall be issued for a site (other than the site located off the coast of Newport Beach, California, which is known as “LA–3”) unless such site has received a final designation pursuant to this subsection or an alternative site has been selected pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413/b">section 1413(b) of this title</ref>. Beginning <date date="2011-01-01">January 1, 2011</date>, no permit for dumping pursuant to this Act or authorization for dumping under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413/e">section 1413(e) of this title</ref> shall be issued for the site located off the coast of Newport Beach, California, which is known as “LA–3”, unless such site has received a final designation pursuant to this subsection or an alternative site has been selected pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413/b">section 1413(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857bd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Management plans for previously designated sites</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Administrator shall develop a site management plan for any site designated prior to <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, as expeditiously as practicable, but not later than <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, giving priority consideration to management plans for designated sites that are considered to have the greatest impact on the environment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857be-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Fish wastes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No permit is required under this subchapter for the transportation for dumping or the dumping of fish wastes, except when deposited in harbors or other protected or enclosed coastal waters, or where the Administrator finds that such deposits could endanger health, the environment, or ecological systems in a specific location. Where the Administrator makes such a finding, such material may be deposited only as authorized by a permit issued by the Administrator under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0857bf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1412/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreign State permits; acceptance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of transportation of material, by an agency or instrumentality of the United States or by a vessel or aircraft registered in the United States or flying the United States flag, from a location in a foreign State Party to the Convention, a permit issued pursuant to the authority of that foreign State Party, in accordance with Convention requirements, and which otherwise could have been issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall be accepted, for the purposes of this subchapter, as if it were issued by the Administrator under the authority of this section: <i>Provided</i>, That in the case of an agency or instrumentality of the United States, no application shall be made for a permit to be issued pursuant to the authority of a foreign State Party to the Convention unless the Administrator concurs in the filing of such application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c0857c0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/532/tI/s102">Pub. L. 92–532, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1054">86 Stat. 1054</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/254/s1/4">Pub. L. 93–254, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1974-03-22">Mar. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/51">88 Stat. 51</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/572/s3">Pub. L. 96–572, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3345">94 Stat. 3345</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/688/tIII/s3201/b">Pub. L. 100–688, title III, § 3201(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4153">102 Stat. 4153</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/580/tV/s506/a">Pub. L. 102–580, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-31">Oct. 31, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4868">106 Stat. 4868</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/303/tV/s582">Pub. L. 104–303, title V, § 582</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3791">110 Stat. 3791</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/53/tV/s562">Pub. L. 106–53, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/355">113 Stat. 355</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/114/tV/s5046">Pub. L. 110–114, title V, § 5046</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1209">121 Stat. 1209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c0857c1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c0857c2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6c0857c3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(4), means <ref href="/us/pl/92/532">Pub. L. 92–532</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter, chapter 41 (§ 2801 et seq.) of this title, and chapters 32 (§ 1431 et seq.) and 32A (§ 1447 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c0857c4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/110/114">Pub. L. 110–114</ref> substituted “<date date="2011-01-01">January 1, 2011</date>” for “<date date="2003-01-01">January 1, 2003</date>” in third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/53">Pub. L. 106–53</ref> substituted “<date date="2003-01-01">January 1, 2003</date>” for “<date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>” in third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/303">Pub. L. 104–303</ref> inserted “(other than the site located off the coast of Newport Beach, California, which is known as ‘LA–3’)” after “for a site” and inserted at end “Beginning <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>, no permit for dumping pursuant to this Act or authorization for dumping under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413/e">section 1413(e) of this title</ref> shall be issued for the site located off the coast of Newport Beach, California, which is known as ‘LA–3’, unless such site has received a final designation pursuant to this subsection or an alternative site has been selected pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1413/b">section 1413(b) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/580">Pub. L. 102–580</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “The Administrator may, considering the criteria established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, designate recommended sites or times for dumping and, when he finds it necessary to protect critical areas, shall, after consultation with the Secretary, also designate sites or times within which certain materials may not be dumped.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/688">Pub. L. 100–688</ref> substituted “agents, high-level” for “agents and high-level” and inserted “and medical waste,” after “radioactive waste,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/572">Pub. L. 96–572</ref> inserted applicability to United States agency or instrumentality, and proviso respecting such agency or instrumentality.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/254/s1/4/A">Pub. L. 93–254, § 1(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “for which no permit may be issued,” for “as provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1411">section 1411 of this title</ref>,”, inserted “or in the case of a vessel or aircraft registered in the United States or flying the United States flag,” after “instrumentality of the United States,”, and required the Administrator to apply the standards and criteria binding upon the United States under the Convention, including its Annexes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/93/254/s1/4/B">Pub. L. 93–254, § 1(4)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c0857c5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6c0857c6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/254/s2">Pub. L. 93–254, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-03-22">Mar. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/51">88 Stat. 51</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/254/s2">“The amendments made by subparagraph 1(4)(A)(iii) and paragraph 1(4)(B) of this Act [enacting provision of subsec. (a) respecting application of standards by Administrator and subsec. (e) of this section] shall become effective on the date that the Convention on the Prevention of Marine Pollution by Dumping of Wastes and Other Matters enters into force for the United States.”</quotedContent>
 [The Convention entered into force for the United States <date date="1975-08-30">Aug. 30, 1975</date>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of subsec. (a) of this section, other than last sentence, by <ref href="/us/pl/93/254">Pub. L. 93–254</ref> effective <date date="1974-03-22">Mar. 22, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/254/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 93–254</ref>, set out in part as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id6c0857c7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 6 months after <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/532/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 92–532</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1411">section 1411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
