<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c0d11f7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416"><num value="1416">§ 1416.</num><heading> Relationship to other laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d11f8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Voiding of preexisting licenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After the effective date of this subchapter, all licenses, permits, and authorizations other than those issued pursuant to this subchapter shall be void and of no legal effect, to the extent that they purport to authorize any activity regulated by this subchapter, and whether issued before or after the effective date of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d11f9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions under authority of Rivers and Harbors Act</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to actions taken before the effective date of this subchapter under the authority of the Rivers and Harbors Act of 1899 (<ref href="/us/stat/30/1151">30 Stat. 1151</ref>), as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s401">33 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d11fa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Impairment of navigation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Prior to issuing any permit under this subchapter, if it appears to the Administrator that the disposition of material, other than dredged material, may adversely affect navigation in the territorial sea of the United States, or in the approaches to any harbor of the United States, or may create an artificial island on the Outer Continental Shelf, the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary and no permit shall be issued if the Secretary determines that navigation will be unreasonably impaired.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d11fb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> State programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d11fc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> State rights preserved</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as expressly provided in this subsection, nothing in this subchapter shall preclude or deny the right of any State to adopt or enforce any requirements respecting dumping of materials into ocean waters within the jurisdiction of the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d11fd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal projects</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a Federal project, a State may not adopt or enforce a requirement that is more stringent than a requirement under this subchapter if the Administrator finds that such requirement—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0d11fe-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is not supported by relevant scientific evidence showing the requirement to be protective of human health, aquatic resources, or the environment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0d11ff-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is arbitrary or capricious; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0d1200-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is not applicable or is not being applied to all projects without regard to Federal, State, or private participation and the Secretary of the Army concurs in such finding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d1201-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption from State requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may exempt a Federal project from any State requirement respecting dumping of materials into ocean waters if it is in the paramount interest of the United States to do so.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d1202-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of site of origin prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any requirement respecting dumping of materials into ocean waters applied by a State shall be applied without regard to the site of origin of the material to be dumped.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d1203-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing conservation programs not affected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be deemed to affect in any manner or to any extent any provision of the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s661–666c">16 U.S.C. 661–666c</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d1204-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Dumping of dredged material in Long Island Sound from any Federal, etc., project</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to other provisions of law and not withstanding the specific exclusion relating to dredged material in the first sentence in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a">section 1412(a) of this title</ref>, the dumping of dredged material in Long Island Sound from any Federal project (or pursuant to Federal authorization) or from a dredging project by a non-Federal applicant exceeding 25,000 cubic yards shall comply with the requirements of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0d1205-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1416/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings clause</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall restrict, affect or modify the rights of any person (1) to seek damages or enforcement of any standard or limitation under State law, including State common law, or (2) to seek damages under other Federal law, including maritime tort law, resulting from noncompliance with any requirement of this Act or any permit under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c0d1206-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/532/tI/s106">Pub. L. 92–532, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1058">86 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/572/s4">Pub. L. 96–572, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-12-22">Dec. 22, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3345">94 Stat. 3345</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tI/s127/d">Pub. L. 99–499, title I, § 127(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1693">100 Stat. 1693</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/596/tII/s203">Pub. L. 101–596, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3006">104 Stat. 3006</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/580/tV/s505">Pub. L. 102–580, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1992-10-31">Oct. 31, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4867">106 Stat. 4867</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c0d1207-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c0d1208-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6c0d1209-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), means the effective date of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/92/532">Pub. L. 92–532</ref>, which is six months after <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>. See <ref href="/us/pl/92/532/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 92–532</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1411">section 1411 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rivers and Harbors Act of 1899, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means the Act popularly known as the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1899, <ref href="/us/act/1899-03-03/ch425">act Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/1151">30 Stat. 1151</ref>, which enacted sections 401, 403, 404, 406 to 409, 411 to 416, 418, 502, 549, 686, and 687 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s661–666c">16 U.S.C. 661–666c</ref>), referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-03-10/ch55">act Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/401">48 Stat. 401</ref>, which is classified generally to sections 661 to 666c–1 of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s661/a">section 661(a) of Title 16</ref>, Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s661">section 661 of Title 16</ref>, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (g), means <ref href="/us/pl/92/532">Pub. L. 92–532</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter, chapter 41 (§ 2801 et seq.) of this title, and chapters 32 (§ 1431 et seq.) and 32A (§ 1447 et seq.) of Title 16.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c0d120a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/580">Pub. L. 102–580</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “After the effective date of this subchapter, no State shall adopt or enforce any rule or regulation relating to any activity regulated by this subchapter. Any State may, however, propose to the Administrator criteria relating to the dumping of materials into ocean waters within its jurisdiction, or into other ocean waters to the extent that such dumping may affect waters within the jurisdiction of such State, and if the Administrator determines, after notice and opportunity for hearing, that the proposed criteria are not inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter, may adopt those criteria and may issue regulations to implement such criteria. Such determination shall be made by the Administrator within one hundred and twenty days of receipt of the proposed criteria. For the purposes of this subsection, the term ‘State’ means any State, interstate or regional authority, Federal territory or Commonwealth or the District of Columbia.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/596">Pub. L. 101–596</ref>, which directed the substitution of “the requirements of this subchapter” for all after “shall comply with” in “subsection 116(g) of the Marine Protection Research and Sanctuaries Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1416/g">33 U.S.C. 1416(g)</ref>)”, was executed by making the substitution for “the criteria established pursuant to the second sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1412/a">section 1412(a) of this title</ref> relating to the effects of dumping. Subsection (d) of this section shall not apply to this subsection.” which followed “shall comply with” in section 106(f) of the Marine Protection Research and Sanctuaries Act of 1972, which is classified to subsec. (f) of this section, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/99/499">Pub. L. 99–499</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/572">Pub. L. 96–572</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c0d120b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id6c0d120c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 6 months after <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/532/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 92–532</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1411">section 1411 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6c0d120d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6c0d120e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Territorial Sea of United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For extension of territorial sea of United States, see Proc. No. 5928, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">section 1331 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
