<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c0f834b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443"><num value="1443">§ 1443.</num><heading> Research program respecting ocean dumping and other methods of waste disposal</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0f834c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation with public authorities, agencies, and institutions, private agencies and institutions, and individuals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f834d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> conduct research, investigations, experiments, training, demonstrations, surveys, and studies for the purpose of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0f834e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> determining means of minimizing or ending, as soon as possible after <date date="1980-10-06">October 6, 1980</date>, the dumping into ocean waters, or waters described in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1411/b">section 1411(b) of this title</ref>, of material which may unreasonably degrade or endanger human health, welfare, or amenities, or the marine environment, ecological systems, or economic potentialities, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c0f834f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> developing disposal methods as alternatives to the dumping described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f8350-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> encourage, cooperate with, promote the coordination of, and render financial and other assistance to appropriate public authorities, agencies, and institutions (whether Federal, State, interstate, or local) and appropriate private agencies, institutions, and individuals in the conduct of research and other activities described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0f8351-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination date for ocean dumping of sewage sludge not affected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect in any way the <date date="1981-12-31">December 31, 1981</date>, termination date, established in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1412a">section 1412a of this title</ref>, for the ocean dumping of sewage sludge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0f8352-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional management plans for waste disposal</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator, in cooperation with the Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, and other officials of appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies, shall assess the feasibility in coastal areas of regional management plans for the disposal of waste materials. Such plans should integrate where appropriate Federal, State, regional, and local waste disposal activities into a comprehensive regional disposal strategy. These plans should address, among other things—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f8353-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the sources, quantities, and types of materials that require and will require disposal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f8354-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the environmental, economic, social, and human health factors (and the methods used to assess these factors) associated with disposal alternatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f8355-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the improvements in production processes, methods of disposal, and recycling to reduce the adverse effects associated with such disposal alternatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f8356-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the applicable laws and regulations governing waste disposal; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f8357-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> improvements in permitting processes to reduce administrative burdens.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c0f8358-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on sewage disposal in New York metropolitan area</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator, in cooperation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall submit to the Congress and the President, not later than one year after <date date="1986-04-07">April 7, 1986</date>, a report on sewage sludge disposal in the New York City metropolitan region. The report shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f8359-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consider the factors listed in subsection (c) as they relate to landfilling, incineration, ocean dumping, or any other feasible disposal or reuse/recycling option;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f835a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> include an assessment of the cost of these alternatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c0f835b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1443/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> recommend such regulatory or legislative changes as may be necessary to reduce the adverse impacts associated with sewage sludge disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c0f835c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/532/tII/s203">Pub. L. 92–532, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1061">86 Stat. 1061</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/381/s1">Pub. L. 96–381, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-10-06">Oct. 6, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1523">94 Stat. 1523</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tVI/s6063">Pub. L. 99–272, title VI, § 6063</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/131">100 Stat. 131</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c0f835d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c0f835e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6c0f835f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(1)(A), <date date="1980-10-06">October 6, 1980</date>, was substituted for “the date of the enactment of this section”, which has been translated to reflect the probable intent of Congress as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/96/381">Pub. L. 96–381</ref> which amended this section generally and which was approved <date date="1980-10-06">Oct. 6, 1980</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c0f8360-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/381">Pub. L. 96–381</ref> substituted provision authorizing the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct research, etc., and to encourage and cooperate with public authorities, etc., for the purpose of determining means of minimizing or ending, as soon as possible after <date date="1980-10-06">Oct. 6, 1980</date>, dumping in ocean waters, or waters described in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1411/b">section 1411(b) of this title</ref>, of materials which may unreasonably degrade or endanger human health or the marine environment and to develop disposal methods as alternatives to dumping for provision authorizing the Secretary of Commerce to conduct research, etc., and to encourage and cooperate with public authorities, etc., for the purpose of minimizing or ending all dumping of materials within five years after the effective date of <ref href="/us/pl/92/532">Pub. L. 92–532</ref>, which was approved <date date="1972-10-23">Oct. 23, 1972</date>, and inserted provision directing that nothing in this section be construed to affect in any way the <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, termination date, established by <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1412a">section 1412a of this title</ref> for ocean dumping of sewage sludge.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
