<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c143e3f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504"><num value="1504">§ 1504.</num><heading> Procedure</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e40-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations; issuance, amendment, or rescission; scope</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s468/b">section 468(b) of title 6</ref>, the Secretary shall have the authority to issue regulations to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter, in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, without regard to subsection (a) thereof. Such regulations shall pertain to, but need not be limited to, application, issuance, transfer, renewal, suspension, and termination of licenses. Such regulations shall provide for full consultation and cooperation with all other interested Federal agencies and departments and with any potentially affected coastal State, and for consideration of the views of any interested members of the general public. The Secretary is further authorized, consistent with the purposes and provisions of this chapter, to amend or rescind any such regulation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e41-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional regulations; criteria for site evaluation and preconstruction testing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall, as soon as practicable after <date date="1975-01-03">January 3, 1975</date>, prescribe regulations relating to those activities involved in site evaluation and preconstruction testing at potential deepwater port locations that may (1) adversely affect the environment; (2) interfere with authorized uses of the Outer Continental Shelf; or (3) pose a threat to human health and welfare. Such activity may thenceforth not be undertaken except in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to this subsection. Such regulations shall be consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e42-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e43-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e44-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Each person that submits to the Secretary an application shall include in the application a detailed plan that contains all information required under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e45-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Action by secretary</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 21 days after the date of receipt of an application, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e46-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> determine whether the application contains all information required under paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e47-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e48-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> if the Secretary determines that such information is contained in the application, not later than 5 days after making the determination, publish in the Federal Register—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6c143e49-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> a notice of the application; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6c143e4a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> a summary of the plans; or</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e4b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> if the Secretary determines that all required information is not contained in the application—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6c143e4c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> notify the applicant of the applicable deficiencies; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6c143e4d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> take no further action with respect to the application until those deficiencies have been remedied.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e4e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>On publication of a notice relating to an application under subparagraph (B)(ii)(I), the Secretary shall be subject to subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e4f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each application shall include such financial, technical, and other information as the Secretary determines to be necessary or appropriate, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e50-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the name, address, citizenship, telephone number, and the ownership interest in the applicant, of each person having any ownership interest in the applicant of greater than 3 per centum;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e51-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to the extent feasible, the name, address, citizenship, and telephone number of any person with whom the applicant has made, or proposes to make, a significant contract for the construction or operation of the deepwater port and a copy of any such contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e52-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the name, address, citizenship, and telephone number of each affiliate of the applicant and of any person required to be disclosed pursuant to subparagraphs (A) or (B), together with a description of the manner in which such affiliate is associated with the applicant or any person required to be disclosed under subparagraph (A) or (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e53-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the proposed location and capacity of the deepwater port, including all components thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e54-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the type and design of all components of the deepwater port and any storage facilities associated with the deepwater port;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e55-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> with respect to construction in phases, a detailed description of each phase, including anticipated dates of completion for each of the specific components thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e56-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the location and capacity of existing and proposed storage facilities and pipelines which will store or transport oil transported through the deepwater port, to the extent known by the applicant or any person required to be disclosed pursuant to subparagraphs (A), (B), or (C);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e57-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> with respect to any existing and proposed refineries which will receive oil transported through the deepwater port, the location and capacity of each such refinery and the anticipated volume of such oil to be refined by each such refinery, to the extent known by the applicant or any person required to be disclosed pursuant to subparagraphs (A), (B), or (C);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e58-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the financial and technical capabilities of the applicant to construct or operate the deepwater port;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e59-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> other qualifications of the applicant to hold a license under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e5a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> the nation of registry for, and the nationality or citizenship of officers and crew serving on board, vessels transporting natural gas that are reasonably anticipated to be servicing the deepwater port;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e5b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> a description of procedures to be used in constructing, operating, and maintaining the deepwater port, including systems of oil spill prevention, containment, and cleanup; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e5c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> such other information as may be required by the Secretary to determine the environmental impact of the proposed deepwater port.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e5d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon written request of any person subject to this subsection, the Secretary may make a determination in writing to exempt such person from any of the informational filing provisions enumerated in this subsection or the regulations implementing this section if the Secretary determines that such information is not necessary to facilitate the Secretary’s determinations under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1503">section 1503 of this title</ref> and that such exemption will not limit public review and evaluation of the deepwater port project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e5e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Application area; publication in Federal Register; “application area” defined; submission of other applications; notice of intent and submission of completed applications; denial of pending application prior to consideration of other untimely applications</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e5f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> At the time notice of an application is published pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary shall publish a description in the Federal Register of an application area encompassing the deepwater port site proposed by such application and within which construction of the proposed deepwater port would eliminate, at the time such application was submitted, the need for any other deepwater port within that application area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e60-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> As used in this section, “application area” means any reasonable geographical area within which a deepwater port may be constructed and operated. Such application area shall not exceed a circular zone, the center of which is the principal point of loading and unloading at the port, and the radius of which is the distance from such point to the high water mark of the nearest adjacent coastal State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e61-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall accompany such publication with a call for submission of any other applications for licenses for the ownership, construction, and operation of a deepwater port within the designated application area. Persons intending to file applications for such license shall submit a notice of intent to file an application with the Secretary not later than 60 days after the publication of notice pursuant to subsection (c) of this section and shall submit the completed application no later than 90 days after publication of such notice. The Secretary shall publish notice of any such application received in accordance with subsection (c) of this section. No application for a license for the ownership, construction, and operation of a deepwater port within the designated application area for which a notice of intent to file was received after such 60-day period, or which is received after such 90-day period has elapsed, shall be considered until the application pending with respect to such application area have been denied pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e62-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> This subsection shall not apply to deepwater ports for natural gas.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e63-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendations to Secretary of Transportation; application for all Federal authorizations; copies of application to Federal agencies and departments with jurisdiction; recommendation of approval or disapproval and of manner of amendment to comply with laws or regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e64-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 30 days after <date date="1975-01-03">January 3, 1975</date>, the Secretary of the Interior, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Chief of Engineers of the United States Army Corps of Engineers, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the heads of any other Federal departments or agencies having expertise concerning, or jurisdiction over, any aspect of the construction or operation of deepwater ports shall transmit to the Secretary written comments as to their expertise or statutory responsibilities pursuant to this chapter or any other Federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e65-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An application filed with the Secretary shall constitute an application for all Federal authorizations required for ownership, construction, and operation of a deepwater port. At the time notice of any application is published pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary shall forward a copy of such application to those Federal agencies and departments with jurisdiction over any aspect of such ownership, construction, or operation for comment, review, or recommendation as to conditions and for such other action as may be required by law. Each agency or department involved shall review the application and, based upon legal considerations within its area of responsibility, recommend to the Secretary, the approval or disapproval of the application not later than 45 days after the last public hearing on a proposed license for a designated application area. In any case in which the agency or department recommends disapproval, it shall set forth in detail the manner in which the application does not comply with any law or regulation within its area of responsibility and shall notify the Secretary how the application may be amended so as to bring it into compliance with the law or regulation involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e66-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> NEPA compliance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e67-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of lead agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “lead agency” has the meaning given the term in section 111 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4336e">42 U.S.C. 4336e</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e68-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Lead agency</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e69-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For all applications, the Maritime Administration shall be the Federal lead agency for purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e6a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) in accordance with subparagraph (A) shall fulfill the requirement of the Federal lead agency in carrying out the responsibilities under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e6b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Public notice and hearings; evidentiary hearing in District of Columbia; decision of Secretary based on evidentiary record; consolidation of hearings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A license may be issued only after public notice and public hearings in accordance with this subsection. At least one such public hearing shall be held in each adjacent coastal State. Any interested person may present relevant material at any hearing. After hearings in each adjacent coastal State are concluded if the Secretary determines that there exists one or more specific and material factual issues which may be resolved by a formal evidentiary hearing, at least one adjudicatory hearing shall be held in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref> in the District of Columbia. The record developed in any such adjudicatory hearing shall be basis for the Secretary’s decision to approve or deny a license. Hearings held pursuant to this subsection shall be consolidated insofar as practicable with hearings held by other agencies. All public hearings on all applications for any designated application area shall be consolidated and shall be concluded not later than 240 days after notice of the initial application has been published pursuant to subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e6c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Fees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e6d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e6e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each person applying for a license pursuant to this chapter shall remit to the Secretary at the time the application is filed a nonrefund­able application fee established by regulation by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e6f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In addition to a fee under subparagraph (A), an applicant shall also reimburse the United States and the appropriate adjacent coastal State for any additional costs incurred in processing an application.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e70-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Usage fees</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e71-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of directly related land-based facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “directly related land-based facility”, with respect to a deepwater port facility, means an onshore tank farm and any pipelines connecting the tank farm to the deepwater port facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e72-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, and unless prohibited by law, an adjacent coastal State may fix reasonable fees for the use of a deepwater port facility, and such State and any other State in which land-based facilities directly related to a deepwater port facility are located may set reasonable fees for the use of such land-based facilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e73-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A fee may be established pursuant to this paragraph as compensation for any economic cost attributable to the construction and operation of the applicable deepwater port and the applicable land-based facilities, which cannot be recovered under other authority of the applicable State or political subdivision thereof, including, but not limited to, ad valorem taxes, and for environmental and administrative costs attributable to the construction and operation of the applicable deepwater port and the applicable land-based facilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e74-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount of a fee established under this paragraph shall not exceed the applicable economic, environmental, and administrative costs of the applicable State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e75-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/2/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A fee established under this paragraph shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e76-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Rental payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A licensee shall pay annually in advance the fair market rental value (as determined by the Secretary of the Interior) of the subsoil and seabed of the outer Continental Shelf of the United States to be utilized by the deepwater port, including the fair market rental value of the right-of-way necessary for the pipeline segment of the port located on such subsoil and seabed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e77-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Application approval; period for determination; priorities; criteria for determination of application best serving national interest</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e78-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall approve or deny any application for a designated application area submitted pursuant to this chapter not later than 90 days after the last public hearing on a proposed license for that area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e79-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In the event more than one application is submitted for an application area, the Secretary, unless one of the proposed deepwater ports clearly best serves the national interest, shall issue a license according to the following order of priorities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e7a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> First, to an adjacent coastal State (or combination of States), any political subdivision thereof, or agency or instrumentality, including a wholly owned corporation of any such government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e7b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Second, to a person who is neither (i) engaged in producing, refining, or marketing oil, nor (ii) an affiliate of any person who is engaged in producing, refining, or marketing oil or an affiliate of any such affiliate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e7c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Third, to any other person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e7d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In determining whether any one proposed deepwater port clearly best serves the national interest, the Secretary shall consider the following factors:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e7e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The degree to which the proposed deepwater ports affect the environment, as determined under criteria established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1505">section 1505 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e7f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> National security, including an assessment of the implications for the national security of the United States or an allied country (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/d/1">section 2350f(d)(1) of title 10</ref>) of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e80-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any significant differences between anticipated completion dates for the proposed deepwater ports.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e81-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any differences in costs of construction and operation of the proposed deepwater ports, to the extent that such differential may significantly affect the ultimate cost of oil to the consumer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e82-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applications for deepwater ports for natural gas.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e83-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for determination</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall approve or deny any application for a deepwater port for natural gas submitted pursuant to this chapter not later than 90 days after the last public hearing on a proposed license.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e84-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of failure to determine</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary fails to approve or deny an application for a deepwater port for natural gas by the applicable deadline under subparagraph (A), the reporting requirements under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) shall not apply to the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c143e85-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Decision on amended license applications.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e86-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of amended license application</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this paragraph, the term “amended license application” means a license application for a deepwater port for natural gas—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e87-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that was originally submitted to the Secretary prior to the issuance of the proclamation issued by the President on <date date="2020-03-13">March 13, 2020</date>, with respect to the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID–19) pandemic; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e88-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to which the applicant, based on guidance offered by the Secretary, has made subsequent revisions since the submission of the initial license application and submitted such revised application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e89-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited review and approval</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall expedite the review and subsequent approval or denial of amended license applications submitted pursuant to this section that meet the eligibility criteria described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e8a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility criteria</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To be eligible for review under this paragraph, an amended license application shall meet the following criteria:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e8b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The amended license application is for a natural gas deepwater port facility.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e8c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Secretary had determined that the project as specified in the initial license application was not likely to have any significant adverse environmental impact on species and habitat, consistent with law including National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e8d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The Secretary has determined that the results of the environmental review conducted for the initial license application is still applicable to the amended license application and an additional environmental review is not required.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e8e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The Secretary had published an affirmative Record of Decision for the initial license application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c143e8f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/i/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for decision</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall approve or deny an amended license application submitted pursuant to this paragraph by no later than 270 consecutive days after the date on which the Secretary determines that the amended license application is complete and meets the requirements under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e90-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> LNG tankers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e91-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall develop and implement a program to promote the transportation of liquefied natural gas to and from the United States on United States flag vessels.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e92-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to be provided</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">When the Coast Guard is operating as a contributing agency in the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission’s shoreside licensing process for a liquefied natural gas or liquefied petroleum gas terminal located on shore or within State seaward boundaries, the Coast Guard shall provide to the Commission the information described in subsection (c)(2)(K) with respect to vessels reasonably anticipated to be servicing that port.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e93-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Transparency in issuance of licenses and permits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e94-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of applicable deadline</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “applicable deadline”, with respect to an applicant, means the deadline or date applicable to the applicant under any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e95-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1503/c/6">Section 1503(c)(6) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e96-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1503/d/3">Section 1503(d)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e97-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Subsection (c)(1)(B) (including clause (ii)(I) of that subsection).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e98-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Subsection (d)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e99-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e9a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e9b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Paragraph (1) or (4)(A) of subsection (i).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143e9c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspensions and delays</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary suspends or delays an applicable deadline, the Secretary shall submit to the applicant, and publish in the Federal Register, a written statement—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e9d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> describing the reasons for the suspension or delay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e9e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> describing and requesting any information necessary to issue the applicable license or permit and the status of applicable license or permit application at the lead agency and any cooperating agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143e9f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> identifying the applicable deadline with respect to the statement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143ea0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicant rights to technical assistance</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143ea1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An applicant that receives a statement under paragraph (2) may submit to the Secretary a request for a meeting with appropriate personnel of the Department of Transportation and representatives of each cooperating Federal agency, as appropriate, determined by the Secretary to be relevant with respect to the application, including such officials as are appropriate, who shall provide technical assistance, status, process, and timeline updates and additional information as necessary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143ea2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A meeting requested under clause (i) shall be held not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives the request under that clause.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143ea3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">On receipt of a request under paragraph (3)(A), and not less frequently than once every 30 days thereafter until the date on which the application process is no longer suspended or delayed, the Secretary shall submit a notice of the delay, including a description of the time elapsed since the applicable deadline and the nature and circumstances of the applicable suspension or delay, to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143ea4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143ea5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c143ea6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Briefing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary suspends or delays an applicable deadline, not later than 120 days after that applicable deadline, and not less frequently than once every 120 days thereafter until the date on which the application process is no longer suspended or delayed, the Secretary (or a designee of the Secretary) shall provide a briefing regarding the time elapsed since the applicable deadline and the nature and circumstances of the applicable suspension or delay to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143ea7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c143ea8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1504/k/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c143ea9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/627/s5">Pub. L. 93–627, § 5</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2131">88 Stat. 2131</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/419/s2/f">Pub. L. 98–419, § 2(f)</ref>, <date date="1984-09-25">Sept. 25, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1607">98 Stat. 1607</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/tV/s505">Pub. L. 104–324, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3927">110 Stat. 3927</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/tI/s106/c">Pub. L. 107–295, title I, § 106(c)</ref>, (f), (g), <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2086-2088">116 Stat. 2086–2088</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/241/tIII/s304/c/1">Pub. L. 109–241, title III, § 304(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/527">120 Stat. 527</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tIX/s903/d">Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 903(d)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3011">124 Stat. 3011</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dG/tLVXXXV">Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8502(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4747">134 Stat. 4747</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dC/tXXXV/s3514/k/4">Pub. L. 118–31, div. C, title XXXV, § 3514(k)(4)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/814">137 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dC/tXXXV/s3538">Pub. L. 118–159, div. C, title XXXV, § 3538</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2316">138 Stat. 2316</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIII/s7342/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7342(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1777">139 Stat. 1777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c143eaa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c143eab-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6c143eac-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsecs. (f)(2) and (i)(5)(C)(ii), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The proclamation issued by the President on <date date="2020-03-13">March 13, 2020</date>, with respect to the Coronavirus Disease 2019, referred to in subsec. (i)(5)(A)(i), means Proc. No. 9994, <date date="2020-03-13">Mar. 13, 2020</date>, 85 F.R. 15337, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1621">section 1621 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c143ead-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s7342/a">Pub. L. 119–60, § 7342(a)</ref>, substituted “Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s468/b">section 468(b) of title 6</ref>, the Secretary shall have the authority to issue regulations to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter, in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, without regard to subsection (a) thereof.” for “The Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after <date date="1975-01-03">January 3, 1975</date>, and after consultation with other Federal agencies, issue regulations to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, without regard to subsection (a) thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s7342/b">Pub. L. 119–60, § 7342(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f) and struck out former subsec. (f). Text read as follows: “For all applications, the Secretary, in cooperation with other involved Federal agencies and departments, shall comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.]. Such compliance shall fulfill the requirement of all Federal agencies in carrying out their responsibilities under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 pursuant to this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (i)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/A/i">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/A/i">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(A)(i)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “Any person making an application under this chapter shall submit detailed plans to the Secretary. Within 21 days after the receipt of an application, the Secretary shall determine whether the application appears to contain all of the information required by paragraph (2) hereof. If the Secretary determines that such information appears to be contained in the application, the Secretary shall, no later than 5 days after making such a determination, publish notice of the application and a summary of the plans in the Federal Register. If the Secretary determines that all of the required information does not appear to be contained in the application, the Secretary shall notify the applicant and take no further action with respect to the application until such deficiencies have been remedied.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/A/ii">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted heading, substituted “Each application shall include such financial, technical, and other information as the Secretary determines to be necessary or appropriate, including—” for “Each application shall include such financial, technical, and other information as the Secretary deems necessary or appropriate. Such information shall include, but need not be limited to—” in introductory provisions, struck out “of this paragraph” after “subparagraph (A) or (B)” in two places in subpar. (C), and after “subparagraphs (A), (B), or (C)” in subpars. (G) and (H), and realigned margins of subpars. (A) to (M).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/B">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c)” for “subsection (c) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/C/i">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(C)(i)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/C/i">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(C)(i)</ref>, (ii), inserted par. (1) heading, designated first sentence of par. (1) as subpar. (A) and inserted subpar. heading, designated second sentence as subpar. (B), inserted subpar. heading, and substituted “In addition to a fee under subparagraph (A)” for “In addition”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/C/iii/I">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(C)(iii)(I)</ref>, (II), inserted par. heading and struck out “As used in this paragraph, the term ‘land-based facilities directly related to a deepwater port facility’ means the onshore tank farm and pipelines connecting such tank farm to the deepwater port facility.” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/C/iii/II">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(C)(iii)(II)</ref>, added subpar. (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2)(B) to (E). Pub. L. 11831, § 3514(k)(4)(C)(iii)(II), (III), designated first sentence of par. (2) as subpar. (B) and inserted subpar. heading; designated second sentence as subpar. (C), inserted subpar. heading, and substituted “the applicable” for “such” wherever appearing and “A fee may be established pursuant to this paragraph” for “Fees may be fixed under authority of this paragraph”; designated third sentence as subpar. (D), inserted subpar. heading, and substituted “the applicable” for “such” in two places and “The amount of a fee established under this paragraph” for “Fees under this paragraph”; and designated fourth sentence as subpar. (E), inserted subpar. heading, and substituted “A fee established under this paragraph” for “Such fees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/C/iv">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(C)(iv)</ref>, inserted heading and substituted “outer” for “Outer” before “Continental”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/D/i/I">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(D)(i)(I)</ref>, inserted “First,” after subpar. designation and substituted period for semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/D/i/II">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(D)(i)(II)</ref>, inserted “Second,” after subpar. designation and substituted period for semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/D/i/III">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(D)(i)(III)</ref>, inserted “Third,” after subpar. designation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/D/ii/III">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(D)(ii)(III)</ref>, substituted “(A) The degree” for “(A) the degree” and period for semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(3)(B) to (D). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/D/ii/I">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(D)(ii)(I)</ref>, (II), (IV), added subpar. (B), redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C) and substituted “Any” for “any” and a period for “; and”, and redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D) and substituted “Any” for “any”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/D/iii">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(D)(iii)</ref>, inserted par. heading, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and inserted subpar. heading, struck out “Paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of this subsection shall not apply to an application for a deepwater port for natural gas.” at end, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/E">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(E)</ref>, struck out “of Transportation” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/4/F">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(4)(F)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c)(2)(K). <ref href="/us/pl/111/281">Pub. L. 111–281</ref> realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c)(2)(K) to (M). <ref href="/us/pl/109/241">Pub. L. 109–241</ref> added subpar. (K) and redesignated former subpars. (K) and (L) as (L) and (M), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/s106/c/1">Pub. L. 107–295, § 106(c)(1)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/s106/f">Pub. L. 107–295, § 106(f)</ref>, substituted “NEPA compliance” for “Environmental impact statement for single application area; criteria” in heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “For all timely applications covering a single application area, the Secretary, in cooperation with other involved Federal agencies and departments, shall, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4332/2/C">section 4332(2)(C) of title 42</ref>, prepare a single, detailed environmental impact statement, which shall fulfill the requirement of all Federal agencies in carrying out their responsibilities pursuant to this chapter to prepare an environmental impact statement. In preparing such statement the Secretary shall consider the criteria established under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1505">section 1505 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/s106/g">Pub. L. 107–295, § 106(g)</ref>, inserted “and unless prohibited by law,” after “Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/s106/c/2">Pub. L. 107–295, § 106(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324">Pub. L. 104–324</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/419">Pub. L. 98–419</ref> substituted “issued” for “issued, transferred, or renewed”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c143eae-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6c143eaf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2025 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIII/s7342/e">Pub. L. 119–60, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7342(e)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1778">139 Stat. 1778</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIII/s7342/e">“Nothing in this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section], or the amendments made by this section, shall apply to any application submitted before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6c143eb0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIII/s7342/c">Pub. L. 119–60, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7342(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1777">139 Stat. 1777</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIII/s7342/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Commandant shall transfer the authorities provided to the Coast Guard in part 148 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>]), except as provided in paragraph (2), to the Secretary of Transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retention of authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall retain responsibility for authorities pertaining to design, construction, equipment, and operation of deepwater ports and navigational safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updates to authority</inline>.—</heading><content>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to reflect the updates to authorities prescribed by this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/107/295/tI/s106/e">Pub. L. 107–295, title I, § 106(e)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2087">116 Stat. 2087</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/295/tI/s106/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agency and department expertise and responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>], the heads of Federal departments or agencies having expertise concerning, or jurisdiction over, any aspect of the construction or operation of deepwater ports for natural gas shall transmit to the Secretary of Transportation written comments as to such expertise or statutory responsibilities pursuant to the Deepwater Port Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1501">33 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.) or any other Federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim final rule</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may issue an interim final rule as a temporary regulation implementing this section [amending this section and sections 1501 to 1503, 1507, and 1520 of this title] (including the amendments made by this section) as soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this section, without regard to the provisions of chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final rules</inline>.—</heading><content>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue additional final rules that, in the discretion of the Secretary, are determined to be necessary under the Deepwater Port Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1501">33 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.) for the application and issuance of licenses for a deepwater port for natural gas.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6c143eb1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIII/s7342/d">Pub. L. 119–60, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7342(d)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1778">139 Stat. 1778</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIII/s7342/d">“Nothing in this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section], or the amendments made by this section, may be construed to limit the authorities of other governmental agencies previously delegated authorities of the Deepwater Port Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1501">33 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.) or any other law.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6c143eb2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Information To Be Provided</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/241/tIII/s304/c/2">Pub. L. 109–241, title III, § 304(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/527">120 Stat. 527</ref>, which required the Coast Guard, when operating as a contributing agency in the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission’s shoreside licensing process for certain liquefied natural gas or liquefied petroleum gas terminals, to provide the information described in subsec. (c)(2)(K) of this section, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dG/tLVXXXV">Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV</ref> [LXXXV], § 8502(b)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4747">134 Stat. 4747</ref>. See subsec. (j)(2) of this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
