<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c16aed3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508"><num value="1508">§ 1508.</num><heading> Adjacent coastal States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aed4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In issuing a notice relating to an application for a deepwater port under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c/1/B/ii/I">section 1504(c)(1)(B)(ii)(I) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall designate as an adjacent coastal State, with respect to the deepwater port, any coastal State that would be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c16aed5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> directly connected by pipeline to that deepwater port; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c16aed6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> located within 15 miles of that deepwater port.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aed7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Input from adjacent coastal States and other interested states</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aed8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of applications to governors for approval</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aed9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/b/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 10 days after the date on which the Secretary designates adjacent coastal States under subsection (a) with respect to a deepwater port proposed in an application, the Secretary shall transmit a complete copy of the application to the Governor of each adjacent coastal State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aeda-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/b/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall not issue a license without the approval of the Governor of each adjacent coastal State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aedb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/b/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Presumed approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Governor of an adjacent coastal State fails to transmit a required approval or disapproval to the Secretary not later than 45 days after the last public hearing on applications for a particular application area, such approval shall be conclusively presumed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aedc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/b/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Inconsistency with certain state programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Governor of an adjacent coastal State notifies the Secretary that an application, which would otherwise be approved pursuant to this paragraph, is inconsistent with State programs relating to environmental protection, land and water use, and coastal zone management, the Secretary shall condition the license granted so as to make it consistent with such State programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aedd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Other interested states</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any other State with an interest relating to a deepwater port proposed in an application shall have the opportunity to make its views known to, and shall be given full consideration by, the Secretary regarding the location, construction, and operation of the deepwater port.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aede-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reasonable progress toward development of coastal zone management program; planning grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall not issue a license unless the adjacent coastal State to which the deepwater port is to be directly connected by pipeline has developed, or is making, at the time the application is submitted, reasonable progress toward developing an approved coastal zone management program pursuant to the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">16 U.S.C. 1451</ref> et seq.] in the area to be directly and primarily impacted by land and water development in the coastal zone resulting from such deepwater port. For the purposes of this chapter, a State shall be considered to be making reasonable progress if it is receiving a planning grant pursuant to section 305 of the Coastal Zone Management Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1454">16 U.S.C. 1454</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16aedf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1508/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> State agreements or compacts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The consent of Congress is given to two or more coastal States to negotiate and enter into agreements or compacts, not in conflict with any law or treaty of the United States, (1) to apply for a license for the ownership, construction, and operation of a deepwater port or for the transfer of such license, and (2) to establish such agencies, joint or otherwise, as are deemed necessary or appropriate for implementing and carrying out the provisions of any such agreement or compact. Such agreement or compact shall be binding and obligatory upon any State or party thereto without further approval by Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c16aee0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/627/s9">Pub. L. 93–627, § 9</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2136">88 Stat. 2136</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dC/tXXXV/s3514/k/6">Pub. L. 118–31, div. C, title XXXV, § 3514(k)(6)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/818">137 Stat. 818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c16aee1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c16aee2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6c16aee3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, referred to in subsec. (c), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/89/454">Pub. L. 89–454</ref> as added by <ref href="/us/pl/92/583">Pub. L. 92–583</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1280">86 Stat. 1280</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1451 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1451">section 1451 of Title 16</ref>, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c16aee4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/6/A">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(6)(A)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) The Secretary, in issuing notice of application pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c">section 1504(c) of this title</ref>, shall designate as an “adjacent coastal State” any coastal State which (A) would be directly connected by pipeline to a deepwater port as proposed in an application, or (B) would be located within 15 miles of any such proposed deepwater port.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) The Secretary shall, upon request of a State, and after having received the recommendations of the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, designate such State as an “adjacent coastal State” if he determines that there is a risk of damage to the coastal environment of such State equal to or greater than the risk posed to a State directly connected by pipeline to the proposed deepwater port. This paragraph shall apply only with respect to requests made by a State not later than the 14th day after the date of publication of notice of an application for a proposed deepwater port in the Federal Register in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1504/c">section 1504(c) of this title</ref>. The Secretary shall make the designation required by this paragraph not later than the 45th day after the date he receives such a request from a State.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/6/B/i">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(6)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/6/B/i">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(6)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), inserted par. (1) heading, designated first sentence par. (1) as subpar. (A), inserted subpar. heading, and substituted “Not later than 10 days after the date on which the Secretary designates adjacent coastal States under subsection (a) with respect to a deepwater port proposed in an application” for “Not later than 10 days after the designation of adjacent coastal States pursuant to this chapter”; designated second sentence as subpar. (B) and inserted subpar. heading; designated third sentence as subpar. (C), inserted subpar. heading, and substituted “If the Governor of an adjacent coastal State fails to transmit a required” for “If the Governor fails to transmit his”; and designated fourth sentence as subpar. (D), inserted subpar. heading, and substituted “If the Governor of an adjacent coastal State” for “If the Governor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s3514/k/6/B/iii">Pub. L. 118–31, § 3514(k)(6)(B)(iii)</ref>, inserted heading and, in text, substituted “Any other State with an interest relating to a deepwater port proposed in an application” for “Any other interested State” and “the deepwater port” for “a deepwater port”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
