<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c16af0a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514"><num value="1514">§ 1514.</num><heading> Remedies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16af0b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who willfully violates any provision of this chapter or any rule, order, or regulation issued pursuant thereto commits a class A misdemeanor for each day of violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16af0c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Orders of compliance; Attorney General’s civil action; jurisdiction and venue</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c16af0d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Whenever on the basis of any information available to him the Secretary finds that any person is in violation of any provision of this chapter or any rule, regulation, order, license, or condition thereof, or other requirements under this chapter, he shall issue an order requiring such person to comply with such provision or requirement, or he shall bring a civil action in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c16af0e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any order issued under this subsection shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the violation and a time for compliance, not to exceed thirty days, which the Secretary determines is reasonable, taking into account the seriousness of the violation and any good faith efforts to comply with applicable requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c16af0f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon a request by the Secretary, the Attorney General shall commence a civil action for appropriate relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction or a civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 per day of such violation, for any violation for which the Secretary is authorized to issue a compliance order under paragraph (1) of this subsection. Any action under this subsection may be brought in the district court of the United States for the district in which the defendant is located or resides, or is doing business, and such court shall have jurisdiction to restrain such violation, require compliance, or impose such penalty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16af10-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Attorney General’s action for equitable relief; scope of relief</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon a request by the Secretary, the Attorney General shall bring an action in an appropriate district court of the United States for equitable relief to redress a violation by any person of any provision of this chapter, any regulation under this chapter, or any license condition. The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to grant such relief as is necessary or appropriate, including mandatory or prohibitive injunctive relief, interim equitable relief, compensatory damages, and punitive damages.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c16af11-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1514/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Vessels; liability in rem; exempt vessels; consent or privy of owners or bareboat charterers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any vessel, except a public vessel engaged in noncommercial activities, used in a violation of this chapter or of any rule or regulation issued pursuant to this chapter, shall be liable in rem for any civil penalty assessed or criminal fine imposed and may be proceeded against in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction thereof; but no vessel shall be liable unless it shall appear that one or more of the owners, or bareboat charterers, was at the time of the violation, a consenting party or privy to such violation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c16af12-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/627/s15">Pub. L. 93–627, § 15</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2140">88 Stat. 2140</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/tIV/s4302/m">Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4302(m)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/539">104 Stat. 539</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c16af13-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c16af14-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c16af15-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/380">Pub. L. 101–380</ref> substituted “commits a class A misdemeanor for each day of violation” for “shall on conviction be fined not more than $25,000 for each day of violation or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c16af16-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6c16af17-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/380">Pub. L. 101–380</ref> applicable to incidents occurring after <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/s1020">section 1020 of Pub. L. 101–380</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2701">section 2701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6c16af18-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deposit of Certain Penalties Into Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Penalties paid pursuant to this chapter and sections 1319(c) and 1321 of this title to be deposited in the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund created under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s9509">section 9509 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/s4304">section 4304 of Pub. L. 101–380</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s9509">section 9509 of Title 26</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
