<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c2025b3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905"><num value="1905">§ 1905.</num><heading> Pollution reception facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2025b4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Adequacy; criteria</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025b5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall establish regulations setting criteria for determining the adequacy of a port’s or terminal’s reception facilities for mixtures containing oil or noxious liquid substances and shall establish procedures whereby a person in charge of a port or terminal may request the Secretary to certify that the port’s or terminal’s facilities for receiving the residues and mixtures containing oil or noxious liquid substance from seagoing ships are adequate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025b6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary, after consulting with appropriate Federal agencies, shall establish regulations setting criteria for determining the adequacy of reception facilities for garbage at a port or terminal, and stating such additional measures and requirements as are appropriate to ensure such adequacy. Persons in charge of ports and terminals shall provide reception facilities, or ensure that such facilities are available, for receiving garbage in accordance with those regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025b7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary and the Administrator, after consulting with appropriate Federal agencies, shall jointly prescribe regulations setting criteria for determining the adequacy of reception facilities for receiving ozone depleting substances, equipment containing such substances, and exhaust gas cleaning residues at a port or terminal, and stating any additional measures and requirements as are appropriate to ensure such adequacy. Persons in charge of ports and terminals shall provide reception facilities, or ensure that reception facilities are available, in accordance with those regulations. The Secretary and the Administrator may jointly prescribe regulations to certify, and may issue certificates to the effect, that a port’s or terminal’s facilities for receiving ozone depleting substances, equipment containing such substances, and exhaust gas cleaning residues from ships are adequate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2025b8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Traffic considerations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining the adequacy of reception facilities required by the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol at a port or terminal, and in establishing regulations under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary or the Administrator may consider, among other things, the number and types of ships or seagoing ships using the port or terminal, including their principal trades.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2025b9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Certificate; issuance; validity; inspection; review of suspension or revocation by Secretary</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025ba-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If reception facilities of a port or terminal meet the requirements of Annex I and Annex II to the Convention and the regulations prescribed under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, issue a certificate to that effect to the applicant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025bb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025bc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Subject to subparagraph (B), if reception facilities of a port or terminal meet the requirements of Annex V to the Convention and the regulations prescribed under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary may, after consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, issue a certificate to that effect to the person in charge of the port or terminal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025bd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary may not issue a certificate attesting to the adequacy of reception facilities under this paragraph unless, prior to the issuance of the certificate, the Secretary conducts an inspection of the reception facilities of the port or terminal that is the subject of the certificate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025be-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary may, with respect to certificates issued under this paragraph prior to <date date="1996-10-19">October 19, 1996</date>, prescribe by regulation differing periods of validity for such certificates.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025bf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A certificate issued under this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2025c0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> is valid for the 5-year period beginning on the date of issuance of the certificate, except that if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c2025c1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the charge for operation of the port or terminal is transferred to a person or entity other than the person or entity that is the operator on the date of issuance of the certificate—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6c2025c2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the certificate shall expire on the date that is 30 days after the date of the transfer; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6c2025c3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the new operator shall be required to submit an application for a certificate before a certificate may be issued for the port or terminal; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6c2025c4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the certificate is suspended or revoked by the Secretary, the certificate shall cease to be valid; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2025c5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall be available for inspection upon the request of the master, other person in charge, or agent of a ship using or intending to use the port or terminal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025c6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The suspension or revocation of a certificate issued under this subsection may be appealed to the Secretary and acted on by the Secretary in the manner prescribed by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2025c7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of list of certificated ports or terminals</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025c8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall maintain a list of ports or terminals with respect to which a certificate issued under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2025c9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is in effect; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2025ca-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has been revoked or suspended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025cb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall make the list referred to in paragraph (1) available to the general public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2025cc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Entry; denial</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025cd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except in the case of force majeure, the Secretary shall deny entry to a seagoing ship required by the Convention or the Antarctic Protocol to retain onboard while at sea, residues and mixtures containing oil or noxious liquid substances, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2025ce-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the port or terminal is one required by Annexes I and II of the Convention or Article 9 of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol or regulations hereunder to have adequate reception facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2025cf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the port or terminal does not hold a valid certificate issued by the Secretary under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025d0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may deny the entry of a ship to a port or terminal required by the MARPOL Protocol, this chapter, or regulations prescribed under this section relating to the provision of adequate reception facilities for garbage, ozone depleting substances, equipment containing those substances, or exhaust gas cleaning residues, if the port or terminal is not in compliance with the MARPOL Protocol, this chapter, or those regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2025d1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Surveys</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025d2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary and the Administrator are authorized to conduct surveys of existing reception facilities in the United States to determine measures needed to comply with the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2025d3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1905/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Not later than 18 months after <date date="1996-10-19">October 19, 1996</date>, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations that require the operator of each port or terminal that is subject to any requirement of the MARPOL Protocol relating to reception facilities to post a placard in a location that can easily be seen by port and terminal users. The placard shall state, at a minimum, that a user of a reception facility of the port or terminal should report to the Secretary any inadequacy of the reception facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c2025d4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/478/s6">Pub. L. 96–478, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2299">94 Stat. 2299</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/tII/s2103">Pub. L. 100–220, title II, § 2103</ref>, <date date="1987-12-29">Dec. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1461">101 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/225/tII/s201/1">Pub. L. 101–225, title II, § 201(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1910">103 Stat. 1910</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/tII/s201/d">Pub. L. 104–227, title II, § 201(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-02">Oct. 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3042">110 Stat. 3042</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 104–324, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3943">110 Stat. 3943</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s7">Pub. L. 110–280, § 7</ref>, <date date="2008-07-21">July 21, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2614">122 Stat. 2614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c2025d5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c2025d6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c2025d7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s7/1">Pub. L. 110–280, § 7(1)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s7/2">Pub. L. 110–280, § 7(2)</ref>, inserted “or the Administrator” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s7/3">Pub. L. 110–280, § 7(3)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary may deny the entry of a ship to a port or terminal required by regulations issued under this section to provide adequate reception facilities for garbage if the port or terminal is not in compliance with those regulations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s7/4">Pub. L. 110–280, § 7(4)</ref>, substituted “Secretary and the Administrator are” for “Secretary is”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s7/5">Pub. L. 110–280, § 7(5)</ref>, struck out subpar. (A) designation before “Not later”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/d/1">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “the MARPOL Protocol”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s801/a/1">Pub. L. 104–324, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, (2), designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), substituted “Subject to subparagraph (B), if” for “If”, and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s801/a/3">Pub. L. 104–324, § 801(a)(3)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “is valid until suspended or revoked by the Secretary for cause or because of changed conditions; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s801/a/4">Pub. L. 104–324, § 801(a)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “The Secretary shall periodically cause to be published in the Federal Register a list of the ports or terminals holding a valid certificate issued under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/d/2">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(d)(2)</ref>, (3), inserted “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “the Convention” in introductory provisions and inserted “or Article 9 of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol” after “the Convention” in subpar. (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s801/b">Pub. L. 104–324, § 801(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2)(A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/d/4">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(d)(4)</ref>, inserted “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “the MARPOL Protocol”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/225">Pub. L. 101–225</ref> substituted “Annex I and Annex II” for “Annex V”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2103/a">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2103(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “a port’s or terminal’s reception facilities for mixtures containing oil or noxious liquid substances” for “reception facilities of a port or terminal”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2103/b">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2103(b)</ref>, inserted “and in establishing regulations under subsection (a) of this section,” and “ships or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2103/c">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2103(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “If, upon inspection, reception facilities of a port or terminal are adequate to meet the requirements of the MARPOL Protocol and the regulations established hereunder, the Secretary shall, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, issue a certificate to that effect to the applicant. A certificate issued under this subsection—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) is valid until suspended or revoked by the Secretary for cause or because of changed conditions; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) shall be available for inspection upon the request of the master, other person in charge, or agent of a seagoing ship using or intending to use the port or terminal.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The suspension or revocation of a certificate issued under this subsection may be appealed to the Secretary and acted on by him in the manner prescribed by regulation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2103/d">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2103(d)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, in subpar. (A), substituted “Annexes I and II of the Convention” for “the MARPOL Protocol”, and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c2295d8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6c2295d9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/220">Pub. L. 100–220</ref> effective <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, the date on which Annex V to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships, 1973, entered into force for the United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2002/a">section 2002(a) of Pub. L. 100–220</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id6c2295da-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a), (c), and (f) of this section effective <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/478/s14/b">section 14(b) of Pub. L. 96–478</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
