<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c2295e5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907"><num value="1907">§ 1907.</num><heading> Violations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295e6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General prohibition; cooperation and enforcement; detection and monitoring measures; reports; evidence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is unlawful to act in violation of the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, this chapter, or the regulations issued thereunder. The Secretary shall cooperate with other parties to the MARPOL Protocol or to the Antarctic Protocol in the detection of violations and in enforcement of the MARPOL Protocol and Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol. The Secretary shall use all appropriate and practical measures of detection and environmental monitoring, and shall establish adequate procedures for reporting violations and accumulating evidence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295e7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigations; subpenas: issuance by Secretary, enforcement; action by Secretary; information to party</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receipt of evidence that a violation has occurred, the Secretary shall cause the matter to be investigated. In any investigation under this section the Secretary may issue subpenas to require the attendance of any witness and the production of documents and other evidence. In case of refusal to obey a subpena issued to any person, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to invoke the aid of the appropriate district court of the United States to compel compliance. Upon completion of the investigation, the Secretary shall take the action required by the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol and whatever further action he considers appropriate under the circumstances. If the initial evidence was provided by a party to the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol, the Secretary, acting through the Secretary of State, shall inform that party of the action taken or proposed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295e8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Ship inspections; reports to Secretary; additional action</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295e9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> This subsection applies to inspections relating to possible violations of Annex I or Annex II to the Convention, of Article 3 or Article 4 of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, or of this chapter by any seagoing ship referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1902/a/2">section 1902(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295ea-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> While at a port or terminal subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, a ship to which the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol applies may be inspected by the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2295eb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to verify whether or not the ship has discharged a harmful substance in violation of the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, or this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c2295ec-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to comply with a request from a party to the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol for an investigation as to whether the ship may have discharged a harmful substance anywhere in violation of the MARPOL Protocol or Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol. An investigation may be undertaken under this clause only when the requesting party has furnished sufficient evidence to allow the Secretary reasonably to believe that a discharge has occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If an inspection under this subsection indicates that a violation has occurred, the investigating officer shall forward a report to the Secretary for appropriate action. The Secretary shall undertake to notify the master of the ship concerned and, acting in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall take any additional action required by Article 6 of the Convention.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295ed-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Garbage disposal inspections; covered ships; enforcement actions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295ee-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may inspect a ship referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1902/a/3">section 1902(a)(3) of this title</ref> to verify whether the ship has disposed of garbage in violation of Annex V to the Convention, Article 5 of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, or this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295ef-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an inspection under this subsection indicates that a violation has occurred, the Secretary may undertake enforcement action under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1908">section 1908 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295f0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Harmful substance or garbage disposal inspections; covered ships; enforcement actions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295f1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may inspect at any time a ship of United States registry or nationality or operating under the authority of the United States to which the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol applies to verify whether the ship has discharged a harmful substance or disposed of garbage in violation of those Protocols or this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295f2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an inspection under this subsection indicates that a violation of the MARPOL Protocol, of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, or of this chapter has occurred the Secretary may undertake enforcement action under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1908">section 1908 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295f3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspections; enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295f4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may inspect a ship to which this chapter applies as provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1902/a/5">section 1902(a)(5) of this title</ref>, to verify whether the ship is in compliance with Annex VI to the Convention and this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295f5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an inspection under this subsection or any other information indicates that a violation has occurred, the Secretary, or the Administrator in a matter referred by the Secretary, may undertake enforcement action under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c2295f6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1907/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (b) and paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Administrator shall have all of the authorities of the Secretary, as specified in subsection (b) of this section, for the purposes of enforcing regulations 17 and 18 of Annex VI to the Convention to the extent that shoreside violations are the subject of the action and in any other matter referred to the Administrator by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c2295f7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/478/s8">Pub. L. 96–478, § 8</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2300">94 Stat. 2300</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/tII/s2104">Pub. L. 100–220, title II, § 2104</ref>, <date date="1987-12-29">Dec. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1462">101 Stat. 1462</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/225/tII/s201/2">Pub. L. 101–225, title II, § 201(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1910">103 Stat. 1910</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/tII/s201/e">Pub. L. 104–227, title II, § 201(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-02">Oct. 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3043">110 Stat. 3043</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s8">Pub. L. 110–280, § 8</ref>, <date date="2008-07-21">July 21, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2614">122 Stat. 2614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c2295f8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c2295f9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c2295fa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280">Pub. L. 110–280</ref> amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Remedies and requirements of this chapter supplement and neither amend nor repeal any other provisions of law, except as expressly provided in this chapter. Nothing in this chapter shall limit, deny, amend, modify, or repeal any other remedy available to the United States or any other person, except as expressly provided in this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/e/1">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(e)(1)</ref>, (2), inserted “Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “violation of the MARPOL Protocol,”, “or to the Antarctic Protocol” after “to the MARPOL Protocol”, and “and Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol” after “enforcement of the MARPOL Protocol”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/e/3">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(e)(3)</ref>, inserted “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “MARPOL Protocol” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/e/4">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(e)(4)</ref>, inserted “, of Article 3 or Article 4 of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “to the Convention”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/e/5">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(e)(5)</ref>, (6), inserted “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “which the MARPOL Protocol” in introductory provisions, “, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “MARPOL Protocol” in subpar. (A), and “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “to the MARPOL Protocol” and “or Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol” after “of the MARPOL Protocol” in subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/e/8">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(e)(8)</ref>, inserted “, Article 5 of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “Convention”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/e/9">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(e)(9)</ref>, inserted “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “MARPOL Protocol” and substituted “those Protocols” for “that Protocol”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/e/10">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(e)(10)</ref>, inserted “, of Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “MARPOL Protocol”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsecs. (c)(1), (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/225">Pub. L. 101–225</ref> inserted “or of this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2104/a">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2104(a)</ref>, added par. (1), designated existing provisions as par. (2), redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, and in closing provisions of par. (2) substituted “The” for “If a report made under this subsection involves a ship, other than one of United States registry or nationality or one operated under the authority of the United States, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2104/b">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2104(b)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c2295fb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6c2295fc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/220">Pub. L. 100–220</ref> effective <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, the date on which Annex V to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships, 1973, entered into force for the United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2002/a">section 2002(a) of Pub. L. 100–220</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
