<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c2295fd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908"><num value="1908">§ 1908.</num><heading> Penalties for violations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295fe-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties; payment for information leading to conviction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person who knowingly violates the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, this chapter, or the regulations issued thereunder commits a class D felony. In the discretion of the Court, an amount equal to not more than ½ of such fine may be paid to the person giving information leading to conviction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c2295ff-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalties; separate violations; assessment notice; considerations affecting amount; payment for information leading to assessment of penalty</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person who is found by the Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, to have—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c229600-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> violated the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, this chapter, or the regulations issued thereunder shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty, not to exceed $25,000 for each violation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c229601-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> made a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation in any matter in which a statement or representation is required to be made to the Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter, under the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, this chapter, or the regulations thereunder, shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty, not to exceed $5,000 for each statement or representation.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each day of a continuing violation shall constitute a separate violation. The amount of the civil penalty shall be assessed by the Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter or his designee, by written notice. In determining the amount of the penalty, the Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter, shall take into account the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the prohibited acts committed and, with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior offenses, ability to pay, and other matters as justice may require. An amount equal to not more than ½ of such penalties may be paid by the Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter, to the person giving information leading to the assessment of such penalties.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c229602-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Abatement of civil penalties; collection by Attorney General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter, may compromise, modify, or remit, with or without conditions, any civil penalty which is subject to assessment or which has been assessed under this section. If any person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty after it has become final, the Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter, may refer the matter to the Attorney General of the United States for collection in any appropriate district court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c229603-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability in rem; district court jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A ship operated in violation of the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, this chapter, or the regulations thereunder is liable in rem for any fine imposed under subsection (a) or civil penalty assessed pursuant to subsection (b), and may be proceeded against in the United States district court of any district in which the ship may be found.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c229604-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Ship clearance or permits; refusal or revocation; bond or other surety</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any ship subject to the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, or this chapter, its owner, operator, or person in charge is liable for a fine or civil penalty under this section, or if reasonable cause exists to believe that the ship, its owner, operator, or person in charge may be subject to a fine or civil penalty under this section, the Secretary of the Treasury, upon the request of the Secretary, shall refuse or revoke the clearance required by <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s60105">section 60105 of title 46</ref>. Clearance may be granted upon the filing of a bond or other surety satisfactory to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c229605-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Referrals for appropriate action by foreign country</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a), (b), or (d) of this section, if the violation is by a ship registered in or of the nationality of a country party to the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol, or one operated under the authority of a country party to the MARPOL Protocol or the Antarctic Protocol, the Secretary, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter acting in coordination with the Secretary of State, may refer the matter to the government of the country of the ship’s registry or nationality, or under whose authority the ship is operating for appropriate action, rather than taking the actions required or authorized by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c229606-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1908/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposits in Abandoned Seafarers Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any penalty collected under subsection (a) or (b) that is not paid under that subsection to the person giving information leading to the conviction or assessment of such penalties shall be deposited in the Abandoned Seafarers Fund established under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s11113">section 11113 of title 46</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c229607-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/478/s9">Pub. L. 96–478, § 9</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2301">94 Stat. 2301</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/tII/s2105">Pub. L. 100–220, title II, § 2105</ref>, <date date="1987-12-29">Dec. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1463">101 Stat. 1463</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/tIV/s4302/n">Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4302(n)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/539">104 Stat. 539</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/tVI/s688">Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 688</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2222">107 Stat. 2222</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/tII/s201/f">Pub. L. 104–227, title II, § 201(f)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-02">Oct. 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3043">110 Stat. 3043</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s10">Pub. L. 110–280, § 10</ref>, <date date="2008-07-21">July 21, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2615">122 Stat. 2615</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/281/tIII/s320/c">Pub. L. 113–281, title III, § 320(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3054">128 Stat. 3054</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c229608-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c229609-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6c22960a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (e), “<ref href="/us/usc/t46/s60105">section 60105 of title 46</ref>” substituted for “section 4197 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (46 U.S.C. App. 91)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/109/304/s18/c">Pub. L. 109–304, § 18(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1709">120 Stat. 1709</ref>, which Act enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s60105">section 60105 of Title 46</ref>, Shipping.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c22960b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/113/281">Pub. L. 113–281</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s10/1">Pub. L. 110–280, § 10(1)</ref>, substituted “MARPOL Protocol,” for “MARPOL Protocol,,” wherever appearing in subsecs. (a), (b), and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s10/2/C">Pub. L. 110–280, § 10(2)(C)</ref>, in concluding provisions, inserted “or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter” after “Secretary,” and “, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter,” after “Secretary” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s10/2/A">Pub. L. 110–280, § 10(2)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted “or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter,” after “Secretary,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s10/2/B">Pub. L. 110–280, § 10(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter,” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s10/3">Pub. L. 110–280, § 10(3)</ref>, inserted “, or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter,” after “Secretary” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/280/s10/4">Pub. L. 110–280, § 10(4)</ref>, inserted “or the Administrator as provided for in this chapter” after “Secretary,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/f/1">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(f)(1)</ref>, inserted “, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “MARPOL Protocol,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/f/2">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(f)(2)</ref>, (3), inserted “, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “MARPOL Protocol,” in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/f/4">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(f)(4)</ref>, inserted “, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “MARPOL Protocol,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/f/5">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(f)(5)</ref>, inserted “, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol,” after “MARPOL Protocol”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/227/s201/f/6">Pub. L. 104–227, § 201(f)(6)</ref>, inserted “or the Antarctic Protocol” after “MARPOL Protocol” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182">Pub. L. 103–182</ref> substituted “shall refuse or revoke the clearance required by <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s91">section 91 of title 46</ref>, Appendix. Clearance may be granted upon the filing of a bond or other surety satisfactory to the Secretary.” for “shall refuse or revoke—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the clearance required by <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s91">section 91 of title 46</ref>, Appendix; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) a permit to proceed under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s313">section 313 of title 46</ref>, Appendix, or <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1443">section 1443 of title 19</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Clearance or a permit to proceed may be granted upon the filing of a bond or other surety satisfactory to the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/380">Pub. L. 101–380</ref> substituted “commits a class D felony” for “shall, for each violation, be fined not more than $50,000 or be imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2105/a/1">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2105(a)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “In the discretion of the Court, an amount equal to not more than ½ of such fine may be paid to the person giving information leading to conviction.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2105/a/2">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2105(a)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “An amount equal to not more than ½ of such penalties may be paid by the Secretary to the person giving information leading to the assessment of such penalties.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2105/b">Pub. L. 100–220, § 2105(b)</ref>, substituted “to the government of the country of the ship’s registry or nationality, or under whose authority the ship is operating” for “to that country”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c22960c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6c22960d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/380">Pub. L. 101–380</ref> applicable to incidents occurring after <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/s1020">section 1020 of Pub. L. 101–380</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2701">section 2701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6c22960e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/220">Pub. L. 100–220</ref> effective <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, the date on which Annex V to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships, 1973, entered into force for the United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/220/s2002/a">section 2002(a) of Pub. L. 100–220</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
