<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c24e072-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1953"><num value="1953">§ 1953.</num><heading> Coast Guard program</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commandant of the Coast Guard, in consultation with the Interagency Committee, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c24e073-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1953/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> take actions to reduce violations of and improve implementation of MARPOL Annex V and the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1901">33 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq.) with respect to the discard of plastics and other garbage from vessels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c24e074-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1953/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> take actions to cost-effectively monitor and enforce compliance with MARPOL Annex V and the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1901">33 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq.), including through cooperation and coordination with other Federal and State enforcement programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c24e075-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1953/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> take actions to improve compliance with requirements under MARPOL Annex V and section 6 of the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1905">33 U.S.C. 1905</ref>) that all United States ports and terminals maintain and monitor the adequacy of receptacles for the disposal of plastics and other garbage, including through promoting voluntary government-industry partnerships;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c24e076-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1953/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> develop and implement a plan, in coordination with industry and recreational boaters, to improve ship-board waste management, including recordkeeping, and access to waste reception facilities for ship-board waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c24e077-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1953/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> take actions to improve international cooperation to reduce marine debris; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c24e078-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s1953/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> establish a voluntary reporting program for commercial vessel operators and recreational boaters to report incidents of damage to vessels and disruption of navigation caused by marine debris, and observed violations of laws and regulations relating to the disposal of plastics and other marine debris.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id6c24e079-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/449/s102">Pub. L. 109–449, § 102</ref>, formerly § 4, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3335">120 Stat. 3335</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/213/tVI/s605">Pub. L. 112–213, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1578">126 Stat. 1578</ref>; renumbered § 102, <ref href="/us/pl/119/65">Pub. L. 119–65</ref>, §§ 2(a)(2), 6(a), <date date="2025-12-26">Dec. 26, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1986">139 Stat. 1986</ref>, 1990.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c24e07a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c24e07b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6c24e07c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships, referred to in pars. (1) and (2), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/478">Pub. L. 96–478</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2297">94 Stat. 2297</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 33 (§ 1901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6c24e07d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—<ref href="/us/pl/119/65/s6/a">Pub. L. 119–65, § 6(a)</ref>, which directed amendment of this section by substituting “Under Secretary” for “Administrator”, could not be executed because the word “Administrator” did not appear.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/213">Pub. L. 112–213</ref> struck out subsec. (a) designation and heading “Strategy” and struck out subsecs. (b) and (c) which required reports on the Coast Guard’s progress in implementing former subsec. (a) and on the effectiveness of international and national measures to prevent and reduce marine debris and its impact.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
