<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c29c23c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2103"><num value="2103">§ 2103.</num><heading> National artificial reef plan</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="1984-11-08">November 8, 1984</date>, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the Regional Fishery Managment <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002096">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002096"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Management”.</note> Councils, interested States, Interstate Fishery Commissions, and representatives of the private sector, shall develop and publish a long-term plan which will meet the purpose of this chapter and be consistent with the standards established under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2102">section 2102 of this title</ref>. The plan must include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c23d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2103/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> geographic, hydrographic, geologic, biological, ecological, social, economic, and other criteria for siting artificial reefs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c23e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2103/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> design, material, and other criteria for constructing artificial reefs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c23f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2103/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> mechanisms and methodologies for monitoring the compliance of artificial reefs with the requirements of permits issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2104">section 2104 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c240-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2103/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> mechanisms and methodologies for managing the use of artificial reefs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c241-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2103/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a synopsis of existing information on artificial reefs and needs for further research on artificial reef technology and management strategies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c242-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2103/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> an evaluation of alternatives for facilitating the transfer of artificial reef construction materials to persons holding permits issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2104">section 2104 of this title</ref>, including, but not limited to, credits for environmental mitigation and modified tax obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id6c29c243-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/623/tII/s204">Pub. L. 98–623, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3395">98 Stat. 3395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c29c244-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6c29c245-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6c29c246-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
