<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c29c247-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104"><num value="2104">§ 2104.</num><heading> Permits for construction and management of artificial reefs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c29c248-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial action on permits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In issuing a permit for artificial reefs under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s403">section 403 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref>, or <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1333/e">section 1333(e) of title 43</ref>, the Secretary of the Army (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c249-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consult with and consider the views of appropriate Federal agencies, States, local governments, and other interested parties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c24a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensure that the provisions for siting, constructing, monitoring, and managing the artificial reef are consistent with the criteria and standards established under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c24b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> ensure that the title to the artificial reef construction material is unambiguous, and that responsibility for maintenance and the financial ability to assume liability for future damages are clearly established; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c29c24c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> consider the plan developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2103">section 2103 of this title</ref> and notify the Secretary of Commerce of any need to deviate from that plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c29c24d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions of permits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c29c24e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each permit issued by the Secretary subject to this section shall specify the design and location for construction of the artificial reef and the types and quantities of materials that may be used in constructing such artificial reef. In addition, each such permit shall specify such terms and conditions for the construction, operation, maintenance, monitoring, and managing the use of the artificial reef as are necessary for compliance with all applicable provisions of law and as are necessary to ensure the protection of the environment and human safety and property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c29c24f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Before issuing a permit under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342">section 1342 of this title</ref> for any activity relating to the siting, design, construction, operation, maintenance, monitoring, or managing of an artificial reef, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall consult with the Secretary to ensure that such permit is consistent with any permit issued by the Secretary subject to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c29c250-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability of permittee</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c29c251-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A person to whom a permit is issued in accordance with subsection (a) and any insurer of that person shall not be liable for damages caused by activities required to be undertaken under any terms and conditions of the permit, if the permittee is in compliance with such terms and conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c29c252-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A person to whom a permit is issued in accordance with subsection (a) and any insurer of that person shall be liable, to the extent determined under applicable law, for damages to which paragraph (1) does not apply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c29c253-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may not issue a permit subject to this section to a person unless that person demonstrates to the Secretary the financial ability to assume liability for all damages that may arise with respect to an artificial reef and for which such permittee may be liable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6c29c254-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any person who has transferred title to artificial reef construction materials to a person to whom a permit is issued in accordance with subsection (a) shall not be liable for damages arising from the use of such materials in an artificial reef, if such materials meet applicable requirements of the plan published under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2103">section 2103 of this title</ref> and are not otherwise defective at the time title is transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c29c255-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability of the United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter creates any liability on the part of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c29c256-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2104/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, is found to have violated any provision of a permit issued in accordance with subsection (a) shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty, not to exceed $10,000 for each violation. The amount of the civil penalty shall be assessed by the Secretary by written notice. In determining the amount of such penalty, the Secretary shall take into account the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation. The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit with or without conditions, any civil penalty which is subject to imposition or which has been imposed under this section. If any person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty after it has become final, the Secretary may refer the matter to the Attorney General for collection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c29c257-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/623/tII/s205">Pub. L. 98–623, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3396">98 Stat. 3396</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
