<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c4d76d7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s2293a"><num value="2293a">§ 2293a.</num><heading> Reprogramming of funds for projects by Corps of Engineers</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">None of the funds made available before, on, or after <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, in an appropriations Act may be expended to prevent or limit any reprogramming of funds for a project to be carried out by the Corps of Engineers using funds appropriated in any Act making appropriations for energy and water development, based on whether the project was included by the President in the budget transmitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> or is otherwise proposed by the President or considered part of the budget by the Office of Management and Budget, if the project received funds in an Act making appropriations for energy and water development or any other appropriations Act making additional funds available for energy and water development.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6c4d76d8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/234/tII/s2307">Pub. L. 109–234, title II, § 2307</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/457">120 Stat. 457</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6c4d76d9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6c4d76da-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6c4d76db-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006, and not as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
