<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6c929643-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914"><num value="3914">§ 3914.</num><heading> Requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c929644-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), none of the amounts made available under this chapter may be used for the construction, alteration, maintenance, or repair of a project eligible for assistance under this chapter unless all of the iron and steel products used in the project are produced in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c929645-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of iron and steel products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “iron and steel products” means the following products made primarily of iron or steel: lined or unlined pipes and fittings, manhole covers and other municipal castings, hydrants, tanks, flanges, pipe clamps and restraints, valves, structural steel, reinforced precast concrete, and construction materials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c929646-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply in any case or category of cases in which the Administrator finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c929647-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> applying subsection (a) would be inconsistent with the public interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c929648-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> iron and steel products are not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities and of a satisfactory quality; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6c929649-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> inclusion of iron and steel products produced in the United States will increase the cost of the overall project by more than 25 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c92964a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Administrator receives a request for a waiver under this section, the Administrator shall make available to the public, on an informal basis, a copy of the request and information available to the Administrator concerning the request, and shall allow for informal public input on the request for at least 15 days prior to making a finding based on the request. The Administrator shall make the request and accompanying information available by electronic means, including on the official public Internet Web site of the Environmental Protection Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6c92964b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s3914/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> International agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall be applied in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6c92964c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tV/s5035">Pub. L. 113–121, title V, § 5035</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1344">128 Stat. 1344</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
