<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b38d249-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s494a"><num value="494a">§ 494a.</num><heading> Study of bridges over navigable waters</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a comprehensive study on the construction or alteration of any bridge, drawbridge, or causeway over the navigable waters of the United States with a channel depth of 25 feet or greater that may impede or obstruct future navigation to or from port facilities and for which a permit under the Act of <date date="1906-03-23">March 23, 1906</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s491">33 U.S.C. 491</ref> et seq.), popularly known as the Bridge Act of 1906, was requested during the period beginning on <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>, and ending on <date date="2011-08-03">August 3, 2011</date>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b38d24a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tIX/s905">Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3012">124 Stat. 3012</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/213/tVII/s702/a">Pub. L. 112–213, title VII, § 702(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1580">126 Stat. 1580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b38d24b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b38d24c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6b38d24d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1906-03-23">March 23, 1906</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s491">33 U.S.C. 491</ref> et seq.), popularly known as the Bridge Act of 1906, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1906-03-23/ch1130">act Mar. 23, 1906, ch. 1130</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/84">34 Stat. 84</ref>, which enacted sections 491 to 494 and 495 to 498 of this title. For complete classification of this Act of the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s491">section 491 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b38d24e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/213">Pub. L. 112–213</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a comprehensive study on the proposed construction or alteration of any bridge, drawbridge, or causeway over navigable waters with a channel depth of 25 feet or greater of the United States that may impede or obstruct future navigation to or from port facilities.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
