<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b3b43d8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s516"><num value="516">§ 516.</num><heading> Apportionment of cost</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the time the Secretary shall authorize the bridge owner to proceed with the project, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s515">section 515 of this title</ref>, and after an opportunity to the bridge owner to be heard thereon, the Secretary shall determine and issue an order specifying the proportionate shares of the total cost of the project to be borne by the United States and by the bridge owner. Such apportionment shall be made on the following basis: The bridge owner shall bear such part of the cost as is attributable to the direct and special benefits which will accrue to the bridge owner as a result of the alteration, including the expectable savings in repair or maintenance costs; and that part of the cost attributable to the requirements of traffic by railroad or highway, or both, including any expenditure for increased carrying capacity of the bridge, and including such proportion of the actual capital cost of the old bridge or of such part of the old bridge as may be altered or changed or rebuilt, as the used service life of the whole or a part, as the case may be, bears to the total estimated service life of the whole or such part: <i>Provided</i>, That in the event the alteration or relocation of any bridge may be desirable for the reason that the bridge unreasonably obstructs navigation, but also for some other reason, the Secretary may require equitable contribution from any interested person, firm, association, corporation, municipality, county, or State desiring such alteration or relocation for such other reason, as a condition precedent to the making of an order for such alteration or relocation. The United States shall bear the balance of the cost, including that part attributable to the necessities of navigation: <i>And provided further</i>, That where the bridge owner proceeds with the alteration on a successive partial bid basis the Secretary is authorized to issue an order of apportionment of cost for the entire alteration based on the accepted bid for the first part of the alteration and an estimate of cost for the remainder of the work. The Secretary is authorized to revise the order of apportionment of cost, to the extent he deems reasonable and proper, to meet any changed conditions.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b3b43d9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-06-21/ch409/s6">June 21, 1940, ch. 409, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/499">54 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-16/ch889/s2">July 16, 1952, ch. 889, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/733">66 Stat. 733</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/640/s1/c">Pub. L. 85–640, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-14">Aug. 14, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/595">72 Stat. 595</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b3b43da-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b3b43db-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b3b43dc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/640">Pub. L. 85–640</ref> permitted issuance of an order of apportionment of cost for entire alteration based on the accepted bid for first part of alteration and an estimate of cost for remainder of work where bridge owner proceeds with alteration on a successive partial bid basis.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1952—Act <date date="1952-07-16">July 16, 1952</date>, made railroads share equally with proprietors of highways in bearing cost of alterations necessary to remove obstacles to navigation.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
