<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b3ffed1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s546"><num value="546">§ 546.</num><heading> Investigation of stream flow and watersheds; surveys in connection with dams</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The surveys of navigable streams shall include such stream-flow measurements and other investigations of the watersheds as may be necessary for preparation of plans of improvement and a proper consideration of all uses of the stream affecting navigation, and whenever necessary similar investigations may be made in connection with all navigable streams under improvement. Whenever permission for the construction of dams in navigable streams is granted, or is under consideration by Congress, such surveys and investigations of the sections of the streams affected may be made as are necessary to secure conformity with rational plans for the improvement of the streams for navigation.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b3ffed2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1910-06-25/ch382/s3">June 25, 1910, ch. 382, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/669">36 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b3ffed3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b3ffed4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b3ffed5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from section 3 of act <date date="1910-06-25">June 25, 1910</date>, popularly known as the “Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1910”. Other provisions of such section were omitted, as superseded by <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s545">section 545 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id6b3ffed6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">General provisions regulating the construction of dams were made by the Dam <ref href="/us/act/1906-06-21/ch3508">Act of June 21, 1906, ch. 3508</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/386">34 Stat. 386</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1910-06-23/ch360">act June 23, 1910, ch. 360</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/593">36 Stat. 593</ref>, apparently omitted from the Code as superseded.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
