<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b44b9eb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576"><num value="576">§ 576.</num><heading> Revolving fund; establishment; availability; reimbursement; transfer of funds; limitation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9ec-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Revolving fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For establishment of a revolving fund, to be available without fiscal year limitation, for expenses necessary for the maintenance and operation of the plant and equipment of the Corps of Engineers used in civil works functions, including acquisition of plant and equipment, maintenance, repair, and purchase, operation, and maintenance of not to exceed four aircraft at any one time, temporary financing of services finally chargeable to appropriations for civil works functions, and the furnishing of facilities and services for military functions of the Department of the Army and other Government agencies and private persons, as authorized by law. In addition, the Secretary of the Army is authorized to provide capital for the fund by capitalizing the present inventories, plant and equipment of the civil works functions of the Corps of Engineers. The fund shall be credited with reimbursements or advances for the cost of equipment, facilities, and services furnished, at rates which shall include charges for overhead and related expenses, depreciation of plant and equipment, and accrued leave: <i>Provided</i>, That on <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>, (1) the fund shall assume the assets, liabilities, and obligations of the Plant accounts, as carried on the records of the Corps of Engineers as of <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, under the appropriations for “Maintenance and improvement of existing river and harbor works”, “Flood control, general”, and “Flood control, Mississippi River and tributaries”, and (2) there shall be transferred from said appropriations to the fund amounts equivalent to the unexpended cash balances of the Plant accounts on <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>: <i>Provided further</i>, That the total capital of said fund shall not exceed $140,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9ed-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9ee-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No funds may be expended or obligated from the revolving fund described in subsection (a) to newly construct, or perform a major renovation on, a building for use by the Corps of Engineers unless specifically authorized by law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9ef-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Statutory construction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b44b9f0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> change any authority provided under subchapter I of chapter 169 of title 10; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002021"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b44b9f1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> change the use of funds under subsection (a) for purposes other than those described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9f2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmission to Congress of prospectus</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To secure consideration for an authorization under subsection (b), the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representative and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a prospectus of the proposed construction or major renovation of a building that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9f3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a brief description of the building;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9f4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the location of the building;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9f5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an estimate of the maximum cost to be provided by the revolving fund for the building to be constructed or renovated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9f6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the total size of the building after the proposed construction or major renovation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9f7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the number of personnel proposed to be housed in the building after the construction or major renovation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9f8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a statement that other suitable space owned by the Federal Government is not available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9f9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> a statement of rents and other housing costs currently being paid for the tenants proposed to be housed in the building; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b44b9fa-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the size of the building currently housing the tenants proposed to be housed in the building.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9fb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of building project surveys</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9fc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If requested by resolution by the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate or the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Secretary shall create a building project survey for the construction or major renovation of a building described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9fd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within a reasonable time after creating a building project survey under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the survey that includes the information required to be included in a prospectus under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b44b9fe-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s576/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Major renovation defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “major renovation” means a renovation or alteration of a building for use by the Corps of Engineers with a total expenditure of more than $20,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b44b9ff-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1953-07-27/ch245/s101">July 27, 1953, ch. 245, § 101</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/199">67 Stat. 199</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/tI/s1160">Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1160</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1667">130 Stat. 1667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b44ba00-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b44ba01-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6b44ba02-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter I of chapter 169 of title 10, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(A), probably means subchapter I (§ 2801 et seq.) of chapter 169 of Title 10, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b44ba03-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s190b">section 190b of Title 10</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 10, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041/s1">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/1">70A Stat. 1</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b44ba04-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—<ref href="/us/pl/114/322">Pub. L. 114–322</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsecs. (b) to (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b44ba05-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b44ba06-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Headquarters Aircraft; Transfer and Reassignment of Property Accountability to Army Military Activity</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/101/tI/s105">Pub. L. 101–101, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1989-09-29">Sept. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/649">103 Stat. 649</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/101/tI/s105">“Notwithstanding section 110 of the Energy and Water Development Appropriation Act, 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Public Law 100–202</ref> [set out below], the Secretary of the Army is authorized to transfer and re­assign property accountability for the headquarters aircraft of the Corps of Engineers, Serial Number 045, from the assets of the civil works revolving fund, to the military activity of the Army that the Secretary determines is appropriate, except that the aircraft shall be made available on a priority basis as necessary for activities in support of the Army’s civil works mission.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b472a07-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Retention of Three Operational Aircraft; Notice of Intended Use Outside United States</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/d/tI/s110">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(d) [title I, § 110]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-104">101 Stat. 1329–104</ref>, 1329–112, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/202/s101/d/tI/s110">“The Chief of Engineers is directed to retain three operational aircraft authorized pursuant to <ref href="/us/act/1953-07-27/s101">section 101 of the Act of July 27, 1953</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/199">67 Stat. 199</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s576">33 U.S.C. 576</ref>], together with their attendant crews, and may only dispose of any of these aircraft if authorized to do so by a future congressional enactment for that purpose. The Chief of Engineers shall provide at least thirty days advance written notification to the Appropriations Committees of the Senate and House of Representatives of any intended use of any of these aircraft for a trip destined outside the United States or its territories or possessions.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
