<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b151d46-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh"><num value="59hh">§ 59hh.</num><heading> Declaration of nonnavigability for portion of Pelican Island, Texas</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d47-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army is authorized to convey to the City <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002002"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> of Galveston, Texas, fee simple absolute title to all or any part of a parcel of land containing approximately 605 acres known as the San Jacinto Disposal Area located on the east end of Galveston Island, Texas, in the W.A.A. Wallace Survey, A–647 and A–648, City <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> of Galveston, Galveston County, Texas, being part of the old Fort San Jacinto site, at the fair market value of such parcel to be determined in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d). Such conveyance shall only be made by the Secretary of the Army upon the agreement of the Secretary and the City <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">1</ref> as to all compensation due herein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d48-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation for conveyance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d49-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receipt of compensation from the city of Galveston, the Secretary shall convey the parcel, or any part of the parcel, as described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d4a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Full parcel</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the full 605-acre parcel is conveyed, the compensation shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b151d4b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conveyance to the Department of the Army of fee simple absolute title to a parcel of land containing approximately 564 acres on Pelican Island, Texas, in the Eneas Smith Survey, A–190, Pelican Island, city of Galveston, Galveston County, Texas, adjacent to property currently owned by the United States, with the fair market value of the parcel being determined in accordance with subsection (d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b151d4c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> payment to the United States of an amount equal to the difference between the fair market value of the parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a) and the fair market value of the parcel to be conveyed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d4d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Partial parcel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the conveyance is 125 acres or less, compensation shall be an amount equal to the fair market value of the parcel to be conveyed, with the fair market value of the parcel being determined in accordance with subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d4e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Disposition of spoil</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Costs of maintaining the Galveston Harbor and Channel will continue to be governed by the Local Cooperation Agreement (LCA) between the United States of America and the City <sup>1</sup> of Galveston dated <date date="1973-10-18">October 18, 1973</date>, as amended. Upon conveyance of the parcel, or any part of the parcel, described in subsection (a), the Department of the Army shall be compensated directly for the present value of the total costs to the Department for disposal of dredge material and site preparation pursuant to the LCA, if any,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002003"><num>2</num> So in original.</note> in excess of the present value of the total costs that would have been incurred if this conveyance had not been made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d4f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of fair market value</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The fair market value of the land to be conveyed pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) shall be determined by independent appraisers using the market value method.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d50-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Navigational servitude</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d51-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Declaration of nonnavigability; public interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Unless the Secretary finds, after consultation with local and regional public officials (including local and regional public planning organizations), that the proposed projects to be undertaken within the parcel described in subsection (a) are not in the public interest then, subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), such parcel is declared to be nonnavigable waters of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d52-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limits on applicability; regulatory requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The declaration under paragraph (1) shall apply only to those parts of the parcel described in subsection (a) which are or will be bulkheaded and filled or otherwise occupied by permanent structures, including marina facilities. All such work is subject to all applicable Federal statutes and regulations including, but not limited to, sections 401 and 403 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref>, and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d53-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Expiration date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, 20 years after <date date="1993-10-28">October 28, 1993</date>, any area or part thereof described in subsection (a) is not bulkheaded or filled or occupied by permanent structures, including marina facilities, in accordance with the requirements set out in paragraph (2), or if work in connection with any activity permitted in paragraph (2) is not commenced within 5 years after issuance of such permits, then the declaration of nonnavigability for such area or part thereof shall expire.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d54-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59hh/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Survey and study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The 605-acre parcel and the 564-acre parcel shall be surveyed and further legally described prior to conveyance. Not later than 60 days following <date date="1993-10-28">October 28, 1993</date>, if he deems it necessary, the Secretary of the Army shall complete a review of the applicability of <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref> to the said parcels.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b151d55-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/126/tI/s108">Pub. L. 103–126, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1993-10-28">Oct. 28, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1320">107 Stat. 1320</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/53/tV/s585">Pub. L. 106–53, title V, § 585</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/377">113 Stat. 377</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b151d56-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b151d57-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6b151d58-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (e)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b151d59-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/53/s585/1">Pub. L. 106–53, § 585(1)</ref>, inserted “all or any part of” after “absolute title to” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/53/s585/2">Pub. L. 106–53, § 585(2)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Upon receipt of compensation from the City of Galveston, the Secretary shall convey the parcel as described in subsection (a) of this section. Such compensation shall include—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) conveyance to the Department of the Army of fee simple absolute title to a parcel of land containing approximately 564 acres on Pelican Island, Texas, in the Eneas Smith Survey, A–190, Pelican Island, City of Galveston, Galveston County, Texas, adjacent to property currently owned by the United States. The fair market value of such parcel will be determined in accordance with the provision of subsection (d) of this section; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) payment to the United States of an amount equal to the difference of the fair market value of the parcel to be conveyed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section and the fair market value of the parcel to be conveyed pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/53/s585/3">Pub. L. 106–53, § 585(3)</ref>, in second sentence, inserted “, or any part of the parcel,” after “parcel” and “, if any,” after “LCA”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
