<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b151d5a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii"><num value="59ii">§ 59ii.</num><heading> Declaration of nonnavigability of a portion of the canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal in Richmond, Virginia</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d5b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Canal declared nonnavigable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The portion of the canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal in Richmond, Virginia, located between the Great Ship Lock on the east and the limits of the City of Richmond on the west is hereby declared to be a nonnavigable waterway of the United States for purposes of subtitle II of title 46.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d5c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Ensuring public safety</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation shall provide such technical advice, information, and assistance as the City of Richmond, Virginia, or its designee may request to insure that the vessels operating on the waters declared nonnavigable by subsection (a) are built, maintained, and operated in a manner consistent with protecting public safety.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d5d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of declaration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d5e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Transportation may terminate the effectiveness of the declaration made by subsection (a) by publishing a determination that vessels operating on the waters declared nonnavigable by subsection (a) have not been built, maintained, and operated in a manner consistent with protecting public safety.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b151d5f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Public input</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before making a determination under this subsection, the Secretary of Transportation shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b151d60-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> consult with appropriate State and local government officials regarding whether such a determination is necessary to protect public safety and will serve the public interest; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b151d61-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s59ii/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide to persons who might be adversely affected by the determination the opportunity for comment and a hearing on whether such action is necessary to protect public safety and will serve the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b151d62-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/32/s2">Pub. L. 106–32, § 2</ref>, <date date="1999-06-01">June 1, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/115">113 Stat. 115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b151d63-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b151d64-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b151d65-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/32/s1">Pub. L. 106–32, § 1</ref>, <date date="1999-06-01">June 1, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/115">113 Stat. 115</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/32/s1">
<inline>“The Congress finds the following:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal played an important part in the economic development of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the City of Richmond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The canal ceased to operate as a functioning waterway in the conduct of commerce in the late 1800s.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Portions of the canal have been found by a Federal district court to be nonnavigable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The restored portion of the canal will be utilized to provide entertainment and education to visitors and will play an important part in the economic development of downtown Richmond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The restored portion of the canal will not be utilized for general public boating, and will be restricted to activities similar to those conducted on similar waters in San Antonio, Texas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The continued classification of the canal as a navigable waterway based upon historic usage that ceased more than 100 years ago does not serve the public interest and is unnecessary to protect public safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Congressional action is required to clarify that the canal is no longer to be considered a navigable waterway for purposes of subtitle II of title 46, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
