<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b50a05d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s624"><num value="624">§ 624.</num><heading> Limitation on improvement work by private contract</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b50a05e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s624/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations respecting comparison of private contract price with estimation of cost of performance of work by Government plant or by well-equipped contractor</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No works of river and harbor improvement shall be done by private contract—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b50a05f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s624/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, determines that Government plant is reasonably available to perform the subject work and the contract price for doing the work is more than 25 per centum in excess of the estimated comparable cost of doing the work by Government plant; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b50a060-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s624/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in any other circumstance where the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, determines that the contract price is more than 25 per centum in excess of what he determines to be a fair and reasonable estimated cost of a well-equipped contractor doing the work.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b50a061-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s624/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations involved in determinations of estimation of cost of performance of work by Government plant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In estimating the comparable cost of doing the work under subsection (a)(1) by Government plant the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers shall, in addition to the cost of labor and materials, take into account proper charges for depreciation of plant, all supervising and overhead expenses, interest on the capital invested in the Government plant (but the rate of interest shall not exceed the maximum prevailing rate being paid by the United States on current issues of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness) and such other Government expenses and charges as the Chief of Engineers determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b50a062-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s624/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations involved in determinations of estimation of cost of performance of work by well-equipped contractor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining a fair and reasonable estimated cost of doing work by private contract under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall, in addition to the cost of labor and materials, take into account proper charges for depreciation of plant, all expenses for supervision, overhead, workmen’s compensation, general liability insurance, taxes (State and local), interest on capital invested in plant, and such other expenses and charges the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b50a063-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1919-03-02/ch95/s8">Mar. 2, 1919, ch. 95, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/1290">40 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/269/s2">Pub. L. 95–269, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-04-26">Apr. 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/219">92 Stat. 219</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b50a064-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b50a065-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b50a066-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1919.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b50a067-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/269">Pub. L. 95–269</ref> designated existing provision as subsec. (a), substituted provisions relating to determinations by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, respecting contract prices for performance of works of river and harbor improvement by a Government plant or by a well-equipped contractor as a limitation on performance of the work by private contract, for provisions relating to limitation on use of funds for works of river and harbor improvement pursuant to private contract based on estimation of cost for performance of work by Government plant and factors constituting cost estimation, and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b50a068-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b50a069-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Compensation for Increased Costs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provision for payment to contractors to compensate for loss occasioned by increased cost of materials during the war with Germany was made by section 10 of act <date date="1919-03-02">Mar. 2, 1919</date>, and <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-05/ch252/s5">act June 5, 1920, ch. 252, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1014">41 Stat. 1014</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b50a06a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeal of Limitation on Costs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A provision for limitation on the costs of projects made by section 1 of act <date date="1919-03-02">Mar. 2, 1919</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-05/ch252/s3">act June 5, 1920, ch. 252, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1013">41 Stat. 1013</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
