<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b50a076-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s627"><num value="627">§ 627.</num><heading> Application of appropriation when separate works are included therein</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where separate works or items are consolidated in River and Harbor Acts and an aggregate amount is appropriated therefor, any balances remaining to the credit of the separate works or items may be transferred to the credit of the corresponding aggregate amounts appropriated for the consolidated items, and the amounts appropriated or transferred shall, unless otherwise expressed, be expended in securing maintenance and improvement according to the respective projects adopted by Congress, after giving due regard to the respective needs of traffic. The allotments to the respective works consolidated shall be made by the Secretary of the Army upon recommendations by the Chief of Engineers. In case such works or items are consolidated and separate amounts are given with each project, the amounts so named shall be expended upon such separate projects unless, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Army, another allotment or division should be made of the same. Any balances remaining to the credit of the consolidated items shall be carried to the credit of the respective aggregate amounts appropriated for the consolidated items.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b50a077-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1915-03-04/ch142/s3">Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 142, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/1052">38 Stat. 1052</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b50a078-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b50a079-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b50a07a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1915.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id6b50a07b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p>Section 3 of act <date date="1915-03-04">Mar. 4, 1915</date>, superseded <ref href="/us/act/1913-03-04/ch144/s7">act Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 144, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/827">37 Stat. 827</ref>, which read as follows:<quotedContent>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Where separate works or items are consolidated in this or subsequent river and harbor Acts and an aggregate amount is appropriated therefor the amounts appropriated shall, unless otherwise expressed, be expended in securing maintenance and improvement according to the respective projects adopted by Congress, after giving due regard to the respective needs of traffic. The allotments to the respective works consolidated shall be made by the Secretary of War upon recommendations by the Chief of Engineers. In case such works or items are consolidated and separate amounts are given with each project, the amounts so named shall be expended upon such separate projects unless, in the discretion of the Secretary of War, another allotment or division should be made of the same. Any balances remaining to the credit of the consolidated items shall be carried to the credit of the respective aggregate amounts appropriated for the consolidated items.”</p>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b50a07c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id6b50a07d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Section 205(a) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. Section 1 of act <date date="1956-08-10">Aug. 10, 1956</date>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="similarProvisions" id="id6b50a07e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Similar Provisions</heading><p>The Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act, <ref href="/us/act/1919-03-02/ch95/s2">Mar. 2, 1919, ch. 95, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/1287">40 Stat. 1287</ref>, contained the following provision: <quotedContent>“Where separate works or items are consolidated herein and an aggregate amount is appropriated therefor, the amount so appropriated shall, unless otherwise expressed, be expended in securing the maintenance and improvement according to the respective projects adopted by Congress after giving due regard to the respective needs of traffic. The allotments to the respective works so consolidated shall be made by the Chief of Engineers as authorized by the Secretary of War. In case such works or items are consolidated and separate amounts are given to individual projects the amounts so named shall be expended upon such separate projects. Any balances remaining to the credit of the consolidated items shall be carried to the credit of the respective aggregate amounts appropriated for the consolidated items.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1918-07-18/ch155/s2">act July 18, 1918, ch. 155, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/910">40 Stat. 910</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
