<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b50a0de-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s648"><num value="648">§ 648.</num><heading> Arkansas River; levee and bank protection</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The jurisdiction of the Mississippi River Commission is extended so as to include that part of the Arkansas River between its mouth and the intersection thereof with the division line between Lincoln and Jefferson Counties, and any funds which are appropriated by Congress for improving the Mississippi River between Head of Passes and the mouth of the Ohio River, and which may be allotted to levees and bank revetment, may be expended within the limits of said extended jurisdiction under the direction of the Secretary of the Army, in accordance with the plans, specifications, and recommendations of the Mississippi River Commission, as approved by the Chief of Engineers, and upon like terms and conditions for levees and bank revetment upon any part of the Mississippi River now under the jurisdiction of said commission, and in such manner as will best promote and accomplish the purposes for which commission was created, in so far as the territory hereby added to its said jurisdiction may be involved.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b50a0df-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1916-07-27/ch260/s1">July 27, 1916, ch. 260, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/402">39 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b50a0e0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b50a0e1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b50a0e2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from part of section 1 of the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1916.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b50a0e3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id6b50a0e4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Section 205(a) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. Section 1 of act <date date="1956-08-10">Aug. 10, 1956</date>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
