<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b55824b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s662"><num value="662">§ 662.</num><heading> Organization; compensation of members; rules and regulations of procedure; traveling expenses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Said commission shall organize by the selection of such officers as may be required in the performance of its duties the same to be selected from the members thereof. The members of said commission shall receive no greater compensation than is now allowed by law to each, respectively, as an officer of said Corps of Engineers. It shall also adopt rules and regulations, not inconsistent with law, to govern its deliberations and prescribe the method of procedure under the provisions of this chapter. While traveling on duty the officers of the commission shall receive the mileage allowed by law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b55824c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1893-03-01/ch183/s2">Mar. 1, 1893, ch. 183, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/27/507">27 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1900-06-06/ch791/s1">June 6, 1900, ch. 791, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/31/631">31 Stat. 631</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b55824d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b55824e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b55824f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p>The last sentence of this section is from a provision accompanying an appropriation for the expenses of the Commission in the Sundry Civil Appropriation Act for 1901, which originally read as follows: <quotedContent>“So much of the Act of March third, eighteen hundred and ninety-nine, as provides that the members of the California Debris Commission shall receive only actual expenses in lieu of mileage while traveling on duty is hereby repealed, and hereafter the officers of the commission shall receive the mileage allowed by law.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1899-03-03/ch424/s1">Act Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 424, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/1109">30 Stat. 1109</ref>, mentioned in said provision, provided that the officers of the Commission traveling on duty might be paid their actual traveling expenses, in lieu of mileage allowed by law, and should thereafter receive no mileage.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b558250-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6b558251-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">California Debris Commission abolished and functions transferred to Secretary of the Army by <ref href="/us/pl/99/662/tXI/s1106">Pub. L. 99–662, title XI, § 1106</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4229">100 Stat. 4229</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s661">section 661 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
