<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b57cbc6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701"><num value="701">§ 701.</num><heading> Flood control generally</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">[Laws applicable to works of improvement relating to flood control.]</inline> All the provisions of existing law relating to examinations and surveys and to works of improvement of rivers and harbors shall apply, so far as applicable, to examinations and surveys and to works of improvement relating to flood control. And all expenditures of funds appropriated for works and projects relating to flood control shall be made in accordance with and subject to the law governing the disbursement and expenditure of funds appropriated for the improvement of rivers and harbors.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">[Examinations and surveys; details from Government departments; reports.]</inline> All examinations and surveys of projects relating to flood control shall include a comprehensive study of the watershed or watersheds, and the report thereon in addition to any other matter upon which a report is required shall give such data as it may be practicable to secure in regard to (a) the extent and character of the area to be affected by the proposed improvement; (b) the probable effect upon any navigable water or waterway; (c) the possible economical development and utilization of water power; and (d) such other uses as may be properly related to or coordinated with the project. And the heads of the several departments of the Government may, in their discretion, and shall upon the request of the Secretary of the Army, detail representatives from their respective departments to assist the Engineers of the Army in the study and examination of such watersheds, to the end that duplication of work may be avoided and the various services of the Government economically coordinated therein: <i>Provided</i>, That all reports on preliminary examinations hereafter authorized, together with the report of the Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors thereon and the separate report of the representative of any other department, shall be submitted to the Secretary of the Army by the Chief of Engineers, with his recommendations, and shall be transmitted by the Secretary of the Army to the House of Representatives, and are ordered to be printed when so made.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">[Reports by Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors.]</inline> In the consideration of all works and projects relating to flood control which may be submitted to the Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors for consideration and recommendation, said board shall, in addition to any other matters upon which it may be required to report, state its opinion as to (a) what Federal interest, if any, is involved in the proposed improvement; (b) what share of the expense, if any, should be borne by the United States; and (c) the advisability of adopting the project.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b57cbc7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1917-03-01/ch144/s3">Mar. 1, 1917, ch. 144, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/950">39 Stat. 950</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s12/c">Pub. L. 103–437, § 12(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4590">108 Stat. 4590</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b57cbc8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b57cbc9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b57cbca-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1 and 2 of act <date date="1917-03-01">Mar. 1, 1917</date>, are classified to sections 702 and 703 of this title. Section 4 amended <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s643">section 643 of this title</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s702h">section 702h of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b57cbcb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> struck out par. at end which read as follows: “All examinations and reports which may now be made by the Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors upon request of the Committee on Rivers and Harbors relating to works or projects of navigation shall in like manner be made upon request of the Committee on Flood Control on all works and projects relating to flood control.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b57cbcc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id6b57cbcd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Section 205(a) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. Section 1 of act <date date="1956-08-10">Aug. 10, 1956</date>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b57cbce-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors and Reassignment of Duties and Responsibilities</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors 180 days after <date date="1992-10-31">Oct. 31, 1992</date>, and reassignment of duties and responsibilities by Secretary of Army, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/580/s223">section 223 of Pub. L. 102–580</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s541">section 541 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6b57cbcf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b57cbd0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Floodplain Management</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to the reduction of the risk of flood loss, the minimization of the impact of floods on human safety, health, and welfare, and the management of floodplains, see Ex. Ord. No. 11988, <date date="1977-05-24">May 24, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 26951, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id6b57cbd1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11296</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11296, <date date="1966-08-10">Aug. 10, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 10663, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/90/608">Pub. L. 90–608</ref>, ch. IV, § 402, <date date="1968-10-21">Oct. 21, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1194">82 Stat. 1194</ref>, which related to the evaluation of flood hazard in locating federally owned or financed buildings, roads, and other facilities, and in disposing of federal lands and properties, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 11988, <date date="1977-05-24">May 24, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 26951, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
