<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b57cbe7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701b"><num value="701b">§ 701b.</num><heading> Supervision of Secretary of the Army; reclamation projects unaffected</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Federal investigations and improvements of rivers and other waterways for flood control and allied purposes shall be under the jurisdiction of and shall be prosecuted by the Department of the Army under the direction of the Secretary of the Army and supervision of the Chief of Engineers, except as otherwise provided by Act of Congress; and in his reports upon examinations and surveys, the Secretary of the Army shall be guided as to flood-control measures by the principles set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701a">section 701a of this title</ref> in the determination of the Federal interests involved: <i>Provided</i>, That the foregoing grant of authority shall not interfere with investigations and river improvements incident to reclamation projects that may now be in progress or may be hereafter undertaken by the Bureau of Reclamation of the Interior Department pursuant to any general or specific authorization of law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b57cbe8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-06-22/ch688/s2">June 22, 1936, ch. 688, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1570">49 Stat. 1570</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-28/ch795/s1">June 28, 1938, ch. 795, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1215">52 Stat. 1215</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/ch377/s1">Aug. 18, 1941, ch. 377, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/638">55 Stat. 638</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-04/ch656/s7">Aug. 4, 1954, ch. 656, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/668">68 Stat. 668</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b57cbe9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b57cbea-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b57cbeb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-08-04">Aug. 4, 1954</date>, repealed provisions conferring authority on the Department of Agriculture under the direction of the Secretary of Agriculture to make preliminary examinations and surveys and to prosecute works of improvement for runoff and waterflow retardation and soil erosion prevention on the watersheds of rivers and other waterways.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1941—Act <date date="1941-08-18">Aug. 18, 1941</date>, reenacted without change portion of section preceding semicolon.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1938—Act <date date="1938-06-28">June 28, 1938</date>, reenacted without change portion of section preceding semicolon.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b57cbec-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id6b57cbed-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Section 205(a) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. Section 1 of act <date date="1956-08-10">Aug. 10, 1956</date>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id6b57cbee-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1954-08-04/ch656/s7">Act Aug. 4, 1954, ch. 656, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/668">68 Stat. 668</ref>, which amended this section by repealing provisions relating to the Department of Agriculture, provided in part that: <quotedContent>“(a) the authority of that Department of Agriculture, under the direction of the Secretary, to prosecute the works of improvement for runoff and waterflow retardation and soil erosion prevention authorized to be carried out by the Department by the act of <date date="1944-12-22">December 22, 1944</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/58/887">58 Stat. 887</ref>), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701a–1">section 701a–1 of this title</ref>], and (b) the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture to undertake emergency measures for runoff retardation and soil erosion prevention authorized to be carried out by <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-28/s7">section 7 of the act of June 28, 1938</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/52/1215">52 Stat. 1215</ref>), as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1950-05-17/s216">section 216 of the act of May 17, 1950</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/64/163">64 Stat. 163</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701b–1">section 701b–1 of this title</ref>], shall not be affected by the provisions of this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b57cbef-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Risk-Based Analysis Methodology</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/303/tII/s202/h">Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 202(h)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3676">110 Stat. 3676</ref>, required the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study of the Corps of Engineers’ use of risk-based analysis for the evaluation of hydrology, hydraulics, and economics in flood damage reduction studies and, not later than 18 months after <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, to submit to Congress a report on the results of the study as well as such recommendations as the Secretary considered appropriate.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
