<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b5cadbc-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701c–3"><num value="701c–3">§ 701c–3.</num><heading> Lease receipts; payment of portion to States</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">75 per centum of all moneys received and deposited in the Treasury of the United States during any fiscal year on account of the leasing of lands acquired by the United States for flood control, navigation, and allied purposes, including the development of hydroelectric power, shall be paid at the end of such year by the Secretary of the Treasury to the State in which such property is situated, to be expended as the State legislature may prescribe for the benefit of public schools and public roads of the county, or counties, in which such property is situated, or for defraying any of the expenses of county government in such county or counties, including public obligations of levee and drainage districts for flood control and drainage improvements: <i>Provided</i>, That when such property is situated in more than one State or county, the distributive share to each from the proceeds of such property shall be proportional to its area therein. For the purposes of this section, the term “money” includes, but is not limited to, such bonuses, royalties and rentals (and any interest or other charge paid to the United States by reason of the late payment of any royalty, rent, bonus or other amount due to the United States) paid to the United States from a mineral lease issued under the authority of the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s351">30 U.S.C. 351</ref> et seq.] or paid to the United States from a mineral lease in existence at the time of the acquisition of the land by the United States.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b5cadbd-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/ch377/s7">Aug. 18, 1941, ch. 377, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/650">55 Stat. 650</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-24/ch596/s5">July 24, 1946, ch. 596, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/642">60 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-06-16/ch114">June 16, 1953, ch. 114</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/61">67 Stat. 61</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1264">Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1264</ref>, title II, § 206, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1266">68 Stat. 1266</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXXV/s2506/c">Pub. L. 102–486, title XXV, § 2506(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3107">106 Stat. 3107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b5cadbe-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b5cadbf-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6b5cadc0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1947-08-07/ch513">act Aug. 7, 1947, ch. 513</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/913">61 Stat. 913</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 7 (§ 351 et seq.) of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s351">section 351 of Title 30</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b5cadc1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> inserted sentence at end defining term “money” for purposes of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-09-03">Sept. 3, 1954</date>, extended the 75 percent rental provision so as also to include moneys received and deposited with respect to the leasing of lands acquired for navigation and allied purposes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Act <date date="1953-06-16">June 16, 1953</date>, inserted “or for defraying any of the expenses of county government in such county or counties, including public obligations of levee and drainage districts for flood control and drainage improvements” after “situated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Act <date date="1946-07-24">July 24, 1946</date>, increased the percentage return to the States from 25 percent to 75 percent.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
