<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b5ef821-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n"><num value="701n">§ 701n.</num><heading> Emergency response to natural disasters</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b5ef822-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b5ef823-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is authorized an emergency fund to be expended in preparation for emergency response to any natural disaster, in flood fighting and rescue operations, or in the repair or restoration of any flood control work threatened or destroyed by flood, including the strengthening, raising, extending, realigning, or other modification thereof as may be necessary in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers for the adequate functioning of the work for flood control and subject to the condition that the Chief of Engineers may include modifications to the structure or project, or in implementation of nonstructural alternatives to the repair or restoration of such flood control work if requested by the non-Federal sponsor; in the emergency protection of federally authorized hurricane or shore protection being threatened when in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers such protection is warranted to protect against imminent and substantial loss to life and property; in the repair and restoration of any federally authorized hurricane or shore protective structure or project damaged or destroyed by wind, wave, or water action of other than an ordinary nature to the pre-storm level of protection, to the design level of protection, or, notwithstanding the authorized dimensions of the structure or project, to a level sufficient to meet the authorized purpose of such structure or project, whichever provides greater protection, when, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers, such repair and restoration is warranted for the adequate functioning of the structure or project for hurricane or shore protection, including to ensure the structure or project is functioning adequately to protect against projected changes in wave action or height or storm surge (including changes that result from relative sea level change over the useful life of the structure or project), subject to the condition that the Chief of Engineers may, if requested by the non-Federal sponsor, include modifications to the structure or project (including the addition of new project features) to address major deficiencies, increase resilience, increase benefits from the reduction of damages from inundation, wave action, or erosion, or implement nonstructural alternatives to the repair or restoration of the structure. The emergency fund may also be expended for emergency dredging for restoration of authorized project depths for Federal navigable channels and waterways made necessary by flood, drought, earthquake, or other natural disasters. In any case in which the Chief of Engineers is otherwise performing work under this section in an area for which the Governor of the affected State has requested a determination that an emergency exists or a declaration that a major disaster exists under the Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.], the Chief of Engineers is further authorized to perform on public and private lands and waters for a period of ten days following the Governor’s request any emergency work made necessary by such emergency or disaster which is essential for the preservation of life and property, including, but not limited to, channel clearance, emergency shore protection, clearance and removal of debris and wreckage endangering public health and safety, and temporary restoration of essential public facilities and services. The Chief of Engineers, in the exercise of his discretion, is further authorized to provide emergency supplies of clean water, on such terms as he determines to be advisable, to any locality which he finds is confronted with a source of contaminated water causing or likely to cause a substantial threat to the public health and welfare of the inhabitants of the locality. The appropriation of such moneys for the initial establishment of this fund and for its replenishment on an annual basis, is authorized: <i>Provided</i>, That pending the appropriation of sums to such emergency fund, the Secretary of the Army may allot, from existing flood-control appropriations, such sums as may be necessary for the immediate prosecution of the work herein authorized, such appropriations to be reimbursed from the appropriation herein authorized when made. The Chief of Engineers is authorized, in the prosecution of work in connection with rescue operations, or in conducting other flood emergency work, to acquire on a rental basis such motor vehicles, including passenger cars and buses, as in his discretion are deemed necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616924-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cost and benefit feasibility assessment.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616925-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration of benefits</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In preparing a cost and benefit feasibility assessment for any emergency project described in paragraph (1), the Chief of Engineers shall consider the benefits to be gained by such project for the protection of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b616926-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> residential establishments;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b616927-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> commercial establishments, including the protection of inventory; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b616928-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> agricultural establishments, including the protection of crops.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616929-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special conditions.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b61692a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to carry out work</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Chief of Engineers may carry out repair or restoration work described in paragraph (1) that does not produce benefits greater than the cost if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b61692b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the non-Federal sponsor agrees to pay, or provide contributions equal to, an amount sufficient to make the remaining costs of the project equal to the estimated value of the benefits of the repair or restoration work; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b61692c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61692d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/B/i/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the damage to the structure was not a result of negligent operation or maintenance; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61692e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/B/i/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> repair of the project could benefit another Corps project.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b61692f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of payments and contributions</inline>.—</heading><content>Non-Federal payments or contributions pursuant to clause (i) shall be in addition to any non-Federal payments or contributions required by the Chief of Engineers that are applicable to the remaining costs of the repair or restoration work.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616930-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extended assistance</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon request by a locality receiving assistance under the fourth sentence of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, enter into an agreement with the locality to provide such assistance beyond the time period otherwise provided for by the Secretary under such sentence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616931-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonstructural alternatives defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term “nonstructural alternatives” includes efforts to restore or protect natural resources, including streams, rivers, floodplains, wetlands, or coasts, if those efforts will reduce flood risk.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616932-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Feasibility study.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616933-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after receiving, from a non-Federal sponsor of a project to repair or rehabilitate a flood control work described in paragraph (1), a request to initiate a feasibility study to further modify the relevant flood control work to provide for an increased level of protection, the Secretary shall provide to the non-Federal sponsor a written decision on whether the Secretary has the authority under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s549a">section 549a of this title</ref> to undertake the requested feasibility study.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616934-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recommendation</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary determines under subparagraph (B) that the Secretary does not have the authority to undertake the requested feasibility study, the Secretary shall include the request for a feasibility study in the annual report submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2282d">section 2282d of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616935-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency supplies of drinking water; drought; well construction and water transportation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616936-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, upon a written request for assistance under this paragraph made by any farmer, rancher, or political subdivision within a distressed area, and after a determination by the Secretary that (A) as a result of the drought such farmer, rancher, or political subdivision has an inadequate supply of water, (B) an adequate supply of water can be made available to such farmer, rancher, or political subdivision through the construction of a well, and (C) as a result of the drought such well could not be constructed by a private business, the Secretary, subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, may enter into an agreement with such farmer, rancher, or political subdivision for the construction of such well.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616937-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary, upon a written request for assistance under this paragraph made by any farmer, rancher, or political subdivision within a distressed area, and after a determination by the Secretary that as a result of the drought such farmer, rancher, or political subdivision has an inadequate supply of water and water cannot be obtained by such farmer, rancher, or political subdivision, the Secretary may transport water to such farmer, rancher, or political subdivision by methods which include, but are not limited to, small-diameter emergency water lines and tank trucks, until such time as the Secretary determines that an adequate supply of water is available to such farmer, rancher, or political subdivision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616938-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b616939-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any agreement entered into by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall require the farmer, rancher, or political subdivision for whom the well is constructed to pay to the United States the reasonable cost of such construction, with interest, over such number of years, not to exceed thirty, as the Secretary deems appropriate. The rate of interest shall be that rate which the Secretary determines would apply if the amount to be repaid was a loan made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/b/2">section 636(b)(2) of title 15</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b61693a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall not construct any well pursuant to this subsection unless the farmer, rancher, or political subdivision for whom the well is being constructed has obtained, prior to construction, all necessary State and local permits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b61693b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Federal share for the transportation of water pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be 100 per centum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b61693c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b61693d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “construction” includes construction, reconstruction, or repair;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b61693e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “distressed area” means an area which the Secretary determines due to drought conditions has an inadequate water supply which is causing, or is likely to cause, a substantial threat to the health and welfare of the inhabitants of the area including threat of damage or loss of property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b61693f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the term “political subdivision” means a city, town, borough, county, parish, district, association, or other public body created by or pursuant to State law and having jurisdiction over the water supply of such public body;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616940-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the term “reasonable cost” means the lesser of (i) the cost to the Secretary of constructing a well pursuant to this subsection exclusive of the cost of transporting equipment used in the construction of wells, or (ii) the cost to a private business of constructing such well;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616941-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616942-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/b/5/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616943-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616944-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Levee owner’s manual</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="1996-10-12">October 12, 1996</date>, in accordance with chapter 5 of title 5, the Secretary of the Army shall prepare a manual describing the maintenance and upkeep responsibilities that the Corps of Engineers requires of a non-Federal interest in order for the non-Federal interest to receive Federal assistance under this section. The Secretary shall provide a copy of the manual at no cost to each non-Federal interest that is eligible to receive Federal assistance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616945-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Systemwide improvement plan</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616946-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding the status of compliance of a non-Federal interest with the requirements of a levee owner’s manual described in paragraph (1), or any other eligibility requirement established by the Secretary related to the maintenance and upkeep responsibilities of the non-Federal interest, the Secretary shall consider the non-Federal interest to be eligible for repair and rehabilitation assistance under this section if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b616947-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> in coordination with the Secretary, the non-Federal interest develops a systemwide improvement plan, prior to the natural disaster, that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b616948-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> identifies any items of deferred or inadequate maintenance and upkeep, including any such items identified by the Secretary or through periodic inspection of the flood control work;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b616949-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> identifies any additional measures, including repair and rehabilitation work, that the Secretary determines necessary to ensure that the flood control work performs as designed and intended;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61694a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> includes specific timelines for addressing such items and measures;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61694b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> requires the non-Federal interest to be responsible for the cost of addressing the items and measures identified under subclauses (I) and (II); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b61694c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the Secretary—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61694d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> determines that the systemwide improvement plan meets the requirements of clause (i) and the Secretary, acting through the District Commander, approves such plan; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61694e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> determines that the non-Federal interest makes satisfactory progress in meeting the timelines described in subclause (III) of that clause.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6b61694f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Grandfathered encroachments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">At the request of the non-Federal interest, the Secretary—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b616950-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall review documentation developed by the non-Federal interest showing a covered encroachment does not negatively impact the integrity of the flood control work;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b616951-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall make a written determination with respect to whether removal or modification of such covered encroachment is necessary to ensure the encroachment does not negatively impact the integrity of the flood control work; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b616952-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> may not determine that a covered encroachment is a deficiency requiring corrective action unless such action is necessary to ensure the encroachment does not negatively impact the integrity of the flood control work.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616953-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 to carry out paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616954-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616955-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered encroachment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “covered encroachment” means a permanent nonproject structure that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b616956-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is located inside the boundaries of a flood control work;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b616957-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is depicted on construction drawings or operation and maintenance plans for the flood control work that are signed by an engineer of record; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b616958-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> is determined by the Secretary to be an encroachment of such flood control work.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616959-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance and upkeep</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “maintenance and upkeep” means all maintenance and general upkeep of a levee performed on a regular and consistent basis that is not repair and rehabilitation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6b61695a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Repair and rehabilitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “repair and rehabilitation”—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b61695b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> means the repair or rebuilding of a levee or other flood control structure, after the structure has been damaged by a flood, to the level of protection provided by the structure before the flood; but</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6b61695c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> does not include—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61695d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any improvement to the structure; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id6b61695e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c/4/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> repair or rebuilding described in clause (i) if, in the normal course of usage, the structure becomes structurally unsound and is no longer fit to provide the level of protection for which the structure was designed.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b61695f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Increased level of protection</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In conducting repair or restoration work under subsection (a), at the request of the non-Federal sponsor, the Chief of Engineers may increase the level of protection above the level to which the system was designed, or, if the repair or restoration includes repair or restoration of a pumping station, increase the capacity of a pump, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616960-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the Chief of Engineers determines the improvements are in the public interest, including consideration of whether—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b616961-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the authority under this section has been used more than once at the same location;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b616962-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> there is an opportunity to decrease significantly the risk of loss of life and property damage; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6b616963-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> there is an opportunity to decrease total life cycle rehabilitation costs for the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b616964-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the non-Federal sponsor agrees to pay the difference between the cost of repair or restoration to the original design level or original capacity and the cost of achieving the higher level of protection or capacity sought by the non-Federal sponsor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b616965-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s701n/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall notify and consult with the non-Federal sponsor regarding the opportunity to request implementation of nonstructural alternatives to the repair or restoration of a flood control work under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b616966-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/ch377/s5">Aug. 18, 1941, ch. 377, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/650">55 Stat. 650</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-24/ch596/s12">July 24, 1946, ch. 596, § 12</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/652">60 Stat. 652</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-30/ch771">June 30, 1948, ch. 771</ref>, title II, § 206, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1182">62 Stat. 1182</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-05-17/ch188">May 17, 1950, ch. 188</ref>, title II, § 210, <ref href="/us/stat/64/183">64 Stat. 183</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-06-28/ch194">June 28, 1955, ch. 194</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/186">69 Stat. 186</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/874/tII/s206">Pub. L. 87–874, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1194">76 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/251/tI/s82">Pub. L. 93–251, title I, § 82</ref>, <date date="1974-03-07">Mar. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/34">88 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/51/s2">Pub. L. 95–51, § 2</ref>, <date date="1977-06-20">June 20, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/233">91 Stat. 233</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/662/tIX/s917">Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 917</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4192">100 Stat. 4192</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/45/s9">Pub. L. 100–45, § 9</ref>, <date date="1987-05-27">May 27, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/323">101 Stat. 323</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/707/tI/s109/m">Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 109(m)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4709">102 Stat. 4709</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/640/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 101–640, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4633">104 Stat. 4633</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/303/tII/s202/e">Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 202(e)</ref>, (f), <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3675">110 Stat. 3675</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tIII/s3029/a">Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3029(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1305">128 Stat. 1305</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/tI/s1176">Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1176</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1673">130 Stat. 1673</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/tI">Pub. L. 115–270, title I</ref>, §§ 1160, 1161(a), 1162, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3795">132 Stat. 3795</ref>, 3796; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dAA/tI/s120">Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2633">134 Stat. 2633</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dH/tLXXXI/s8102/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8102(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3695">136 Stat. 3695</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/272/dA/tI/s1146/a">Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1146(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/3036">138 Stat. 3036</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b616967-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b616968-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6b616969-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/288">Pub. L. 93–288</ref>, <date date="1974-05-22">May 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/143">88 Stat. 143</ref>, known as the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, which is classified principally to chapter 68 (§ 5121 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b61696a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/272/s1146/a/1">Pub. L. 118–272, § 1146(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which related to eligibility of non-Federal interest for repair and rehabilitation assistance under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(A) to (C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/272/s1146/a/2">Pub. L. 118–272, § 1146(a)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and redesignated former subpars. (A) and (B) as (B) and (C), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> substituted “in the repair and restoration of any federally authorized hurricane or shore protective structure or project damaged or destroyed by wind, wave, or water action of other than an ordinary nature to the pre-storm level of protection, to the design level of protection, or, notwithstanding the authorized dimensions of the structure or project, to a level sufficient to meet the authorized purpose of such structure or project, whichever provides greater protection, when, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers, such repair and restoration is warranted for the adequate functioning of the structure or project for hurricane or shore protection, including to ensure the structure or project is functioning adequately to protect against projected changes in wave action or height or storm surge (including changes that result from relative sea level change over the useful life of the structure or project), subject to the condition that the Chief of Engineers may, if requested by the non-Federal sponsor, include modifications to the structure or project (including the addition of new project features) to address major deficiencies, increase resilience, increase benefits from the reduction of damages from inundation, wave action, or erosion, or implement nonstructural alternatives to the repair or restoration of the structure.” for “in the repair and restoration of any federally authorized hurricane or shore protective structure or project damaged or destroyed by wind, wave, or water action of other than an ordinary nature to either the pre-storm level or the design level of protection, whichever provides greater protection, when, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers, such repair and restoration is warranted for the adequate functioning of the structure or project for hurricane or shore protection, subject to the condition that the Chief of Engineers may include modifications to the structure or project to address major deficiencies or implement nonstructural alternatives to the repair or restoration of the structure if requested by the non-Federal sponsor.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(i)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s120/1/A/i">Pub. L. 116–260, § 120(1)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “, or provide contributions equal to,” after “pay”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s120/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–260, § 120(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, in heading, inserted “and contributions” after “of payments” and, in text, inserted “or contributions” after “Non-Federal payments” and after “non-Federal payments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s120/1/B">Pub. L. 116–260, § 120(1)(B)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s120/2/A">Pub. L. 116–260, § 120(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Eligibility” for “Levee owners manual” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s120/2/B">Pub. L. 116–260, § 120(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Levee owner’s manual” for “In general” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s120/2/C">Pub. L. 116–260, § 120(2)(C)</ref>, (D), added par. (2), redesignated former pars. (2) and (3) as (3) and (4), respectively, and substituted “paragraph (1)” for “this subsection” in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/s1160">Pub. L. 115–270, § 1160</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “strengthening, raising, extending, realigning, or other modification thereof” for “strengthening, raising, extending, or other modification thereof” and “structure or project damaged or destroyed by wind, wave, or water action of other than an ordinary nature to either the pre-storm level or the design level of protection, whichever provides greater protection, when, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers,” for “structure or project damaged or destroyed by wind, wave, or water action of other than an ordinary nature to the design level of protection when, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/s1161/a">Pub. L. 115–270, § 1161(a)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “In preparing a cost and benefit feasibility assessment for any emergency project described in paragraph (1), the Chief of Engineers shall consider the benefits to be gained by such project for the protection of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) residential establishments;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) commercial establishments, including the protection of inventory; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) agricultural establishments, including the protection of crops.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/s1162">Pub. L. 115–270, § 1162</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/s1176/1">Pub. L. 114–322, § 1176(1)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/s1176/2">Pub. L. 114–322, § 1176(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) and (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/121">Pub. L. 113–121</ref> inserted “and subject to the condition that the Chief of Engineers may include modifications to the structure or project” after “work for flood control” and substituted “structure or project damaged or destroyed by wind, wave, or water action of other than an ordinary nature to the design level of protection when, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers, such repair and restoration is warranted for the adequate functioning of the structure or project for hurricane or shore protection, subject to the condition that the Chief of Engineers may include modifications to the structure or project to address major deficiencies or implement nonstructural alternatives to the repair or restoration of the structure if requested by the non-Federal sponsor” for “structure damaged or destroyed by wind, wave, or water action of other than an ordinary nature when in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers such repair and restoration is warranted for the adequate functioning of the structure for hurricane or shore protection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/303/s202/e">Pub. L. 104–303, § 202(e)</ref>, in first sentence, inserted “, or in implementation of nonstructural alternatives to the repair or restoration of such flood control work if requested by the non-Federal sponsor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/303/s202/f">Pub. L. 104–303, § 202(f)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/640">Pub. L. 101–640</ref> substituted “preparation for emergency response to any natural disaster” for “flood emergency preparation” and inserted provision permitting the emergency fund to be used for emergency dredging for restoration of authorized depths for Federal navigable channels and waterways made necessary by flood, drought, earthquake, or other natural disasters.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/707">Pub. L. 100–707</ref> substituted “and Emergency Assistance Act” for “Act of 1974”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/45">Pub. L. 100–45</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/662">Pub. L. 99–662</ref> inserted provision relating to authority of the Chief of Engineers, when the Governor of an affected State requests a determination that an emergency or major disaster exists, to perform on public and private lands and waters, for a period of ten days following the Governor’s request, any emergency work made necessary by such emergency or disaster which is essential for the preservation of life and property, and substituted “clean water” for “clean drinking water” and “contaminated water” for “contaminated drinking water”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/51">Pub. L. 95–51</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/251">Pub. L. 93–251</ref> struck out limitation of emergency fund to $15,000,000, provided for emergency supplies of clean drinking water to localities confronted with source of contaminated drinking water, and substituted in proviso “of sums to such emergency fund” for “of said sum”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/874">Pub. L. 87–874</ref> authorized expenditures from the emergency fund for the protection of federally authorized hurricane or shore protection being threatened when such is warranted to protect against imminent and substantial loss to life and property, and for the repair and restoration of any such federally authorized hurricane or shore protective structure damaged or destroyed by wind or water action of an extraordinary nature when such is warranted for the adequate functioning of the structure for hurricane or shore protection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Act <date date="1955-06-28">June 28, 1955</date>, authorized expenditure for flood emergency preparation and eliminated the requirement of maintenance of flood control works threatened by flood.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-05-17">May 17, 1950</date>, expanded scope of work considered under emergency repairs to flood-control structures, and substituted “$15,000,000” for “$2,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Act <date date="1948-06-30">June 30, 1948</date>, inserted provisions relating to the strengthening, extending, or modification of flood-control works.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Act <date date="1946-07-24">July 24, 1946</date>, substituted “$2,000,000” for “$1,000,000”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b61696b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id6b61696c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Section 205(a) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. Section 1 of act <date date="1956-08-10">Aug. 10, 1956</date>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b61696d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transition</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/272/dA/tI/s1146/c">Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1146(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/3038">138 Stat. 3038</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/272/dA/tI/s1146/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and repealing provisions set out as a note below] shall have no effect on any written agreement signed by the Secretary [of the Army] and a non-Federal interest pursuant to paragraph (2) of <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/s5/c">section 5(c) of the Act of August 18, 1941</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c">33 U.S.C. 701n(c)</ref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>]), if the non-Federal interest otherwise continues to meet the requirements of that paragraph (as so in effect).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b61696e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Participation in Preparedness Exercises</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/272/dA/tI/s1146/d">Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1146(d)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/3038">138 Stat. 3038</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/272/dA/tI/s1146/d">“The Secretary [of the Army] may not condition the eligibility of a non-Federal interest for rehabilitation assistance under <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/s5">section 5 of the Act of August 18, 1941</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n">33 U.S.C. 701n</ref>), on the participation of the non-Federal interest in disaster preparedness exercises that are unrelated to necessary repairs, rehabilitation, maintenance, and upkeep of a flood control work.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b61696f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Great Lakes Advance Measures Assistance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dH/tLXXXI/s8102/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8102(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3696">136 Stat. 3696</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dH/tLXXXI/s8102/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of the Army] shall not deny a request from the Governor of a Great Lakes State to provide advance measures assistance pursuant to <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/s5/a">section 5(a) of the Act of August 18, 1941</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n/a">33 U.S.C. 701n(a)</ref>) to reduce the risk of damage from rising water levels in the Great Lakes solely on the basis that the damage is caused by erosion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal share</inline>.—</heading><content>Assistance provided by the Secretary pursuant to a request described in paragraph (1) shall be at Federal expense if the assistance is for the construction of advance measures to a temporary construction standard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Great lakes state defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘Great Lakes State’ means the State of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, or Wisconsin.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b616970-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Technical Assistance for Levee Inspections</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dH/tLXXXI/s8120">Pub. L. 117–263, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8120</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3711">136 Stat. 3711</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dH/tLXXXI/s8120">“In any instance where the Secretary [of the Army] requires, as a condition of eligibility for Federal assistance under <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/s5">section 5 of the Act of August 18, 1941</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n">33 U.S.C. 701n</ref>), that a non-Federal sponsor of a flood control project undertake an electronic inspection of the portion of such project that is under normal circumstances submerged, the Secretary shall provide to the non-Federal sponsor credit or reimbursement for the cost of carrying out such inspection against the non-Federal share of the cost of repair or restoration of such project carried out under such section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b616971-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continued Eligibility</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/270/tI/s1161/b">Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1161(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3796">132 Stat. 3796</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dAA/tI/s121">Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2634">134 Stat. 2634</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dAA/tI/s121">
<inline>“Notwithstanding a non-Federal flood control work’s status in the Rehabilitation and Inspection Program carried out pursuant to <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/s5">section 5 of the Act of August 18, 1941</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n">33 U.S.C. 701n</ref>), any unconstructed emergency project for the non-Federal flood control work that was formulated during the five fiscal years preceding the fiscal year in which this Act was enacted [<date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>] but that was determined to not produce benefits greater than costs shall remain eligible for assistance under such section 5 until the last day of the fifth fiscal year following the fiscal year in which this Act was enacted if—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the non-Federal sponsor agrees, in accordance with such section 5, as amended by this Act, to pay, or provide contributions equal to, an amount sufficient to make the remaining costs of the project equal to the estimated value of the benefits of the repair or restoration work; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Secretary [of the Army] determines that the damage to the structure was not as a result of negligent operation or maintenance.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b616972-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Systemwide Improvement Framework</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tIII/s3011">Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3011</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1284">128 Stat. 1284</ref>, which provided that levee system remained eligible for rehabilitation assistance under this section as long as levee system sponsor continued to make satisfactory progress on approved systemwide improvement framework or letter of intent, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/118/272/dA/tI/s1146/b/1">Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1146(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/3038">138 Stat. 3038</ref>. See subsection (c)(2) of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b616973-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Vegetation Management Guidelines</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tIII/s3013">Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3013</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1284">128 Stat. 1284</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/121/tIII/s3013">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘guidelines’ means the Corps of Engineers policy guidelines for management of vegetation on levees, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Engineering Technical Letter 1110–2–571 entitled ‘Guidelines for Landscape Planting and Vegetation Management at Levees, Floodwalls, Embankment Dams, and Appurtenant Structures’ and adopted <date date="2009-04-10">April 10, 2009</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the draft policy guidance letter entitled ‘Process for Requesting a Variance from Vegetation Standards for Levees and Floodwalls’ (77 Fed. Reg. 9637 (<date date="2012-02-17">Feb. 17, 2012</date>)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of the Army] shall carry out a comprehensive review of the guidelines in order to determine whether current Federal policy relating to levee vegetation is appropriate for all regions of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Factors.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the review, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> the varied interests and responsibilities in managing flood risks, including the need—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to provide the greatest benefits for public safety with limited resources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to ensure that levee safety investments minimize environmental impacts and provide corresponding public safety benefits;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the levee safety benefits that can be provided by woody vegetation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> the preservation, protection, and enhancement of natural resources, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the benefit of vegetation on levees in providing habitat for species of concern, including endangered, threatened, and candidate species; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the impact of removing levee vegetation on compliance with other regulatory requirements;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> protecting the rights of Indian tribes pursuant to treaties and statutes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> determining how vegetation impacts the performance of a levee or levee system during a storm or flood event;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> the available science and the historical record regarding the link between vegetation on levees and flood risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> the avoidance of actions requiring significant economic costs and environmental impacts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> other factors relating to the factors described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) identified in public comments that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Variance considerations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the review, the Secretary shall specifically consider factors that promote and allow for consideration of variances from guidelines on a Statewide, tribal, regional, or watershed basis, including variances based on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> regional or watershed soil conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> hydrologic factors;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> vegetation patterns and characteristics;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> environmental resources, including endangered, threatened, or candidate species and related regulatory requirements;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> levee performance history, including historical information on original construction and subsequent operation and maintenance activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> any effects on water supply;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vii">“(vii)</num><content> any scientific evidence on the link between levee vegetation and levee safety;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="viii">“(viii)</num><content> institutional considerations, including implementation challenges and conflicts with or violations of Federal or State environmental laws;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ix">“(ix)</num><content> the availability of limited funds for levee construction and rehabilitation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="x">“(x)</num><content> the economic and environmental costs of removing woody vegetation on levees; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="xi">“(xi)</num><content> other relevant factors identified in public comments that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading><content>The scope of a variance approved by the Secretary may include a complete exemption to guidelines, if appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation and Consultation; Recommendations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall carry out the review under this section in consultation with other applicable Federal agencies, representatives of State, regional, local, and tribal governments, appropriate nongovernmental organizations, and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recommendations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regional integration teams</inline>.—</heading><content>Corps of Engineers Regional Integration Teams, representing districts, divisions, and headquarters, in consultation with State and Federal resource agencies, and with participation by local agencies, shall submit to the Secretary any recommendations for vegetation management policies for levees that conform with Federal and State laws and other applicable requirements, including recommendations relating to the review of guidelines under subsection (b) and the consideration of variances under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State, tribal, regional, and local entities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall consider and accept recommendations from any State, tribal, regional, or local entity for vegetation management policies for levees that conform with Federal and State laws and other applicable requirements, including recommendations relating to the review of guidelines under subsection (b) and the consideration of variances under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Independent Consultation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>As part of the review, the Secretary shall solicit and consider the views of independent experts on the engineering, environmental, and institutional considerations underlying the guidelines, including the factors described in subsection (c) and any information obtained by the Secretary under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of views</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The views of the independent experts obtained under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> made available to the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> included in supporting materials issued in connection with the revised guidelines required under subsection (f).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision of Guidelines.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>], the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> revise the guidelines based on the results of the review, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> recommendations received as part of the consultation described in subsection (d)(1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the views received under subsection (e);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> provide the public not less than 30 days to review and comment on draft guidelines before issuing final guidelines; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that contains a summary of the activities of the Secretary and a description of the findings of the Secretary under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Content; incorporation into manual</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The revised guidelines shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> provide a practical, flexible process for approving Statewide, tribal, regional, or watershed variances from the guidelines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> reflect due consideration of the factors described in subsection (c); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> incorporate State, tribal, and regional vegetation management guidelines for specific areas that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> are consistent with the guidelines; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> have been adopted through a formal public process; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> be incorporated into the manual proposed under <ref href="/us/act/1941-08-18/s5/c">section 5(c) of the Act of August 18, 1941</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n/c">33 U.S.C. 701n(c)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to meet deadlines</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the Secretary fails to submit a report by the required deadline under this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a detailed explanation of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> why the deadline was missed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> solutions needed to meet the deadline; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a projected date for submission of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim Actions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Until the date on which revisions to the guidelines are adopted in accordance with subsection (f), the Secretary shall not require the removal of existing vegetation as a condition or requirement for any approval or funding of a project, or any other action, unless the specific vegetation has been demonstrated to present an unacceptable safety risk.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revisions</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning on the date on which the revisions to the guidelines are adopted in accordance with subsection (f), the Secretary shall reconsider, on request of an affected entity, any previous action of the Corps of Engineers in which the outcome was affected by the former guidelines.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/303/tII/s202/g">Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 202(g)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3676">110 Stat. 3676</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/303/tII/s202/g">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall undertake a comprehensive review of the current policy guidelines on vegetation management for levees. The review shall examine current policies in view of the varied interests in providing flood control, preserving, protecting, and enhancing natural resources, protecting the rights of Native Americans pursuant to treaty and statute, and such other factors as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation and consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The review under this section [subsection] shall be undertaken in cooperation with interested Federal agencies and in consultation with interested representatives of State and local governments and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision of guidelines</inline>.—</heading><content>Based upon the results of the review, the Secretary shall revise, not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>], the policy guidelines so as to provide a coherent and coordinated policy for vegetation management for levees. Such revised guidelines shall address regional variations in levee management and resource needs and shall be incorporated in the manual proposed under section 5(c) of such Act of <date date="1941-08-18">August 18, 1941</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n">33 U.S.C. 701n</ref>[(c)]).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6b63b264-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b63b265-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
