<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b6623f3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s702a–5"><num value="702a–5">§ 702a–5.</num><heading> Back levee north of Eudora Floodway</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The back-protection levee north of the Eudora Floodway shall be constructed to the same grade and section as the levees opposite on the east side of the Mississippi River: <i>Provided</i>, That this levee extending from the head of the Eudora Floodway north to the Arkansas River shall be so located as to afford adequate space for the passage of flood waters without endangering the levees opposite on the east side of the river and shall be constructed contemporaneously with the construction of the Eudora Floodway; except that, until the Eudora Floodway is in operative condition, there shall be left in this back levee north of the head of the Eudora Floodway openings which shall be sufficient, in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers, to permit the passage of all flood waters to be reasonably contemplated in the event of any break in the riverside fuse-plug levee prior to the time the Eudora Floodway shall be in operative condition.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b6623f4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-06-15/ch548/s11">June 15, 1936, ch. 548, § 11</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1511">49 Stat. 1511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b6623f5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b6623f6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b6623f7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Abandonment and Repeal of Projects</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abandonment of Boeuf Floodway and Eudora Floodway as well as Northward Extension and back protection levee extending from head of Eudora Floodway north to Arkansas River and repeal of provisions relating to prosecution of work, see <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s702a–12">section 702a–12 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
