<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b6fc176-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s854a–2"><num value="854a–2">§ 854a–2.</num><heading> Pay and allowances; date of acceptance of promotion</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any commissioned officer of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration promoted to a higher grade at any time after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, shall be deemed for all purposes to have accepted his promotion to higher grade upon the date such promotion is made by the President unless he shall expressly decline such promotion, and shall receive the pay and allowances of the higher grade from such date unless he is entitled under some other provision of law to receive the pay and allowances of the higher grade from an earlier date. No such officer who shall have subscribed to the oath of office required by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3331">section 3331 of title 5</ref>, shall be required to renew such oath or to take a new oath upon his promotion to a higher grade, if his service after the taking of such an oath shall have been continuous.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b6fc177-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1942-12-03/ch670/s3">Dec. 3, 1942, ch. 670, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/56/1039">56 Stat. 1039</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b6fc178-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b6fc179-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b6fc17a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3331">Section 3331 of title 5</ref>” substituted in text for “section 1757, Revised Statutes” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Section 1757 of the Revised Statutes had been classified to section 16 of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to this section are contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s3031">section 3031 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6b6fc17b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6b6fc17c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Coast and Geodetic Survey consolidated with Weather Bureau to form a new agency in Department of Commerce to be known as Environmental Science Services Administration, and commissioned officers of Survey transferred to ESSA, by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1965, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s851">section 851 of this title</ref>. The Reorg. Plan also transferred to Secretary of Commerce all functions of Coast and Geodetic Survey and Director of Survey. Subsequently, Environmental Science Services Administration abolished, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration established, and Commissioned Officer Corps of ESSA redesignated Commissioned Officer Corps of NOAA by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. For further details, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s851">section 851 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
