<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b747c35-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s875"><num value="875">§ 875.</num><heading> Powers of officers as notaries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In places where the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration is serving which are not within the jurisdiction of any one of the States of the continental United States, excluding Alaska, commanding officers of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration vessels, and such other officers of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as the Secretary of Commerce may designate, may exercise the general powers of the notary public in the administration of oaths for the execution, acknowledgment, and attestation of instruments and papers, and the performance of all other notarial acts. The powers conferred shall be limited to acts performed in behalf of the personnel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or in connection with the proper execution of the functions of that agency.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b747c36-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-03/ch932/s1">Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 932, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/988">70 Stat. 988</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/624/s24">Pub. L. 86–624, § 24</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/418">74 Stat. 418</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b747c37-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b747c38-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b747c39-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/624">Pub. L. 86–624</ref> substituted “the States of the continental United States, excluding Alaska” for “the several States”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6b747c3a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6b747c3b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Coast and Geodetic Survey consolidated with Weather Bureau to form a new agency in Department of Commerce to be known as Environmental Science Services Administration, and commissioned officers of Survey transferred to ESSA, by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1965, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s851">section 851 of this title</ref>. The Reorg. Plan also transferred to Secretary of Commerce all functions of Coast and Geodetic Survey and Director of Survey. Subsequently, Environmental Science Services Administration abolished, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration established, and Commissioned Officer Corps of ESSA redesignated Commissioned Officer Corps of NOAA by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. For further details, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s851">section 851 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
