<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b7936df-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893"><num value="893">§ 893.</num><heading> Ocean and atmospheric research and development program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b7936e0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, shall establish a coordinated program of ocean, coastal, Great Lakes, and atmospheric research and development, in collaboration with academic institutions and other nongovernmental entities, that shall focus on the development of advanced technologies and analytical methods that will promote United States leadership in ocean and atmospheric science and competitiveness in the applied uses of such knowledge.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b7936e1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Oceanic and atmospheric research and development program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall implement programs and activities—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936e2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to identify emerging and innovative research and development priorities to enhance United States competitiveness, support development of new economic opportunities based on NOAA research, observations, monitoring modeling, and predictions that sustain ecosystem services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936e3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to promote United States leadership in oceanic and atmospheric science and competitiveness in the applied uses of such knowledge, including for the development and expansion of economic opportunities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936e4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to advance ocean, coastal, Great Lakes, and atmospheric research and development, including potentially transformational research, in collaboration with other relevant Federal agencies, academic institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental programs, consistent with NOAA’s mission to understand, observe, and model the Earth’s atmosphere and biosphere, including the oceans, in an integrated manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b7936e5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No later than 12 months after <date date="2011-01-04">January 4, 2011</date>, the Administrator, in consultation with the National Science Foundation or other such agencies with mature transformational research portfolios, shall develop and submit a report to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Science and Technology that describes NOAA’s strategy for enhancing transformational research in its research and development portfolio to increase United States competitiveness in oceanic and atmospheric science and technology. The report shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936e6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> define “transformational research”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936e7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identify emerging and innovative areas of research and development where transformational research has the potential to make significant and revolutionary – <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002031"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> advancements in both understanding and U.S. science leadership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936e8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> describe how transformational research priorities are identified and appropriately – <sup>1</sup> balanced in the context of NOAA’s broader research portfolio;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936e9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> describe NOAA’s plan for developing a competitive peer review and priority-setting – <sup>1</sup> process, funding mechanisms, performance and evaluation measures, and transition-to-operation guidelines for transformational research; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b7936ea-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s893/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> describe partnerships with other agencies involved in transformational research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b7936eb-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/69/tIV/s4001">Pub. L. 110–69, title IV, § 4001</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/599">121 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/358/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 111–358, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3996">124 Stat. 3996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b7936ec-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b7936ed-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b7936ee-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/111/358">Pub. L. 111–358</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b7936ef-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id6b7936f0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Science and Technology of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Twelfth Congress, <date date="2011-01-05">Jan. 5, 2011</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
