<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b7df1df-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s905"><num value="905">§ 905.</num><heading> Exclusiveness of liability</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b7df1e0-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s905/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Employer liability; failure of employer to secure payment of compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The liability of an employer prescribed in <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> shall be exclusive and in place of all other liability of such employer to the employee, his legal representative, husband or wife, parents, dependents, next of kin, and anyone otherwise entitled to recover damages from such employer at law or in admiralty on account of such injury or death, except that if an employer fails to secure payment of compensation as required by this chapter, an injured employee, or his legal representative in case death results from the injury, may elect to claim compensation under the chapter, or to maintain an action at law or in admiralty for damages on account of such injury or death. In such action the defendant may not plead as a defense that the injury was caused by the negligence of a fellow servant, or that the employee assumed the risk of his employment, or that the injury was due to the contributory negligence of the employee. For purposes of this subsection, a contractor shall be deemed the employer of a subcontractor’s employees only if the subcontractor fails to secure the payment of compensation as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b7df1e1-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s905/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Negligence of vessel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event of injury to a person covered under this chapter caused by the negligence of a vessel, then such person, or anyone otherwise entitled to recover damages by reason thereof, may bring an action against such vessel as a third party in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s933">section 933 of this title</ref>, and the employer shall not be liable to the vessel for such damages directly or indirectly and any agreements or warranties to the contrary shall be void. If such person was employed by the vessel to provide stevedoring services, no such action shall be permitted if the injury was caused by the negligence of persons engaged in providing stevedoring services to the vessel. If such person was employed to provide shipbuilding, repairing, or breaking services and such person’s employer was the owner, owner pro hac vice, agent, operator, or charterer of the vessel, no such action shall be permitted, in whole or in part or directly or indirectly, against the injured person’s employer (in any capacity, including as the vessel’s owner, owner pro hac vice, agent, operator, or charterer) or against the employees of the employer. The liability of the vessel under this subsection shall not be based upon the warranty of seaworthiness or a breach thereof at the time the injury occurred. The remedy provided in this subsection shall be exclusive of all other remedies against the vessel except remedies available under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b7df1e2-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s905/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Outer Continental Shelf</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event that the negligence of a vessel causes injury to a person entitled to receive benefits under this Act by virtue of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1333">section 1333 of title 43</ref>, then such person, or anyone otherwise entitled to recover damages by reason thereof, may bring an action against such vessel in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section. Nothing contained in subsection (b) of this section shall preclude the enforcement according to its terms of any reciprocal indemnity provision whereby the employer of a person entitled to receive benefits under this chapter by virtue of <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1333">section 1333 of title 43</ref> and the vessel agree to defend and indemnify the other for cost of defense and loss or liability for damages arising out of or resulting from death or bodily injury to their employees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b7df1e3-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1927-03-04/ch509/s5">Mar. 4, 1927, ch. 509, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1426">44 Stat. 1426</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/576/s18/a">Pub. L. 92–576, § 18(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1263">86 Stat. 1263</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/426">Pub. L. 98–426</ref>, §§ 4(b), 5(a)(1), (b), <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1641">98 Stat. 1641</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b7df1e4-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b7df1e5-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b7df1e6-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s4/b">Pub. L. 98–426, § 4(b)</ref>, inserted at end “For purposes of this subsection, a contractor shall be deemed the employer of a subcontractor’s employees only if the subcontractor fails to secure the payment of compensation as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s5/a/1">Pub. L. 98–426, § 5(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “If such person was employed to provide shipbuilding, repairing, or breaking services and such person’s employer was the owner, owner pro hac vice, agent, operator, or charterer of the vessel, no such action shall be permitted, in whole or in part or directly or indirectly, against the injured person’s employer (in any capacity, including as the vessel’s owner, owner pro hac vice, agent, operator, or charterer) or against the employees of the employer” for “If such person was employed by the vessel to provide ship building or repair services, no such action shall be permitted if the injury was caused by the negligence of persons engaged in providing ship building or repair services to the vessel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s5/b">Pub. L. 98–426, § 5(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—<ref href="/us/pl/92/576">Pub. L. 92–576</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), substituted “the chapter” for “this chapter”, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b7df1e7-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6b7df1e8-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s4/b">section 4(b) of Pub. L. 98–426</ref> effective <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, and applicable both with respect to claims filed after <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, and to claims pending on that date, and amendment by section 5(a)(1), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/426">Pub. L. 98–426</ref> applicable with respect to any injury after <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, see section 28(a), (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/426">Pub. L. 98–426</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6b7df1e9-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/576">Pub. L. 92–576</ref> effective 30 days after <date date="1972-10-27">Oct. 27, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/576/s22">section 22 of Pub. L. 92–576</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
