<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b89d80b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s924"><num value="924">§ 924.</num><heading> Witnesses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall be required to attend as a witness in any proceeding before a deputy commissioner at a place outside of the State of his residence and more than one hundred miles from his place of residence, unless his lawful mileage and fee for one day’s attendance shall be first paid or tendered to him; but the testimony of any witness may be taken by deposition or interrogatories according to the rules of practice of the Federal district court for the judicial district in which the case is pending (or of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia if the case is pending in the District).</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6b89d80c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1927-03-04/ch509/s24">Mar. 4, 1927, ch. 509, § 24</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1437">44 Stat. 1437</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-25/ch804">June 25, 1936, ch. 804</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1921">49 Stat. 1921</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s32/b">June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/991">62 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s127">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/107">63 Stat. 107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b89d80d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b89d80e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6b89d80f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">As originally enacted, this section contained a reference to the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia. Act <date date="1936-06-25">June 25, 1936</date>, substituted “the district court of the United States for the District of Columbia” for “the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia”, and act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, as amended by act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, substituted “United States District Court for the District of Columbia” for “district court of the United States for the District of Columbia”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
