<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b89d857-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s932"><num value="932">§ 932.</num><heading> Security for compensation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b89d858-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s932/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Every employer shall secure the payment of compensation under this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b89d859-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s932/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> By insuring and keeping insured the payment of such compensation with any stock company or mutual company or association, or with any other person or fund, while such person or fund is authorized (A) under the laws of the United States or of any State, to insure workmen’s compensation, and (B) by the Secretary, to insure payment of compensation under this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6b89d85a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s932/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> By furnishing satisfactory proof to the Secretary of his financial ability to pay such compensation and receiving an authorization from the Secretary to pay such compensation directly. The Secretary may, as a condition to such authorization, require such employer to deposit in a depository designated by the Secretary either an indemnity bond or securities (at the option of the employer) of a kind and in an amount determined by the Secretary, based on the employer’s financial condition, the employer’s previous record of payments, and other relevant factors, and subject to such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, which shall include authorization to the Secretary in case of default to sell any such securities sufficient to pay compensation awards or to bring suit upon such bonds, to procure prompt payment of compensation under this chapter. Any employer securing compensation in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph shall be known as a self-insurer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b89d85b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s932/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In granting authorization to any carrier to insure payment of compensation under this chapter the Secretary may take into consideration the recommendation of any State authority having supervision over carriers or over workmen’s compensation, and may authorize any carrier to insure the payment of compensation under this chapter in a limited territory. Any marine protection and indemnity mutual insurance corporation or association, authorized to write insurance against liability for loss or damage from personal injury and death, and for other losses and damages, incidental to or in respect of the ownership, operation, or chartering of vessels on a mutual assessment plan, shall be deemed a qualified carrier to insure compensation under this chapter. The Secretary may suspend or revoke any such authorization for good cause shown after a hearing at which the carrier shall be entitled to be heard in person or by counsel and to present evidence. No suspension or revocation shall affect the liability of any carrier already incurred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b89d85c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1927-03-04/ch509/s32">Mar. 4, 1927, ch. 509, § 32</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1439">44 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/426">Pub. L. 98–426</ref>, §§ 20, 27(a)(2), <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1652">98 Stat. 1652</ref>, 1654.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b89d85d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b89d85e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b89d85f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s27/a/2">Pub. L. 98–426, § 27(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “commission”. See Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s20">Pub. L. 98–426, § 20</ref>, inserted “based on the employer’s financial condition, the employer’s previous record of payments, and other relevant factors,” after “in an amount determined by the commission,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s27/a/2">Pub. L. 98–426, § 27(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “commission”. See Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s27/a/2">Pub. L. 98–426, § 27(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “commission”. See Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b89d860-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6b89d861-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/426">Pub. L. 98–426</ref> effective <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s28/e/1">section 28(e)(1) of Pub. L. 98–426</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
