<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b8eba27-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s982"><num value="982">§ 982.</num><heading> Management of Corporation; appointment of Administrator; terms; vacancy; Advisory Board; establishment; membership; meetings; duties; compensation and expenses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b8eba28-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s982/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The management of the corporation shall be vested in an Administrator who shall be appointed by the President. Any Administrator appointed to fill a vacancy in that position prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6b8eba29-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s982/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> There is established the Advisory Board of the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation which shall be composed of five members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, not more than three of whom shall belong to the same political party. The Advisory Board shall meet at the call of the Administrator, who shall require it to meet not less often than once each ninety days; shall review the general policies of the Corporation, including its policies in connection with design and construction of facilities and the establishment of rules of measurement for vessels and cargo and rates of charges or tolls; and shall advise the Administrator with respect thereto. Members of the Advisory Board shall receive for their services as members compensation of not to exceed $50 per diem when actually engaged in the performance of their duties, together with their necessary traveling expenses while going to and coming from meetings.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b8eba2a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-05-13/ch201/s2">May 13, 1954, ch. 201, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/93">68 Stat. 93</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/615/s1">Pub. L. 93–615, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1977">88 Stat. 1977</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/166/s2/x">Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(x)</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1289">126 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dAA/tV/s512/a/2">Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title V, § 512(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2756">134 Stat. 2756</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b8eba2b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6b8eba2c-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6b8eba2d-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> substituted “Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation” for “Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/166">Pub. L. 112–166</ref> struck out “, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for a term of seven years” before period at end of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/615/s1/a">Pub. L. 93–615, § 1(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally, inserting provisions relating to a term of seven years and the length of the term of any Administrator appointed to fill a vacancy in the position of the Administrator prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/615/s1/b">Pub. L. 93–615, § 1(b)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (b). Former subsec. (b), relating to the appointment and duties of a Deputy Administrator, was repealed.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6b8eba2e-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6b8eba2f-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/166">Pub. L. 112–166</ref> effective 60 days after <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, and applicable to appointments made on and after that effective date, including any nomination pending in the Senate on that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/166/s6/a">section 6(a) of Pub. L. 112–166</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s113">section 113 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6b8eba30-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/615/s2">Pub. L. 93–615, § 2</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1977">88 Stat. 1977</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/615/s2">“The amendments made to <ref href="/us/act/1954-05-13/s2">section 2 of the Act of May 13, 1954</ref>, by the first section of this Act [amending this section] shall (1) take effect upon the first appointment of an Administrator of the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation which is made after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>], and (2) be applicable to such first appointment and to each subsequent appointment to such position.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6b8eba31-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Boards</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory boards in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a board established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such board is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a board established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
