<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6b910455-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s987"><num value="987">§ 987.</num><heading> Services and facilities of other agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b910456-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s987/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of personnel, services, facilities, and information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation may, with the consent of the agency concerned, accept and utilize, on a reimbursable basis, the officers, employees, services, facilities, and information of any agency of the Federal Government, except that any such agency having custody of any data relating to any of the matters within the jurisdiction of the Corporation shall, upon request of the Administrator, make such data available to the Corporation without reimbursement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6b910457-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e" identifier="/us/usc/t33/s987/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributions to retirement and disability, and employees’ compensation, funds; payment of costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation shall contribute to the civil-service retirement and disability fund, on the basis of annual billings as determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, for the Government’s share of the cost of the civil-service retirement system applicable to the Corporation’s employees and their beneficiaries. The Corporation shall also contribute to the employee’s compensation fund, on the basis of annual billings as determined by the Secretary of Labor, for the benefit payments made from such fund on account of the Corporation’s employees. The annual billings shall also include a statement of the fair portion of the cost of the administration of the respective funds, which shall be paid by the Corporation into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6b910458-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-05-13/ch201/s8">May 13, 1954, ch. 201, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/95">68 Stat. 95</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6b910459-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6b91045a-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6b91045b-3a70-11f1-9100-cf79f4fb4b3e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Director of the Office of Personnel Management” substituted for “Civil Service Commission” and “Commission” in subsec. (b) pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1978, § 102, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, which transferred all functions vested by statute in United States Civil Service Commission to Director of Office of Personnel Management (except as otherwise specified), effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, as provided by section 1–102 of Ex. Ord. No. 12107, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1055, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
