<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id83bd1120-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323"><num value="1323">§ 1323.</num><heading> Functions and authorities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id83bd1121-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Council shall perform functions that include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd1122-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Identifying and recommending development by the National Institute of Standards and Technology of supply chain risk management standards, guidelines, and practices for executive agencies to use when assessing and developing mitigation strategies to address supply chain risks, particularly in the acquisition and use of covered articles under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s1326/a">section 1326(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd1123-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Identifying or developing criteria for sharing information with executive agencies, other Federal entities, and non-Federal entities with respect to supply chain risk, including information related to the exercise of authorities provided under this section and sections 1326 and 4713 of this title. At a minimum, such criteria shall address—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1124-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the content to be shared;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1125-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the circumstances under which sharing is mandated or voluntary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1126-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the circumstances under which it is appropriate for an executive agency to rely on information made available through such sharing in exercising the responsibilities and authorities provided under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s4713">section 4713 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd1127-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Identifying an appropriate executive agency to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1128-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> accept information submitted by executive agencies based on the criteria established under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1129-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> facilitate the sharing of information received under subparagraph (A) to support supply chain risk analyses under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s1326">section 1326 of this title</ref>, recommendations under this section, and covered procurement actions under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s4713">section 4713 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd112a-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> share with the Council information regarding covered procurement actions by executive agencies taken under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s4713">section 4713 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd112b-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> inform the Council of orders issued under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd112c-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Identifying, as appropriate, executive agencies to provide—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd112d-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shared services, such as support for making risk assessments, validation of products that may be suitable for acquisition, and mitigation activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd112e-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> common contract solutions to support supply chain risk management activities, such as subscription services or machine-learning-enhanced analysis applications to support informed decision making.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd112f-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Identifying and issuing guidance on additional steps that may be necessary to address supply chain risks arising in the course of executive agencies providing shared services, common contract solutions, acquisitions vehicles, or assisted acquisitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd1130-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Engaging with the private sector and other nongovernmental stakeholders in performing the functions described in paragraphs (1) and (2) and on issues relating to the management of supply chain risks posed by the acquisition of covered articles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd1131-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Carrying out such other actions, as determined by the Council, that are necessary to reduce the supply chain risks posed by acquisitions and use of covered articles.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id83bd1132-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Office and Committees</inline>.—</heading><content>The Council may establish a program office and any committees, working groups, or other constituent bodies the Council deems appropriate, in its sole and unreviewable discretion, to carry out its functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id83bd1133-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority for Exclusion or Removal Orders.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd1134-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Criteria</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To reduce supply chain risk, the Council shall establish criteria and procedures for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1135-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> recommending orders applicable to executive agencies requiring the exclusion of sources or covered articles from executive agency procurement actions (in this section referred to as “exclusion orders”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1136-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> recommending orders applicable to executive agencies requiring the removal of covered articles from executive agency information systems (in this section referred to as “removal orders”);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1137-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> requesting and approving exceptions to an issued exclusion or removal order when warranted by circumstances, including alternative mitigation actions or other findings relating to the national interest, including national security reviews, national security investigations, or national security agreements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bd1138-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> ensuring that recommended orders do not conflict with standards and guidelines issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s11331">section 11331 of title 40</ref> and that the Council consults with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology regarding any recommended orders that would implement standards and guidelines developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bd1139-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Council shall use the criteria established under paragraph (1), information made available under subsection (a)(3), and any other information the Council determines appropriate to issue recommendations, for application to executive agencies or any subset thereof, regarding the exclusion of sources or covered articles from any executive agency procurement action, including source selection and consent for a contractor to subcontract, or the removal of covered articles from executive agency information systems. Such recommendations shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf823a-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> information necessary to positively identify the sources or covered articles recommended for exclusion or removal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf823b-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information regarding the scope and applicability of the recommended exclusion or removal order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf823c-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a summary of any risk assessment reviewed or conducted in support of the recommended exclusion or removal order;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf823d-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a summary of the basis for the recommendation, including a discussion of less intrusive measures that were considered and why such measures were not reasonably available to reduce supply chain risk;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf823e-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a description of the actions necessary to implement the recommended exclusion or removal order; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf823f-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> where practicable, in the Council’s sole and unreviewable discretion, a description of mitigation steps that could be taken by the source that may result in the Council rescinding a recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bf8240-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of recommendation and review</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A notice of the Council’s recommendation under paragraph (2) shall be issued to any source named in the recommendation advising—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8241-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that a recommendation has been made;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8242-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> of the criteria the Council relied upon under paragraph (1) and, to the extent consistent with national security and law enforcement interests, of information that forms the basis for the recommendation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8243-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that, within 30 days after receipt of notice, the source may submit information and argument in opposition to the recommendation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8244-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> of the procedures governing the review and possible issuance of an exclusion or removal order pursuant to paragraph (5); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8245-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> where practicable, in the Council’s sole and unreviewable discretion, a description of mitigation steps that could be taken by the source that may result in the Council rescinding the recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bf8246-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any notice issued to a source under paragraph (3) shall be kept confidential until—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8247-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an exclusion or removal order is issued pursuant to paragraph (5); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8248-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the source has been notified pursuant to paragraph (6).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bf8249-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusion and removal orders.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf824a-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Order issuance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Recommendations of the Council under paragraph (2), together with any information submitted by a source under paragraph (3) related to such a recommendation, shall be reviewed by the following officials, who may issue exclusion and removal orders based upon such recommendations:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id83bf824b-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary of Homeland Security, for exclusion and removal orders applicable to civilian agencies, to the extent not covered by clause (ii) or (iii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id83bf824c-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense, for exclusion and removal orders applicable to the Department of Defense and national security systems other than sensitive compartmented information systems.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id83bf824d-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence, for exclusion and removal orders applicable to the intelligence community and sensitive compartmented information systems, to the extent not covered by clause (ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf824e-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading><content>The officials identified in subparagraph (A) may not delegate any authority under this subparagraph to an official below the level one level below the Deputy Secretary or Principal Deputy Director, except that the Secretary of Defense may delegate authority for removal orders to the Commander of the United States Cyber Command, who may not redelegate such authority to an official below the level one level below the Deputy Commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf824f-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Facilitation of exclusion orders</inline>.—</heading><content>If officials identified under this paragraph from the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence issue orders collectively resulting in a governmentwide exclusion, the Administrator for General Services and officials at other executive agencies responsible for management of the Federal Supply Schedules, governmentwide acquisition contracts and multi-agency contracts shall help facilitate implementation of such orders by removing the covered articles or sources identified in the orders from such contracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8250-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review of exclusion and removal orders</inline>.—</heading><content>The officials identified under this paragraph shall review all exclusion and removal orders issued under subparagraph (A) not less frequently than annually pursuant to procedures established by the Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8251-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rescission</inline>.—</heading><content>Orders issued pursuant to subparagraph (A) may be rescinded by an authorized official from the relevant issuing agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bf8252-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notifications</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Upon issuance of an exclusion or removal order pursuant to paragraph (5)(A), the official identified under that paragraph who issued the order shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8253-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> notify any source named in the order of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id83bf8254-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the exclusion or removal order; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id83bf8255-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to the extent consistent with national security and law enforcement interests, information that forms the basis for the order;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8256-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide classified or unclassified notice of the exclusion or removal order to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id83bf8257-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide the exclusion or removal order to the agency identified in subsection (a)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bf8258-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance</inline>.—</heading><content>Executive agencies shall comply with exclusion and removal orders issued pursuant to paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id83bf8259-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Request Information</inline>.—</heading><content>The Council may request such information from executive agencies as is necessary for the Council to carry out its functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id83bf825a-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Councils</inline>.—</heading><content>The Council shall consult and coordinate, as appropriate, with other relevant councils and interagency committees, including the Chief Information Officers Council, the Chief Acquisition Officers Council, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, and the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, with respect to supply chain risks posed by the acquisition and use of covered articles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id83bf825b-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rules of Construction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bf825c-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to limit the authority of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy to carry out the responsibilities of that Office under any other provision of law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id83bf825d-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2" identifier="/us/usc/t41/s1323/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to authorize the issuance of an exclusion or removal order based solely on the fact of foreign ownership of a potential procurement source that is otherwise qualified to enter into procurement contracts with the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id83bf825e-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/115/390/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 115–390, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5180">132 Stat. 5180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id83bf825f-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id83bf8260-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id83bf8261-3a70-11f1-ab1a-a784e0a454e2"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days after <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, and applicable to contracts that are awarded before, on, or after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/390/s202/c">section 202(c) of Pub. L. 115–390</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s1321">section 1321 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title II of <ref href="/us/pl/115/390">Pub. L. 115–390</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/390/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 115–390</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s1321">section 1321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
