<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id051b7728-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1307"><num value="1307">§ 1307.</num><heading> Convict-made goods; importation prohibited</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All goods, wares, articles, and merchandise mined, produced, or manufactured wholly or in part in any foreign country by convict labor or/and forced labor or/and indentured labor under penal sanctions shall not be entitled to entry at any of the ports of the United States, and the importation thereof is hereby prohibited, and the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to prescribe such regulations as may be necessary for the enforcement of this provision.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">“Forced labor”, as herein used, shall mean all work or service which is exacted from any person under the menace of any penalty for its nonperformance and for which the worker does not offer himself voluntarily. For purposes of this section, the term “forced labor or/and indentured labor” includes forced or indentured child labor.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id051b7729-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title III, § 307, <ref href="/us/stat/46/689">46 Stat. 689</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/200/tIV/s411/a">Pub. L. 106–200, title IV, § 411(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/298">114 Stat. 298</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/tIX/s910/a/1">Pub. L. 114–125, title IX, § 910(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/239">130 Stat. 239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id051b772a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id051b772b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id051b772c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions in the same language as the provisions in this section were made by <ref href="/us/act/1913-10-03/ch16">act Oct. 3, 1913, ch. 16</ref>, § IV, I, <ref href="/us/stat/38/195">38 Stat. 195</ref>, superseding similar provisions of previous tariff acts. That subdivision was superseded by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIII/s307">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title III, § 307</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/937">42 Stat. 937</ref>, and repealed by section 321 of that act. Section 307 of act <date date="1922-09-21">Sept. 21, 1922</date>, was superseded by section 307 of act <date date="1930-06-17">June 17, 1930</date>, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id051b772d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—<ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref> struck out “The provisions of this section relating to goods, wares, articles, and merchandise mined, produced, or manufactured by forced labor or/and indentured labor, shall take effect on <date date="1932-01-01">January 1, 1932</date>; but in no case shall such provisions be applicable to goods, wares, articles, or merchandise so mined, produced, or manufactured which are not mined, produced, or manufactured in such quantities in the United States as to meet the consumptive demands of the United States.” after “enforcement of this provision.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/200">Pub. L. 106–200</ref> inserted at end “For purposes of this section, the term ‘forced labor or/and indentured labor’ includes forced or indentured child labor.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id051b772e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id051b772f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2016 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/125/tIX/s910/a/2">Pub. L. 114–125, title IX, § 910(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/239">130 Stat. 239</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/125/tIX/s910/a/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date that is 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id051b7730-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/200/tIV/s411/b">Pub. L. 106–200, title IV, § 411(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/298">114 Stat. 298</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/200/tIV/s411/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id051b7731-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Use of Funds To Prevent Enforcement of Ban on Importation of Convict-Made Goods</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/90/tV/s514">Pub. L. 108–90, title V, § 514</ref>, <date date="2003-10-01">Oct. 1, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1154">117 Stat. 1154</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/90/tV/s514">“For fiscal year 2004 and thereafter, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Homeland Security shall be available for any activity or for paying the salary of any Government employee where funding an activity or paying a salary to a Government employee would result in a determination, regulation, or policy that would prohibit the enforcement of section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id051b7732-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Use of Funds To Allow Importation of Forced or Indentured Child Labor</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/90/tV/s515">Pub. L. 108–90, title V, § 515</ref>, <date date="2003-10-01">Oct. 1, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1154">117 Stat. 1154</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/90/tV/s515">
<inline>“For fiscal year 2004 and thereafter, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Homeland Security may be used to allow—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the importation into the United States of any good, ware, article, or merchandise mined, produced, or manufactured by forced or indentured child labor, as determined under section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the release into the United States of any good, ware, article, or merchandise on which there is in effect a detention order under such section 307 on the basis that the good, ware, article, or merchandise may have been mined, produced, or manufactured by forced or indentured child labor.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id051b7733-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reporting Requirement on Forced Labor Products Destined for United States Market</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dC/tXXXVII/s3702">Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXVII, § 3702</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2275">112 Stat. 2275</ref>, required the Commissioner of Customs, by 1 year after <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, to prepare and transmit to Congress a report, with specified information, on products made with forced labor that are destined for the United States market.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id051b7734-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sense of Congress Requesting President To Instruct Secretary of the Treasury To Enforce Section 1307 Without Delay</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tI/s1906">Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1906</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1313">102 Stat. 1313</ref>, related to Congressional findings of deplorable forced labor conditions in former Soviet Union and request of President to instruct Secretary of the Treasury to enforce this section without delay, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/tII/s204/a">Pub. L. 103–199, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2322">107 Stat. 2322</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
