<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0524ec8d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315"><num value="1315">§ 1315.</num><heading> Effective date of rates of duty</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0524ec8e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Articles entered or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise specially provided for, the rate or rates of duty imposed by or pursuant to this chapter or any other law on any article entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption shall be the rate or rates in effect when the documents comprising the entry for consumption or withdrawal from warehouse for consumption and any estimated or liquidated duties then required to be paid have been deposited with the Customs Service by written, electronic or such other means as the Secretary by regulation shall prescribe, except that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0524ec8f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any article released under an informal mail entry shall be subject to duty at the rate or rates in effect when the preparation of the entry is completed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0524ec90-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any article which is not subject to a quantitative or tariff-rate quota and which is covered by an entry for immediate transportation made at the port of original importation under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1552">section 1552 of this title</ref>, if entered for consumption at the port designated by the consignee, or his agent, in such transportation entry without having been taken into the custody of the appropriate customs officer under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1490">section 1490 of this title</ref>, shall be subject to the rate or rates in effect when the transportation entry was accepted at the port of original importation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0524ec91-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any article for which duties may, under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1505">section 1505 of this title</ref>, be paid at a time later than the time of making entry shall be subject to the rate or rates in effect at the time of entry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0524ec92-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Articles removed from intended place of release</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any article which has been entered for consumption but which, before release from custody of the Customs Service, is removed from the port or other place of intended release because of inaccessibility, overcarriage, strike, act of God, or unforeseen contingency, shall be subject to duty at the rate or rates in effect when the entry for consumption and any required duties were deposited in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, but only if the article is returned to such port or place within ninety days after the date of removal and the identity of the article as that covered by the entry is established in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0524ec93-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Quantity of merchandise at time of importation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Insofar as duties are based upon the quantity of any merchandise, such duties shall, except as provided in chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States and <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1562">section 1562 of this title</ref> (relating respectively to certain beverages and to manipulating warehouses), be levied and collected upon the quantity of such merchandise at the time of its importation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0524ec94-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1315/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date of administrative rulings resulting in higher rates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No administrative ruling resulting in the imposition of a higher rate of duty or charge than the Secretary of the Treasury shall find to have been applicable to imported merchandise under an established and uniform practice shall be effective with respect to articles entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption prior to the expiration of thirty days after the date of publication in the Federal Register of notice of such ruling; but this provision shall not apply with respect to the imposition of antidumping duties, or the imposition of countervailing duties under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref> (as in effect on the day before the effective date of title II of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act) or <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>. This subsection shall not apply with respect to increases in rates of duty resulting from the enactment of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to replace the Tariff Schedules of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0524ec95-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title III, § 315, <ref href="/us/stat/46/695">46 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch679/s6">June 25, 1938, ch. 679, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1081">52 Stat. 1081</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-08/ch397/s3/a">Aug. 8, 1953, ch. 397, § 3(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/508">67 Stat. 508</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/271/tIII/s301/b">Pub. L. 91–271, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/287">84 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/tIII/s331/c">Pub. L. 93–618, title III, § 331(c)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2053">88 Stat. 2053</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/410/tI/s101">Pub. L. 95–410, title I, § 101</ref>, title II, § 204, <date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/888">92 Stat. 888</ref>, 900; <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/tXI/s1106/e">Pub. L. 96–39, title XI, § 1106(e)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/312">93 Stat. 312</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tI/s1213/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1213(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1155">102 Stat. 1155</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/tVI/s633">Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 633</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2198">107 Stat. 2198</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tII/s261/d/1/B/i">Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 261(d)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4909">108 Stat. 4909</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0524ec96-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0524ec97-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0524ec98-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States and the Tariff Schedules of the United States, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (d), are not set out in the Code. See Publication of Harmonized Tariff Schedule note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For the effective date of title II of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act [<ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>], referred to in subsec. (d), as <date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/s291">section 291 of Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1994 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0524ec99-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> inserted “(as in effect on the day before the effective date of title II of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act) or <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s633/1">Pub. L. 103–182, § 633(1)</ref>, substituted “Customs Service by written, electronic or such other means as the Secretary by regulation shall prescribe,” for “appropriate customs officer in the form and manner prescribed by regulations of the Secretary of the Treasury,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s633/2">Pub. L. 103–182, § 633(2)</ref>, substituted “custody of the Customs Service” for “customs custody”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s633/3">Pub. L. 103–182, § 633(3)</ref>, substituted “chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States” for “paragraph 813”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> inserted at end “This subsection shall not apply with respect to increases in rates of duty resulting from the enactment of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to replace the Tariff Schedules of the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref> amended directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s331/c">Pub. L. 93–618, § 331(c)</ref>, to correct a typographical error, and did not involve any change in text. See 1975 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/410/s101">Pub. L. 95–410, § 101</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/410/s204">Pub. L. 95–410, § 204</ref>, substituted “publication in the Federal Register” for “publication in the weekly Treasury Decisions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/618">Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref>, inserted “or the imposition of countervailing duties under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref>” after “antidumping duties”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref> substituted reference to the appropriate customs officer for reference to the collector.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Act <date date="1953-08-08">Aug. 8, 1953</date>, amended section generally by dividing section into subsections, and by changing the provisions set out as subsecs. (a) and (b) to clarify such provisions with respect to effective dates of rates of duty.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1938—Act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, amended section generally, among which changes it inserted provisions set out as subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0524ec9a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0524ec9b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tII/s261/d/2">Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 261(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4910">108 Stat. 4910</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/465/tII/s261/d/2">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section and sections 1337, 1671, 1677i, 2192, and 2194 of this title and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the effective date of this title [<date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>, see Effective Date of 1994 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>].</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0524ec9c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> effective <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, and applicable with respect to articles entered on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1217/b/1">section 1217(b)(1) of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0524ec9d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/618/tIII/s331/d">Pub. L. 93–618, title III, § 331(d)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2053">88 Stat. 2053</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tII/s261/d/1/A/i">Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 261(d)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4909">108 Stat. 4909</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/465/tII/s261/d/1/A/i">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 1303 and 1516 of this title] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>.]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> For purposes of applying the provisions of section 303(a)(4) of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1303/a/4">section 1303(a)(4) of this title</ref>] (as amended by subsection (a)) with respect to any investigation which was initiated before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>] under section 303 of such Act (as in effect before such date), such investigation shall be treated as having been initiated on the day after such date of enactment under section 303(a)(3)(B) of such Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0524ec9e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/271/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 91–271</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1500">section 1500 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0524ec9f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1953 Amendment; Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1953-08-08">Aug. 8, 1953</date>, effective on and after thirtieth day following <date date="1953-08-08">Aug. 8, 1953</date>, and savings provision, see notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1304">section 1304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0524eca0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1938 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, effective on thirtieth day following <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, except as otherwise specifically provided, see section 37 of act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id0524eca1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0524eca2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id0524eca3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all other officers of Department of the Treasury and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Treasury, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions, by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 26, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, 1281, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Customs officers, referred to in text, were under Department of the Treasury.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
