<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0524ecd4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1319a"><num value="1319a">§ 1319a.</num><heading> Duty on coffee; ratification of duties imposed by Legislature of Puerto Rico</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The taxes and duties imposed by the Legislature of Puerto Rico by Joint Resolution Numbered 59 approved by the Governor of Puerto Rico <date date="1930-05-05">May 5, 1930</date>, and by Act Numbered 77 approved by the Governor of Puerto Rico <date date="1931-05-05">May 5, 1931</date>, as amended by Act Numbered 7 approved by the Governor <date date="1934-04-09">April 9, 1934</date>, including therein such taxes and duties on coffee brought into Puerto Rico from any State or Territory or district or possession of the United States, or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, are legalized and ratified, and the collection of all such taxes and duties made under or by authority of either of said acts of the Puerto Rican Legislature, including such taxes and duties on coffee brought into Puerto Rico from any State, Territory, district, or possession of the United States, or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, is legalized, ratified, and confirmed as fully to all intents and purposes as if the same had, by prior Act of Congress, been specifically authorized and directed.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id0524ecd5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/ch604">June 18, 1934, ch. 604</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1017">48 Stat. 1017</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-20/ch578">Aug. 20, 1935, ch. 578</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/665">49 Stat. 665</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0524ecd6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0524ecd7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0524ecd8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of Tariff Act of 1930 which constitutes this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0524ecd9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-20">Aug. 20, 1935</date>, amended section generally.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
