<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id053cba69-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1442"><num value="1442">§ 1442.</num><heading> Residue cargo</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any vessel having on board merchandise shown by the manifest to be destined to a foreign port or place may, after the report and entry of such vessel under the provisions of this chapter, proceed to such foreign port of destination with the cargo so destined therefor, without unlading the same and without the payment of duty thereon. Any vessel arriving from a foreign port or place having on board merchandise shown by the manifest to be destined to a port or ports in the United States other than the port of entry at which such vessel first arrived and made entry may proceed with such merchandise from port to port or from district to district for the unlading thereof.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id053cba6a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 442, <ref href="/us/stat/46/713">46 Stat. 713</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id053cba6b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id053cba6c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id053cba6d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in R.S. §§ 2776 (as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1884-06-26/ch121/s29">act June 26, 1884, ch. 121, § 29</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/23/59">23 Stat. 59</ref>), 2777–2779, 2782, and 2783, all of which were superseded by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s442">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 442</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/952">42 Stat. 952</ref>, and were repealed by section 642 thereof. Section 442 of the 1922 act was superseded by section 442 of act <date date="1930-06-17">June 17, 1930</date>, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions authorizing the Secretary of the Treasury to require bonds in cases of vessels carrying goods destined for ports other than port of entry were contained in the 1922 act and prior acts. These provisions were omitted from this section. General provisions authorizing the Secretary to require bonds where not specifically required are contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1623">section 1623 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Special provisions concerning Astoria and Portland were contained in R.S. §§ 2588 and 2590, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/s642">section 642 of the act of Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
