<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id053f2b4a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1467"><num value="1467">§ 1467.</num><heading> Special inspection, examination, and search</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a vessel from a foreign port or place or from a port or place in any Territory or possession of the United States arrives at a port or place in the United States or the Virgin Islands, whether directly or via another port or place in the United States or the Virgin Islands, the appropriate customs officer for such port or place of arrival may, under such regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe and for the purpose of assuring compliance with any law, regulation, or instruction which the Secretary of the Treasury or the Customs Service is authorized to enforce, cause inspection, examination, and search to be made of the persons, baggage, and merchandise discharged or unladen from such vessel, whether or not any or all such persons, baggage, or merchandise has previously been inspected, examined, or searched by officers of the customs.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id053f2b4b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 467, as added <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch679/s11">June 25, 1938, ch. 679, § 11</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1083">52 Stat. 1083</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/271/tIII/s301/g">Pub. L. 91–271, title III, § 301(g)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/288">84 Stat. 288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id053f2b4c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id053f2b4d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id053f2b4e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref> substituted reference to appropriate customs officer for reference to collector of customs.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id053f2b4f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id053f2b50-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/271/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 91–271</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1500">section 1500 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id053f2b51-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section effective on the thirtieth day following <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, except as otherwise specifically provided, see section 37 of act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, set out as an Effective Date of 1938 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id053f2b52-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id053f2b53-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id053f2b54-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of officers of Department of the Treasury and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Treasury, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions, by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by Reorg. Plan No. 26 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, 1281, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
