<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id054657c2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1500"><num value="1500">§ 1500.</num><heading> Appraisement, classification, and liquidation procedure</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Customs Service shall, under rules and regulations prescribed by the Secretary—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id054657c3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1500/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> fix the final appraisement of merchandise by ascertaining or estimating the value thereof, under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401a">section 1401a of this title</ref>, by all reasonable ways and means in his power, any statement of cost or costs of production in any invoice, affidavit, declaration, other document to the contrary notwithstanding;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id054657c4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1500/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> fix the final classification and rate of duty applicable to such merchandise;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id054657c5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1500/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> fix the final amount of duty to be paid on such merchandise and determine any increased or additional duties, taxes, and fees due or any excess of duties, taxes, and fees deposited;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id054657c6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1500/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> liquidate the entry and reconciliation, if any, of such merchandise; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id054657c7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1500/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> give or transmit, pursuant to an electronic data interchange system, notice of such liquidation to the importer, his consignee, or agent in such form and manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id054657c8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 500, <ref href="/us/stat/46/729">46 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-02/ch887/s4/b">Aug. 2, 1956, ch. 887, § 4(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/948">70 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/271/tII/s204/a">Pub. L. 91–271, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/283">84 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/tII/s202/a/4">Pub. L. 96–39, title II, § 202(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/202">93 Stat. 202</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/tVI/s638">Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 638</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2203">107 Stat. 2203</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id054657c9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id054657ca-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id054657cb-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s500">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 500</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/965">42 Stat. 965</ref>. That section was superseded by section 500 of act <date date="1930-06-17">June 17, 1930</date>, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions dealing with the subject matter of subdivision (a) of this section were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1913-10-03/ch16">act Oct. 3, 1913, ch. 16</ref>, § III, K, <ref href="/us/stat/38/185">38 Stat. 185</ref>, reenacting without change the provisions of the Customs Administrative <ref href="/us/act/1890-06-10/ch407/s10">Act of June 10, 1890, ch. 407, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/136">26 Stat. 136</ref>, as reenacted by the Payne-Aldrich Tariff <ref href="/us/act/1909-08-05/ch6/s28">Act of Aug. 5, 1909, ch. 6, § 28</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/97">36 Stat. 97</ref>. A provision somewhat similar to subdivision (a)(5) of this section was contained in section III, M, of the 1913 act, the provisions of which were substituted for provisions of the same nature contained in section 13 of the Customs Administrative Act of <date date="1890-06-10">June 10, 1890</date>, as amended by the Payne-Aldrich Tariff <ref href="/us/act/1909-08-05/ch6/s28">Act of Aug. 5, 1909, ch. 6, § 28</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/99">36 Stat. 99</ref>. Said section III of the 1913 act was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s643">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 643</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/989">42 Stat. 989</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. §§ 2609, 2610, relative to merchant appraisers, were superseded by the provisions relating to appraisers and appraisements in the Customs Administrative <ref href="/us/act/1890-06-10/ch407">Act of June 10, 1890, ch. 407</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/131">26 Stat. 131</ref>, and later acts, and were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s642">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 642</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/989">42 Stat. 989</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2902 prescribed the mode of appraisal of merchandise, prior to repeal by the Customs Administrative <ref href="/us/act/1890-06-10/ch407/s29">Act of June 10, 1890, ch. 407, § 29</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/141">26 Stat. 141</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2911 required appraisers to adopt the value of the best article in a package containing articles wholly or in part of wool or cotton of similar kind but different quality, charged at an average price, and R.S. § 2912 related to appraisal of wool of different qualities when imported in the same bale, bag, or package, and of bales of different qualities when embraced in the same invoice, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s642">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 642</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/989">42 Stat. 989</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2945 imposed a penalty on any merchant chosen by the collector to make any appraisement required under any act respecting imports and tonnage, who should, after due notice, decline or neglect to assess at such appraisement. This section was repealed by the Customs Administrative <ref href="/us/act/1890-06-10/ch407/s29">Act of June 10, 1890, ch. 407, § 29</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/141">26 Stat. 141</ref>, and was again repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s642">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 642</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/989">42 Stat. 989</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2946 related to the ascertainment of value at ports where there were no appraisers, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/s642">section 642 of the act of Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior provision similar to subdivision (b) was contained in <ref href="/us/act/1913-10-03/ch16">act Oct. 3, 1913, ch. 16</ref>, § III, M, <ref href="/us/stat/38/186">38 Stat. 186</ref>, the provisions of which were substitutes for those of the Customs Administrative <ref href="/us/act/1890-06-10/ch407/s13">Act of June 10, 1890, ch. 407, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/136">26 Stat. 136</ref>, as amended by the Payne-Aldrich Tariff <ref href="/us/act/1909-08-05/ch6/s28">Act of Aug. 5, 1909, ch. 6, § 28</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/99">36 Stat. 99</ref>. Section III, M, was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s643">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 643</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/989">42 Stat. 989</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">An earlier provision on the subject was contained in R.S. § 2929, prior to repeal by Customs Administrative <ref href="/us/act/1890-06-10/ch407/s29">Act of June 10, 1890, ch. 407, § 29</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/141">26 Stat. 141</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Somewhat similar to subdivision (d), R.S. § 2943 provided that one of the assistant appraisers at the port of New York should be detailed for the supervision of examination of merchandise damaged on the voyage of importation, and to make examinations and appraisals and to report, etc. It was repealed, with R.S. § 2927, which provided for appraisal of such goods, and other sections, by the Customs Administrative <ref href="/us/act/1890-06-10/ch407/s29">Act of June 10, 1890, ch. 407, § 29</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/141">26 Stat. 141</ref>, reenacted and designated as section 28 by the Payne-Aldrich Tariff <ref href="/us/act/1909-08-05/ch6/s28">Act of Aug. 5, 1909, ch. 6, § 28</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/104">36 Stat. 104</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id054657cc-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s638/1">Pub. L. 103–182, § 638(1)</ref>, substituted “The Customs Service” for “The appropriate customs officer” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subd. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s638/2">Pub. L. 103–182, § 638(2)</ref>, substituted “fix the final appraisement of” for “appraise”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subd. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s638/3">Pub. L. 103–182, § 638(3)</ref>, substituted “fix the final” for “ascertain the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subd. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s638/4">Pub. L. 103–182, § 638(4)</ref>, inserted “final” after “fix the” and “, taxes, and fees” after “duties” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subds. (d) and (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s638/5">Pub. L. 103–182, § 638(5)</ref>, amended subds. (d) and (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subds. (d) and (e) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(d) liquidate the entry of such merchandise; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(e) give notice of such liquidation to the importer, his consignee, or agent in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe in such regulations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subd. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref> substituted “by ascertaining or estimating the value thereof, under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401a">section 1401a of this title</ref>, by all reasonable ways and means in his power, any statement of cost or costs of production in any invoice, affidavit, declaration, or other document” for “in the unit of quantity in which the merchandise is usually bought and sold by ascertaining or estimating the value thereof by all reasonable ways and means in his power, any statement of cost or costs of production in any invoice, affidavit, declaration, or other document”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref> struck out “(a)” preceding first sentence and, in such provisions, as so redesignated, substituted provisions which set forth the customs functions to be performed by the appropriate customs officer for provisions which set forth the customs functions to be performed by the appraiser, and struck out subds. (b) to (f), which allocated specific customs functions to appraisers, assistant and deputy appraisers, and examiners, and authorized the designation of acting appraisers where necessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subd. (f). Act <date date="1956-08-02">Aug. 2, 1956</date>, struck out “take the oath,” before “perform all the duties” in second sentence, and struck out comma after “perform all duties”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id054657cd-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id054657ce-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref> effective <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/s204/a">section 204(a) of Pub. L. 96–39</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401a">section 1401a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id054657cf-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/271/tII/s203">Pub. L. 91–271, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/283">84 Stat. 283</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/271/tII/s203">“Titles II and III of this Act [see Short Title of 1970 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1654">section 1654 of this title</ref>] shall take effect with respect to articles entered, or withdrawn, from warehouse for consumption, on or after <date date="1970-10-01">October 1, 1970</date>, and such other articles entered or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption prior to such date, the appraisement of which has not become final before <date date="1970-10-01">October 1, 1970</date>, and for which an appeal for reappraisement has not been timely filed with the Bureau of Customs [now the United States Customs Service] before <date date="1970-10-01">October 1, 1970</date>, or with respect to which a protest has not been disallowed in whole or in part before <date date="1970-10-01">October 1, 1970</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id054657d0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id054657d1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id054657d2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers of Department of the Treasury and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Treasury, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions, by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by Reorg. Plan No. 26 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, 1281, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
