<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0548c802-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504"><num value="1504">§ 1504.</num><heading> Limitation on liquidation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c803-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Liquidation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c804-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Entries for consumption</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Unless an entry of merchandise for consumption is extended under subsection (b) of this section or suspended as required by statute or court order, except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1675/a/3">section 1675(a)(3) of this title</ref>, an entry of merchandise for consumption not liquidated within 1 year from—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0548c805-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the date of entry of such merchandise,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0548c806-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the date of the final withdrawal of all such merchandise covered by a warehouse entry,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0548c807-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the date of withdrawal from warehouse of such merchandise for consumption if, pursuant to regulations issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1505/a">section 1505(a) of this title</ref>, duties may be deposited after the filing of any entry or withdrawal from warehouse,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0548c808-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> if a reconciliation is filed, or should have been filed, the date of the filing under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1484">section 1484 of this title</ref> or the date the reconciliation should have been filed, whichever is earlier; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0548c809-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002028">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002028"><num>1</num> See 2004 Amendment notes below.</note> if a reconfigured entry is filed under an import activity summary statement, the date the import activity summary statement is filed or should have been filed, whichever is earlier;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be deemed liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duties asserted by the importer of record. Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1500/e">section 1500(e) of this title</ref>, notice of liquidation need not be given of an entry deemed liquidated.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c80a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Entries or claims for drawback</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c80b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B) or (C), unless an entry or claim for drawback is extended under subsection (b) or suspended as required by statute or court order, an entry or claim for drawback not liquidated within 1 year from the date of entry or claim shall be deemed liquidated at the drawback amount asserted by the claimant or claim. Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1500/e">section 1500(e) of this title</ref>, notice of liquidation need not be given of an entry deemed liquidated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c80c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Unliquidated imports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An entry or claim for drawback whose designated or identified import entries have not been liquidated and become final within the 1-year period described in subparagraph (A), or within the 1-year period described in subparagraph (C), shall be deemed liquidated upon the deposit of estimated duties on the unliquidated imported merchandise, and upon the filing with the Customs Service of a written request for the liquidation of the drawback entry or claim. Such a request must include a waiver of any right to payment or refund under other provisions of law. The Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe any necessary regulations for the purpose of administering this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c80d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An entry or claim for drawback filed before <date date="2004-12-03">December 3, 2004</date>, the liquidation of which is not final as of <date date="2004-12-03">December 3, 2004</date>, shall be deemed liquidated on the date that is 1 year after <date date="2004-12-03">December 3, 2004</date>, at the drawback amount asserted by the claimant at the time of the entry or claim.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c80e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments or refunds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Payment or refund of duties owed pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2) shall be made to the importer of record or drawback claimant, as the case may be, not later than 90 days after liquidation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c80f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury may extend the period in which to liquidate an entry if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0548c810-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the information needed for the proper appraisement or classification of the imported or withdrawn merchandise, or for determining the correct drawback amount, or for ensuring compliance with applicable law, is not available to the Customs Service; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0548c811-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the importer of record or drawback claimant, as the case may be, requests such extension and shows good cause therefor.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall give notice of an extension under this subsection to the importer of record or drawback claimant, as the case may be, and the surety of such importer of record or drawback claimant. Notice shall be in such form and manner (which may include electronic transmittal) as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe. Any entry the liquidation of which is extended under this subsection shall be treated as having been liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duty asserted by the importer of record, or the drawback amount asserted by the drawback claimant, at the expiration of 4 years from the applicable date specified in subsection (a).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c812-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of suspension</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the liquidation of any entry is suspended, the Secretary shall by regulation require that notice of the suspension be provided, in such manner as the Secretary considers appropriate, to the importer of record or drawback claimant, as the case may be, and to any authorized agent and surety of such importer of record or drawback claimant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0548c813-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1504/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal of suspension</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1675/a/3">section 1675(a)(3) of this title</ref>, when a suspension required by statute or court order is removed, the Customs Service shall liquidate the entry, unless liquidation is extended under subsection (b), within 6 months after receiving notice of the removal from the Department of Commerce, other agency, or a court with jurisdiction over the entry. Any entry (other than an entry with respect to which liquidation has been extended under subsection (b)) not liquidated by the Customs Service within 6 months after receiving such notice shall be treated as having been liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duty asserted by the importer of record or (in the case of a drawback entry or claim) at the drawback amount asserted by the drawback claimant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0548c814-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 504, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/410/tII/s209/a">Pub. L. 95–410, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/902">92 Stat. 902</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/573/tI/s191/d">Pub. L. 98–573, title I, § 191(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2971">98 Stat. 2971</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/tVI/s641">Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2204">107 Stat. 2204</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tII/s220/c">Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 220(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4865">108 Stat. 4865</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/295/s3/a/7">Pub. L. 104–295, § 3(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3516">110 Stat. 3516</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/tI/s1563/e">Pub. L. 108–429, title I, § 1563(e)</ref>, title II, § 2102, <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2585">118 Stat. 2585</ref>, 2597.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0548c815-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0548c816-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0548c817-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1504, <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497/tIV/s504">act June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title IV, § 504</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/732">46 Stat. 732</ref>, related to duties on coverings and containers, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/87/456/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 87–456, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-05-24">May 24, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/75">76 Stat. 75</ref>, effective, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/87/456/s501/a">section 501(a) of Pub. L. 87–456</ref>, with respect to articles entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption on or after <date date="1963-08-31">Aug. 31, 1963</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0548c818-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—<ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s2102/2">Pub. L. 108–429, § 2102(2)</ref>, struck out “at the time of entry” after “duties asserted” in subsec. (a)(1) (concluding provisions), after “asserted by the claimant” in subsec. (a)(2)(A), and after “of duty asserted” and “drawback amount asserted” in subsecs. (b) (concluding provisions) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s2102/1">Pub. L. 108–429, § 2102(1)</ref>, which directed striking “or” at end of par. (3), substituting “filed, whichever is earlier; or” for “filed;” in par. (4), and adding par. (5) after par. (4), was executed by striking “or” at end of par. (1)(C), substituting “filed, whichever is earlier; or” for “filed,” in par. (1)(D), and adding the text of par. (5) after par. (1)(D) and editorially redesignating it as par. (1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s2102/1">Pub. L. 108–429, § 2102(1)</ref>, was technically incapable of execution subsequent to the amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s1563/e/1">Pub. L. 108–429, § 1563(e)(1)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s1563/e/1">Pub. L. 108–429, § 1563(e)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (a). Text read as follows: “Unless an entry is extended under subsection (b) of this section or suspended as required by statute or court order, except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1675/a/3">section 1675(a)(3) of this title</ref>, an entry of merchandise not liquidated within one year from:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the date of entry of such merchandise;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the date of the final withdrawal of all such merchandise covered by a warehouse entry;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) the date of withdrawal from warehouse of such merchandise for consumption where, pursuant to regulations issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1505/a">section 1505(a) of this title</ref>, duties may be deposited after the filing of an entry or withdrawal from warehouse; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) if a reconciliation is filed, or should have been filed, the date of the filing under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1484">section 1484 of this title</ref> or the date the reconciliation should have been filed;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be deemed liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duties asserted at the time of entry by the importer of record. Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1500/e">section 1500(e) of this title</ref>, notice of liquidation need not be given of an entry deemed liquidated.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s1563/e/1">Pub. L. 108–429, § 1563(e)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (b). Text read as follows: “The Secretary may extend the period in which to liquidate an entry if—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the information needed for the proper appraisement or classification of the merchandise, or for insuring compliance with applicable law, is not available to the Customs Service; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the importer of record requests such extension and shows good cause therefor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall give notice of an extension under this subsection to the importer of record and the surety of such importer of record. Notice shall be in such form and manner (which may include electronic transmittal) as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe. Any entry the liquidation of which is extended under this subsection shall be treated as having been liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duty asserted at the time of entry by the importer of record at the expiration of 4 years from the applicable date specified in subsection (a) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s1563/e/2">Pub. L. 108–429, § 1563(e)(2)</ref>, inserted “or drawback claimant, as the case may be,” after “to the importer of record” and “or drawback claimant” after “of such importer of record”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s1563/e/3">Pub. L. 108–429, § 1563(e)(3)</ref>, inserted “or (in the case of a drawback entry or claim) at the drawback amount asserted at the time of entry by the drawback claimant” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/295">Pub. L. 104–295</ref> inserted “, unless liquidation is extended under subsection (b),” after “shall liquidate the entry” in first sentence, and “(other than an entry with respect to which liquidation has been extended under subsection (b))” after “Any entry” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/s220/c/1">Pub. L. 103–465, § 220(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1675/a/3">section 1675(a)(3) of this title</ref>,” before “an entry of merchandise not liquidated” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/s220/c/2">Pub. L. 103–465, § 220(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1675/a/3">section 1675(a)(3) of this title</ref>, when a suspension” for “When a suspension”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s641/1/A">Pub. L. 103–182, § 641(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Unless an entry is extended under subsection (b) or suspended as required by statute or court order” for “Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s641/1/B">Pub. L. 103–182, § 641(1)(B)</ref>–(D), added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s641/2">Pub. L. 103–182, § 641(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “The Secretary may extend the period in which to liquidate an entry by giving notice of such extension to the importer of record in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe in regulations, if—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) information needed for the proper appraisement or classification of the merchandise is not available to the appropriate customs officer;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) liquidation is suspended as required by statute or court order; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) the importer of record requests such extension and shows good cause therefor.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s641/2">Pub. L. 103–182, § 641(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “If the liquidation of any entry is suspended, the Secretary shall, by regulation, require that notice of such suspension be provided to the importer of record concerned and to any authorized agent and surety of such importer of record.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/s641/2">Pub. L. 103–182, § 641(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) “Limitation” read as follows: “Any entry of merchandise not liquidated at the expiration of four years from the applicable date specified in subsection (a) of this section, shall be deemed liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duty asserted at the time of entry by the importer of record, unless liquidation continues to be suspended as required by statute or court order. When such a suspension of liquidation is removed, the entry shall be liquidated within 90 days therefrom.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/573/s191/d/1">Pub. L. 98–573, § 191(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “importer of record” for “importer, his consignee, or agent” in provisions following par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/573/s191/d/2">Pub. L. 98–573, § 191(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “importer of record” for “importer, his consignee, or agent” in provisions preceding par. (1), and substituted “importer of record” for “importer, consignee, or his agent” in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/573/s191/d/3">Pub. L. 98–573, § 191(d)(3)</ref>, substituted “importer of record” for “importer or consignee” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/573/s191/d/4">Pub. L. 98–573, § 191(d)(4)</ref>, substituted “importer of record” for “importer, his consignee, or agent”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0548c819-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0548c81a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/429/tI/s1563/g/2">Pub. L. 108–429, title I, § 1563(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2587">118 Stat. 2587</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/429/tI/s1563/g/2">
<inline>“The amendments made by subsection (e) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>], and shall apply to—</inline>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> any entry of merchandise for consumption or entry or claim for drawback filed on and after such date of enactment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any entry or claim for drawback filed before such date of enactment if the liquidation of the entry or claim is not final on such date of enactment.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s2102">section 2102 of Pub. L. 108–429</ref> applicable to merchandise entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after the 15th day after <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/s2108">section 2108 of Pub. L. 108–429</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0548c81b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/295">Pub. L. 104–295</ref> applicable as of <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/295/s3/b">section 3(b) of Pub. L. 104–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1321">section 1321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0548c81c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, on the date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States (<date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>), and applicable with respect to investigations, reviews, and inquiries initiated and petitions filed under specified provisions of this chapter after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/s291">section 291 of Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0548c81d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/573">Pub. L. 98–573</ref> applicable with respect to articles entered on or after 15th day after <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/573/s195/a">section 195(a) of Pub. L. 98–573</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1322">section 1322 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0548c81e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/410/tII/s209/b">Pub. L. 95–410, title II, § 209(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/903">92 Stat. 903</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/410/tII/s209/b">“The amendment made by this section [enacting this section] applies to the entry or withdrawal of merchandise for consumption on or after 180 days after the enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id0548c81f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
