<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id05523e82-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516"><num value="1516">§ 1516.</num><heading> Petitions by domestic interested parties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05523e83-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Request for classification and rate of duty; petition</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id05523e84-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall, upon written request by an interested party furnish the classification and the rate of duty imposed upon designated imported merchandise of a class or kind manufactured, produced, or sold at wholesale by such interested party. If the interested party believes that the appraised value, the classification, or rate of duty is not correct, it may file a petition with the Secretary setting forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05523e85-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a description of the merchandise,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05523e86-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the appraised value, the classification, or the rate of duty that it believes proper, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05523e87-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the reasons for its belief.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id05523e88-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> As used in this section, the term “interested party” means a person who is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05523e89-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05523e8a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a certified union or recognized union or group of workers which is representative of an industry engaged in the manufacture, production, or wholesale in the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05523e8b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a trade or business association a majority of whose members are manufacturers, producers, or wholesalers in the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">of goods of the same class or kind as the designated imported merchandise. Such term includes an association, a majority of whose members is composed of persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id05523e8c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any producer of a raw agricultural product who is considered under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1677/4/E">section 1677(4)(E) of this title</ref> to be part of the industry producing a processed agricultural product of the same class or kind as the designated imported merchandise shall, for purposes of this section, be treated as an interested party producing such processed agricultural product.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05523e8d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination on petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, after receipt and consideration of a petition filed by such an interested party, the Secretary determines that the appraised value, the classification, or rate of duty is not correct, he shall determine the proper appraised value, classification, or rate of duty and shall notify the petitioner of his determination. All such merchandise entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption more than thirty days after the date such notice to the petitioner is published in the weekly Customs Bulletin shall be appraised, classified, or assessed as to the rate of duty in accordance with the Secretary’s determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05523e8e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contest by petitioner of appraised value, classification, or rate of duty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that the appraised value, classification, or rate of duty with respect to which a petition was filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section is correct, he shall notify the petitioner. If dissatisfied with the determination of the Secretary, the petitioner may file with the Secretary, not later than thirty days after the date of the notification, notice that it desires to contest the appraised value, classification, or rate of duty. Upon receipt of notice from the petitioner, the Secretary shall cause publication to be made of his determination as to the proper appraised value, classification, or rate of duty and of the petitioner’s desire to contest, and shall thereafter furnish the petitioner with such information as to the entries and consignees of such merchandise, entered after the publication of the determination of the Secretary, at such ports of entry designated by the petitioner in his notice of desire to contest, as will enable the petitioner to contest the appraised value, classification, or rate of duty imposed upon such merchandise in the liquidation of one such entry at such port. The Secretary shall direct the appropriate customs officer at such ports to immediately notify the petitioner by mail when the first of such entries is liquidated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05523e8f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Appraisal, classification, and liquidation of entries of merchandise covered by published decisions of Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the filing of an action pursuant to chapter 169 of title 28, merchandise of the character covered by the published decision of the Secretary (when entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption on or before the date of publication of a decision of the United States Court of International Trade or of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, not in harmony with the published decision of the Secretary) shall be appraised or classified, or both, and the entries liquidated, in accordance with the decision of the Secretary and, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the final liquidations of these entries shall be conclusive upon all parties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05523e90-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Consignee or his agent as party in interest before the Court of International Trade</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The consignee or his agent shall have the right to appear and to be heard as a party in interest before the United States Court of International Trade.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05523e91-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Appraisement, classification, and assessment of duty of merchandise covered by published decision of Secretary in accordance with final judicial decision of Court of International Trade or Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit sustaining cause of action in whole or in part; suspension of liquidation of entries; publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the cause of action is sustained in whole or in part by a decision of the United States Court of International Trade or of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, merchandise of the character covered by the published decision of the Secretary, which is entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption after the date of publication in the Federal Register by the Secretary or the administering authority of a notice of the court decision, shall be subject to appraisement, classification, and assessment of duty in accordance with the final judicial decision in the action, and the liquidation of entries covering the merchandise so entered or withdrawn shall be suspended until final disposition is made of the action, whereupon the entries shall be liquidated, or if necessary, reliquidated in accordance with the final decision. Such notice of the court decision shall be published within ten days from the date of the issuance of the court decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05523e92-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1516/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations implementing required procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Regulations shall be prescribed by the Secretary to implement the procedures required under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id05523e93-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 516, <ref href="/us/stat/46/735">46 Stat. 735</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch679/s17/a">June 25, 1938, ch. 679, § 17(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1084">52 Stat. 1084</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s39">June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 39</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/992">62 Stat. 992</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/271/tII/s209">Pub. L. 91–271, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/286">84 Stat. 286</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/tIII">Pub. L. 93–618, title III</ref>, §§ 321(f)(1), 331(b), <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2048">88 Stat. 2048</ref>, 2052; <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/tX/s1001/b/1">Pub. L. 96–39, title X, § 1001(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/303">93 Stat. 303</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/tVI">Pub. L. 96–417, title VI</ref>, §§ 601(6), 607, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1744">94 Stat. 1744</ref>, 1745; <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s163/a/1">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 163(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/49">96 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1888/5">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1888(5)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2925">100 Stat. 2925</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tI/s1326/d/3">Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1326(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1204">102 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id05523e94-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id05523e95-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id05523e96-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s516">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 516</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/970">42 Stat. 970</ref>. That section was superseded by section 516 of act <date date="1930-06-17">June 17, 1930</date>, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id05523e97-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> inserted “Such term includes an association, a majority of whose members is composed of persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsecs. (d), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> substituted “Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit” for “Court of Customs and Patent Appeals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/s607/a">Pub. L. 96–417, § 607(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated as subpars. (A), (B), and (C), former pars. (1), (2), and (3), struck out “(as defined in section 1677(9)(C), (D), and (E) of this title)” after “interested party”, covered in par. (2), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/417">Pub. L. 96–417</ref>, §§ 601(6), 607(b), redesignated the United States Customs Court as the United States Court of International Trade and substituted reference to chapter 169 for <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2632">section 2632 of title 28</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/s601/6">Pub. L. 96–417, § 601(6)</ref>, redesignated the United States Customs Court as the United States Court of International Trade.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—<ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref> completely revised the section to provide an expedited process for judicial review of an appealable determination, expanded the size of the group of parties having standing to obtain review of an appealable determination, and, in the process, revised subsecs. (a), (b), and (c), redesignated former subsecs. (e), (f), (g), and (h) as (d), (e), (f), and (g), and struck out former subsec. (d) relating to the contest of the Secretary’s determination that foreign merchandise was not being sold in the United States at less than fair value or that bounty or grant was not being paid.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s331/b">Pub. L. 93–618, § 331(b)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to additional duty described in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1303">section 1303 of this title</ref> (to be known as “countervailing duties”) and to special duty described in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s161">section 161 of this title</ref> (to be known as “antidumping duties”).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s331/b">Pub. L. 93–618, § 331(b)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to countervailing duties and antidumping duties.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s321/f/1">Pub. L. 93–618, § 321(f)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and redesignated subsecs. (d) to (g) as (e) to (h), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref> substituted provisions requiring the Secretary to furnish to the American manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler the classification, and the rate of duty, if any, imposed upon designated imported merchandise, and provisions authorizing the American manufacturer, etc., to file a protest with the Secretary if the appraised value is too low, the classification is not correct, or the proper rate of duty is not being assessed, for provisions setting forth the procedure for the determination of a protest by an American manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler that the appraised value of any imported merchandise of a class or kind manufactured, produced, or sold at wholesale by him is too low.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref> substituted provisions authorizing the Secretary to determine the proper appraised value, classification, or rate of duty of the imported merchandise, and to notify the American manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler of his determination, for provision setting forth the procedure for the determination of a protest by an American manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler that the classification of, and the rate of duty, if any, is not proper.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref> substituted provisions setting forth the procedure for the petitioner to contest the decisions of the Secretary with respect to a petition filed pursuant to subsec. (a) of this section, for provisions requiring the collector to mail to the consignee or his agent a copy of every appeal and every protest filed by an American manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler, and authorizing such consignee or his agent to appear and be heard as a party in interest before the Customs Court.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref> added subsecs. (d) to (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, repealed last sentence relating to procedure of proceeding over all other cases on Customs Court docket. See sections 2602 and 2638 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, repealed last sentence relating to finality of Customs Court’s decision. See <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2637">section 2637 of Title 28</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, repealed subsec. (d) relating to inspection of documents. See <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2634">section 2634 of Title 28</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1938—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, amended subsec. (b) generally.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id05523e98-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523e99-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> applicable with respect to investigations initiated after <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, and to reviews initiated under section 1673e(c) or 1675 of this title after <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1337/b">section 1337(b) of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523e9a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523e9b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/417">Pub. L. 96–417</ref> effective <date date="1980-11-01">Nov. 1, 1980</date>, and applicable with respect to civil actions pending on or commenced on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/s701/a">section 701(a) of Pub. L. 96–417</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s251">section 251 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523e9c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref> effective <date date="1980-01-01">Jan. 1, 1980</date>, see sections 1002 and 107 of <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref>, set out as Effective Date notes under sections 1516a and 1671 of this title, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523e9d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/618/tIII/s321/g/3">Pub. L. 93–618, title III, § 321(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2049">88 Stat. 2049</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/618/tIII/s321/g/3">“The amendment made by subsection (f) [amending this section and sections 2631 and 2632 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure] shall apply with respect to determinations under section 201 of the Antidumping Act, 1921 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s160">section 160 of this title</ref>], resulting from questions of dumping raised or presented on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s331/b">section 331(b) of Pub. L. 93–618</ref> effective <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s331/d/1">section 331(d)(1) of Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1315">section 1315 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523e9e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/271">Pub. L. 91–271</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/271/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 91–271</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1500">section 1500 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523e9f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1948 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s38">Act June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 38</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/992">62 Stat. 992</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that act is effective <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05523ea0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1938 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, effective on thirtieth day following <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, except as otherwise specifically provided, see section 37 of act <date date="1938-06-25">June 25, 1938</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id05523ea1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1801–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id05523ea2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of Subsection (b) to Complaints</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch679/s17/b">Act June 25, 1938, ch. 679, § 17(b)</ref>, (c), <ref href="/us/stat/52/1086">52 Stat. 1086</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1951-06-16/ch141/s9/b">act June 16, 1951, ch. 141, § 9(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/75">65 Stat. 75</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/act/1951-06-16/ch141/s9/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The provisions of subsection (b) of section 516 of the Tariff Act of 1930 [this section], as amended by this act, shall apply only in the case of complaints filed after the effective date of this act [see Effective Date of 1938 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>]. The provisions of subsection (b) of section 516 of the Tariff Act of 1930, as in force prior to the effective date of this act, shall continue in force with respect to any proceedings commenced by the filing of a complaint thereunder, except that upon the expiration of thirty days after the effective date of this act, or upon the expiration of thirty days after the date of a decision of the Secretary adverse to the complainant, whichever is the later, any such proceedings in which a protest has not been duly filed shall be deemed to have been terminated unless the complainant shall have filed with the Secretary after the effective date of this act a notice that he desires to protest the classification of, or rate of duty assessed upon, the merchandise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> [Repealed. <ref href="/us/act/1951-06-16/ch141/s9/b">June 16, 1951, ch. 141, § 9(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/75">65 Stat. 75</ref>.]</heading><content>”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id05523ea3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id05523ea4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Secretary of the Treasury under this section insofar as they relate to any protest, petition, or notice of desire to contest described in section 1002(b)(1) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1516a">section 1516a of this title</ref>, transferred to Secretary of Commerce pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1979, § 5(a)(1)(D), 44 F.R. 69275, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1381">93 Stat. 1381</ref>, eff. <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, as provided by section 1–107(a) of Ex. Ord. No. 11288, <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, 45 F.R. 993, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2171">section 2171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
