<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id05596a3a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1551"><num value="1551">§ 1551.</num><heading> Bonding of carriers</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under such regulations and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05596a3b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1551/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any common carrier of merchandise owning or operating a railroad, steamship, or other transportation line or route for the transportation of merchandise in the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05596a3c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1551/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any contract carrier authorized to operate as such by any agency of the United States, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05596a3d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1551/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any freight forwarder authorized to operate as such by any agency of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">upon application, may, in the discretion of the Secretary, be designated as a carrier of bonded merchandise for the final release of which from customs custody a permit has not been issued. A private carrier, upon application, may, in the discretion of the Secretary, be designated under the preceding sentence as a carrier of bonded merchandise, subject to such regulations and, in the case of each applicant, to such special terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe to safeguard the revenues of the United States with respect to the transportation of bonded merchandise by such applicant.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id05596a3e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 551, <ref href="/us/stat/46/742">46 Stat. 742</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1945-12-28/ch605">Dec. 28, 1945, ch. 605</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/667">59 Stat. 667</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/598">Pub. L. 87–598</ref>, <date date="1962-08-24">Aug. 24, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/400">76 Stat. 400</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/854">Pub. L. 87–854</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1130">76 Stat. 1130</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/240/s3">Pub. L. 90–240, § 3</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/776">81 Stat. 776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id05596a3f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id05596a40-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id05596a41-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s551">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 551</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/975">42 Stat. 975</ref>. That section was superseded by section 551 of act <date date="1930-06-17">June 17, 1930</date>, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior provisions concerning transportation of merchandise in bond without appraisement to another port of entry were contained in the Immediate Transportation <ref href="/us/act/1880-06-10/ch190">Act of June 10, 1880, ch. 190</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/21/173">21 Stat. 173</ref>, as amended, section 3 of which required the merchandise to be transported by carriers designated by the Secretary of the Treasury, and required them to give bonds as the Secretary should require. That act was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s643">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 643</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/989">42 Stat. 989</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id05596a42-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/240">Pub. L. 90–240</ref> provided that a private carrier, upon application, could, in the discretion of the Secretary, be designated as a carrier of bonded merchandise, subject to regulations, terms, and conditions prescribed by the Secretary, safeguard the revenues of the United States with respect to the transportation of bonded merchandise by such applicant.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/854">Pub. L. 87–854</ref> amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Under such regulations and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe, any common carrier of merchandise owning or operating a railroad, steamship, or other transportation line or route for the transportation of merchandise in the United States, or any freightforwarder authorized to operate as such by any agency of the United States, upon application, may, in the discretion of the Secretary, be designated as a carrier of bonded merchandise for the final release of which from customs custody a permit has not been issued.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/87/598">Pub. L. 87–598</ref> substituted “authorized to operate as such by any agency of the United States,” for “, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1002/5">section 1002(5) of title 49</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1945—Act <date date="1945-12-28">Dec. 28, 1945</date>, substituted “Under such regulations and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe, any common carrier of merchandise owning or operating a railroad, steamship, or other transportation line or route for the transportation of merchandise in the United States, or any freight forwarder, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1002/5">section 1002(5) of title 49</ref>, upon application, may, in the discretion of the Secretary” for “Any common carrier of merchandise owning or operating railroad, steamship, or other transportation lines or routes for the transportation of merchandise in the United States, upon application and the filing of a bond in a form and penalty and with such sureties as may be approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, may”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
