<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id056a0c57-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1621"><num value="1621">§ 1621.</num><heading> Limitation of actions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No suit or action to recover any duty under section 1592(d), 1593a(d) of this title, or any pecuniary penalty or forfeiture of property accruing under the customs laws shall be instituted unless such suit or action is commenced within five years after the time when the alleged offense was discovered, or in the case of forfeiture, within 2 years after the time when the involvement of the property in the alleged offense was discovered, whichever was later; except that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056a0c58-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1621/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of an alleged violation of section 1592 or 1593a of this title, no suit or action (including a suit or action for restoration of lawful duties under subsection (d) of such sections) may be instituted unless commenced within 5 years after the date of the alleged violation or, if such violation arises out of fraud, within 5 years after the date of discovery of fraud, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056a0c59-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1621/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the time of the absence from the United States of the person subject to the penalty or forfeiture, or of any concealment or absence of the property, shall not be reckoned within the 5-year period of limitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id056a0c5a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 621, <ref href="/us/stat/46/758">46 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-05/ch438">Aug. 5, 1935, ch. 438</ref>, title III, § 306, <ref href="/us/stat/49/527">49 Stat. 527</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/410/tI/s110/e">Pub. L. 95–410, title I, § 110(e)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/897">92 Stat. 897</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/182/tVI/s668">Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 668</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2216">107 Stat. 2216</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/185/s11">Pub. L. 106–185, § 11</ref>, <date date="2000-04-25">Apr. 25, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/217">114 Stat. 217</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id056a0c5b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id056a0c5c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id056a0c5d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s621">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 621</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/988">42 Stat. 988</ref>. That section was superseded by section 621 of act <date date="1930-06-17">June 17, 1930</date>, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions substantially similar to those in this section, except that the period of limitation was three years, were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1874-06-22/ch391/s22">act June 22, 1874, ch. 391, § 22</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/18/190">18 Stat. 190</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch356/tIV/s643">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 643</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/989">42 Stat. 989</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id056a0c5e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/185">Pub. L. 106–185</ref> inserted “, or in the case of forfeiture, within 2 years after the time when the involvement of the property in the alleged offense was discovered, whichever was later” after “within five years after the time when the alleged offense was discovered” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/182">Pub. L. 103–182</ref> inserted “any duty under section 1592(d), 1593a(d) of this title, or” before “any pecuniary penalty” and substituted “discovered; except that—” along with pars. (1) and (2) for “discovered: <i>Provided</i>, That in the case of an alleged violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1592">section 1592 of this title</ref> arising out of gross negligence or negligence, such suit or action shall not be instituted more than five years after the date the alleged violation was committed: <i>Provided further</i>, That the time of the absence from the United States of the person subject to such penalty or forfeiture, or of any concealment or absence of the property, shall not be reckoned within this period of limitation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/410">Pub. L. 95–410</ref> prescribed for any suit or action for violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1592">section 1592 of this title</ref> arising out of gross negligence or negligence a five year limitation period following date of alleged violation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-05">Aug. 5, 1935</date>, substituted “the alleged offense was discovered” for “such penalty or forfeiture accrued”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id056a0c5f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id056a0c60-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/185">Pub. L. 106–185</ref> applicable to any forfeiture proceeding commenced on or after the date that is 120 days after <date date="2000-04-25">Apr. 25, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/185/s21">section 21 of Pub. L. 106–185</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1324">section 1324 of Title 8</ref>, Aliens and Nationality.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id056a0c61-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/410">Pub. L. 95–410</ref> for alleged violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1592">section 1592 of this title</ref> arising out of gross negligence or negligence committed on or after <date date="1978-10-03">Oct. 3, 1978</date>, or before such date without commencement of proceedings except where barred by provisions of this section in effect prior to such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/410/s110/f/2">section 110(f)(2) of Pub. L. 95–410</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1592">section 1592 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
