<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id056c7cc0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a"><num value="1628a">§ 1628a.</num><heading> Exchange of information related to trade enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id056c7cc1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to subsections (c) and (d), if the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection suspects that merchandise is being imported into the United States in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1526">section 1526 of this title</ref> or section 602, 1201(a)(2), or 1201(b)(1) of title 17 and determines that the examination or testing of the merchandise by a person described in subsection (b) would assist the Commissioner in determining if the merchandise is being imported in violation of that section, the Commissioner, to permit the person to conduct the examination and testing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056c7cc2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall provide to the person information that appears on the merchandise and its packaging and labels, including unredacted images of the merchandise and its packaging and labels; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056c7cc3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may, subject to any applicable bonding requirements, provide to the person unredacted samples of the merchandise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id056c7cc4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Person described</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person described in this subsection is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056c7cc5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of merchandise suspected of being imported in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1526">section 1526 of this title</ref>, the owner of the trademark suspected of being copied or simulated by the merchandise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056c7cc6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the case of merchandise suspected of being imported in violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t17/s602">section 602 of title 17</ref>, the owner of the copyright suspected of being infringed by the merchandise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056c7cc7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of merchandise suspected of being primarily designed or produced for the purpose of circumventing a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work protected under that title, and being imported in violation of section 1201(a)(2) of that title, the owner of a copyright in the work; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id056c7cc8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in the case of merchandise suspected of being primarily designed or produced for the purpose of circumventing protection afforded by a technological measure that effectively protects a right of an owner of a copyright in a work or a portion of a work, and being imported in violation of section 1201(b)(1) of that title, the owner of the copyright.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id056c7cc9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subsection (a) applies only with respect to merchandise suspected of infringing a trademark or copyright that is recorded with U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id056c7cca-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1628a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner may not provide under subsection (a) information, photographs, or samples to a person described in subsection (b) if providing such information, photographs, or samples would compromise an ongoing law enforcement investigation or national security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id056c7ccb-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title IV, § 628A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 114–125, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/149">130 Stat. 149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
