<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id058b7681-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a"><num value="1681a">§ 1681a.</num><heading> Requirements for entry of certain cigarettes and smokeless tobacco products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id058b7682-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products may be imported into the United States only if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7683-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the original manufacturer of those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products has timely submitted, or has certified that it will timely submit, to the Secretary of Health and Human Services the lists of the ingredients added to the tobacco in the manufacture of such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1335a">section 1335a of title 15</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4403">section 4403 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7684-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> the precise warning statements in the precise format specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333">section 1333 of title 15</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4402">section 4402 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be, are permanently imprinted on both—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id058b7685-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the primary packaging of all those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id058b7686-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any other pack, box, carton, or container of any kind in which those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products are to be offered for sale or otherwise distributed to consumers;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7687-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the manufacturer or importer of those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products is in compliance with respect to those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products being imported into the United States with a rotation plan approved by the Federal Trade Commission pursuant to section 1333(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002058">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002058"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 15 or section 4402(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002058">1</ref> of title 15, as the case may be;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7688-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> if such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products bear a United States trademark registered for such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products, the owner of such United States trademark registration for cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products (or a person authorized to act on behalf of such owner) has consented to the importation of such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products into the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7689-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the importer has submitted at the time of entry all of the certificates described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id058b768a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products satisfying the conditions of any of the following paragraphs shall not be subject to the requirements of subsection (a):</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id058b768b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Personal-use cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products that are imported into the United States in personal use quantities that are allowed entry free of tax and duty under subchapter IV of chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States. The preceding sentence shall not apply to any cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products sold in connection with a delivery sale.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id058b768c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products imported into the United States for analysis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products that are imported into the United States solely for the purpose of analysis in quantities suitable for such purpose, but only if the importer submits at the time of entry a certificate signed, under penalties of perjury, by the consignee (or a person authorized by such consignee) providing such facts as may be required by the Secretary to establish that such consignee is a manufacturer of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products, a Federal or State government agency, a university, or is otherwise engaged in bona fide research and stating that such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products will be used solely for analysis and will not be sold in domestic commerce in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id058b768d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products intended for noncommercial use, reexport, or repackaging</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id058b768e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for which the owner of such United States trademark registration for cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products (or a person authorized to act on behalf of such owner) has consented to the importation of such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products into the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id058b768f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for which the importer submits a certificate signed by the manufacturer or export warehouse (or a person authorized by such manufacturer or export warehouse) to which such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products are to be delivered (as provided in subparagraph (A)) stating, under penalties of perjury, with respect to those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products, that it will not distribute those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products into domestic commerce unless prior to such distribution all steps have been taken to comply with paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a), and, to the extent applicable, section 5754(a)(1)(B) and (C) of title 26.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this section, a trademark is registered in the United States if it is registered in the United States Patent and Trademark Office under the provisions of title I of the Act of <date date="1946-07-05">July 5, 1946</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">15 U.S.C. 1051</ref> et seq.] (popularly known as the “Trademark Act of 1946”), and a copy of the certificate of registration of such mark has been filed with the Secretary. The Secretary shall make available to interested parties a current list of the marks so filed.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id058b7690-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Customs certifications required for cigarette or smokeless tobacco product imports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The certificates that must be submitted by the importer of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products at the time of entry in order to comply with subsection (a)(5) are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7691-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a certificate signed by the manufacturer of such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products or an authorized official of such manufacturer stating under penalties of perjury, with respect to those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products, that such manufacturer has timely submitted, and will continue to submit timely, to the Secretary of Health and Human Services the ingredient reporting information required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1335a">section 1335a of title 15</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4403">section 4403 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7692-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> a certificate signed by such importer or an authorized official of such importer stating under penalties of perjury that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id058b7693-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the precise warning statements in the precise format required by <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333">section 1333 of title 15</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4402">section 4402 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be, are permanently imprinted on both—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id058b7694-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the primary packaging of all those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id058b7695-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any other pack, box, carton, or container of any kind in which those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products are to be offered for sale or otherwise distributed to consumers; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id058b7696-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products being imported into the United States, such importer has complied, and will continue to comply, with a rotation plan approved by the Federal Trade Commission pursuant to section 1333(c) <sup>1</sup> of title 15 or section 4402(d) <sup>1</sup> of title 15, as the case may be; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7697-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7698-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products bear a United States trademark registered for cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products, a certificate signed by the owner of such United States trademark registration for cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products (or a person authorized to act on behalf of such owner) stating under penalties of perjury that such owner (or authorized person) consents to the importation of such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products into the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b7699-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a certificate signed by the importer or an authorized official of such importer stating under penalties of perjury that the consent referred to in subparagraph (A) is accurate, remains in effect, and has not been withdrawn.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary may provide by regulation for the submission of certifications under this section in electronic form if, prior to the entry of any cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products into the United States, the person required to provide such certifications submits to the Secretary a written statement, signed under penalties of perjury, verifying the accuracy and completeness of all information contained in such electronic submissions.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id058b769a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> State access to customs certifications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A State, through its Attorney General, shall be entitled to obtain copies of any certification required under subsection (c) directly—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b769b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> upon request to the agency of the United States responsible for collecting such certification; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id058b769c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s1681a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> upon request to the importer, manufacturer, or authorized official of such importer or manufacturer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id058b769d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, title VIII, § 802, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/476/tIV/s4004/a">Pub. L. 106–476, title IV, § 4004(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2178">114 Stat. 2178</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dC/tIV/s401/b">Pub. L. 109–432, div. C, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, (c), (e)(1), (2), (4)(B), <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3048">120 Stat. 3048</ref>, 3049.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id058b769e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id058b769f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id058b76a0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is not set out in the Code. See Publication of Harmonized Tariff Schedule note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trademark Act of 1946, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-05/ch540">act July 5, 1946, ch. 540</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/427">60 Stat. 427</ref>, also popularly known as the Lanham Act. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1051 et seq.) of chapter 22 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1051">section 1051 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1333 and 4402 of title 15, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3) and (c)(2)(B), were amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dA/tII">Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 201(a), 202(b), 204(a), 205(a), 206, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1842">123 Stat. 1842</ref>, 1845, 1846, 1848, 1849, and, as so amended, sections 1333(c) and 4402(d) no longer relate to the Federal Trade Commission’s approval of a rotation plan.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id058b76a1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another section 802 of act <date date="1930-06-17">June 17, 1930</date>, is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1683">section 1683 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id058b76a2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/4/B">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(4)(B)</ref>, inserted “and smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/A/i">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4403">section 4403 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1335a">section 1335a of title 15</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4402">section 4402 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be,” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333">section 1333 of title 15</ref>” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/A/iii">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4402/d">section 4402(d) of title 15</ref>, as the case may be” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333/c">section 1333(c) of title 15</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” wherever appearing, was executed by making the insertion after “Cigarettes” in introductory provisions, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/B/i">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” wherever appearing, was executed by making the insertion after “Cigarettes” in subsec. (b)(1), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/b">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(b)</ref>, inserted at end “The preceding sentence shall not apply to any cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products sold in connection with a delivery sale.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “Cigarettes” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” wherever appearing, was executed by making the insertion after “Cigarettes” and “cigarettes” wherever appearing, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/C/i">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco product” after “cigarette” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in introductory and concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4403">section 4403 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1335a">section 1335a of title 15</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/C/iii">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(C)(iii)</ref>, inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4402">section 4402 of title 15</ref>, as the case may be,” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333">section 1333 of title 15</ref>” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” in cls. (i) and (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/2/C/iv">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(2)(C)(iv)</ref>, inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4402/d">section 4402(d) of title 15</ref>, as the case may be” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1333/c">section 1333(c) of title 15</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/e/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “or smokeless tobacco products” after “cigarettes” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/c">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(c)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id058b76a3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id058b76a4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/432">Pub. L. 109–432</ref> applicable with respect to goods entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after the 15th day after <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/g">section 401(g) of Pub. L. 109–432</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id058b76a5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 30 days after <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/476/s4004/b">section 4004(b) of Pub. L. 106–476</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
