<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id05951350-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2011"><num value="2011">§ 2011.</num><heading> Implementation of the Agreement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05951351-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2011/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Modification of Harmonized Tariff Schedule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to proclaim the modifications of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States provided for in title IV of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05951352-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2011/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duty-free treatment of Canadian motor-vehicle equipment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At any time after the issuance of the proclamation authorized by subsection (a), the President is authorized to proclaim further modifications of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to provide for the duty-free treatment of any Canadian article which is original motor-vehicle equipment (as defined by such Schedules as modified pursuant to subsection (a)) if he determines that the importation of such article is actually or potentially of commercial significance and that such duty-free treatment is required to carry out the Agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id05951353-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/283/tII/s201">Pub. L. 89–283, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1016">79 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tI/s1214/i">Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1214(i)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1157">102 Stat. 1157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id05951354-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id05951355-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id05951356-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, referred to in text, is not set out in the Code. See Publication of Harmonized Tariff Schedule note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title IV of this Act, referred to in subsec. (a), means title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/89/283">Pub. L. 89–283</ref> which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref> and Schedules 2, 3, 5, 6, and 7 of the Tariff Schedules of the United States, and enacted provisions set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Agreement, referred to in subsec. (b), is the Agreement Concerning Automotive Products, which was entered into between the United States and Canada on <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, see Proc. No. 3682, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 13683 and Proc. No. 3743, <date date="1966-09-08">Sept. 8, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 12003, set out as notes below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id05951357-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States” for “Tariff Schedules of the United States”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id05951358-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05951359-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> effective <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, and applicable with respect to articles entered on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1217/b/1">section 1217(b)(1) of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0595135a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0595135b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proc. No. 3682. Implementation of Agreement Concerning Automotive Products</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 3682, <date date="1965-10-21">Oct. 21, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 13683, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS the United States and Canada on <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, entered into an Agreement Concerning Automotive Products, which provides that Canada shall accord duty-free treatment to imports of certain automotive products of the United States and that, after enactment of implementing legislation, the United States shall accord duty-free treatment to certain automotive products of Canada retroactively to the earliest date administratively possible following the date on which the agreement has been implemented by Canada (art. II, 89th Cong. 1st sess., H. Rep. 537, 38);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS the agreement of <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, was implemented by Canada through the granting of the requisite duty-free treatment to United States products on <date date="1965-01-18">January 18, 1965</date>;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS title II [sections 2011 to 2015 of this title] and IV [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>] of the Automotive Products Trade Act of 1965 have been enacted to provide for modifications of the Tariff Schedules of the United States (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">19 U.S.C. 1202</ref>) to implement the agreement of <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, such modifications to enter into force in the manner proclaimed by the President (<ref href="/us/stat/79/1016">79 Stat. 1016</ref>);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS sections 201(a) and 203 of the Automotive Products Trade Act of 1965 [subsec. (a) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref>] authorize the President to proclaim the modifications of the Tariff Schedules of the United States provided for in sections 403, 404, and 405 of that Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>] with retroactive effect as of the earliest date after <date date="1965-01-17">January 17, 1965</date>, which he determines to be practicable, and section 401(b) of that Act provides that the rates of duty in column numbered 1 of the tariff schedules that are modified pursuant to such proclamation shall be treated as having been proclaimed by the President as being required to carry out a foreign trade agreement to which the United States is a party (<ref href="/us/stat/79/1016">79 Stat. 1016</ref>); and</p>
<p>WHEREAS I determine that the earliest date, after <date date="1965-01-17">January 17, 1965</date>, as of which it is practicable to give retroactive effect to this proclamation is <date date="1965-01-18">January 18, 1965</date>:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">NOW, THEREFORE, I, LYNDON B. JOHNSON, under the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the statutes, particularly sections 201(a) and 203 of the Automotive Products Trade Act of 1965 [subsec. (a) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref>], do proclaim (1) that the modifications of the Tariff Schedules of the United States provided for in sections 403 and 404 of that Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>] shall enter into force on the day following the date of this proclamation, and (2) that the modifications of the tariff schedules provided for in section 405 of that Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>] shall enter into force on <date date="1965-12-20">December 20, 1965</date>, effective with respect to articles which are or have been entered for consumption, or for warehouse, on or after <date date="1965-01-18">January 18, 1965</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand and caused the Seal of the United States of America to be affixed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">DONE at the City of Washington this twenty-first day of October in the year of our Lord nineteen hundred and sixty-five, and of the Independence of the United States of America the one hundred and ninetieth.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">[<inline class="small-caps">seal]</inline></p>
<signature>
<name>Lyndon B. Johnson.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0595135c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proc. No. 3743. Implementation of Agreement Concerning Automotive Products</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 3743, <date date="1966-09-08">Sept. 8, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 12003, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS the United States and Canada on <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, entered into an Agreement Concerning Automotive Products, which provides that Canada shall accord duty-free treatment to imports of certain automotive products of the United States and that, after enactment of implementing legislation, the United States shall accord duty-free treatment to certain automotive products of Canada retroactively to the earliest date administratively possible following the date on which the agreement has been implemented by Canada (art. II, 89th Cong. 1st sess., H. Rep. 537, 38);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS, the agreement of <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, was implemented by Canada through the granting of the requisite duty-free treatment to United States products on <date date="1965-01-18">January 18, 1965</date>;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS titles II [sections 2011 to 2015 of this title] and IV of the Automotive Products Trade Act of 1965 [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>] have been enacted to provide for modifications of the Tariff Schedules of the United States (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">19 U.S.C. 1202</ref>) to implement the agreement of <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, such modifications to enter into force in the manner proclaimed by the President (<ref href="/us/stat/79/1016">79 Stat. 1016</ref>);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS sections 201 and 203 of the Automotive Products Trade Act of 1965 [sections 2011 and 2013 of this title] authorize the President to proclaim such modifications of the Tariff Schedules of the United States as will provide for the duty-free treatment of Canadian articles which are original motor-vehicle equipment either if the modifications of such articles are set forth in title IV of that Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>] or if the President subsequently determines that the importation of the articles is actually or potentially of commercial significance and that such duty-free treatment is required by the agreement, such proclamation to provide for retroactive effect for such duty-free treatment as of the earliest date after <date date="1965-01-17">January 17, 1965</date>, which the President determines to be practicable;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS, by Proclamation No. 3682 of <date date="1965-10-21">October 21, 1965</date> (30 F.R. 13683), the President pursuant to sections 201 and 203 [sections 2011 and 2013 of this title] proclaimed the modifications of the Tariff Schedules of the United States provided for in title IV of the Automotive Products Trade Act of 1965 [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>]; and</p>
<p>WHEREAS I determine (a) under subsection (b) of section 201 [subsection (b) of this section] that the importation of the Canadian articles which are original motor-vehicle equipment and which are dutiable under TSUS items 688.04, 688.06, and 688.15 is actually or potentially of commercial significance and that duty-free treatment of such Canadian articles is required to carry out the agreement of <date date="1965-01-16">January 16, 1965</date>, and (b) under section 203 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref>] that the earliest date, after <date date="1965-01-17">January 17, 1965</date>, as of which it is practicable to give retroactive effect to this proclamation is <date date="1965-01-18">January 18, 1965</date>:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">NOW, THEREFORE, I, LYNDON, B. JOHNSON, under the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the statutes, particularly sections 201(b) and 203 of the Automotive Products Trade Act of 1965 [subsection (b) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref>] do proclaim that the Tariff Schedules of the United States are modified by inserting in proper numerical sequence new items 688.05, 688.07, and 688.16, each such item having the article description “If Canadian article and original motor-vehicle equipment (see headnote 2, part 6B, schedule 6) . . .” subordinate to the immediately preceding article description and having “Free” in rate of duty column numbered 1. Such modifications shall enter into force on the day following the date of this proclamation and shall be effective with respect to articles which are or have been entered for consumption, or for warehouse, on or after <date date="1965-01-18">January 18, 1965</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand and caused the Seal of the United States of America to be affixed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">DONE at the City of Washington this eighth day of September in the year of our Lord nineteen hundred and sixty-six, and of the Independence of the United States of America the one hundred and ninety-first.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">[<inline class="small-caps">seal]</inline></p>
<signature>
<name>Lyndon B. Johnson.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
