<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id05951399-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2051"><num value="2051">§ 2051.</num><heading> Implementation of the Agreement; executive designation and duty of Federal agencies</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President of the United States is authorized to designate a Federal agency or agencies which shall be responsible for carrying out the provisions of the Agreement for Facilitating the International Circulation of Visual and Auditory Materials of an Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Character and a related protocol of signature, opened for signature at Lake Success on <date date="1949-07-15">July 15, 1949</date> (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Agreement”). It shall be the duty of the Federal agency or agencies so designated to take appropriate measures for the carrying out of the provisions of the Agreement including the issuance of regulations. In carrying out this section, such Federal agency or agencies may not consider visual or auditory material to fail to qualify as being of international educational character—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0595139a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2051/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> because it advocates a particular position or viewpoint, whether or not it presents or acknowledges opposing viewpoints;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0595139b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2051/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> because it might lend itself to misinterpretation, or to misrepresentation of the United States or other countries, or their people or institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0595139c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2051/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> because it is not representative, authentic, or accurate or does not represent the current state of factual knowledge of a subject or aspect of a subject unless the material contains widespread and gross misstatements of fact;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0595139d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2051/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> because it does not augment international understanding and goodwill, unless its primary purpose or effect is not to instruct or inform through the development of a subject or an aspect of a subject and its content is not such as to maintain, increase, or diffuse knowledge; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0595139e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2051/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> because in the opinion of the agency the material is propaganda.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such Federal agency or agencies may not label as propaganda any material that receives a certificate of international educational character under this section and the Agreement.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id0595139f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/634/s1">Pub. L. 89–634, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-10-08">Oct. 8, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/879">80 Stat. 879</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tII/s207">Pub. L. 102–138, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/693">105 Stat. 693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id059513a0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id059513a1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id059513a2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/138">Pub. L. 102–138</ref> inserted provisions at end limiting the authority of a Federal agency or agencies to fail to qualify visual or auditory material as being of international educational character and providing that any material that receives a certificate of international educational character not be labeled as propaganda.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id059513a3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id059513a4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11311. Implementation of Beirut Agreement Relating to Audio-Visual Materials</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11311, <date date="1966-10-14">Oct. 14, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 13413, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me as President of the United States, including the provisions of the Joint Resolution of <date date="1966-10-08">October 8, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/89/634">Public Law 89–634</ref> [this chapter and amendment to <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of this title</ref>], and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref> of the United States Code, I hereby order and proclaim that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1. Pursuant to section 3(b) of the Joint Resolution, the amendments to the Tariff Schedules of the United States made by section 3(a) of the Joint Resolution shall apply with respect to articles entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption, on and after <date date="1967-01-01">January 1, 1967</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2. Pursuant to the “Agreement for Facilitating the International Circulation of Visual and Auditory Materials of an Educational, Scientific and Cultural Character”, made at Beirut in 1948, the Joint Resolution, and headnote 1 to schedule 8, part 6 of the Tariff Schedules of the United States, the United States Information Agency is hereby designated as the agency to carry out the provisions of the Agreement and related protocol, and to make any determinations and to prescribe any regulations required by headnote 1.</p>
<signature>
<name>Lyndon B. Johnson.</name>
</signature>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For abolition of United States Information Agency (other than Broadcasting Board of Governors and International Broadcasting Bureau), transfer of functions, and treatment of references thereto, see sections 6531, 6532, and 6551 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
