<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id05aa708d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2154"><num value="2154">§ 2154.</num><heading> Prerequisites for offers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id05aa708e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2154/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In any negotiation seeking an agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2133">section 2133 of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s4202">section 4202 of this title</ref>, the President may make a formal offer for the modification or continuance of any United States duty, import restrictions, or barriers to (or other distortions of) international trade, the continuance of United States duty-free or excise treatment, or the imposition of additional duties, import restrictions, or other barrier to (or other distortion of) international trade including trade in services, foreign direct investment and intellectual property as covered by this subchapter, with respect to any article or matter only after he has received a summary of the hearings at which an opportunity to be heard with respect to such article has been afforded under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>. In addition, the President may make an offer for the modification or continuance of any United States duty, the continuance of United States duty-free or excise treatment, or the imposition of additional duties, with respect to any article included in a list published and furnished under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2151/a">section 2151(a) of this title</ref>, only after he has received advice concerning such article from the Commission under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2151/b">section 2151(b) of this title</ref>, or after the expiration of the 6-month or 90-day period provided for in that section, as appropriate, whichever first occurs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id05aa708f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2154/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> In determining whether to make offers described in subsection (a) in the course of negotiating any trade agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s4202">section 4202 of this title</ref>, and in determining the nature and scope of such offers, the President shall take into account any advice or information provided, or reports submitted, by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05aa7090-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2154/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05aa7091-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2154/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any advisory committee established under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2155">section 2155 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05aa7092-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2154/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any organization that holds public hearings under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">with respect to any article, or domestic industry, that is sensitive, or potentially sensitive, to imports.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id05aa7093-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/618/tI/s134">Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1995">88 Stat. 1995</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tI/s1111/a">Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1111(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1137">102 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/dB/tXXI/s2110/a/3">Pub. L. 107–210, div. B, title XXI, § 2110(a)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1020">116 Stat. 1020</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/26/tI/s110/a/4">Pub. L. 114–26, title I, § 110(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/357">129 Stat. 357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id05aa7094-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id05aa7095-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id05aa7096-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—<ref href="/us/pl/114/26">Pub. L. 114–26</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s4202">section 4202 of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803">section 3803 of this title</ref>” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/s2110/a/3">Pub. L. 107–210, § 2110(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803">section 3803 of this title</ref>,” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2902">section 2902 of this title</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/s2110/a/4">Pub. L. 107–210, § 2110(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803">section 3803 of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2902">section 2902 of this title</ref>” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “In any negotiations seeking an agreement under part 1 of this subchapter or section 2133 or 2134 of this title, the President may make an offer for the modification or continuance of any United States duty, import restrictions, or barriers to (or other distortions of) international trade, the continuance of United States duty-free or excise treatment, or the imposition of additional duties, import restriction, or other barrier to (or other distortion of) international trade, with respect to any article only after he has received a summary of the hearings at which an opportunity to be heard with respect to such article has been afforded under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>. In addition, the President may make an offer for the modification or continuance of any United States duty, the continuance of United States duty-free or excise treatment, or the imposition of additional duties, with respect to any article included in a list published and furnished under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2151/a">section 2151(a) of this title</ref>, only after he has received advice concerning such article from the International Trade Commission under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2151/b">section 2151(b) of this title</ref>, or after the expiration of the 6-month or 90-day period provided for in that section, as appropriate, whichever first occurs.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id05ace197-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id05ace198-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under div. B of <ref href="/us/pl/107/210">Pub. L. 107–210</ref>, amending this section, see section 1 of Ex. Ord. No. 13277, <date date="2002-11-19">Nov. 19, 2002</date>, 67 F.R. 70305, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3801">section 3801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
