<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id05c96a84-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311"><num value="2311">§ 2311.</num><heading> Agreements with States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05c96a85-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary to enter into agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized on behalf of the United States to enter into an agreement with any State, or with any State agency (referred to in this subpart as “cooperating States” and “cooperating States agencies” respectively). Under such an agreement, the cooperating State agency (1) as agent of the United States, will receive applications for, and will provide, payments on the basis provided in this part, (2) where appropriate, but in accordance with subsection (f) of this section, will afford adversely affected workers testing, counseling, referral to training and job search programs, and placement services, (3) will make any certifications required under section 2291(c)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002103">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002103"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title, and (4) will otherwise cooperate with the Secretary and with other State and Federal agencies in providing payments and services under this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05c96a86-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Amendment, suspension, and termination of agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each agreement under this subpart shall provide the terms and conditions upon which the agreement may be amended, suspended, or terminated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05c96a87-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Unemployment insurance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each agreement under this subpart shall provide that unemployment insurance otherwise payable to any adversely affected worker will not be denied or reduced for any week by reason of any right to payments under this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05c96a88-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A determination by a cooperating State agency with respect to entitlement to program benefits under an agreement is subject to review in the same manner and to the same extent as determinations under the applicable State law and only in that manner and to that extent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05c96a89-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of benefits and assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any agreement entered into under this section shall provide for the coordination of the administration of the provisions for employment services, training, and supplemental assistance under sections 2295 and 2296 of this title and under title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 <sup>1</sup> upon such terms and conditions as are established by the Secretary in consultation with the States and set forth in such agreement. Any agency of the State jointly administering such provisions under such agreement shall be considered to be a cooperating State agency for purposes of this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05c96a8a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Advising and interviewing adversely affected workers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each cooperating State agency shall, in carrying out subsection (a)(2)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05c96a8b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> advise each worker who applies for unemployment insurance of the benefits under this part and the procedures and deadlines for applying for such benefits,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05c96a8c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> facilitate the early filing of petitions under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref> for any workers that the agency considers are likely to be eligible for benefits under this part,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05c96a8d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> advise each adversely affected worker to apply for training under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2296/a">section 2296(a) of this title</ref> before, or at the same time, the worker applies for trade readjustment allowances under division I of subpart B, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05c96a8e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> as soon as practicable, interview the adversely affected worker regarding suitable training opportunities available to the worker under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2296">section 2296 of this title</ref> and review such opportunities with the worker.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05c96a8f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2311/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of information for coordination of workforce investment activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to promote the coordination of workforce investment activities in each State with activities carried out under this part, any agreement entered into under this section shall provide that the State shall submit to the Secretary, in such form as the Secretary may require, the description and information described in paragraphs (8) and (14) of section 112(b) of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998.<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id05c96a90-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/618/tII/s239">Pub. L. 93–618, title II, § 239</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2024">88 Stat. 2024</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXV/s2513/d/6">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXV, § 2513(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/889">95 Stat. 889</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXIII">Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII</ref>, §§ 13003(a)(3), 13004(c), <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/301">100 Stat. 301</ref>, 303; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tI">Pub. L. 100–418, title I</ref>, §§ 1423(a)(4), 1424(d)(1)(B), (2), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1246">102 Stat. 1246</ref>, 1250; <ref href="/us/pl/105/220/tIII/s321">Pub. L. 105–220, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1087">112 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/14/B">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(14)(B), (f)(11)(B)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–421, 2681–431; <ref href="/us/pl/111/5/dB/tI">Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title I</ref>, §§ 1852, 1853, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/390">123 Stat. 390</ref>, 392; <ref href="/us/pl/112/40/tII">Pub. L. 112–40, title II</ref>, §§ 201(b), (c), 216(a)(1), <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/403">125 Stat. 403</ref>, 407; <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tV/s512/hh/4">Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(hh)(4)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1721">128 Stat. 1721</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/27/tIV">Pub. L. 114–27, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(b), (c), 404(a), <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/374">129 Stat. 374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id05c96a91-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id05c96a92-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Termination of Assistance</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For termination of assistance under this part after <date date="2022-06-30">June 30, 2022</date>, see Termination Date note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id05c96a93-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id05c96a94-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2291/c/2">Section 2291(c)(2) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(3), was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/dA/tI/s115/a">Pub. L. 107–210, div. A, title I, § 115(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/939">116 Stat. 939</ref>, and, as so amended, no longer contains provisions relating to certifications.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Workforce Investment Act of 1998, referred to in subsecs. (e) and (g), is <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/936">112 Stat. 936</ref>, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/tV">Pub. L. 113–128, title V</ref>, §§ 506, 511(a), <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1703">128 Stat. 1703</ref>, 1705, effective <date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>. Title I of the Act was classified principally to chapter 30 (§ 2801 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. Section 112 of the Act was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2822">section 2822 of Title 29</ref>. Pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3361/a">section 3361(a) of Title 29</ref>, references to a provision of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 are deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1425">128 Stat. 1425</ref>. For complete classification of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to the Code, see Tables. For complete classification of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id05c96a95-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section reflects the <date date="2021-07-01">July 1, 2021</date>, reversion to provisions in effect on <date date="2014-01-01">Jan. 1, 2014</date>. See Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of subsecs. (a) to (k) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 93–618</ref>. Another subsec. (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 93–618</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3302">section 3302 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/5/s1852/b/1">section 1852(b)(1) of Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, which directed the temporary redesignation of subsecs. (c) through (g) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 93–618</ref> as subsecs. (d) through (h), respectively, was executed by redesignating subsecs. (c) to (g) set out in this section and not redesignating the subsec. (e) that amended <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3302">section 3302 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/40/s233">Section 233 of Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, which provided for the <date date="2014-01-01">Jan. 1, 2014</date>, revival of this section as in effect on <date date="2011-02-13">Feb. 13, 2011</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/114/27/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 114–27, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/374">129 Stat. 374</ref>, and the provisions of this section, as in effect on <date date="2013-12-31">Dec. 31, 2013</date>, were temporarily revived, effective <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, until <date date="2021-07-01">July 1, 2021</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 402(b), (c), 406. See 2011 and 2015 Amendment notes, Effective and Termination Dates of 2011 Revival notes, and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> was effective <date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>, and was executed to this section as it existed on <date date="2013-12-31">Dec. 31, 2013</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/114/27/s402/b">section 402(b) of Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, which revived the provisions of this section, effective <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>. See 2014 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/5/s1893">Section 1893 of Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, which provided for <date date="2011-02-13">Feb. 13, 2011</date>, termination of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/112/40/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/403">125 Stat. 403</ref>, and the provisions of this section, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref> and as in effect on <date date="2011-02-12">Feb. 12, 2011</date>, were temporarily revived, effective <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, until <date date="2014-01-01">Jan. 1, 2014</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, §§ 201(b), (c), 233. See 2009 and 2011 Amendment notes, Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment notes, and Effective and Termination Dates of 2011 Revival notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1424/d/1/B">section 1424(d)(1)(B) of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, was executed to the subsec. (e) (now subsec. (f)) set out in this section and not the subsec. (e) that amended <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3302">section 3302 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id05c96a96-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—<ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 402(b), (c), 406, temporarily revived the provisions of this section, as in effect on <date date="2013-12-31">Dec. 31, 2013</date>. See Codification note above and 2011 Amendment and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(1), 406, temporarily substituted “Performance measures” for “Data reporting” in heading. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(2)(A), 406, in introductory provisions, temporarily substituted “an annual” for “a quarterly” and “measures” for “data”. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(2)(B), 406, temporarily substituted “primary” for “core”. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(2)(C), 406, temporarily inserted “that promote efficiency and effectiveness” after “assistance program”. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(3)(A), 406, temporarily substituted “Indicators of performance” for “Core indicators described” in heading. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(3)(B), 406, temporarily amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) set out 4 core indicators of performance to be reported as part of the comprehensive performance accountability data. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(4), 406, temporarily substituted “measures” for “data” in heading and “annual” for “quarterly” and “measures” for “data” in text. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, §§ 404(a)(5), 406, temporarily added par. (4). See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s512/hh/4/A">Pub. L. 113–128, § 512(hh)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “Any agreement entered into under this section shall provide for the coordination of the administration of the provisions for employment services, training, and supplemental assistance under sections 2295 and 2296 of this title and under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act” for “Any agreement entered into under this section shall provide for the coordination of the administration of the provisions for employment services, training, and supplemental assistance under sections 2295 and 2296 of this title and under title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998”. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s512/hh/4/B">Pub. L. 113–128, § 512(hh)(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “the descriptions described in sections 102(b)(2)(B)(ii) and 103(b)(3)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, a description of how the State board will carry out the activities described in section 101(d)(3)(F) of such Act,” for “the description and information described in paragraphs (8) and (14) of section 112(b) of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2822/b">29 U.S.C. 2822(b)</ref>)”. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, §§ 201(b), (c), 233, temporarily revived the provisions of this section, as in effect on <date date="2011-02-12">Feb. 12, 2011</date>. See Codification note above and 2009 Amendment and Effective and Termination Dates of 2011 Revival notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, §§ 216(a)(1), 233, temporarily amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The core indicators of performance described in this paragraph are—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the percentage of workers receiving benefits under this part who are employed during the second calendar quarter following the calendar quarter in which the workers cease receiving such benefits;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the percentage of such workers who are employed in each of the third and fourth calendar quarters following the calendar quarter in which the workers cease receiving such benefits; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) the earnings of such workers in each of the third and fourth calendar quarters following the calendar quarter in which the workers cease receiving such benefits.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2011 Revival note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(a)(2), 1893, temporarily substituted “shall” for “will” in two places. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(a)(1), 1893, temporarily amended cl. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (2) read as follows: “where appropriate, but in accordance with subsection (f) of this section, will afford adversely affected workers testing, counseling, referral to training and job search programs, and placement services,”. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(a)(2), 1893, temporarily substituted “shall” for “will”. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(b), 1893, temporarily added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsecs. (c) to (e) as (d) to (f), respectively. Former subsec. (f) temporarily redesignated (g). See Codification notes above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(b)(1), 1893, temporarily redesignated subsec. (f) as (g). Former subsec. (g) temporarily redesignated (h). See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(c)(1), 1893, temporarily struck out “and” at end. See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(c)(2), 1893, temporarily amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows: “as soon as practicable, interview the adversely affected worker regarding suitable training opportunities available to the worker under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2296">section 2296 of this title</ref> and review such opportunities with the worker.” See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(c)(3), 1893, temporarily added par. (5). See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(b)(1), (d), 1893, temporarily redesignated subsec. (g) as (h) and substituted “1998 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2822/b">29 U.S.C. 2822(b)</ref>) and a description of the State’s rapid response activities under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271/a/2/A">section 2271(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref>.” for “1998.” See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i) to (k). <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, §§ 1852(e), 1853, 1893, temporarily added subsecs. (i) to (k). See Codification note above and Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/f/11/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(11)(B)]</ref>, struck out “title III of the Job Training Partnership Act or” before “title I of the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/14/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(14)(B)]</ref>, substituted “under title III of the Job Training Partnership Act or title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998” for “under title III of the Job Training Partnership Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Pub. L. 105–220</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1423/a/4">Pub. L. 100–418, § 1423(a)(4)</ref>, amended cl. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (3) read as follows: “will make determinations and approvals regarding job search programs under sections 2291(c) and 2297(c) of this title, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1424/d/1/B">Pub. L. 100–418, § 1424(d)(1)(B)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) read as follows: “Agreements entered into under this section may be made with one or more State or local agencies including—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the employment service agency of such State,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) any State agency carrying out title III of the Job Training Partnership Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1651">29 U.S.C. 1651</ref> et seq.], or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) any other State or local agency administering job training or related programs.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1424/d/2">Pub. L. 100–418, § 1424(d)(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (f) read as follows: “Each cooperating State agency shall, in carrying out subsection (a)(2) of this section—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) advise each adversely affected worker to apply for training under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2296/a">section 2296(a) of this title</ref> at the time the worker makes application for trade readjustment allowances (but failure of the worker to do so may not be treated as cause for denial of those allowances), and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) within 60 days after application for training is made by the worker, interview the adversely affected worker regarding suitable training opportunities available to the worker under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2296">section 2296 of this title</ref> and review such opportunities with the worker.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s13004/c/1">Pub. L. 99–272, § 13004(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “but in accordance with subsection (f) of this section,” in cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s13003/a/3">Pub. L. 99–272, § 13003(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “training and job search programs” for “training” in cl. (2), added cl. (3), and redesignated former cl. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s13004/c/2">Pub. L. 99–272, § 13004(c)(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> struck out provisions respecting persons applying for payments under this part.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id05c96a97-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id05c96a98-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 2015 Revival</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For revival and applicability, beginning on <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, of the provisions of this section as in effect on <date date="2013-12-31">Dec. 31, 2013</date>, see section 402(b), (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/114/27">Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For reversion, beginning on <date date="2021-07-01">July 1, 2021</date>, to the provisions of this section as in effect on <date date="2014-01-01">Jan. 1, 2014</date>, with certain exceptions and subject to <ref href="/us/pl/114/27/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/27/s406">section 406 of Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05c96a99-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref> effective on the first day of the first full program year after <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date> (<date date="2015-07-01">July 1, 2015</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/113/128/s506">section 506 of Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id05c96a9a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 2011 Revival</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For revival and applicability, beginning on <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, of the provisions of this section as in effect on <date date="2011-02-12">Feb. 12, 2011</date>, see section 201(b), (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/40/s233">Section 233 of Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, formerly set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref>, which provided for the reversion, beginning on <date date="2014-01-01">Jan. 1, 2014</date>, of the provisions of this section to those in effect on <date date="2011-02-13">Feb. 13, 2011</date>, subject to certain exceptions, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/114/27/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 114–27, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/374">129 Stat. 374</ref>, effective <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>. See Codification note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05c96a9b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/40/tII/s216/a/2">Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 216(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/407">125 Stat. 407</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/40/tII/s216/a/2">
<inline>“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall—</inline>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> take effect on <date date="2011-10-01">October 1, 2011</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> apply with respect to agreements under section 239 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2311">19 U.S.C. 2311</ref>) entered into before, on, or after <date date="2011-10-01">October 1, 2011</date>.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05c96a9c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided and subject to certain applicability provisions, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref> effective upon the expiration of the 90-day period beginning on <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/5/s1891">section 1891 of Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/5/s1893">Section 1893 of Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, formerly set out as a Termination Date of 2009 Amendment note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref>, which provided that, except as otherwise provided, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref> not applicable on or after <date date="2011-02-13">Feb. 13, 2011</date>, and that this section be applied and administered beginning <date date="2011-02-13">Feb. 13, 2011</date>, as if amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref> had never been enacted, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/112/40/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/403">125 Stat. 403</ref>, effective <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>. See Codification note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05c96a9d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(14)(B)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, and amendment by section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(f)(11)(B)] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>, see section 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(g)(1), (2)(B)], set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3502">section 3502 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05c96a9e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1424(d)(1)(B), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> effective <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s1423/a/4">section 1423(a)(4) of Pub. L. 100–418</ref> effective on the date that is 90 days after <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, see section 1430(a), (f) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2397">section 2397 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05c96a9f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s13003/a">section 13003(a) of Pub. L. 99–272</ref> applicable with respect to workers covered by petitions filed under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref> on or after <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s13004/c">section 13004(c) of Pub. L. 99–272</ref> effective on <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, see section 13009(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2291">section 2291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id05c96aa0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment and Transition Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective Aug. 1981, with transition provisions applicable, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2514">section 2514 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2291">section 2291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="terminationDate" id="id05c96aa1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">No trade adjustment assistance, vouchers, allowances, or other payments or benefits may be provided under this part after <date date="2022-06-30">June 30, 2022</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/618/s285">section 285 of Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, as modified by <ref href="/us/pl/114/27/s406/a/7">section 406(a)(7) of Pub. L. 114–27</ref>, set out as notes preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2271">section 2271 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
