<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id05f471db-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606"><num value="2606">§ 2606.</num><heading> Import restrictions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05f471dc-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Documentation of lawful exportation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No designated archaeological or ethnological material that is exported (whether or not such exportation is to the United States) from the State Party after the designation of such material under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref> may be imported into the United States unless the State Party issues a certification or other documentation which certifies that such exportation was not in violation of the laws of the State Party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05f471dd-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Customs action in absence of documentation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the consignee of any designated archaeological or ethnological material is unable to present to the customs officer concerned at the time of making entry of such material—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05f471de-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the certificate or other documentation of the State Party required under subsection (a); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05f471df-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> satisfactory evidence that such material was exported from the State Party—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id05f471e0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not less than ten years before the date of such entry and that neither the person for whose account the material is imported (or any related person) contracted for or acquired an interest, directly or indirectly, in such material more than one year before that date of entry, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id05f471e1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> on or before the date on which such material was designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref>,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the customs officer concerned shall refuse to release the material from customs custody and send it to a bonded warehouse or store to be held at the risk and expense of the consignee, notwithstanding any other provision of law, until such documentation or evidence is filed with such officer. If such documentation or evidence is not presented within ninety days after the date on which such material is refused release from customs custody, or such longer period as may be allowed by the Secretary for good cause shown, the material shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture. The presentation of such documentation or evidence shall not bar subsequent action under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2609">section 2609 of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05f471e2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> “Satisfactory evidence” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “satisfactory evidence” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05f471e3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> for purposes of subsection (b)(2)(A)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id05f471e4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> one or more declarations under oath by the importer, or the person for whose account the material is imported, stating that, to the best of his knowledge—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id05f471e5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the material was exported from the State Party not less than ten years before the date of entry into the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id05f471e6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> neither such importer or person (or any related person) contracted for or acquired an interest, directly or indirectly, in such material more than one year before the date of entry of the material; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id05f471e7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a statement provided by the consignor, or person who sold the material to the importer, which states the date, or, if not known, his belief, that the material was exported from the State Party not less than ten years before the date of entry into the United States, and the reasons on which the statement is based; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05f471e8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> for purposes of subsection (b)(2)(B)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id05f471e9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> one or more declarations under oath by the importer or the person for whose account the material is to be imported, stating that, to the best of his knowledge, the material was exported from the State Party on or before the date such material was designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id05f471ea-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a statement by the consignor or person who sold the material to the importer which states the date, or if not known, his belief, that the material was exported from the State Party on or before the date such material was designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2604">section 2604 of this title</ref>, and the reasons on which the statement is based.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id05f471eb-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Related persons</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (b) and (c), a person shall be treated as a related person to an importer, or to a person for whose account material is imported, if such person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05f471ec-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is a member of the same family as the importer or person of account, including, but not limited to, membership as a brother or sister (whether by whole or half blood), spouse, ancestor, or lineal descendant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05f471ed-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is a partner or associate with the importer or person of account in any partnership, association, or other venture; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id05f471ee-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s2606/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> is a corporation or other legal entity in which the importer or person of account directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds power to vote 20 percent or more of the outstanding voting stock or shares in the entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id05f471ef-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/446/tIII/s307">Pub. L. 97–446, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2358">96 Stat. 2358</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id05f471f0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id05f471f1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id05f471f2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the 90th day after <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, or on any date which the President shall prescribe and publish in the Federal Register, with exceptions, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/446/s315">section 315 of Pub. L. 97–446</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2601">section 2601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id05f471f3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id05f471f4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of certain functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12555, <date date="1986-03-10">Mar. 10, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 8475, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2602">section 2602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
