<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id06078522-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203"><num value="3203">§ 3203.</num><heading> Eligible articles</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id06078523-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id06078524-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Unless otherwise excluded from eligibility (or otherwise provided for) by this chapter, the duty-free treatment (or preferential treatment) provided under this chapter shall apply to any article which is the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary country if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id06078525-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that article is imported directly from a beneficiary country into the customs territory of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id06078526-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078527-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the cost or value of the materials produced in a beneficiary country or 2 or more beneficiary countries under this chapter, or a beneficiary country under the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2701">19 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.] or 2 or more such countries, plus</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078528-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the direct costs of processing operations performed in a beneficiary country or countries (under this chapter or the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">is not less than 35 percent of the appraised value of such article at the time it is entered.</continuation>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of determining the percentage referred to in subparagraph (B), the term “beneficiary country” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands. If the cost or value of materials produced in the customs territory of the United States (other than the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) is included with respect to an article to which this paragraph applies, an amount not to exceed 15 percent of the appraised value of the article at the time it is entered that is attributed to such United States cost or value may be applied toward determining the percentage referred to in subparagraph (B).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id06078529-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out paragraph (1) including, but not limited to, regulations providing that, in order to be eligible for duty-free treatment under this chapter, an article must be wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary country, or must be a new or different article of commerce which has been grown, produced, or manufactured in the beneficiary country; but no article or material of a beneficiary country shall be eligible for such treatment by virtue of having merely undergone—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0607852a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> simple combining or packaging operations, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0607852b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> mere dilution with water or mere dilution with another substance that does not materially alter the characteristics of the article.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0607852c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> As used in this subsection, the phrase “direct costs of processing operations” includes, but is not limited to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0607852d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all actual labor costs involved in the growth, production, manufacture, or assembly of the specific merchandise, including fringe benefits, on-the-job training and the cost of engineering, supervisory, quality control, and similar personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0607852e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> dies, molds, tooling, and depreciation on machinery and equipment which are allocable to the specific merchandise.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such phrase does not include costs which are not directly attributable to the merchandise concerned or are not costs of manufacturing the product, such as (i) profit, and (ii) general expense of doing business which are either not allocable to the specific merchandise or are not related to the growth, production, manufacture, or assembly of the merchandise, such as administrative salaries, casualty and liability insurance, advertising, interest, and salesmen’s salaries, commissions or expenses.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0607852f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the President, pursuant to section 223 of the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Expansion Act of 1990, considers that the implementation of revised rules of origin for products of beneficiary countries designated under the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2701">19 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.) would be appropriate, the President may include similarly revised rules of origin for products of beneficiary countries designated under this chapter in any suggested legislation transmitted to the Congress that contains such rules of origin for products of beneficiary countries under the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id06078530-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions and special rules</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id06078531-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain articles that are not import-sensitive</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may proclaim duty-free treatment under this chapter for any article described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) that is the growth, product, or manufacture of an ATPDEA beneficiary country, that is imported directly into the customs territory of the United States from an ATPDEA beneficiary country, and that meets the requirements of this section, if the President determines that such article is not import-sensitive in the context of imports from ATPDEA beneficiary countries:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078532-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Footwear not designated at the time of the effective date of this chapter as eligible for purposes of the generalized system of preferences under title V of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2461">19 U.S.C. 2461</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078533-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Petroleum, or any product derived from petroleum, provided for in headings 2709 and 2710 of the HTS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078534-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Watches and watch parts (including cases, bracelets and straps), of whatever type including, but not limited to, mechanical, quartz digital or quartz analog, if such watches or watch parts contain any material which is the product of any country with respect to which HTS column 2 rates of duty apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078535-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Handbags, luggage, flat goods, work gloves, and leather wearing apparel that were not designated on <date date="1983-08-05">August 5, 1983</date>, as eligible articles for purposes of the generalized system of preferences under title V of the Trade Act of 1974.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id06078536-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (3), duty-free treatment under this chapter may not be extended to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078537-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> textiles and apparel articles which were not eligible articles for purposes of this chapter on <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>, as this chapter was in effect on that date;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078538-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> rum and tafia classified in subheading 2208.40 of the HTS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id06078539-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> sugars, syrups, and sugar-containing products subject to over-quota duty rates under applicable tariff-rate quotas; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0607853a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> tuna prepared or preserved in any manner in airtight containers, except as provided in paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0607853b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Apparel articles and certain textile articles</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0607853c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Apparel articles that are imported directly into the customs territory of the United States from an ATPDEA beneficiary country shall enter the United States free of duty and free of any quantitative restrictions, limitations, or consultation levels, but only if such articles are described in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0607853d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered articles</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The apparel articles referred to in subparagraph (A) are the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0607853e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Apparel articles assembled from products of the United States or ATPDEA beneficiary countries or products not available in commercial quantities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Apparel articles sewn or otherwise assembled in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries, or the United States, or both, exclusively from any one or any combination of the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0607853f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Fabrics or fabric components wholly formed, or components knit-to-shape, in the United States, from yarns wholly formed in the United States or 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the HTS and are formed in the United States). Apparel articles shall qualify under this subclause only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled, if the fabrics are knit fabrics, is carried out in the United States. Apparel articles shall qualify under this subclause only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled, if the fabrics are woven fabrics, is carried out in the United States.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078540-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Fabrics or fabric components formed or components knit-to-shape, in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries, from yarns wholly formed in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries, if such fabrics (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the HTS and are formed in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries) or components are in chief value of llama, alpaca, or vicuña.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078541-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Fabrics or yarns, to the extent that apparel articles of such fabrics or yarns would be eligible for preferential treatment, without regard to the source of the fabrics or yarns, under Annex 401 of the NAFTA.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078542-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional fabrics</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">At the request of any interested party, the President is authorized to proclaim additional fabrics and yarns as eligible for preferential treatment under clause (i)(III) if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078543-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the President determines that such fabrics or yarns cannot be supplied by the domestic industry in commercial quantities in a timely manner;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078544-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the President has obtained advice regarding the proposed action from the appropriate advisory committee established under section 135 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2155">19 U.S.C. 2155</ref>) and the United States International Trade Commission;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078545-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> within 60 days after the request, the President has submitted a report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate that sets forth the action proposed to be proclaimed and the reasons for such action, and the advice obtained under subclause (II);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078546-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> a period of 60 calendar days, beginning with the first day on which the President has met the requirements of subclause (III), has expired; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078547-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> the President has consulted with such committees regarding the proposed action during the period referred to in subclause (III).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078548-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Apparel articles assembled in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries from regional fabrics or regional components</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id06078549-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Subject to the limitation set forth in subclause (II), apparel articles sewn or otherwise assembled in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries from fabrics or from fabric components formed or from components knit-to-shape, in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries, from yarns wholly formed in the United States or 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the HTS and are formed in 1 or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries), whether or not the apparel articles are also made from any of the fabrics, fabric components formed, or components knit-to-shape described in clause (i) (unless the apparel articles are made exclusively from any of the fabrics, fabric components formed, or components knit-to-shape described in clause (i)).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0607854a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> The preferential treatment referred to in subclause (I) shall be extended in the 1-year period beginning <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>, and in each of the 10 succeeding 1-year periods, to imports of apparel articles in an amount not to exceed the applicable percentage of the aggregate square meter equivalents of all apparel articles imported into the United States in the preceding 12-month period for which data are available.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0607854b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><chapeau> For purposes of subclause (II), the term “applicable percentage” means—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0607854c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/iii/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> 2 percent for the 1-year period beginning <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>, increased in each of the 4 succeeding 1-year periods by equal increments, so that for the period beginning <date date="2006-10-01">October 1, 2006</date>, the applicable percentage does not exceed 5 percent; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0607854d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/iii/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> for the 1-year period beginning <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>, and for the succeeding 5-year period, the percentage determined under item (aa) for the 1-year period beginning <date date="2006-10-01">October 1, 2006</date>.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0607854e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Handloomed, handmade, and folklore articles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A handloomed, handmade, or folklore article of an ATPDEA beneficiary country identified under subparagraph (C) that is certified as such by the competent authority of such beneficiary country.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0607854f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain other apparel articles</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id06078550-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/v/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Any apparel article classifiable under subheading 6212.10 of the HTS, except for articles entered under clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv), if the article is both cut and sewn or otherwise assembled in the United States, or one or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries, or both.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id06078551-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/v/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">During the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>, and during each of the 9 succeeding 1-year periods, apparel articles described in subclause (I) of a producer or an entity controlling production shall be eligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph only if the aggregate cost of fabrics (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) formed in the United States that are used in the production of all such articles of that producer or entity that are entered and eligible under this clause during the preceding 1-year period is at least 75 percent of the aggregate declared customs value of the fabric (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) contained in all such articles of that producer or entity that are entered and eligible under this clause during the preceding 1-year period.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id06078552-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/v/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of procedure to ensure compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The United States Customs Service shall develop and implement methods and procedures to ensure ongoing compliance with the requirement set forth in subclause (II). If the Customs Service finds that a producer or an entity controlling production has not satisfied such requirement in a 1-year period, then apparel articles described in subclause (I) of that producer or entity shall be ineligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph during any succeeding 1-year period until the aggregate cost of fabrics (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) formed in the United States that are used in the production of such articles of that producer or entity entered during the preceding 1-year period is at least 85 percent of the aggregate declared customs value of the fabric (exclusive of all findings and trimmings) contained in all such articles of that producer or entity that are entered and eligible under this clause during the preceding 1-year period.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078553-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi"><num value="vi" class="bold">(vi)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id06078554-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for findings and trimmings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">An article otherwise eligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the article contains findings or trimmings of foreign origin, if such findings and trimmings do not exceed 25 percent of the cost of the components of the assembled product. Examples of findings and trimmings are sewing thread, hooks and eyes, snaps, buttons, “bow buds”, decorative lace, trim, elastic strips, zippers, including zipper tapes and labels, and other similar products.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id06078555-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain interlining</heading><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078556-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> An article otherwise eligible for preferential treatment under this paragraph shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the article contains certain interlinings of foreign origin, if the value of such interlinings (and any findings and trimmings) does not exceed 25 percent of the cost of the components of the assembled article.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078557-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> Interlinings eligible for the treatment described in division (aa) include only a chest type plate, “hymo” piece, or “sleeve header”, of woven or weft-inserted warp knit construction and of coarse animal hair or man-made filaments.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078558-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> The treatment described in this subclause shall terminate if the President makes a determination that United States manufacturers are producing such interlinings in the United States in commercial quantities.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id06078559-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> De minimis rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">An article that would otherwise be ineligible for preferential treatment under this subparagraph because the article contains yarns not wholly formed in the United States or in one or more ATPDEA beneficiary countries shall not be ineligible for such treatment if the total weight of all such yarns is not more than 7 percent of the total weight of the good.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0607855a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vi/IV"><num value="IV" class="bold">(IV)</num><heading class="bold"> Special origin rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">An article otherwise eligible for preferential treatment under clause (i) or (iii) shall not be ineligible for such treatment because the article contains nylon filament yarn (other than elastomeric yarn) that is classifiable under subheading 5402.10.30, 5402.10.60, 5402.31.30, 5402.31.60, 5402.32.30, 5402.32.60, 5402.41.10, 5402.41.90, 5402.51.00, or 5402.61.00 of the HTS from a country that is a party to an agreement with the United States establishing a free trade area, which entered into force before <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0607855b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vii"><num value="vii" class="bold">(vii)</num><heading class="bold"> Textile luggage</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Textile luggage—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0607855c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> assembled in an ATPDEA beneficiary country from fabric wholly formed and cut in the United States, from yarns wholly formed in the United States, that is entered under subheading 9802.00.80 of the HTS; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0607855d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/vii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> assembled from fabric cut in an ATPDEA beneficiary country from fabric wholly formed in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0607855e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/B/viii"><num value="viii" class="bold">(viii)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal of designation of fabrics or yarns not available in commercial quantities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the President determines that any fabric or yarn was determined to be eligible for preferential treatment under clause (i)(III) or (ii) on the basis of fraud, the President is authorized to remove that designation from that fabric or yarn with respect to articles entered after such removal.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0607855f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Handloomed, handmade, and folklore articles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (B)(iv), the President shall consult with representatives of the ATPDEA beneficiary countries concerned for the purpose of identifying particular textile and apparel goods that are mutually agreed upon as being handloomed, handmade, or folklore goods of a kind described in section 2.3(a), (b), or (c) of the Annex or Appendix 3.1.B.11 of the Annex.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id06078560-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties for transshipment</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078561-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties for exporters</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the President determines, based on sufficient evidence, that an exporter has engaged in transshipment with respect to apparel articles from an ATPDEA beneficiary country, then the President shall deny all benefits under this chapter to such exporter, and any successor of such exporter, for a period of 2 years.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078562-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties for countries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Whenever the President finds, based on sufficient evidence, that transshipment has occurred, the President shall request that the ATPDEA beneficiary country or countries through whose territory the transshipment has occurred take all necessary and appropriate actions to prevent such transshipment. If the President determines that a country is not taking such actions, the President shall reduce the quantities of apparel articles that may be imported into the United States from such country by the quantity of the transshipped articles multiplied by 3, to the extent consistent with the obligations of the United States under the WTO.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078563-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/D/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Transshipment described</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Transshipment within the meaning of this subparagraph has occurred when preferential treatment under subparagraph (A) has been claimed for an apparel article on the basis of material false information concerning the country of origin, manufacture, processing, or assembly of the article or any of its components. For purposes of this clause, false information is material if disclosure of the true information would mean or would have meant that the article is or was ineligible for preferential treatment under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id06078564-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Bilateral emergency actions</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078565-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The President may take bilateral emergency tariff actions of a kind described in section 4 of the Annex with respect to any apparel article imported from an ATPDEA beneficiary country if the application of tariff treatment under subparagraph (A) to such article results in conditions that would be cause for the taking of such actions under such section 4 with respect to a like article described in the same 8-digit subheading of the HTS that is imported from Mexico.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id06078566-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules relating to bilateral emergency action</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of applying bilateral emergency action under this subparagraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078567-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the requirements of paragraph (5) of section 4 of the Annex (relating to providing compensation) shall not apply;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078568-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the term “transition period” in section 4 of the Annex shall mean the period ending <date date="2013-07-31">July 31, 2013</date>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id06078569-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/3/E/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the requirements to consult specified in section 4 of the Annex shall be treated as satisfied if the President requests consultations with the ATPDEA beneficiary country in question and the country does not agree to consult within the time period specified under section 4 of the Annex.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0607856a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Tuna</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0607856b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Tuna that is harvested by United States vessels or ATPDEA beneficiary country vessels, that is prepared or preserved in any manner, in an ATPDEA beneficiary country, in foil or other flexible airtight containers weighing with their contents not more than 6.8 kilograms each, and that is imported directly into the customs territory of the United States from an ATPDEA beneficiary country, shall enter the United States free of duty and free of any quantitative restrictions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0607856c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0607856d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> United States vessel</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A “United States vessel” is—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0607856e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a vessel that has a certificate of documentation with a fishery endorsement under chapter 121 of title 46; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce5f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> in the case of a vessel without a fishery endorsement, a vessel that is documented under the laws of the United States and for which a license has been issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s973g">section 973g of title 16</ref>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce60-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> ATPDEA vessel</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">An “ATPDEA vessel” is a vessel—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce61-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> which is registered or recorded in an ATPDEA beneficiary country;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce62-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> which sails under the flag of an ATPDEA beneficiary country;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce63-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> which is at least 75 percent owned by nationals of an ATPDEA beneficiary country or by a company having its principal place of business in an ATPDEA beneficiary country, of which the manager or managers, chairman of the board of directors or of the supervisory board, and the majority of the members of such boards are nationals of an ATPDEA beneficiary country and of which, in the case of a company, at least 50 percent of the capital is owned by an ATPDEA beneficiary country or by public bodies or nationals of an ATPDEA beneficiary country;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce64-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> of which the master and officers are nationals of an ATPDEA beneficiary country; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce65-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/4/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> of which at least 75 percent of the crew are nationals of an ATPDEA beneficiary country.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce66-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Customs procedures</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce67-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce68-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Any importer that claims preferential treatment under paragraph (1), (3), or (4) shall comply with customs procedures similar in all material respects to the requirements of Article 502(1) of the NAFTA as implemented pursuant to United States law, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce69-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce6a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/A/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In order to qualify for the preferential treatment under paragraph (1), (3), or (4) and for a Certificate of Origin to be valid with respect to any article for which such treatment is claimed, there shall be in effect a determination by the President that each country described in subclause (II)—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0609ce6b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/A/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> has implemented and follows, or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0609ce6c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/A/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> is making substantial progress toward implementing and following,</content>
</item>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">  procedures and requirements similar in all material respects to the relevant procedures and requirements under chapter 5 of the NAFTA.</continuation>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce6d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Country described</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">A country is described in this subclause if it is an ATPDEA beneficiary country—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0609ce6e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> from which the article is exported; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0609ce6f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> in which materials used in the production of the article originate or in which the article or such materials undergo production that contributes to a claim that the article is eligible for preferential treatment under paragraph (1), (3), or (4).</content>
</item>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce70-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certificate of Origin</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Certificate of Origin that otherwise would be required pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph (A) shall not be required in the case of an article imported under paragraph (1), (3), or (4) if such Certificate of Origin would not be required under Article 503 of the NAFTA (as implemented pursuant to United States law), if the article were imported from Mexico.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce71-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on cooperation of ATPDEA countries concerning circumvention</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The United States Commissioner of Customs shall conduct a study analyzing the extent to which each ATPDEA beneficiary country—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce72-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has cooperated fully with the United States, consistent with its domestic laws and procedures, in instances of circumvention or alleged circumvention of existing quotas on imports of textile and apparel goods, to establish necessary relevant facts in the places of import, export, and, where applicable, transshipment, including investigation of circumvention practices, exchanges of documents, correspondence, reports, and other relevant information, to the extent such information is available;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce73-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has taken appropriate measures, consistent with its domestic laws and procedures, against exporters and importers involved in instances of false declaration concerning quantities, description, classification, or origin of textile and apparel goods; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce74-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/5/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> has penalized the individuals and entities involved in any such circumvention, consistent with its domestic laws and procedures, and has worked closely to seek the cooperation of any third country to prevent such circumvention from taking place in that third country.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The Commissioner of Customs shall submit to the Congress, not later than <date date="2003-10-01">October 1, 2003</date>, a report on the study conducted under this subparagraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce75-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce76-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Annex</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “the Annex” means Annex 300-B of the NAFTA.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce77-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> ATPDEA beneficiary country</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “ATPDEA beneficiary country” means any “beneficiary country”, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3202/a/1">section 3202(a)(1) of this title</ref>, which the President designates as an ATPDEA beneficiary country, taking into account the criteria contained in subsections (c) and (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3202">section 3202 of this title</ref> and other appropriate criteria, including the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce78-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Whether the beneficiary country has demonstrated a commitment to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce79-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> undertake its obligations under the WTO, including those agreements listed in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3511/d">section 3511(d) of this title</ref>, on or ahead of schedule; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce7a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> participate in negotiations toward the completion of the FTAA or another free trade agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce7b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The extent to which the country provides protection of intellectual property rights consistent with or greater than the protection afforded under the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights described in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3511/d/15">section 3511(d)(15) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce7c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> The extent to which the country provides internationally recognized worker rights, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce7d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the right of association;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce7e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the right to organize and bargain collectively;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce7f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> a prohibition on the use of any form of forced or compulsory labor;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce80-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/iii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> a minimum age for the employment of children; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce81-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/iii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> acceptable conditions of work with respect to minimum wages, hours of work, and occupational safety and health.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce82-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Whether the country has implemented its commitments to eliminate the worst forms of child labor, as defined in section 507(6) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2467/6">19 U.S.C. 2467(6)</ref>].</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce83-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The extent to which the country has met the counternarcotics certification criteria set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291j">section 2291j of title 22</ref> for eligibility for United States assistance.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce84-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> The extent to which the country has taken steps to become a party to and implements the Inter-American Convention Against Corruption.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce85-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><chapeau> The extent to which the country—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce86-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/vii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> applies transparent, nondiscriminatory, and competitive procedures in government procurement equivalent to those contained in the Agreement on Government Procurement described in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3511/d/17">section 3511(d)(17) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0609ce87-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/vii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> contributes to efforts in international fora to develop and implement international rules in transparency in government procurement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0609ce88-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> The extent to which the country has taken steps to support the efforts of the United States to combat terrorism.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce89-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> NAFTA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “NAFTA” means the North American Free Trade Agreement entered into between the United States, Mexico, and Canada on <date date="1992-12-17">December 17, 1992</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce8a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> WTO</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “WTO” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3501">section 3501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce8b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> ATPDEA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “ATPDEA” means the Andean Trade Promotion and Drug Eradication Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce8c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/6/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> FTAA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “FTAA” means the Free Trade Area for the Americas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce8d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of duty-free treatment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce8e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President may by proclamation suspend the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter with respect to any eligible article and may proclaim a duty rate for such article if such action is proclaimed under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2251">19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.] or <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1862">section 1862 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce8f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In any report by the United States International Trade Commission to the President under section 202(f) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2252/f">19 U.S.C. 2252(f)</ref>] regarding any article for which duty-free treatment has been proclaimed by the President pursuant to this chapter, the Commission shall state whether and to what extent its findings and recommendations apply to such article when imported from beneficiary countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce90-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2253">19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>], the suspension of the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter shall be treated as an increase in duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce91-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> No proclamation providing solely for a suspension referred to in paragraph (3) of this subsection with respect to any article shall be taken under section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2253">19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>] unless the United States International Trade Commission, in addition to making an affirmative determination with respect to such article under section 202(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2252/b">19 U.S.C. 2252(b)</ref>], determines in the course of its investigation under such section that the serious injury (or threat thereof) substantially caused by imports to the domestic industry producing a like or directly competitive article results from the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce92-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce93-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any action taken under section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2253">19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>] that is in effect when duty-free treatment is proclaimed under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref> shall remain in effect until modified or terminated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce94-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If any article is subject to any such action at the time duty-free treatment is proclaimed under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>, the President may reduce or terminate the application of such action to the importation of such article from beneficiary countries prior to the otherwise scheduled date on which such reduction or termination would occur pursuant to the criteria and procedures of section 204 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2254">19 U.S.C. 2254</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0609ce95-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency relief with respect to perishable products</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce96-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If a petition is filed with the United States International Trade Commission pursuant to the provisions of section 201 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2251">19 U.S.C. 2251</ref>] regarding a perishable product and alleging injury from imports from beneficiary countries, then the petition may also be filed with the Secretary of Agriculture with a request that emergency relief be granted pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection with respect to such article.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce97-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Within 14 days after the filing of a petition under paragraph (1) of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609ce98-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if the Secretary of Agriculture has reason to believe that a perishable product from a beneficiary country is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities as to be a substantial cause of serious injury, or the threat thereof, to the domestic industry producing a perishable product like or directly competitive with the imported product and that emergency action is warranted, he shall advise the President and recommend that the President take emergency action; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609ce99-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary of Agriculture shall publish a notice of his determination not to recommend the imposition of emergency action and so advise the petitioner.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce9a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Within 7 days after the President receives a recommendation from the Secretary of Agriculture to take emergency action pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, he shall issue a proclamation withdrawing the duty-free treatment provided by this chapter or publish a notice of his determination not to take emergency action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609ce9b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The emergency action provided by paragraph (3) of this subsection shall cease to apply—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609ce9c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> upon the taking of action under section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2253">19 U.S.C. 2253</ref>],</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609ce9d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> on the day a determination by the President not to take action under section 203(b)(2) of such Act becomes final,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609ce9e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the event of a report of the United States International Trade Commission containing a negative finding, on the day of the Commission’s report is submitted to the President, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609ce9f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> whenever the President determines that because of changed circumstances such relief is no longer warranted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0609cea0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term “perishable product” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609cea1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> live plants and fresh cut flowers provided for in chapter 6 of the HTS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609cea2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> fresh or chilled vegetables provided for in headings 0701 through 0709 (except subheading 0709.52.00) and heading 0714 of the HTS;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609cea3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> fresh fruit provided for in subheadings 0804.20 through 0810.90 (except citrons of subheadings 0805.90.00, tamarinds and kiwi fruit of subheading 0810.90.20, and cashew apples, mameyes colorados, sapodillas, soursops and sweetsops of subheading 0810.90.40) of the HTS; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0609cea4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/d/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> concentrated citrus fruit juice provided for in subheadings 2009.11.00, 2009.19.40, 2009.20.40, 2009.30.20, and 2009.30.60 of the HTS.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0609cea5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Fees under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s624">section 624 of title 7</ref></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No proclamation issued pursuant to this chapter shall affect fees imposed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s624">section 624 of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0609cea6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3203/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Tariff-rate quotas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No quantity of an agricultural product subject to a tariff-rate quota that exceeds the in-quota quantity shall be eligible for duty-free treatment under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0609cea7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/182/tII/s204">Pub. L. 102–182, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1239">105 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tIV/s404/e/2">Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 404(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4961">108 Stat. 4961</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/dC/tXXXI/s3103/a">Pub. L. 107–210, div. C, title XXXI, § 3103(a)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1024">116 Stat. 1024</ref>, 1033; <ref href="/us/pl/108/429/tII/s2004/e">Pub. L. 108–429, title II, § 2004(e)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2593">118 Stat. 2593</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dD/tV/s5005/b">Pub. L. 109–432, div. D, title V, § 5005(b)</ref>, title VII, § 7003, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3190">120 Stat. 3190</ref>, 3194; <ref href="/us/pl/110/42/s2">Pub. L. 110–42, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-06-30">June 30, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/235">121 Stat. 235</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/191/s2/b">Pub. L. 110–191, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-02-29">Feb. 29, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/646">122 Stat. 646</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/436/s1/b">Pub. L. 110–436, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-16">Oct. 16, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4977">122 Stat. 4977</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/124/s2/b">Pub. L. 111–124, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-28">Dec. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/3484">123 Stat. 3484</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/344/tII/s201/c">Pub. L. 111–344, title II, § 201(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-29">Dec. 29, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3616">124 Stat. 3616</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/42/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 112–42, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/494">125 Stat. 494</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0609cea8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0609cea9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0609ceaa-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(B) and (f), was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/102/182">Pub. L. 102–182</ref> which enacted this chapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B), (4), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/98/67">Pub. L. 98–67</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/384">97 Stat. 384</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 2701 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2701">section 2701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 223 of the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Expansion Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/382/s223">section 223 of Pub. L. 101–382</ref>, title II, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/659">104 Stat. 659</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(A), means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/102/182">Pub. L. 102–182</ref>, which was approved <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trade Act of 1974, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1)(A), (D), and (c)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/618">Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1978">88 Stat. 1978</ref>. Chapter 1 of title II of the Act is classified generally to part 1 (§ 2251 et seq.) of subchapter II of chapter 12 of this title. Title V of the Act is classified generally to subchapter V (§ 2461 et seq.) of chapter 12 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Andean Trade Promotion and Drug Eradication Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(6)(E), is title XXXI of <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/dC">Pub. L. 107–210, div. C</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1023">116 Stat. 1023</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0609ceab-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/112/42/s501/b/1/A/i">Pub. L. 112–42, § 501(b)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “10 succeeding 1-year periods” for “8 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(III)(bb). <ref href="/us/pl/112/42/s501/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 112–42, § 501(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “and for the succeeding 5-year period” for “and for the succeeding 3-year period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/112/42/s501/b/1/B">Pub. L. 112–42, § 501(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “9 succeeding 1-year periods” for “7 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(E)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/112/42/s501/b/2">Pub. L. 112–42, § 501(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2013-07-31">July 31, 2013</date>” for “<date date="2011-02-12">February 12, 2011</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (b)(3)(E)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/344">Pub. L. 111–344</ref> substituted “<date date="2011-02-12">February 12, 2011</date>” for “<date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/124/s2/b/1/A/i">Pub. L. 111–124, § 2(b)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “8 succeeding 1-year periods” for “7 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(III)(bb). <ref href="/us/pl/111/124/s2/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–124, § 2(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “and for the succeeding 3-year period” for “and for the succeeding 2-year period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/124/s2/b/1/B">Pub. L. 111–124, § 2(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “7 succeeding 1-year periods” for “6 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(E)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/124/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 111–124, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/110/436/s1/b/1/A/i">Pub. L. 110–436, § 1(b)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “7 succeeding 1-year periods” for “6 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/191/s2/b/1/A/i">Pub. L. 110–191, § 2(b)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “6 succeeding 1-year periods” for “5 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(III)(bb). <ref href="/us/pl/110/436/s1/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 110–436, § 1(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “and for the succeeding 2-year period” for “and for the succeeding 1-year period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/191/s2/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 110–191, § 2(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “and for the succeeding 1-year period,” after “for the 1-year period beginning <date date="2007-10-01">October 1, 2007</date>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/110/436/s1/b/1/B">Pub. L. 110–436, § 1(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “6 succeeding 1-year periods” for “5 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/191/s2/b/1/B">Pub. L. 110–191, § 2(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “5 succeeding 1-year periods” for “4 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(E)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/110/436/s1/b/2">Pub. L. 110–436, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2009-12-31">December 31, 2009</date>” for “<date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/191/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 110–191, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>” for “<date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/110/42/s2/1/A">Pub. L. 110–42, § 2(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “The” for “Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3206">section 3206 of this title</ref>, the” and “5 succeeding 1-year periods” for “4 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/110/42/s2/1/B">Pub. L. 110–42, § 2(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “means—” for “means” and “; and” for period, inserted item (aa) designation, and added item (bb).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/110/42/s2/2">Pub. L. 110–42, § 2(2)</ref>, substituted “During” for “Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3206">section 3206 of this title</ref>, during” and “4 succeeding 1-year periods” for “3 succeeding 1-year periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s7003/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 7003(1)</ref>, substituted “Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3206">section 3206 of this title</ref>, the preferential” for “The preferential”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s7003/2">Pub. L. 109–432, § 7003(2)</ref>, substituted “Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3206">section 3206 of this title</ref>, during” for “During”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s5005/b">Pub. L. 109–432, § 5005(b)</ref>, added cl. (viii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(4)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/429">Pub. L. 108–429</ref> reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “A ‘United States vessel’ is a vessel having a certificate of documentation with a fishery endorsement under chapter 121 of title 46.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/s3103/c/2/A">Pub. L. 107–210, § 3103(c)(2)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted “(or otherwise provided for)” after “eligibility” and “(or preferential treatment)” after “duty-free treatment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/s3103/c/2/B">Pub. L. 107–210, § 3103(c)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)” for “subsection (a) of this section” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/s3103/a/2">Pub. L. 107–210, § 3103(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Exceptions and special rules” for “Exceptions to duty-free treatment” in heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The duty-free treatment provided under this chapter shall not apply to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) textile and apparel articles which are subject to textile agreements;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) footwear not designated at the time of the effective date of this chapter as eligible for the purpose of the generalized system of preferences under title V of the Trade Act of 1974;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) tuna, prepared or preserved in any manner, in airtight containers;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) petroleum, or any product derived from petroleum, provided for in headings 2709 and 2710 of the HTS;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(5) watches and watch parts (including cases, bracelets and straps), of whatever type including, but not limited to, mechanical, quartz digital or quartz analog, if such watches or watch parts contain any material which is the product of any country with respect to which HTS column 2 rates of duty apply;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(6) articles to which reduced rates of duty apply under subsection (c) of this section;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(7) sugars, syrups, and molasses classified in subheadings 1701.11.03, 1701.12.02, 1701.99.02, 1702.90.32, 1806.10.42, and 2106.90.12 of the HTS; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(8) rum and tafia classified in subheading 2208.40.00 of the HTS.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/s3103/a/1">Pub. L. 107–210, § 3103(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (d) to (g) as (c) to (f), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (c) which related to duty reductions for certain handbags, luggage, flat goods, work gloves, and leather wearing apparel of beneficiary countries.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0609ceac-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0609cead-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/42">Pub. L. 112–42</ref> applicable to articles entered on or after the 15th day after <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, with retroactive application for certain liquidations and reliquidations, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/42/s501/c">section 501(c) of Pub. L. 112–42</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3805">section 3805 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0609ceae-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s5005/b">section 5005(b) of Pub. L. 109–432</ref> applicable to articles entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after the 15th day after <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s5006">section 5006 of Pub. L. 109–432</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2703">section 2703 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0609ceaf-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> effective on the date of entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States (<date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>), except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/s451">section 451 of Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3601">section 3601 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id0609ceb0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0609ceb1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Articles Eligible for Preferential Treatment Under the Andean Trade Preference Act</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/429/tII/s2003">Pub. L. 108–429, title II, § 2003</ref>, <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2589">118 Stat. 2589</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/429/tII/s2003">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding section 514 of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1514">19 U.S.C. 1514</ref>] or any other provision of law, and subject to subsection (c)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> with respect to any article described in section 204(b)(1)(D) of the Andean Trade Preference Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/1/D">19 U.S.C. 3203(b)(1)(D)</ref>] (as amended by section 3103(a)(2) of the Trade Act of 2002 [<ref href="/us/pl/107/210">Pub. L. 107–210</ref>]) for which the President proclaims duty free treatment pursuant to section 204(b)(1) of the Andean Trade Preference Act, the entry of any such article on or after <date date="2002-08-06">August 6, 2002</date>, and before the date on which the President so proclaims duty free treatment for such article shall be subject to the rate of duty applicable on <date date="2002-08-05">August 5, 2002</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> such entries shall be liquidated or reliquidated as if the reduced duty preferential treatment applied, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall refund any excess duties paid with respect to such entry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Entry</inline>.—</heading><content>As used in this subsection, the term ‘entry’ includes a withdrawal from warehouse for consumption.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requests</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Liquidation or reliquidation may be made under paragraph (1) with respect to an entry only if a request therefor is filed with the Customs Service [Bureau of Customs and Border Protection], within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>], and such request contains sufficient information to enable the Customs Service—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to locate the entry; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to reconstruct the entry if it cannot be located.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0609ceb2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Duty Free or Preferential Treatment of Certain Apparel Articles</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/206/tIII/s3001/b">Pub. L. 107–206, title III, § 3001(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/910">116 Stat. 910</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/206/tIII/s3001/b">“Any duty free or other preferential treatment provided under the Andean Trade Preference Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">19 U.S.C. 3201</ref> et seq.] to apparel articles assembled from fabric formed in the United States shall apply to such articles only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled if the fabrics are knit fabrics, is carried out in the United States. Any duty-free or other preferential treatment provided under the Andean Trade Preference Act to apparel articles assembled from fabric formed in the United States shall apply to such articles only if all dyeing, printing, and finishing of the fabrics from which the articles are assembled if the fabrics are woven fabrics, is carried out in the United States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/107/206/s3001/b">Section 3001(b) of Pub. L. 107–206</ref>, set out above, effective <date date="2002-09-01">Sept. 1, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/206/s3001/c">section 3001(c) of Pub. L. 107–206</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2002 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2703">section 2703 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0609ceb3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0609ceb4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under div. C of <ref href="/us/pl/107/210">Pub. L. 107–210</ref>, amending this section, see section 2 of Ex. Ord. No. 13277, <date date="2002-11-19">Nov. 19, 2002</date>, 67 F.R. 70305, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3801">section 3801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0609ceb5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proc. No. 7616. To Implement the Andean Trade Promotion and Drug Eradication Act</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 7616, <date date="2002-10-31">Oct. 31, 2002</date>, 67 F.R. 67283, as amended by Proc. No. 7748, <date date="2003-12-30">Dec. 30, 2003</date>, 69 F.R. 227, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1. Section 3103 of the Andean Trade Promotion and Drug Eradication Act (title XXXI of the Trade Act of 2002, <ref href="/us/pl/107/210">Public Law 107–210</ref>) [see Tables for classification] (ATPDEA) amended section 204(b) of the Andean Trade Preference Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b">19 U.S.C. 3203(b)</ref>) (ATPA) to provide that certain preferential tariff treatment may be provided to eligible articles that are the product of any country that the President designates as an “ATPDEA beneficiary country” pursuant to section 204(b)(6)(B) of the ATPA, as amended, provided that the President determines that the country has satisfied the requirements of section 204(b)(5)(A)(ii)(I) of the ATPA, as amended, relating to the implementation of procedures and requirements similar to those in chapter 5 of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2. Section 3103(a)(2) of the ATPDEA amended section 204(b) of the ATPA to authorize the President to proclaim duty-free treatment for any article described in section 204(b)(1)(A) through (D) of the ATPA, as amended, that is the growth, product, or manufacture of an ATPDEA beneficiary country, that is imported directly into the customs territory of the United States from an ATPDEA beneficiary country, and that meets the requirements of section 204 of the ATPA, as amended, if the President determines that such article is not import-sensitive in the context of imports from ATPDEA beneficiary countries, provided that the President determines that the country has satisfied the requirements of section 204(b)(5)(A)(ii)(I) of the ATPA, as amended, relating to the implementation of procedures and requirements similar to those in chapter 5 of the NAFTA.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">3. Section 3103(a)(2) of the ATPDEA amended section 204(b) of the ATPA to provide that eligible textile and apparel articles of a designated ATPDEA beneficiary country shall enter the United States free of duty and free of quantitative limitations, provided that the President determines that the country has satisfied the requirements of section 204(b)(5)(A)(ii)(I) of the ATPA, as amended, relating to the implementation of procedures and requirements similar to those in chapter 5 of the NAFTA.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">4. Section 3103(a)(2) of the ATPDEA amended section 204(b) of the ATPA to provide that eligible tuna products of a designated ATPDEA beneficiary country shall enter the United States free of duty and free of quantitative limitations, provided that the President determines that the country has satisfied the requirements of section 204(b)(5)(A)(ii)(I) of the ATPA, as amended, relating to the implementation of procedures and requirements similar to those in chapter 5 of the NAFTA.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">5. Section 203(e)(2)(A) of the ATPA (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3202/e/2/A">19 U.S.C. 3202(e)(2)(A)</ref>) requires the President to publish in the Federal Register notice of proposed action under section 203(e)(1) of the ATPA (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3202/e/1">19 U.S.C. 3202(e)(1)</ref>) at least 30 days prior to taking such action. Section 212(e)(2)(A) of the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act (CBERA) (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2702/e/2/A">19 U.S.C. 2702(e)(2)(A)</ref>) requires the President to publish in the Federal Register notice of proposed action under section 212(e)(1) of the CBERA (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2702/e/1">19 U.S.C. 2702(e)(1)</ref>) at least 30 days prior to taking such action.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">6. In order to implement the tariff treatment provided under the ATPDEA, it is necessary to modify the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTS).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">7. Section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2483">19 U.S.C. 2483</ref>) (1974 Trade Act) authorizes the President to embody in the HTS the substance of the relevant provisions of that Act, and of other acts affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.</p>
<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, GEORGE W. BUSH, President of the United States of America, acting under the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 604 of the 1974 Trade Act, do proclaim as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) I have designated the following countries as ATPDEA beneficiary countries pursuant to section 204(b)(6)(B) of the ATPA, as amended, and have determined that these countries have satisfied the requirements of section 204(b)(5)(A)(ii)(I) of the ATPA, as amended, relating to the implementation of procedures and requirements similar to those in chapter 5 of the NAFTA:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Bolivia</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Colombia</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ecuador</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Peru.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) In order to provide for the preferential treatment provided for in section 204(b) of the ATPA, as amended, the HTS is modified as provided in the annex to this proclamation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) The functions of the President under section 203(e)(2)(A) of the ATPA and section 212(e)(2)(A) of the CBERA with respect to publishing notice of an action he proposes to take. [sic] are delegated to the United States Trade Representative.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) Any provisions of previous proclamations and Executive Orders that are inconsistent with this proclamation are superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(5) This proclamation is effective on the date of signature.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of October, in the year of our Lord two thousand two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and twenty-seventh.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0609ceb6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Presidential Suspension of Designation of Beneficiary Countries</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Proc. No. 8323, <date date="2008-11-25">Nov. 25, 2008</date>, 73 F.R. 72679, provided in par. (4) that the designation of Bolivia as a beneficiary country for purposes of the Andean Trade Promotion and Drug Eradication Act, title XXXI of div. C of <ref href="/us/pl/107/210">Pub. L. 107–210</ref> (see Tables for classification), was suspended effective <date date="2008-12-15">Dec. 15, 2008</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
