<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0610fa8e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534"><num value="3534">§ 3534.</num><heading> Annual report on WTO</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year beginning in 1996, the Trade Representative shall submit to the Congress a report describing, for the preceding fiscal year of the WTO—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa8f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the major activities and work programs of the WTO, including the functions and activities of the committees established under article IV of the WTO Agreement, and the expenditures made by the WTO in connection with those activities and programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa90-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the percentage of budgetary assessments by the WTO that were accounted for by each WTO member country, including the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa91-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the total number of personnel employed or retained by the Secretariat of the WTO, and the number of professional, administrative, and support staff of the WTO;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa92-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> for each personnel category described in paragraph (3), the number of citizens of each country, and the average salary of the personnel, in that category;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa93-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> each report issued by a panel or the Appellate Body in a dispute settlement proceeding regarding Federal or State law, and any efforts by the Trade Representative to provide for implementation of the recommendations contained in a report that is adverse to the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa94-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> each proceeding before a panel or the Appellate Body that was initiated during that fiscal year regarding Federal or State law, the status of the proceeding, and the matter at issue;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa95-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the status of consultations with any State whose law was the subject of a report adverse to the United States that was issued by a panel or the Appellate Body; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0610fa96-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3534/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> any progress achieved in increasing the transparency of proceedings of the Ministerial Conference and the General Council, and of dispute settlement proceedings conducted pursuant to the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id0610fa97-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tI/s124">Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4832">108 Stat. 4832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0610fa98-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0610fa99-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0610fa9a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States (<date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/s130">section 130 of Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3531">section 3531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
