<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0615b56e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704"><num value="3704">§ 3704.</num><heading> United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0615b56f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Declaration of policy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall convene annual high-level meetings between appropriate officials of the United States Government and officials of the governments of sub-Saharan African countries in order to foster close economic ties between the United States and sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0615b570-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, the President, after consulting with Congress and the governments concerned, shall establish a United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum (in this section referred to as the “Forum”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0615b571-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In creating the Forum, the President shall meet the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0615b572-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President shall direct the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of State, and the United States Trade Representative to host the first annual meeting with their counterparts from the governments of sub-Saharan African countries eligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3703">section 3703 of this title</ref>, and those sub-Saharan African countries that the President determines are taking substantial positive steps towards meeting the eligibility requirements in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3703">section 3703 of this title</ref>. The purpose of the meeting shall be to discuss expanding trade and investment relations between the United States and sub-Saharan Africa and the implementation of this chapter including encouraging joint ventures between small and large businesses. The President shall also direct the Secretaries and the United States Trade Representative to invite to the meeting representatives from appropriate sub-Saharan African regional organizations and government officials from other appropriate countries in sub-Saharan Africa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0615b573-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0615b574-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The President, in consultation with the Congress, shall encourage United States nongovernmental organizations to host annual meetings with nongovernmental organizations from sub-Saharan Africa in conjunction with the annual meetings of the Forum for the purpose of discussing the issues described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0615b575-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The President, in consultation with the Congress, shall encourage United States representatives of the private sector to host annual meetings with representatives of the private sector from sub-Saharan Africa in conjunction with the annual meetings of the Forum for the purpose of discussing the issues described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0615b576-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The President shall, to the extent practicable, meet with the heads of governments of sub-Saharan African countries eligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3703">section 3703 of this title</ref>, and those sub-Saharan African countries that the President determines are taking substantial positive steps toward meeting the eligibility requirements in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3703">section 3703 of this title</ref>, not less than once every 2 years for the purpose of discussing the issues described in paragraph (1). The first such meeting should take place not later than 12 months after <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0615b577-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Dissemination of information by USIS</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to assist in carrying out the purposes of the Forum, the United States Information Service shall disseminate regularly, through multiple media, economic information in support of the free market economic reforms described in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0615b578-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3704/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> HIV/AIDS effect on the sub-Saharan African workforce</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In selecting issues of common interest to the United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum, the President shall instruct the United States delegates to the Forum to promote a review by the Forum of the HIV/AIDS epidemic in each sub-Saharan African country and the effect of the HIV/AIDS epidemic on economic development in each country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0615b579-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/200/tI/s105">Pub. L. 106–200, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/255">114 Stat. 255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0615b57a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0615b57b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0615b57c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (c)(1) and (d), was in the original “this title”, meaning title I of <ref href="/us/pl/106/200">Pub. L. 106–200</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/252">114 Stat. 252</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3701">section 3701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
