<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id061a974d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731"><num value="3731">§ 3731.</num><heading> Sense of the Congress regarding comprehensive debt relief for the world’s poorest countries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061a974e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a974f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The burden of external debt has become a major impediment to economic growth and poverty reduction in many of the world’s poorest countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9750-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Until recently, the United States Government and other official creditors sought to address this problem by rescheduling loans and in some cases providing limited debt reduction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9751-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Despite such efforts, the cumulative debt of many of the world’s poorest countries continued to grow beyond their capacity to repay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9752-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In 1997, the Group of Seven, the World Bank, and the International Monetary Fund adopted the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries Initiative (HIPC), a commitment by the international community that all multilateral and bilateral creditors, acting in a coordinated and concerted fashion, would reduce poor country debt to a sustainable level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9753-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The HIPC Initiative is currently undergoing reforms to address concerns raised about country conditionality, the amount of debt forgiven, and the allocation of savings realized through the debt forgiveness program to ensure that the Initiative accomplishes the goals of economic growth and poverty alleviation in the world’s poorest countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061a9754-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of the Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9755-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Congress and the President should work together, without undue delay and in concert with the international community, to make comprehensive debt relief available to the world’s poorest countries in a manner that promotes economic growth and poverty alleviation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9756-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> this program of bilateral and multilateral debt relief should be designed to strengthen and expand the private sector, encourage increased trade and investment, support the development of free markets, and promote broad-scale economic growth in beneficiary countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9757-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> this program of debt relief should also support the adoption of policies to alleviate poverty and to ensure that benefits are shared widely among the population, such as through initiatives to advance education, improve health, combat AIDS, and promote clean water and environmental protection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9758-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> these debt relief agreements should be designed and implemented in a transparent manner and with the broad participation of the citizenry of the debtor country and should ensure that country circumstances are adequately taken into account;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9759-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> no country should receive the benefits of debt relief if that country does not cooperate with the United States on terrorism or narcotics enforcement, is a gross violator of the human rights of its citizens, or is engaged in conflict or spends excessively on its military; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a975a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3731/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> in order to prevent adverse impact on a key industry in many developing countries, the International Monetary Fund must mobilize its own resources for providing debt relief to eligible countries without allowing gold to reach the open market, or otherwise adversely affecting the market price of gold.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id061a975b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/200/tI/s121">Pub. L. 106–200, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/267">114 Stat. 267</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
