<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id061a9796-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737"><num value="3737">§ 3737.</num><heading> Additional authorities and increased flexibility to provide assistance under the Development Fund for Africa</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061a9797-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of sustainable development assistance to support further economic growth</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that sustained economic growth in sub-Saharan Africa depends in large measure upon the development of a receptive environment for trade and investment, and that to achieve this objective the United States Agency for International Development should continue to support programs which help to create this environment. Investments in human resources, development, and implementation of free market policies, including policies to liberalize agricultural markets and improve food security, and the support for the rule of law and democratic governance should continue to be encouraged and enhanced on a bilateral and regional basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061a9798-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Declarations of policy</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress makes the following declarations:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a9799-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Development Fund for Africa established under chapter 10 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293">22 U.S.C. 2293</ref> et seq.) has been an effective tool in providing development assistance to sub-Saharan Africa since 1988.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a979a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Development Fund for Africa will complement the other provisions of this chapter and lay a foundation for increased trade and investment opportunities between the United States and sub-Saharan Africa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a979b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Assistance provided through the Development Fund for Africa will continue to support programs and activities that promote the long term economic development of sub-Saharan Africa, such as programs and activities relating to the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a979c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Strengthening primary and vocational education systems, especially the acquisition of middle-level technical skills for operating modern private businesses and the introduction of college level business education, including the study of international business, finance, and stock exchanges.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a979d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Strengthening health care systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a979e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Supporting democratization, good governance and civil society and conflict resolution efforts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a979f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Increasing food security by promoting the expansion of agricultural and agriculture-based industrial production and productivity and increasing real incomes for poor individuals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a97a0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Promoting an enabling environment for private sector-led growth through sustained economic reform, privatization programs, and market-led economic activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a97a1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Promoting decentralization and local participation in the development process, especially linking the rural production sectors and the industrial and market centers throughout Africa.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a97a2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Increasing the technical and managerial capacity of sub-Saharan African individuals to manage the economy of sub-Saharan Africa.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a97a3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Ensuring sustainable economic growth through environmental protection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a97a4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3737/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The African Development Foundation has a unique congressional mandate to empower the poor to participate fully in development and to increase opportunities for gainful employment, poverty alleviation, and more equitable income distribution in sub-Saharan Africa. The African Development Foundation has worked successfully to enhance the role of women as agents of change, strengthen the informal sector with an emphasis on supporting micro and small sized enterprises, indigenous technologies, and mobilizing local financing. The African Development Foundation should develop and implement strategies for promoting participation in the socioeconomic development process of grassroots and informal sector groups such as nongovernmental organizations, cooperatives, artisans, and traders into the programs and initiatives established under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id061a97a5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/200/tI/s127">Pub. L. 106–200, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="2000-05-18">May 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/272">114 Stat. 272</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id061a97a6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id061a97a7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id061a97a8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>. Chapter 10 of part I of the Act is classified generally to part X (§ 2293 et seq.) of subchapter I of chapter 32 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id061a97a9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/106/200/s127">section 127 of Pub. L. 106–200</ref>. Subsec. (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/106/200/s127">section 127 of Pub. L. 106–200</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293">section 2293 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id061a97aa-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id061a97ab-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">African Development Foundation changed to United States African Development Foundation by <ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dK/tIII">Pub. L. 113–76, div. K, title III</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/482">128 Stat. 482</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s290h–1">section 290h–1 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
