<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id061a97d6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801"><num value="3801">§ 3801.</num><heading> Short title and findings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061a97d7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Short title</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2002”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061a97d8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a97d9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The expansion of international trade is vital to the national security of the United States. Trade is critical to the economic growth and strength of the United States and to its leadership in the world. Stable trading relationships promote security and prosperity. Trade agreements today serve the same purposes that security pacts played during the Cold War, binding nations together through a series of mutual rights and obligations. Leadership by the United States in international trade fosters open markets, democracy, and peace throughout the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a97da-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The national security of the United States depends on its economic security, which in turn is founded upon a vibrant and growing industrial base. Trade expansion has been the engine of economic growth. Trade agreements maximize opportunities for the critical sectors and building blocks of the economy of the United States, such as information technology, telecommunications and other leading technologies, basic industries, capital equipment, medical equipment, services, agriculture, environmental technology, and intellectual property. Trade will create new opportunities for the United States and preserve the unparalleled strength of the United States in economic, political, and military affairs. The United States, secured by expanding trade and economic opportunities, will meet the challenges of the twenty-first century.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061a97db-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Support for continued trade expansion requires that dispute settlement procedures under international trade agreements not add to or diminish the rights and obligations provided in such agreements. Therefore—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a97dc-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the recent pattern of decisions by dispute settlement panels of the WTO and the Appellate Body to impose obligations and restrictions on the use of antidumping, countervailing, and safeguard measures by WTO members under the Antidumping Agreement, the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures, and the Agreement on Safeguards has raised concerns; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061a97dd-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3801/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Congress is concerned that dispute settlement panels of the WTO and the Appellate Body appropriately apply the standard of review contained in Article 17.6 of the Antidumping Agreement, to provide deference to a permissible interpretation by a WTO member of provisions of that Agreement, and to the evaluation by a WTO member of the facts where that evaluation is unbiased and objective and the establishment of the facts is proper.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id061a97de-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/210/dB/tXXI/s2101">Pub. L. 107–210, div. B, title XXI, § 2101</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/993">116 Stat. 993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id061a97df-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id061a97e0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id061a97e1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “This title”, meaning title XXI of <ref href="/us/pl/107/210/dB">Pub. L. 107–210, div. B</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/993">116 Stat. 993</ref>, which enacted this chapter and amended sections 2151 to 2155, 2191, and 2212 of this title. For complete classification of title XXI to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id061a97e2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id061a97e3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/210/s1">Pub. L. 107–210, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/933">116 Stat. 933</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/210/s1">“This Act [see Tables for classification] may be cited as the ‘Trade Act of 2002’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id061a97e4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id061a97e5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13277. Delegation of Certain Authorities and Assignment of Certain Functions Under the Trade Act of 2002</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13277, <date date="2002-11-19">Nov. 19, 2002</date>, 67 F.R. 70305, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 13346, § 4, <date date="2004-07-08">July 8, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 41906, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including the Trade Act of 2002 (the “Act”) (<ref href="/us/pl/107/210">Public Law 107–210</ref>) [see Short Title note above] and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Trade Promotion</i>. (a) Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the authorities granted to and functions specifically assigned to the President under Division B of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3801">19 U.S.C. 3801</ref> et seq.] are delegated and assigned, respectively, to the United States Trade Representative (U.S. Trade Representative).</p>
<p>(b) The exercise of the following authorities of, and functions specifically assigned to the President, under Division B of the Act are reserved to the President:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Section 2102(c)(1), (c)(6), (c)(10) and (e) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3802/c/1">19 U.S.C. 3802(c)(1)</ref>, (6), (10), (e)];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Section 2103(a)(1), (a)(4), (a)(6), b(1) [(b)(1)], (c)(1)(B)(i), and (c)(2) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803/a/1">19 U.S.C. 3803(a)(1)</ref>, (4), (6), (b)(1), (c)(1)(B)(i), (2)];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Section 2105(a)(1)(A) and (C) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3805/a/1/A">19 U.S.C. 3805(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (C)]; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) Section 2108(b) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3808/b">19 U.S.C. 3808(b)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c)(i) The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the U.S. Trade Representative, shall carry out the functions of section 2102(c)(2) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3802/c/2">19 U.S.C. 3802(c)(2)</ref>] with respect to establishing consultative mechanisms. The U.S. Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Labor, shall carry out the reporting function under section 2102(c)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) The Secretary of State, in consultation with the U.S. Trade Representative, shall carry out the functions under section 2102(c)(3) of the Act with respect to establishing consultative mechanisms, with the advice and assistance of the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Commerce and, as the Secretary of State determines appropriate, the heads of such other departments and agencies. The U.S. Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall carry out the reporting function under section 2103(c)(3) [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803/c/3">19 U.S.C. 3803(c)(3)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) The U.S. Trade Representative shall carry out the functions under section 2102(c)(5) of the Act. The U.S. Trade Representative shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, carry out the reporting function and the function of making a report available under section 2102(c)(5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) The Secretary of Labor shall carry out section 2102(c)(7) of the Act, in consultation with the Secretary of State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the U.S. Trade Representative, shall carry out the functions under section 2102(c)(8) and (c)(9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) The Secretary of the Treasury shall carry out section 2102(c)(12) of the Act, including any appropriate consultations with the Congress relating thereto.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Andean Trade</i>. (a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the authorities granted and the functions specifically assigned to the President under Division C of the Act [see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>] are delegated and assigned respectively, to the U.S. Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretaries of State, Commerce, the Treasury, and Labor.</p>
<p>(b) The exercise of the following authorities of, and functions specifically assigned to, the President under Division C of the Act are reserved to the President:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) The authority to proclaim under sections 204(b)(1) and 204(b)(3)(B)(ii), and the authority to designate beneficiary countries under section 204(b)(6)(B), of the Andean Trade Preference Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3203/b/1">19 U.S.C. 3203(b)(1)</ref>, (3)(B)(ii), (6)(B)] as amended by section 3103(a)(2) of the Act; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) The authority to make determinations under section 203(e)(1)(B) of the Andean Trade Preference Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3202/e/1/B">19 U.S.C. 3202(e)(1)(B)</ref>] as amended by section 3103(b) of the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The head of the executive department of which the United States Customs Service is a part shall take such actions to carry out determinations and actions pursuant to the Andean Trade Preference Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3201">19 U.S.C. 3201</ref> et seq.], as directed pursuant to the authority delegated to the U.S. Trade Representative under this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Guidance for Exercising Authority and Performing Duties</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budget, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) In exercising authority delegated by, or performing functions assigned in, this order, and in performing duties related to the trade agreements program as defined in Executive Order 11846 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2111">19 U.S.C. 2111</ref> note], officers of the United States:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) Shall ensure that all actions taken by them are consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to (A) conduct the foreign affairs of the United States, including the commencement, conduct, and termination of negotiations with foreign countries and international organizations, (B) withhold information the disclosure of which could impair the foreign relations, the national security, the deliberative processes of the Executive, or the performance of the Executive’s constitutional duties, (C) recommend for congressional consideration such measures as the President may judge necessary or expedient, and (D) supervise the unitary executive branch;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) May redelegate authority delegated by this order and may further assign functions assigned by this order to officers of any other department or agency within the executive branch to the extent permitted by law and such redelegation or further assignment shall be published in the Federal Register; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iii) Shall consult the Attorney General as appropriate in implementing this subsection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. [Amended Ex. Ord. No. 11846, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2111">section 2111 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Judicial Review</i>. This order is intended only to improve the internal management of the Federal Government and is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or equity by a party against the United States, its departments, agencies, instrumentalities or entities, its officers or employees, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
