<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id061ce1ba-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804"><num value="3804">§ 3804.</num><heading> Consultations and assessment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1bb-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice and consultation before negotiation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President, with respect to any agreement that is subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803/b">section 3803(b) of this title</ref>, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061ce1bc-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide, at least 90 calendar days before initiating negotiations, written notice to the Congress of the President’s intention to enter into the negotiations and set forth therein the date the President intends to initiate such negotiations, the specific United States objectives for the negotiations, and whether the President intends to seek an agreement, or changes to an existing agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061ce1bd-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> before and after submission of the notice, consult regarding the negotiations with the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, such other committees of the House and Senate as the President deems appropriate, and the Congressional Oversight group convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3807">section 3807 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061ce1be-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> upon the request of a majority of the members of the Congressional Oversight Group under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3807/c">section 3807(c) of this title</ref>, meet with the Congressional Oversight Group before initiating the negotiations or at any other time concerning the negotiations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1bf-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Negotiations regarding agriculture</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1c0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before initiating or continuing negotiations the subject matter of which is directly related to the subject matter under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3802/b/10/A/i">section 3802(b)(10)(A)(i) of this title</ref> with any country, the President shall assess whether United States tariffs on agricultural products that were bound under the Uruguay Round Agreements are lower than the tariffs bound by that country. In addition, the President shall consider whether the tariff levels bound and applied throughout the world with respect to imports from the United States are higher than United States tariffs and whether the negotiation provides an opportunity to address any such disparity. The President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate concerning the results of the assessment, whether it is appropriate for the United States to agree to further tariff reductions based on the conclusions reached in the assessment, and how all applicable negotiating objectives will be met.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1c1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Special consultations on import sensitive products</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061ce1c2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Before initiating negotiations with regard to agriculture, and, with respect to the Free Trade Area for the Americas and negotiations with regard to agriculture under the auspices of the World Trade Organization, as soon as practicable after <date date="2002-08-06">August 6, 2002</date>, the United States Trade Representative shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1c3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> identify those agricultural products subject to tariff-rate quotas on <date date="2002-08-06">August 6, 2002</date>, and agricultural products subject to tariff reductions by the United States as a result of the Uruguay Round Agreements, for which the rate of duty was reduced on <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, to a rate which was not less than 97.5 percent of the rate of duty that applied to such article on <date date="1994-12-31">December 31, 1994</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1c4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> consult with the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate concerning—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1c5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> whether any further tariff reductions on the products identified under clause (i) should be appropriate, taking into account the impact of any such tariff reduction on the United States industry producing the product concerned;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1c6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> whether the products so identified face unjustified sanitary or phytosanitary restrictions, including those not based on scientific principles in contravention of the Uruguay Round Agreements; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1c7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> whether the countries participating in the negotiations maintain export subsidies or other programs, policies, or practices that distort world trade in such products and the impact of such programs, policies, and practices on United States producers of the products;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1c8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> request that the International Trade Commission prepare an assessment of the probable economic effects of any such tariff reduction on the United States industry producing the product concerned and on the United States economy as a whole; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1c9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> upon complying with clauses (i), (ii), and (iii), notify the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate of those products identified under clause (i) for which the Trade Representative intends to seek tariff liberalization in the negotiations and the reasons for seeking such tariff liberalization.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id061ce1ca-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> If, after negotiations described in subparagraph (A) are commenced—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1cb-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the United States Trade Representative identifies any additional agricultural product described in subparagraph (A)(i) for tariff reductions which were not the subject of a notification under subparagraph (A)(iv), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1cc-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any additional agricultural product described in subparagraph (A)(i) is the subject of a request for tariff reductions by a party to the negotiations,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the Trade Representative shall, as soon as practicable, notify the committees referred to in subparagraph (A)(iv) of those products and the reasons for seeking such tariff reductions.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1cd-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Negotiations regarding the fishing industry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before initiating, or continuing, negotiations which directly relate to fish or shellfish trade with any country, the President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and shall keep the Committees apprised of negotiations on an ongoing and timely basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1ce-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Negotiations regarding textiles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Before initiating or continuing negotiations the subject matter of which is directly related to textiles and apparel products with any country, the President shall assess whether United States tariffs on textile and apparel products that were bound under the Uruguay Round Agreements are lower than the tariffs bound by that country and whether the negotiation provides an opportunity to address any such disparity. The President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate concerning the results of the assessment, whether it is appropriate for the United States to agree to further tariff reductions based on the conclusions reached in the assessment, and how all applicable negotiating objectives will be met.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1cf-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with Congress before agreements entered into</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1d0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before entering into any trade agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803/b">section 3803(b) of this title</ref>, the President shall consult with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1d1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1d2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> each other committee of the House and the Senate, and each joint committee of the Congress, which has jurisdiction over legislation involving subject matters which would be affected by the trade agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1d3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Congressional Oversight Group convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3807">section 3807 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1d4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The consultation described in paragraph (1) shall include consultation with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1d5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the nature of the agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1d6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> how and to what extent the agreement will achieve the applicable purposes, policies, priorities, and objectives of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1d7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the implementation of the agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3805">section 3805 of this title</ref>, including the general effect of the agreement on existing laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1d8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Report regarding United States trade remedy laws</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1d9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Changes in certain trade laws</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The President, at least 180 calendar days before the day on which the President enters into a trade agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803/b">section 3803(b) of this title</ref>, shall report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1da-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the range of proposals advanced in the negotiations with respect to that agreement, that may be in the final agreement, and that could require amendments to title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1671">19 U.S.C. 1671</ref> et seq.] or to chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2251">19 U.S.C. 2251</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1db-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> how these proposals relate to the objectives described in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3802/b/14">section 3802(b)(14) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1dc-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">With respect to a trade agreement entered into with Chile or Singapore, the report referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be submitted by the President at least 90 calendar days before the day on which the President enters into that agreement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1dd-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Resolutions</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1de-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> At any time after the transmission of the report under subparagraph (A), if a resolution is introduced with respect to that report in either House of Congress, the procedures set forth in clauses (iii) through (vi) shall apply to that resolution if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1df-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> no other resolution with respect to that report has previously been reported in that House of Congress by the Committee on Ways and Means or the Committee on Finance, as the case may be, pursuant to those procedures; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1e0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> no procedural disapproval resolution under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3805/b">section 3805(b) of this title</ref> introduced with respect to a trade agreement entered into pursuant to the negotiations to which the report under subparagraph (A) relates has previously been reported in that House of Congress by the Committee on Ways and Means or the Committee on Finance, as the case may be.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1e1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “resolution” means only a resolution of either House of Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the __ finds that the proposed changes to United States trade remedy laws contained in the report of the President transmitted to the Congress on __ under section 2104(d)(3) of the Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2002 with respect to __, are inconsistent with the negotiating objectives described in section 2102(b)(14) of that Act.”, with the first blank space being filled with the name of the resolving House of Congress, the second blank space being filled with the appropriate date of the report, and the third blank space being filled with the name of the country or countries involved.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1e2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> Resolutions in the House of Representatives—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1e3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> may be introduced by any Member of the House;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1e4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> shall be referred to the Committee on Ways and Means and, in addition, to the Committee on Rules; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1e5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> may not be amended by either Committee.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1e6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002162">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002162"><num>1</num> So in original. Two cls. (iv) have been enacted.</note> Resolutions in the Senate—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1e7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> may be introduced by any Member of the Senate;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1e8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> shall be referred to the Committee on Finance; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id061ce1e9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> may not be amended.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1ea-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> <sup>1</sup> It is not in order for the House of Representatives to consider any resolution that is not reported by the Committee on Ways and Means and, in addition, by the Committee on Rules.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1eb-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> It is not in order for the Senate to consider any resolution that is not reported by the Committee on Finance.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id061ce1ec-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/d/3/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> The provisions of section 152(d) and (e) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2192/d">19 U.S.C. 2192(d)</ref> and (e)) (relating to floor consideration of certain resolutions in the House and Senate) shall apply to resolutions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1ed-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory Committee reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The report required under section 135(e)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2155/e/1">19 U.S.C. 2155(e)(1)</ref>] regarding any trade agreement entered into under section 3803(a) or (b) of this title shall be provided to the President, the Congress, and the United States Trade Representative not later than 30 days after the date on which the President notifies the Congress under section 3803(a)(1) or 3805(a)(1)(A) of this title of the President’s intention to enter into the agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1ee-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> ITC assessment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1ef-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President, at least 90 calendar days before the day on which the President enters into a trade agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3803/b">section 3803(b) of this title</ref>, shall provide the International Trade Commission (referred to in this subsection as “the Commission”) with the details of the agreement as it exists at that time and request the Commission to prepare and submit an assessment of the agreement as described in paragraph (2). Between the time the President makes the request under this paragraph and the time the Commission submits the assessment, the President shall keep the Commission current with respect to the details of the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1f0-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> ITC assessment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 calendar days after the President enters into the agreement, the Commission shall submit to the President and the Congress a report assessing the likely impact of the agreement on the United States economy as a whole and on specific industry sectors, including the impact the agreement will have on the gross domestic product, exports and imports, aggregate employment and employment opportunities, the production, employment, and competitive position of industries likely to be significantly affected by the agreement, and the interests of United States consumers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id061ce1f1-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3804/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of empirical literature</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In preparing the assessment, the Commission shall review available economic assessments regarding the agreement, including literature regarding any substantially equivalent proposed agreement, and shall provide in its assessment a description of the analyses used and conclusions drawn in such literature, and a discussion of areas of consensus and divergence between the various analyses and conclusions, including those of the Commission regarding the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id061ce1f2-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/210/dB/tXXI/s2104">Pub. L. 107–210, div. B, title XXI, § 2104</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1008">116 Stat. 1008</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id061ce1f3-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id061ce1f4-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id061ce1f5-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tariff Act of 1930, referred to in subsec. (d)(3)(A)(i), is <ref href="/us/act/1930-06-17/ch497">act June 17, 1930, ch. 497</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/590">46 Stat. 590</ref>. Title VII of the Act is classified generally to subtitle IV (§ 1671 et seq.) of chapter 4 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1654">section 1654 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trade Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (d)(3)(A)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/618">Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1978">88 Stat. 1978</ref>. Chapter 1 of title II of the Act is classified generally to part 1 (§ 2251 et seq.) of subchapter II of chapter 12 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 2104(d)(3) and 2102(b)(14) of the Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (d)(3)(C)(ii), are classified to subsec. (d)(3) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3802/b/14">section 3802(b)(14) of this title</ref>, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id061ce1f6-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id061ce1f7-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Resources of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id061ce1f8-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id061ce1f9-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see section 1 of Ex. Ord. No. 13277, <date date="2002-11-19">Nov. 19, 2002</date>, 67 F.R. 70305, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3801">section 3801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
