<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id063e4c38-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3911"><num value="3911">§ 3911.</num><heading> Reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id063e4c39-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3911/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2003-04-25">April 25, 2003</date>, and every 12 months thereafter for such period as this chapter is in effect, the President shall transmit to the Congress a report—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id063e4c3a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3911/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> describing actions taken by countries that have exported rough diamonds to the United States during the preceding 12-month period to control the exportation of the diamonds through the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id063e4c3b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3911/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> describing whether there is statistical information or other evidence that would indicate efforts to circumvent the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme, including cutting rough diamonds for the purpose of circumventing the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id063e4c3c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3911/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> identifying each country that, during the preceding 12-month period, exported rough diamonds to the United States and was exporting rough diamonds not controlled through the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme, if the failure to do so has significantly increased the likelihood that those diamonds not so controlled are being imported into the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id063e4c3d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3911/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identifying any problems or obstacles encountered in the implementation of this chapter or the Kimberly <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002165">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002165"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Kimberley”.</note> Process Certification Scheme.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id063e4c3e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s3911/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Semiannual reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each country identified in subsection (a)(3), the President, during such period as this chapter is in effect, shall, every 6 months after the initial report in which the country was identified, transmit to the Congress a report that explains what actions have been taken by the United States or such country since the previous report to ensure that diamonds the exportation of which was not controlled through the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme are not being imported from that country into the United States. The requirement to issue a semiannual report with respect to a country under this subsection shall remain in effect until such time as the country is controlling the importation and exportation of rough diamonds through the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id063e4c3f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/19/s12">Pub. L. 108–19, § 12</ref>, <date date="2003-04-25">Apr. 25, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/636">117 Stat. 636</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id063e4c40-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id063e4c41-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id063e4c42-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/19/s15">section 15 of Pub. L. 108–19</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id063e4c43-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id063e4c44-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For assignment of functions of President under this section, see section 2 of Ex. Ord. No. 13312, <date date="2003-07-29">July 29, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 45151, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
