<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0643074c-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062"><num value="4062">§ 4062.</num><heading> Commission action on petition</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0643074d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after the date on which an investigation is initiated under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s4061/b">section 4061(b) of this title</ref> with respect to a petition, the Commission shall make the determination required under that section. At that time, the Commission shall also determine whether any CAFTA–DR country is a de minimis supplying country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0643074e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this part, the provisions of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1330/d">section 1330(d) of this title</ref> shall be applied with respect to determinations and findings made under this section as if such determinations and findings were made under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2252">section 2252 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0643074f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional finding and recommendation if determination affirmative</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the determination made by the Commission under subsection (a) with respect to imports of an article is affirmative, or if the President may consider a determination of the Commission to be an affirmative determination as provided for under paragraph (1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1330/d">section 1330(d) of this title</ref>, the Commission shall find, and recommend to the President in the report required under subsection (d), the amount of import relief that is necessary to remedy or prevent the injury found by the Commission in the determination and to facilitate the efforts of the domestic industry to make a positive adjustment to import competition. The import relief recommended by the Commission under this subsection shall be limited to the relief described in <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s4063/c">section 4063(c) of this title</ref>. Only those members of the Commission who voted in the affirmative under subsection (a) are eligible to vote on the proposed action to remedy or prevent the injury found by the Commission. Members of the Commission who did not vote in the affirmative may submit, in the report required under subsection (d), separate views regarding what action, if any, should be taken to remedy or prevent the injury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id06430750-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to President</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which a determination is made under subsection (a) with respect to an investigation, the Commission shall submit to the President a report that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id06430751-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the determination made under subsection (a) and an explanation of the basis for the determination;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id06430752-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the determination under subsection (a) is affirmative, any findings and recommendations for import relief made under subsection (c) and an explanation of the basis for each recommendation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id06430753-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any dissenting or separate views by members of the Commission regarding the determination and recommendation referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id06430754-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s4062/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Public notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon submitting a report to the President under subsection (d), the Commission shall promptly make public such report (with the exception of information which the Commission determines to be confidential) and shall cause a summary thereof to be published in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id06430755-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/53/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 109–53, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/489">119 Stat. 489</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id06430756-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id06430757-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Termination of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For termination of section by <ref href="/us/pl/109/53/s107/d">section 107(d) of Pub. L. 109–53</ref>, see Effective and Termination Dates note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id06430758-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id06430759-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This part, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle A (§§ 311–316) of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/109/53">Pub. L. 109–53</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/488">119 Stat. 488</ref>, which enacted this part and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2252">section 2252 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of subtitle A to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0643075a-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0643075b-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the date the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement enters into force (<date date="2006-03-01">Mar. 1, 2006</date>) and to cease to have effect on the date the Agreement ceases to be in force with respect to the United States, and, during any period in which a country ceases to be a CAFTA–DR country, to cease to have effect with respect to such country, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/53/s107">section 107 of Pub. L. 109–53</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
