<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id050d1e7d-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s64"><num value="64">§ 64.</num><heading> Laws imposing fines applicable to persons acting under customs laws</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All Acts and parts of Acts imposing fines, penalties, or other punishment for offenses committed by an internal revenue officer or other officer of the Department of the Treasury of the United States, or under any bureau thereof, shall apply to all persons whomsoever, employed, appointed, or acting under the authority of any customs law, when such persons are designated or acting as officers or deputies, or persons having the custody or disposition of any public money.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id050d1e7e-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1875-02-08/ch36/s23">Feb. 8, 1875, ch. 36, § 23</ref> (part), <ref href="/us/stat/18/312">18 Stat. 312</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id050d1e7f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id050d1e80-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id050d1e81-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on section 23 (as related to persons acting under any customs law) of act <date date="1875-02-08">Feb. 8, 1875</date>. Provisions of section 23 (as related to persons acting under any internal revenue law or any revenue provisions of any law of the United States) were repealed effective <date date="1939-02-11">Feb. 11, 1939</date>, by section 4 of act <date date="1939-02-10">Feb. 10, 1939</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/53/1">53 Stat. 1</ref>) and incorporated as <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4048">section 4048 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code of 1939. The Internal Revenue Code of 1939 was repealed by the Internal Revenue Code of 1954. The Internal Revenue Code of 1954 was redesignated the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>. Provisions of former section 4048 are covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7344">section 7344 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
