<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id050d1e8f-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d" identifier="/us/usc/t19/s68"><num value="68">§ 68.</num><heading> Enforcement of customs and immigration laws in Guam and the Virgin Islands and along Canadian and Mexican borders; cooperation by Secretary of the Treasury and Attorney General; erection of buildings</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To aid in the enforcement of the customs and immigration laws along the Canadian and Mexican borders and to provide better facilities for such enforcement at points along such borders at which no Federal or other buildings adapted or suitably located for the purpose are available, and for similar purposes in the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General are hereby authorized to expend, and for similar purposes in Guam the Attorney General is hereby authorized to expend, from the funds appropriated for the general maintenance and operation of the Customs and the Immigration and Naturalization Services, respectively, the necessary amounts for the acquisition of land and the erection of buildings, sheds, and office quarters, including living quarters for officers where none are otherwise available: <i>Provided</i>, That the total amount which may be so expended for any one project, including the site, shall not exceed $200,000 and that where the project is for the joint use of the Customs Service and the Immigration and Naturalization Service, the combined cost of the project, including the site, shall be charged to the two appropriations concerned.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id050d1e90-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-26/ch617/s1">June 26, 1930, ch. 617, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/817">46 Stat. 817</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-10-10/ch837">Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 837</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1091">54 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-26/ch414">Sept. 26, 1951, ch. 414</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/336">65 Stat. 336</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-05-18/ch282">May 18, 1956, ch. 282</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/159">70 Stat. 159</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/466">Pub. L. 86–466</ref>, <date date="1960-05-13">May 13, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/130">74 Stat. 130</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/465">Pub. L. 87–465</ref>, <date date="1962-05-31">May 31, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/87">76 Stat. 87</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/87">Pub. L. 89–87</ref>, <date date="1965-07-24">July 24, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/264">79 Stat. 264</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/396">Pub. L. 93–396</ref>, <date date="1974-08-29">Aug. 29, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/794">88 Stat. 794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id050d1e91-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id050d1e92-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id050d1e93-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/396">Pub. L. 93–396</ref> substituted “$200,000” for “$100,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/87">Pub. L. 89–87</ref> extended to Guam and the Virgin Islands the authority of the Attorney General and the Secretary of the Treasury to construct facilities for the enforcement of the customs and immigration laws.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/465">Pub. L. 87–465</ref> substituted “$100,000” for “$40,000” and “$80,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/466">Pub. L. 86–466</ref> substituted “$40,000” and “$80,000” for “$30,000” and “$60,000”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Act <date date="1956-05-18">May 18, 1956</date>, substituted “$30,000” and “$60,000” for “$15,000” and “$30,000”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-09-26">Sept. 26, 1951</date>, substituted “$15,000” and “$30,000” for “$5,000” and “$10,000”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1940—Act <date date="1940-10-10">Oct. 10, 1940</date>, substituted “$5000” and “$10,000” for “$3000” and “$6000”, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id050d1e94-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id050d1e95-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id050d1e96-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of Title 8</ref>, Aliens and Nationality.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id050d1e97-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id050d1e98-3a70-11f1-8ace-823fb135378d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of officers of Department of the Treasury and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Treasury, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions, by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by Reorg. Plan No. 26 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Customs Service was under Department of the Treasury.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Immigration and Naturalization Service of Department of Labor (including Office of Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization) and its functions were transferred to Department of Justice, to be administered under direction and supervision of Attorney General; and functions and powers of Secretary of Labor relating to administration of the Service and its functions or to administration of immigration and naturalization laws were transferred to Attorney General, by Reorg. Plan No. V of 1940, eff. <date date="1940-06-15">June 15, 1940</date>, 5 F.R. 2223, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1238">54 Stat. 1238</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
