<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id2e280a56-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109"><num value="109">§ 109.</num><heading> Standards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e280a57-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that the plans and specifications for each proposed highway project under this chapter provide for a facility that will—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e280a58-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> adequately serve the existing and planned future traffic of the highway in a manner that is conducive to safety, durability, and economy of maintenance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e280a59-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> be designed and constructed in accordance with criteria best suited to accomplish the objectives described in paragraph (1) and to conform to the particular needs of each locality.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e280a5a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The geometric and construction standards to be adopted for the Interstate System shall be those approved by the Secretary in cooperation with the State transportation departments. Such standards, as applied to each actual construction project, shall be adequate to enable such project to accommodate the types and volumes of traffic anticipated for such project for the twenty-year period commencing on the date of approval by the Secretary, under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>, of the plans, specifications, and estimates for actual construction of such project. Such standards shall in all cases provide for at least four lanes of traffic. The right-of-way width of the Interstate System shall be adequate to permit construction of projects on the Interstate System to such standards. The Secretary shall apply such standards uniformly throughout all the States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e280a5b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Design Criteria for National Highway System.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e280a5c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A design for new construction, reconstruction, resurfacing (except for maintenance resurfacing), restoration, or rehabilitation of a highway on the National Highway System (other than a highway also on the Interstate System) shall consider, in addition to the criteria described in subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a5d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the constructed and natural environment of the area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a5e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the environmental, scenic, aesthetic, historic, community, and preservation impacts of the activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a5f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> cost savings by utilizing flexibility that exists in current design guidance and regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a60-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> access for other modes of transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e280a61-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development of criteria</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary, in cooperation with State transportation departments, may develop criteria to implement paragraph (1). In developing criteria under this paragraph, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a62-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the results of the committee process of the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials as used in adopting and publishing “A Policy on Geometric Design of Highways and Streets”, including comments submitted by interested parties as part of such process;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a63-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the publication entitled “Flexibility in Highway Design” of the Federal Highway Administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a64-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> “Eight Characteristics of Process to Yield Excellence and the Seven Qualities of Excellence in Transportation Design” developed by the conference held during 1998 entitled “Thinking Beyond the Pavement National Workshop on Integrating Highway Development with Communities and the Environment while Maintaining Safety and Performance”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a65-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the publication entitled “Highway Safety Manual” of the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a66-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the publication entitled “Urban Street Design Guide” of the National Association of City Transportation Officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a67-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the publication of the Federal Highway Administration entitled “Wildlife Crossing Structure Handbook: Design and Evaluation in North America” and dated March 2011; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e280a68-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/c/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> any other material that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e280a69-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e280a6a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>On any highway project in which Federal funds hereafter participate, or on any such proj­ect constructed since <date date="1944-12-20">December 20, 1944</date>, the location, form and character of informational, regulatory and warning signs, curb and pavement or other markings, and traffic signals installed or placed by any public authority or other agency, shall be subject to the approval of the State transportation department with the concurrence of the Secretary, who is directed to concur only in such installations as will promote the safety, inclusion, and mobility of all users and efficient utilization of the highways.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b6b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updates</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the Surface Transportation Reauthorization Act of 2021 and not less frequently than every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary shall update the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b6c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Installation of Safety Devices.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b6d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Highway and railroad grade crossings and drawbridges</inline>.—</heading><content>No funds shall be approved for expenditure on any Federal-aid highway, or highway affected under chapter 2 of this title, unless proper safety protective devices complying with safety standards determined by the Secretary at that time as being adequate shall be installed or be in operation at any highway and railroad grade crossing or drawbridge on that portion of the highway with respect to which such expenditures are to be made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b6e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Temporary traffic control devices</inline>.—</heading><content>No funds shall be approved for expenditure on any Federal-aid highway, or highway affected under chapter 2, unless proper temporary traffic control devices to improve safety in work zones will be installed and maintained during construction, utility, and maintenance operations on that portion of the highway with respect to which such expenditures are to be made. Installation and maintenance of the devices shall be in accordance with the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b6f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Secretary shall not, as a condition precedent to his approval under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>, require any State to acquire title to, or control of, any marginal land along the proposed highway in addition to that reasonably necessary for road surfaces, median strips, bikeways, pedestrian walkways, gutters, ditches, and side slopes, and of sufficient width to provide service roads for adjacent property to permit safe access at controlled locations in order to expedite traffic, promote safety, and minimize roadside parking.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b70-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1971-01-30">January 30, 1971</date>, the Secretary shall issue guidelines for minimizing possible soil erosion from highway construction. Such guidelines shall apply to all proposed projects with respect to which plans, specifications, and estimates are approved by the Secretary after the issuance of such guidelines.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b71-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, the Secretary, after consultation with appropriate Federal and State officials, shall submit to Congress, and not later than 90 days after such submission, promulgate guidelines designed to assure that possible adverse economic, social, and environmental effects relating to any proposed project on any Federal-aid system have been fully considered in developing such project, and that the final decisions on the project are made in the best overall public interest, taking into consideration the need for fast, safe and efficient transportation, public services, and the costs of eliminating or minimizing such adverse effects and the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b72-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> air, noise, and water pollution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b73-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> destruction or disruption of man-made and natural resources, aesthetic values, community cohesion and the availability of public facilities and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b74-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> adverse employment effects, and tax and property value losses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b75-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> injurious displacement of people, businesses and farms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b76-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> disruption of desirable community and regional growth.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such guidelines shall apply to all proposed proj­ects with respect to which plans, specifications, and estimates are approved by the Secretary after the issuance of such guidelines.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b77-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary, after consultation with appropriate Federal, State, and local officials, shall develop and promulgate standards for highway noise levels compatible with different land uses and after <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, shall not approve plans and specifications for any proposed project on any Federal-aid system for which location approval has not yet been secured unless he determines that such plans and specifications include adequate measures to implement the appropriate noise level standards. The Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and appropriate Federal, State, and local officials, may promulgate standards for the control of highway noise levels for highways on any Federal-aid system for which project approval has been secured prior to <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>. The Secretary may approve any project on a Federal-aid system to which noise-level standards are made applicable under the preceding sentence for the purpose of carrying out such standards. Such project may include, but is not limited to, the acquisition of additional rights-of-way, the construction of physical barriers, and landscaping. Sums apportioned for the Federal-aid system on which such project will be located shall be available to finance the Federal share of such project. Such project shall be deemed a highway project for all purposes of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b78-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><chapeau> The Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall develop and promulgate guidelines to assure that highways constructed pursuant to this title are consistent with any approved plan for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b79-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the implementation of a national ambient air quality standard for each pollutant for which an area is designated as a nonattainment area under section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b7a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the maintenance of a national ambient air quality standard in an area that was designated as a nonattainment area but that was later redesignated by the Administrator as an attainment area for the standard and that is required to develop a maintenance plan under section 175A of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7505a">42 U.S.C. 7505a</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b7b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> The Secretary shall not approve any proj­ect involving approaches to a bridge under this title, if such project and bridge will significantly affect the traffic volume and the highway system of a contiguous State without first taking into full consideration the views of that State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b7c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b7d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In determining whether any right-of-way on any Federal-aid highway should be used for accommodating any utility facility, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b7e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> first ascertain the effect such use will have on highway and traffic safety, since in no case shall any use be authorized or otherwise permitted, under this or any other provision of law, which would adversely affect safety;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b7f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> evaluate the direct and indirect environmental and economic effects of any loss of productive agricultural land or any impairment of the productivity of any agricultural land which would result from the disapproval of the use of such right-of-way for the accommodation of such utility facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b80-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> consider such environmental and economic effects together with any interference with or impairment of the use of the highway in such right-of-way which would result from the use of such right-of-way for the accommodation of such utility facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b81-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For the purpose of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b82-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “utility facility” means any privately, publicly, or cooperatively owned line, facility, or system for producing, transmitting, or distributing communications, power, electricity, light, heat, gas, oil, crude products, water, steam, waste, storm water not connected with highway drainage, or any other similar commodity, including any fire or police signal system or street lighting system, which directly or indirectly serves the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b83-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “right-of-way” means any real property, or interest therein, acquired, dedicated, or reserved for the construction, operation, and maintenance of a highway.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b84-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protection of Nonmotorized Transportation Traffic</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not approve any project or take any regulatory action under this title that will result in the severance of an existing major route or have significant adverse impact on the safety for nonmotorized transportation traffic and light motorcycles, unless such project or regulatory action provides for a reasonable alternate route or such a route exists.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b85-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content> It is the intent of Congress that any project for resurfacing, restoring, or rehabilitating any highway, other than a highway access to which is fully controlled, in which Federal funds participate shall be constructed in accordance with standards to preserve and extend the service life of highways and enhance highway safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b86-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance With State Laws for Non-NHS Projects.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b87-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/o/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002003"><num>1</num> Designations so in original.</note> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Projects (other than highway projects on the National Highway System) shall be designed, constructed, operated, and maintained in accordance with State laws, regulations, directives, safety standards, design standards, and construction standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b88-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/o/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <sup>1</sup> <inline class="small-caps">Local jurisdictions</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a local jurisdiction may use a roadway design guide recognized by the Federal Highway Administration and adopted by the local jurisdiction that is different from the roadway design guide used by the State in which the local jurisdiction is located for the design of projects on all roadways under the ownership of the local jurisdiction (other than a highway on the National Highway System) for which the local jurisdiction is the project sponsor, provided that the design complies with all other applicable Federal laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b89-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scenic and Historic Values</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary may approve a project for the National Highway System if the project is designed to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b8a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/p/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> allow for the preservation of environmental, scenic, or historic values;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b8b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/p/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensure safe use of the facility; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b8c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/p/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> comply with subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b8d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Phase Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Safety considerations for a project under this title may be met by phase construction consistent with the operative safety management system established in accordance with a statewide transportation improvement program approved by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b8e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/r"><num value="r">(r)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pavement Markings</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not approve any pavement markings project that includes the use of glass beads containing more than 200 parts per million of arsenic or lead, as determined in accordance with Environmental Protection Agency testing methods 3052, 6010B, or 6010C.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e2a7b8f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/s"><num value="s">(s)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Electric Vehicle Charging Stations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b90-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/s/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Standards</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Electric vehicle charging infrastructure installed using funds provided under this title shall provide, at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e2a7b91-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/s/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> non-proprietary charging connectors that meet applicable industry safety standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e2a7b92-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/s/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> open access to payment methods that are available to all members of the public to ensure secure, convenient, and equal access to the electric vehicle charging infrastructure that shall not be limited by membership to a particular payment provider.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e2a7b93-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s109/s/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of projects</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a project to install electric vehicle charging infrastructure using funds provided under this title shall be treated as if the project is located on a Federal-aid highway.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id2e2a7b94-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/767">Pub. L. 85–767</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/894">72 Stat. 894</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/157/s4">Pub. L. 88–157, § 4</ref>, <date date="1963-10-24">Oct. 24, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/277">77 Stat. 277</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/574">Pub. L. 89–574</ref>, §§ 5(a), 14, <date date="1966-09-13">Sept. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/767">80 Stat. 767</ref>, 771; <ref href="/us/pl/91/605/tI/s136/a">Pub. L. 91–605, title I, § 136(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1734">84 Stat. 1734</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/tI">Pub. L. 93–87, title I</ref>, §§ 114, 152(2), 156, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/257">87 Stat. 257</ref>, 276, 277; <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tI">Pub. L. 95–599, title I</ref>, §§ 113, 116(d), 141(f), (g), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2696">92 Stat. 2696</ref>, 2699, 2711; <ref href="/us/pl/96/106/s3">Pub. L. 96–106, § 3</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/797">93 Stat. 797</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/424/tI/s110/a">Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 110(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2105">96 Stat. 2105</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1016/c">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1016(c)</ref>–(f)(1), <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1946">105 Stat. 1946</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tIII">Pub. L. 104–59, title III</ref>, §§ 304, 305(a), <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/579">109 Stat. 579</ref>, 580; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI">Pub. L. 105–178, title I</ref>, §§ 1202(c), 1212(a)(2)(A), 1306, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/169">112 Stat. 169</ref>, 193, 229; <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1110/a">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1110(a)</ref>, (c), title VI, § 6008, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1170">119 Stat. 1170</ref>, 1171, 1874; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 1504, 1519(c)(3), formerly § 1519(c)(4), <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/564">126 Stat. 564</ref>, 575, renumbered § 1519(c)(3), <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1446/d/5/B">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1446(d)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1438">129 Stat. 1438</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1404/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1404(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1409">129 Stat. 1409</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 11123(d), 11129, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/506">135 Stat. 506</ref>, 508.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id2e2a7b95-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id2e2a7b96-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id2e2a7b97-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Surface Transportation Reauthorization Act of 2021, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), is the date of enactment of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, which was approved <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id2e2a7b98-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (c)(2)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11123/d">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11123(d)</ref>, added subpar. (F) and redesignated former subpar. (F) as (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11129/1">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11129(1)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and inserted par. heading, substituted “promote the safety, inclusion, and mobility of all users” for “promote the safe”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11129/2">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11129(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (A), inserted heading, and added par. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (s). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11129/3">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11129(3)</ref>, added subsec. (s).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1404/a/1/A/i">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1404(a)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “shall consider” for “may take into account” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1404/a/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1404(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>–(iv), added subpar. (C) and redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(D) to (F). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1404/a/1/B">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1404(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added subpars. (D) and (E) and redesignated former subpar. (D) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1404/a/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1404(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “pedestrian walkways,” after “bikeways,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1446/d/5/B">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1446(d)(5)(B)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1519/c">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1519(c)</ref>. See 2012 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1519/c/3">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1519(c)(3)</ref>, formerly § 1519(c)(4), as renumbered by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1446/d/5/B">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1446(d)(5)(B)</ref>, struck out “in accordance with section 303 or” after “system established”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (r). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1504">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1504</ref>, added subsec. (r).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s6008">Pub. L. 109–59, § 6008</ref>, inserted dash after “Secretary shall consider” and subpar. (A) designation before “the results”, substituted semicolon for period, and added subpars. (B) to (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1110/a">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1110(a)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1110/c">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1110(c)</ref>, substituted “Not later than <date date="1971-01-30">January 30, 1971</date>, the Secretary shall issue” for “The Secretary shall issue within 30 days after the day of enactment of the Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1970”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsecs. (b), (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1212/a/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1212(a)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “State transportation departments” for “State highway departments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1212/a/2/A/i">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1212(a)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “State transportation department” for “State highway department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1306/a">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1306(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (n) as (m) and struck out former subsec. (m) which read as follows: “The Secretary shall issue guidelines describing the criteria applicable to the Interstate System in order to insure that the condition of these routes is maintained at the level required by the purposes for which they were designed. The initial guidelines shall be issued no later than <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1306/a/2">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1306(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (<i>o</i>) as (n). Former subsec. (n) redesignated (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1202/c">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1202(c)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text of subsec. (n) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary shall not approve any project under this title that will result in the severance or destruction of an existing major route for nonmotorized transportation traffic and light motorcycles, unless such project provides a reasonably alternate route or such a route exists.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (<i>o</i>) to (q). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1306/a/2">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1306(a)(2)</ref>, (b), added subsec. (q) and redesignated former subsecs. (p) and (q) as (<i>o</i>) and (p), respectively. Former subsec. (<i>o</i>) redesignated (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s304/1">Pub. L. 104–59, § 304(1)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which read as follows: “The Secretary shall not approve plans and specifications for proposed highway projects under this chapter if they fail to provide for a facility (1) that will adequately meet the existing and probable future traffic needs and conditions in a manner conducive to safety, durability, and economy of maintenance; (2) that will be designed and constructed in accordance with standards best suited to accomplish the foregoing objectives and to conform to the particular needs of each locality.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s304/2">Pub. L. 104–59, § 304(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Design and Construction Standards for NHS</inline>.—Design and construction standards to be adopted for new construction on the National Highway System, for reconstruction on the National Highway System, and for resurfacing, restoring, and rehabilitating multilane limited access highways on the National Highway System shall be those approved by the Secretary in cooperation with the State highway departments. All eligible work for such projects shall meet or exceed such standards.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s305/a">Pub. L. 104–59, § 305(a)</ref>, substituted “plan for—” and pars. (1) and (2) for “plan for the implementation of any ambient air quality standard for any air quality control region designated pursuant to the Clean Air Act, as amended.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s304/3">Pub. L. 104–59, § 304(3)</ref>, added subsec. (q) and struck out former subsec. (q) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(q) <inline class="small-caps">Historic and Scenic Values</inline>.—If a proposed project under sections 103(e)(4), 133, or 144 involves a historic facility or is located in an area of historic or scenic value, the Secretary may approve such project notwithstanding the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) of this section and section 133(c) if such project is designed to standards that allow for the preservation of such historic or scenic value and such project is designed with mitigation measures to allow preservation of such value and ensure safe use of the facility.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1016/f/1/A">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1016(f)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “highway projects under this chapter” for “projects on any Federal-aid system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1016/c">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1016(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “Projects on the Federal-aid secondary system in which Federal funds participate shall be constructed according to specifications that will provide all-weather service and permit maintenance at a reasonable cost.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1016/f/1/B">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1016(f)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “highway” for “system” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (p), (q). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1016/d">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1016(d)</ref>, (e), added subsecs. (p) and (q).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/97/424">Pub. L. 97–424</ref> added subsec. (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/96/106">Pub. L. 96–106</ref> struck out “any aspect of” after “adversely affect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/s141/f">Pub. L. 95–599, § 141(f)</ref>, inserted “bikeways” after “surfaces, median strips,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/s113">Pub. L. 95–599, § 113</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/s116/d">Pub. L. 95–599, § 116(d)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/s141/g">Pub. L. 95–599, § 141(g)</ref>, added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/s152/2">Pub. L. 93–87, § 152(2)</ref>, substituted “Act” for “Rct”, thus correcting the popular name to read “Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1970”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/s114">Pub. L. 93–87, § 114</ref>, authorized promulgation of noise-level standards for highways on any Federal-aid system for which project approval has been secured prior to <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, and approval of any project on a Federal-aid system to which noise-level standards are made applicable, described the range of the projects, made money available for financing Federal share of the project, and deemed such project a highway project for all purposes of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/s156">Pub. L. 93–87, § 156</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/91/605/s136/a">Pub. L. 91–605, § 136(a)</ref>, substituted provisions ordering the Secretary to issue within 30 days after <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, guidelines, which will apply to all proposed proj­ects approved by the Secretary after their issuance, for minimizing soil erosion from highway construction for provisions authorizing the Secretary to consult with the Secretary of Agriculture respecting guidelines for minimizing soil erosion from highway construction and report such guidelines to Congress not later than <date date="1967-07-01">July 1, 1967</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/91/605/s136/b">Pub. L. 91–605, § 136(b)</ref>, added subsecs. (h) to (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/574/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–574, § 5(a)</ref>, required that in all cases the standards provide for at least four lanes of traffic.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/89/574/s14">Pub. L. 89–574, § 14</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/88/157">Pub. L. 88–157</ref> substituted “Such standards, as applied to each actual construction project, shall be adequate to enable such project to accommodate the types and volumes of traffic anticipated for such project for the twenty-year period commencing on the date of approval by the Secretary, under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>, of the plans, specifications, and estimates for actual construction of such project” for “Such standards shall be adequate to accommodate the types and volumes of traffic forecast for the year 1975”, struck out “up” before “to such standards” and inserted “all” in phrase “throughout all the States”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id2e2a7b99-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e2a7b9a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref> effective <date date="2021-10-01">Oct. 1, 2021</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s10003">section 10003 of Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e2a7b9b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1446/d">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1446(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1438">129 Stat. 1438</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1446(d)(5)(B) is effective as of <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e2a7b9c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e2a7b9d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> effective <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, and applicable to funds authorized to be appropriated or made available after <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, and, with certain exceptions, not applicable to funds appropriated or made available on or before <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1100">section 1100 of Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104">section 104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7b9e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Updates to Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11135">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11135</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/516">135 Stat. 516</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11135">
<inline>“In carrying out the first update to the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s109/d/2">section 109(d)(2) of title 23</ref>, United States Code, to the greatest extent practicable, the Secretary [of Transportation] shall include updates necessary to provide for—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the protection of vulnerable road users (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s148/a">section 148(a) of title 23</ref>, United States Code);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> supporting the safe testing of automated vehicle technology and any preparation necessary for the safe integration of automated vehicles onto public streets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> appropriate use of variable message signs to enhance public safety;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the minimum retroreflectivity of traffic control devices and pavement markings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> any additional recommendations made by the National Committee on Uniform Traffic Control Devices that have not been incorporated into the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7b9f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Roadside Highway Safety Hardware</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11517">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11517</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/601">135 Stat. 601</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11517">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary [of Transportation] shall develop a process for third party verification of full-scale crash testing results from crash test labs, including a method for formally verifying the testing outcomes and providing for an independent pass/fail determination. In establishing such a process, the Secretary shall seek to ensure the independence of crash test labs by ensuring that those labs have a clear separation between device development and testing in cases in which lab employees test devices that were developed within the parent organization of the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continued Issuance of Eligibility Letters</inline>.—</heading><content>Until the implementation of the process described in subsection (a) is complete, the Secretary may, and is encouraged to, ensure that the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration continues to issue Federal-aid reimbursement eligibility letters for roadside safety hardware as a service to States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary seeks to discontinue issuing the letters described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report at least 1 year before discontinuing the letters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading><content>The report described in paragraph (1) shall include a summary of the third-party verification process described in subsection (a) that will replace the Federal Highway Administration issuance of eligibility letters and any other relevant information that the Secretary deems necessary.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba0-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Stormwater Best Management Practices Reports</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11521">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11521</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/603">135 Stat. 603</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11521">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Administrator’ means the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Best management practices report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘best management practices report’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the 2014 report sponsored by the Administrator entitled ‘Determining the State of the Practice in Data Collection and Performance Measurement of Stormwater Best Management Practices’; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the 1997 report sponsored by the Administrator entitled ‘Stormwater Best Management Practices in an Ultra-Urban Setting: Selection and Monitoring’.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reissuance</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>], the Administrator shall update and reissue each best management practices report to reflect new information and advancements in stormwater management.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updates</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not less frequently than once every 5 years after the date on which the Administrator reissues a best management practices report described in subsection (b), the Administrator shall update and reissue the best management practices report until the earlier of the date on which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the best management practices report is withdrawn; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the contents of the best management practices report are incorporated (including by reference) into applicable regulations of the Administrator.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba1-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Retroactive Application of Adjustment to Criteria for Categorical Exclusion for Projects of Limited Federal Assistance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1314/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1314(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1403">129 Stat. 1403</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1314/b">
<inline>“The first adjustment made pursuant to the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1317">section 1317 of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out under this section] shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> be carried out not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> reflect the increase in the Consumer Price Index since <date date="2012-07-01">July 1, 2012</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba2-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Categorical Exclusion Determinations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1315/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1315(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1403">129 Stat. 1403</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1315/b">
<inline>“Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>], the Secretary [of Transportation] shall revise section 771.117(g) of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations, to allow a programmatic agreement under this section [see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1318/e">section 1318(e) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out under this section] to include responsibility for making categorical exclusion determinations—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> for actions described in subsections (c) and (d) of section 771.117 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that meet the criteria for a categorical exclusion under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), and are identified in the programmatic agreement.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba3-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Roadway Design Standard Flexibility</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1404/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1404(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1409">129 Stat. 1409</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1404/b">
<inline>“Notwithstanding section 109(<i>o</i>) of title 23, United States Code, a State may allow a local jurisdiction to use a roadway design publication that is different from the roadway design publication used by the State in which the local jurisdiction is located for the design of a project on a roadway under the ownership of the local jurisdiction (other than a highway on the Interstate System) if—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the local jurisdiction is a direct recipient of Federal funds for the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the roadway design publication—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is recognized by the Federal Highway Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is adopted by the local jurisdiction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the design complies with all other applicable Federal laws.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba4-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Exemptions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1432">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1432</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1429">129 Stat. 1429</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1432">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Any road, highway, railway, bridge, or transit facility that is damaged by an emergency that is declared by the Governor of the State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Homeland Security, or declared as an emergency by the President pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.), and that is in operation or under construction on the date on which the emergency occurs may be reconstructed in the same location with the same capacity, dimensions, and design as before the emergency subject to the exemptions and expedited procedures under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemptions and Expedited Procedures.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternative arrangements</inline>.—</heading><content>Alternative arrangements for an emergency under section 1506.11 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>]) shall apply to reconstruction under subsection (a), and the reconstruction shall be considered necessary to control the immediate impacts of the emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Stormwater discharge permits</inline>.—</heading><content>A general permit for stormwater discharges from construction activities, if available, issued by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency or the director of a State program under section 402(p) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1342/p">33 U.S.C. 1342(p)</ref>), as applicable, shall apply to reconstruction under subsection (a), on submission of a notice of intent to be subject to the permit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>The emergency procedures for issuing permits in accordance with section 325.2(e)(4) of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act) shall apply to reconstruction under subsection (a), and the reconstruction shall be considered an emergency under that regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National historic preservation act exemption</inline>.—</heading><content>Reconstruction under subsection (a) is eligible for an exemption from the requirements of the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966 [<ref href="/us/pl/89/665">Pub. L. 89–665</ref>, see Tables for classification] pursuant to part 78 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Endangered species act exemption</inline>.—</heading><content>An exemption from the requirements of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</ref> et seq.) pursuant to section 7(p) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1536/p">16 U.S.C. 1536(p)</ref>) shall apply to reconstruction under subsection (a) and, if the President makes the determination required under section 7(p) of that Act, the determinations required under subsections (g) and (h) of that section shall be deemed to be made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited consultation under endangered species act</inline>.—</heading><content>Expedited consultation pursuant to section 402.05 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act) shall apply to reconstruction under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other exemptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any reconstruction that is exempt under paragraph (5) shall also be exempt from requirements under—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s703">16 U.S.C. 703</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1271">16 U.S.C. 1271</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s661">16 U.S.C. 661</ref> et seq.).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba5-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Safety for Users</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1442">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1442</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1436">129 Stat. 1436</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1442">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall encourage each State and metropolitan planning organization to adopt standards for the design of Federal surface transportation projects that provide for the safe and adequate accommodation (as determined by the State) of all users of the surface transportation network, including motorized and nonmotorized users, in all phases of project planning, development, and operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>], the Secretary shall make available to the public a report cataloging examples of State law or State transportation policy that provide for the safe and adequate accommodation of all users of the surface transportation network, in all phases of project planning, development, and operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Best Practices</inline>.—</heading><content>Based on the report under subsection (b), the Secretary shall identify and disseminate examples of best practices where States have adopted measures that have successfully provided for the safe and adequate accommodation of all users of the surface transportation network in all phases of project planning, development, and operation.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba6-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Categorical Exclusions in Emergencies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1315">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1315</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/549">126 Stat. 549</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1315">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>], for the repair or reconstruction of any road, highway, or bridge that is in operation or under construction when damaged by an emergency declared by the Governor of the State and concurred in by the Secretary [of Transportation], or for a disaster or emergency declared by the President pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</ref> et seq.), the Secretary shall publish a notice of proposed rulemaking to treat any such repair or reconstruction activity as a class of action categorically excluded from the requirements relating to environmental assessments or environmental impact statements under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, and section 771.117 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act) if such repair or reconstruction activity is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in the same location with the same capacity, dimensions, and design as the original road, highway, or bridge as before the declaration described in this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> commenced within a 2-year period beginning on the date of a declaration described in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall ensure that the rulemaking helps to conserve Federal resources and protects public safety and health by providing for periodic evaluations to determine if reasonable alternatives exist to roads, highways, or bridges that repeatedly require repair and reconstruction activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reasonable alternatives</inline>.—</heading><content>The reasonable alternatives described in paragraph (1) include actions that could reduce the need for Federal funds to be expended on such repair and reconstruction activities, better protect public safety and health and the environment, and meet transportation needs as described in relevant and applicable Federal, State, local and tribal plans.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba7-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Categorical Exclusions for Projects Within the Right-of-way</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1316">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1316</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/549">126 Stat. 549</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1316">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>], designate any project (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 23</ref>, United States Code) within an existing operational right-of-way as an action categorically excluded from the requirements relating to environmental assessments or environmental impact statements under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, and section 771.117(c) of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not later than 150 days after the date of enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations to carry out paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of an Operational Right-of-way</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘operational right-of-way’ means all real property interests acquired for the construction, operation, or mitigation of a project (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 23</ref>, United States Code), including the locations of the roadway, bridges, interchanges, culverts, drainage, clear zone, traffic control signage, landscaping, and any rest areas with direct access to a controlled access highway.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2a7ba8-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Categorical Exclusion for Projects of Limited Federal Assistance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1317">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1317</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/550">126 Stat. 550</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1314/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1314(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1402">129 Stat. 1402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11317">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11317</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/543">135 Stat. 543</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11317">
<inline>“Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>], the Secretary [of Transportation] shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> designate as an action categorically excluded from the requirements relating to environmental assessments or environmental impact statements under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, and section 771.117(c) of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations, any project—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> that receives less than $6,000,000 (as adjusted annually by the Secretary [of Transportation] to reflect any increases in the Consumer Price Index prepared by the Department of Labor) of Federal funds; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with a total estimated cost of not more than $35,000,000 (as adjusted annually by the Secretary to reflect any increases in the Consumer Price Index prepared by the Department of Labor) and Federal funds comprising less than 15 percent of the total estimated project cost; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not later than 150 days after the date of enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations to carry out paragraph (1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2ceba9-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Programmatic Agreements and Additional Categorical Exclusions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1318">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1318</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/550">126 Stat. 550</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1315/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1315(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1403">129 Stat. 1403</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1315/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>], the Secretary [of Transportation] shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> survey the use by the Department [of Transportation] of categorical exclusions in transportation projects since 2005;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> publish a review of the survey that includes a description of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the types of actions categorically excluded; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any requests previously received by the Secretary for new categorical exclusions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> solicit requests from State departments of transportation, transit authorities, metropolitan planning organizations, or other government agencies for new categorical exclusions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">New Categorical Exclusions</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish a notice of proposed rulemaking to propose new categorical exclusions received by the Secretary under subsection (a), to the extent that the categorical exclusions meet the criteria for a categorical exclusion under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, and section 771.117(a) of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (as those regulations are in effect on the date of the notice).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Actions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall issue a proposed rulemaking to move the following types of actions from subsection (d) of section 771.117 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), to subsection (c) of that section, to the extent that such movement complies with the criteria for a categorical exclusion under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act):</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Modernization of a highway by resurfacing, restoration, rehabilitation, reconstruction, adding shoulders, or adding auxiliary lanes (including parking, weaving, turning, and climbing).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Highway safety or traffic operations improvement projects, including the installation of ramp metering control devices and lighting.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Bridge rehabilitation, reconstruction, or replacement or the construction of grade separation to replace existing at-grade railroad crossings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Programmatic Agreements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall seek opportunities to enter into programmatic agreements with the States that establish efficient administrative procedures for carrying out environmental and other required project reviews.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading><content>Programmatic agreements authorized under paragraph (1) may include agreements that allow a State to determine on behalf of the Federal Highway Administration whether a project is categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determinations</inline>.—</heading><content>An agreement described in paragraph (2) may include determinations by the Secretary [of Transportation] of the types of projects categorically excluded (consistent with section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations) in the State in addition to the types listed in subsections (c) and (d) of section 771.117 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Programmatic Agreement Template.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall develop a template programmatic agreement described in subsection (d) that provides for efficient and adequate procedures for evaluating Federal actions described in section 771.117(c) of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this subsection [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>]).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of template</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> on receipt of a request from a State, shall use the template programmatic agreement developed under paragraph (1) in carrying out this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> on consent of the applicable State, may modify the template as necessary to address the unique needs and characteristics of the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outcome measurements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish a method to verify that actions described in section 771.117(c) of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this subsection), are evaluated and documented in a consistent manner by the State that uses the template programmatic agreement under this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebaa-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Engineering Judgment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1529">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1529</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/583">126 Stat. 583</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1529">“Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>], the Secretary [of Transportation] shall issue guidance to State transportation departments clarifying that the standards, guidance, and options for design and application of traffic control devices provided in the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices should not be considered a substitute for engineering judgment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebab-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Highway Signs Relating to Veterans Cemeteries</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/29/s3">Pub. L. 108–29, § 3</ref>, <date date="2003-05-29">May 29, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/772">117 Stat. 772</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/29/s3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the terms of any agreement entered into by the Secretary of Transportation and a State under section 109(d) or 402(a) of title 23, United States Code, a veterans cemetery shall be treated as a site for which a supplemental guide sign may be placed on any Federal-aid highway.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a) shall apply to an agreement entered into before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-05-29">May 29, 2003</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebac-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Roughness Index</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1213/b">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1213(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/200">112 Stat. 200</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1213/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the international roughness index that is used as an indicator of pavement quality on the Federal-aid highway system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required elements</inline>.—</heading><content>The study shall specify the extent of usage of the index and the extent to which the international roughness index measurement is reliable across different manufacturers and types of pavement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>], the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebad-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Environmental Streamlining</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1309">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1309</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/232">112 Stat. 232</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIX/s9004/c">Pub. L. 105–206, title IX, § 9004(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/843">112 Stat. 843</ref>, which directed the Secretary of Transportation to develop and implement a coordinated environmental review process for highway construction and mass transit projects, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tVI/s6002/d">Pub. L. 109–59, title VI, § 6002(d)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1865">119 Stat. 1865</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebae-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Roadside Safety Technologies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1402">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1402</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/236">112 Stat. 236</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIX/s9005/c">Pub. L. 105–206, title IX, § 9005(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/848">112 Stat. 848</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/206/tIX/s9005/c">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Crash Cushions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>], the Secretary shall issue guidance regarding the benefits and safety performance of redirective and nonredirective crash cushions in different road applications, taking into consideration roadway conditions, operating speed limits, the location of the crash cushion in the right-of-way, and any other relevant factors. The guidance shall include recommendations on the most appropriate circumstances for utilization of redirective and nonredirective crash cushions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>States shall use the guidance issued under this subsection in evaluating the safety and cost-effectiveness of utilizing different crash cushion designs and determining whether redirective or nonredirective crash cushions or other safety appurtenances should be installed at specific highway locations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Traffic Flow and Safety Applications of Road Barriers.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall conduct a study on the technologies and methods to enhance safety, streamline construction, and improve capacity by providing positive separation at all times between traffic, equipment, and workers on highway construction projects. The study shall also address how such technologies can be used to improve capacity and safety at those specific highway, bridge, and other appropriate locations where reversible lane, contraflow, and high occupancy vehicle lane operations are implemented during peak traffic periods.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Uses to consider</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consider, at a minimum, uses of positive separation technologies related to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> separating workers from traffic flow when work is in progress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> providing additional safe work space by utilizing adjacent and available traffic lanes during off-peak hours;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> rapid deployment to allow for daily or periodic restoration of lanes for use by traffic during peak hours as needed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> mitigating congestion caused by construction by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> opening all adjacent and available lanes to traffic during peak traffic hours; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> using reversible lanes to optimize capacity of the highway by adjusting to directional traffic flow; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> permanent use of positive separation technologies to create contraflow or reversible lanes to increase the capacity of congested highways, bridges, and tunnels.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>], the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study. The report shall include findings and recommendations for the use of the technologies referred to in paragraph (2) to provide positive separation on appropriate projects.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebaf-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Metric Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tII/s205/c">Pub. L. 104–59, title II, § 205(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/577">109 Stat. 577</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1211/d">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1211(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/188">112 Stat. 188</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1211/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Placement and modification of signs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not require the States to expend any Federal or State funds to construct, erect, or otherwise place or to modify any sign relating to a speed limit, distance, or other measurement on a highway for the purpose of having such sign establish such speed limit, distance, or other measurement using the metric system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other actions</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not require that any State use or plan to use the metric system with respect to designing or advertising, or preparing plans, specifications, estimates, or other documents, for a Federal-aid highway project eligible for assistance under title 23, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Highway</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘highway’ has the meaning such term has under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of title 23</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Metric system</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘metric system’ has the meaning the term ‘metric system of measurement’ has under section 4 of the Metric Conversion Act of 1975 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s205c">15 U.S.C. 205c</ref>).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb0-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Type II Noise Barriers</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s339/b">Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 339(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/605">109 Stat. 605</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s339/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General rule</inline>.—</heading><content>No funds made available out of the Highway Trust Fund may be used to construct Type II noise barriers (as defined by section 772.5(i) of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations) pursuant to subsections (h) and (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s109">section 109 of title 23</ref>, United States Code, if such barriers were not part of a project approved by the Secretary before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to construction of Type II noise barriers along lands that were developed or were under substantial construction before approval of the acquisition of the rights-of-ways for, or construction of, the existing highway.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb1-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Highway Signs for National Highway System</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s359/b">Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 359(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/626">109 Stat. 626</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s359/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall conduct a study to determine the cost, need, and efficacy of establishing a highway sign for identifying routes on the National Highway System. In conducting the study, the Secretary shall make a determination concerning whether to identify National Highway System route numbers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1997-03-01">March 1, 1997</date>, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the results of the study.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb2-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Recycled Paving Material</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1038">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1038</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1987">105 Stat. 1987</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tII/s205/b">Pub. L. 104–59, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, title III, § 327, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/577">109 Stat. 577</ref>, 592, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/59/tII/s205/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Asphalt Pavement Containing Recycled Rubber Demonstration Program</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of title 23, United States Code, or regulation or policy of the Department of Transportation, the Secretary (or a State acting as the Department’s agent) may not disapprove a highway project under chapter 1 of title 23, United States Code, on the ground that the project includes the use of asphalt pavement containing recycled rubber. Under this subsection, a patented application process for recycled rubber shall be eligible for approval under the same conditions that an unpatented process is eligible for approval.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Studies.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall coordinate and conduct, in cooperation with the States, a study to determine—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the threat to human health and the environment associated with the production and use of asphalt pavement containing recycled rubber;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the degree to which asphalt pavement containing recycled rubber can be recycled; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the performance of the asphalt pavement containing recycled rubber under various climate and use conditions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Division of responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall conduct the part of the study relating to paragraph (1)(A) and the Secretary shall conduct the part of the study relating to paragraph (1)(C). The Administrator and the Secretary shall jointly conduct the study relating to paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary and the Administrator, in cooperation with the States, shall jointly conduct a study to determine the economic savings, technical performance qualities, threats to human health and the environment, and environmental benefits of using recycled materials in highway devices and appurtenances and highway projects, including asphalt containing over 80 percent reclaimed asphalt, asphalt containing recycled glass, and asphalt containing recycled plastic.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional elements</inline>.—</heading><content>In conducting the study under paragraph (3), the Secretary and the Administrator shall examine utilization of various technologies by States and shall examine the current practices of all States relating to the reuse and disposal of materials used in federally assisted highway projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>], the Secretary and the Administrator shall transmit to Congress a report on the results of the studies conducted under this subsection, including a detailed analysis of the economic savings and technical performance qualities of using such recycled materials in federally assisted highway projects and the environmental benefits of using such recycled materials in such highway projects in terms of reducing air emissions, conserving natural resources, and reducing disposal of the materials in landfills.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">DOT Guidance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information gathering and distribution</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall gather information and recommendations concerning the use of asphalt containing recycled rubber in highway projects from those States that have extensively evaluated and experimented with the use of such asphalt and implemented such projects and shall make available such information and recommendations on the use of such asphalt to those States which indicate an interest in the use of such asphalt.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Encouragement of use</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary should encourage the use of recycled materials determined to be appropriate by the studies pursuant to subsection (b) in federally assisted highway projects. Procuring agencies shall comply with all applicable guidelines or regulations issued by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Asphalt Pavement Containing Recycled Rubber.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Crumb rubber modifier research</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the National Highway System Designation Act of 1995 [<date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>], the Secretary shall develop testing procedures and conduct research to develop performance grade classifications, in accordance with the strategic highway research program carried out under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s307/d">section 307(d) of title 23</ref>, United States Code, for crumb rubber modifier binders. The testing procedures and performance grade classifications should be developed in consultation with representatives of the crumb rubber modifier industry and other interested parties (including the asphalt paving industry) with experience in the development of the procedures and classifications.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Crumb rubber modifier program development.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may make grants to States to develop programs to use crumb rubber from scrap tires to modify asphalt pavements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of grant funds</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Grant funds made available to States under this paragraph shall be used—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to develop mix designs for crumb rubber modified asphalt pavements;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> for the placement and evaluation of crumb rubber modified asphalt pavement field tests; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> for the expansion of State crumb rubber modifier programs in existence on the date the grant is made available.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purpose of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘asphalt pavement containing recycled rubber’ means any mixture of asphalt and crumb rubber derived from whole scrap tires, such that the physical properties of the asphalt are modified through the mixture, for use in pavement maintenance, rehabilitation, or construction applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘recycled rubber’ is any crumb rubber derived from processing whole scrap tires or shredded tire material taken from automobiles, trucks, or other equipment owned and operated in the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb3-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Survey and Report on Upgrading of Design Standards</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1049">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1049</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2000">105 Stat. 2000</ref>, directed Secretary to conduct a survey to identify current State standards relating to geometric design, traffic control devices, roadside safety, safety appurtenance design, uniform traffic control devices, and sign legibility and directional clarity for all Federal-aid highways and, not later than 2 years after <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, to transmit to Congress a report on the results of the survey and the crashworthiness of traffic lights, traffic signs, guardrails, impact attenuators, concrete barrier treatments, and breakaway utility poles for bridges and roadways currently used by States.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb4-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Erosion Control Guidelines</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1057">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1057</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2002">105 Stat. 2002</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1057">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop erosion control guidelines for States to follow in carrying out construction projects funded in whole or in part under this title [see Tables for classification].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">More Stringent State Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Guidelines developed under subsection (a) shall not preempt any requirement made by or under State law if such requirement is more stringent than the guidelines.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consistency With Other Programs</inline>.—</heading><content>Guidelines developed under subsection (a) shall be consistent with nonpoint source management programs under section 319 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1329">33 U.S.C. 1329</ref>] and coastal nonpoint pollution control guidance under section 6217(g) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1455b/g">16 U.S.C. 1455b(g)</ref>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb5-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Roadside Barrier Technology</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1058">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1058</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2003">105 Stat. 2003</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s328">Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 328</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/593">109 Stat. 593</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s328">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Innovative Barriers</inline>.—</heading><content>Not less than 2½ percent of the mileage of new or replacement permanent or temporary crashworthy barriers included in awarded contracts along Federal-aid highways within the boundaries of a State in each calendar year shall be innovative crashworthy safety barriers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><content>Each State shall annually certify to the Secretary its compliance with the requirements of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Innovative Crashworthy Safety Barrier</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term ‘innovative crashworthy safety barrier’ means a barrier, other than a guardrail or guiderail, classified by the Federal Highway Administration as ‘experimental’ or that was classified as ‘operational’ after <date date="1985-01-01">January 1, 1985</date>, and that meets or surpasses the requirements of the National Cooperative Highway Research Program 350 for longitudinal barriers.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb6-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Roadside Barriers and Safety Appurtenances</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1073">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1073</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2012">105 Stat. 2012</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1073">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initiation of Rulemaking Proceeding</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>], the Secretary shall initiate a rulemaking proceeding to revise the guidelines and establish standards for installation of roadside barriers and other safety appurtenances, including longitudinal barriers, end terminals, and crash cushions. Such rulemaking shall reflect state-of-the-art designs, testing, and evaluation criteria contained in the National Cooperative Highway Research Program Report 230, relating to approval standards which provide an enhanced level of crashworthy performance to accommodate vans, mini-vans, pickup trucks, and 4-wheel drive vehicles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>], the Secretary shall complete the rulemaking proceeding initiated under subsection (a), and issue a final rule regarding the implementation of revised guidelines and standards for acceptable roadside barriers and other safety appurtenances, including longitudinal barriers, end terminals, and crash cushions. Such revised guidelines and standards shall accommodate vans, mini-vans, pickup trucks, and 4-wheel drive vehicles and shall be applicable to the refurbishment and replacement of existing roadside barriers and safety appurtenances as well as to the installation of new roadside barriers and safety appurtenances.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb7-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Studies Relating to Establishment of Standards for Resurfacing, Restoration, and Rehabilitation of Highways and to Establishment of Uniform Standards and Criteria for Testing and Inspecting Highways and Bridges</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/424/tI/s110/b">Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 110(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2105">96 Stat. 2105</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/424/tI/s110/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Secretary of Transportation shall enter into appropriate arrangements with the National Academy of Sciences (1) to conduct a study of the safety cost-effectiveness of geometric design criteria of standards currently in effect for construction and reconstruction of highways, other than highways access to which is fully controlled, to determine the most appropriate minimum standards to apply to resurfacing, restoration, and rehabilitation projects on such highways, which study shall include a study of the cost effectiveness of the hot dip galvanizing process for the installation, repair, or replacement of exposed structural and miscellaneous steel, and (2) to propose standards to preserve and extend the service life of such highways and enhance highway safety. The National Academy of Sciences shall conduct such study in cooperation with the National Transportation Safety Board, the Congressional Budget Office, and the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials. Upon completion of such study, the National Academy of Sciences shall submit such study and its proposed standards to the Secretary of Transportation for review. Within ninety days after submission of such standards to the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary shall submit such study and the proposed standards of the National Academy of Sciences, together with the recommendations of the Secretary, to Congress for approval.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Transportation is directed to coordinate a study with the National Bureau of Standards, the American Society for Testing and Materials, and other organizations as deemed appropriate, (A) to determine the existing quality of design, construction, products, use, and systems for highways and bridges; (B) to determine the need for uniform standards and criteria for design, processing, products, and applications, including personnel training and implementation of enforcement techniques; and (C) to determine the manpower needs and costs of developing a national system for the evaluation and accreditation of testing and inspection agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall submit such study to the Congress not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb8-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expenditure of Federal Funds for Highway Signs Using Metric System</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tI/s144">Pub. L. 95–599, title I, § 144</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2713">92 Stat. 2713</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/106/s14">Pub. L. 96–106, § 14</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/798">93 Stat. 798</ref>, which prohibited use of Federal funds for signing solely in the metric system, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1053">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1053</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2001">105 Stat. 2001</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e2cebb9-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modification of Project Agreements To Effectuate Requirement of Four-Lanes of Traffic</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authorization to modify projects agreements entered into prior to <date date="1966-09-13">September 13, 1966</date>, to effectuate the amendment of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/89/574">Pub. L. 89–574</ref> which added the requirement of four-lanes of traffic, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/574/s5/b">section 5(b) of Pub. L. 89–574</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s106">section 106 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
