<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id2e3d8e0a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s121"><num value="121">§ 121.</num><heading> Payment to States for construction</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e3d8e0b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s121/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary, from time to time as the work progresses, may make payments to a State for costs of construction incurred by the State on a project (including payments made pursuant to a long-term concession agreement, such as availability payments). Such payments may also be made for the value of the materials—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e3d8e0c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s121/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that have been stockpiled in the vicinity of the construction in conformity to plans and specifications for the projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e3d8e0d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s121/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that are not in the vicinity of the construction if the Secretary determines that because of required fabrication at an off-site location the material cannot be stockpiled in such vicinity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e3d8e0e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s121/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Project Agreement</inline>.—</heading><content>No payment shall be made under this chapter except for a project covered by a project agreement. After completion of the project in accordance with the project agreement, a State shall be entitled to payment out of the appropriate sums apportioned or allocated to the State of the unpaid balance of the Federal share payable for such project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e3d8e0f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s121/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Such payments shall be made to such official or officials or depository as may be designated by the State transportation department and authorized under the laws of the State to receive public funds of the State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id2e3d8e10-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/767">Pub. L. 85–767</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/899">72 Stat. 899</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/157/s7/b">Pub. L. 88–157, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1963-10-24">Oct. 24, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/278">77 Stat. 278</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/tI/s117">Pub. L. 93–87, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/259">87 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/280/tI/s118/a">Pub. L. 94–280, title I, § 118(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-05">May 5, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/437">90 Stat. 437</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/tI/s133/b/6">Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 133(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/171">101 Stat. 171</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1018/b">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1018(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1948">105 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI">Pub. L. 105–178, title I</ref>, §§ 1212(a)(2)(A)(i), 1302, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/193">112 Stat. 193</ref>, 226; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tII/s2002/a">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title II, § 2002(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1446">129 Stat. 1446</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id2e3d8e11-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id2e3d8e12-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id2e3d8e13-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> inserted “(including payments made pursuant to a long-term concession agreement, such as availability payments)” after “a project” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1302/1">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1302(1)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which read as follows: “The Secretary may, in his discretion, from time to time as the work progresses, make payments to a State for costs of construction incurred by it on a project. These payments shall at no time exceed the Federal share of the costs of construction incurred to the date of the voucher covering such payment plus the Federal share of the value of the materials which have been stockpiled in the vicinity of such construction in conformity to plans and specifications for the project. Such payments may also be made in the case of any such materials not in the vicinity of such construction if the Secretary determines that because of required fabrication at an off-site location the materials cannot be stockpiled in such vicinity.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1302/1">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1302(1)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “After completion of a project in accordance with the plans and specifications, and approval of the final voucher by the Secretary, a State shall be entitled to payment out of the appropriate sums apportioned to it of the unpaid balance of the Federal share payable on account of such project.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1302/2">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1302(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (e) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which read as follows: “No payment shall be made under this chapter, except for a project located on a Federal-aid system and covered by a project agreement. No final payment shall be made to a State for its costs of construction of a project until the completion of the construction has been approved by the Secretary following inspections pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s114/a">section 114(a) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1302/2">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1302(2)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which read as follows: “In making payments pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall be bound by the limitations with respect to the permissible amounts of such payments continued in sections 106(c), 120, and 130 of this title.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1302/3">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1302(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1212/a/2/A/i">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1212(a)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “State transportation department” for “State highway department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> substituted “106(c), 120,” for “120” and struck out at end “Payments for construction engineering on any project financed with Federal-aid highway funds shall not exceed 15 percent of the Federal share of the cost of construction of such project after excluding from the cost of construction the costs of rights-of-way, preliminary engineering, and construction engineering.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17">Pub. L. 100–17</ref> substituted “15 percent” for “10 per centum” and struck out at end “However, this limitation shall be 15 per centum in any State with respect to which the Secretary finds such higher limitation to be necessary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/280">Pub. L. 94–280</ref> substituted “Federal-aid highway funds” for “Federal-aid primary, secondary, or urban funds” and struck out 10 per centum limitation provision for any project financed with interstate funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87">Pub. L. 93–87</ref> authorized payments to be made for materials not in the construction vicinity where the Secretary determines that because of required fabrication at an off-site location the materials cannot be stockpiled in such vicinity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/88/157">Pub. L. 88–157</ref> substituted “any project financed with Federal-aid primary, secondary, or urban funds” for “any one project” and provided for limitation, on payments for construction engineering on projects financed with Federal-aid primary, secondary, or urban funds, of 15 percent of Federal share of cost of construction of the project where found by the Secretary to be necessary and for 10–percent limitation on projects financed with interstate funds.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id2e3d8e14-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e3d8e15-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e3d8e16-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> effective <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, and applicable to funds authorized to be appropriated or made available after <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, and, with certain exceptions, not applicable to funds appropriated or made available on or before <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1100">section 1100 of Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104">section 104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e3d8e17-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">At-Risk Project Preagreement Authority</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1440">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1440</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1434">129 Stat. 1434</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1440">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Preliminary Engineering</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘preliminary engineering’ means allowable preconstruction project development and engineering costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">At-risk Project Preagreement Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A recipient or subrecipient of Federal-aid funds under title 23, United States Code, may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> incur preliminary engineering costs for an eligible project under title 23, United States Code, before receiving project authorization from the State, in the case of a subrecipient, and the Secretary [of Transportation] to proceed with the project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> request reimbursement of applicable Federal funds after the project authorization is received.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may reimburse preliminary engineering costs incurred by a recipient or subrecipient under subsection (b)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> if the costs meet all applicable requirements under title 23, United States Code, at the time the costs are incurred and the Secretary concurs that the requirements have been met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the case of a project located within a designated nonattainment or maintenance area for air quality, if the conformity requirements of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.) have been met; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> if the costs would have been allowable if incurred after the date of the project authorization by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">At-risk</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A recipient or subrecipient that elects to use the authority provided under this section shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> assume all risk for preliminary engineering costs incurred prior to project authorization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> be responsible for ensuring and demonstrating to the Secretary that all applicable cost eligibility conditions are met after the authorization is received.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restrictions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> allows a recipient or subrecipient to use the authority under this section to advance a project beyond preliminary engineering prior to the completion of the environmental review process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> waives the applicability of Federal requirements to a project other than the reimbursement of preliminary engineering costs incurred prior to an authorization to proceed in accordance with this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> guarantees Federal funding of the project or the eligibility of the project for future Federal-aid highway funding.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e3d8e18-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Submission of Recommendations to Congress for Reimbursement of States for Certain Highways</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/85/845">Pub. L. 85–845</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1083">72 Stat. 1083</ref>, required Secretary of Commerce, within ten days after first day of first session of Eighty-sixth Congress, to submit to Congress recommendations for legislation for purpose of assisting Congress to determine whether or not to reimburse each State of any portion of a toll or free highway (1) which was on National System of Interstate and Defense Highways [now Dwight D. Eisenhower System of Interstate and Defense Highways], (2) which met standards required by Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1956 for such System of Interstate and Defense Highways, and (3) construction of which had been completed since <date date="1947-08-02">Aug. 2, 1947</date>, or which had been in actual use or under construction by contract, for completion, awarded not later than <date date="1957-06-30">June 30, 1957</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
