<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id2e470423-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129"><num value="129">§ 129.</num><heading> Toll roads, bridges, tunnels, and ferries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e470424-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Basic Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470425-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization for federal participation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to the provisions of this section, Federal participation shall be permitted on the same basis and in the same manner as construction of toll-free highways is permitted under this chapter in the—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470426-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> initial construction of a toll highway, bridge, or tunnel or approach to the highway, bridge, or tunnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470427-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> initial construction of 1 or more lanes or other improvements that increase capacity of a highway, bridge, or tunnel (other than a highway on the Interstate System) and conversion of that highway, bridge, or tunnel to a tolled facility, if the number of toll-free lanes, excluding auxiliary lanes, after the construction is not less than the number of toll-free lanes, excluding auxiliary lanes, before the construction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470428-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> initial construction of 1 or more lanes or other improvements that increase the capacity of a highway, bridge, or tunnel on the Interstate System and conversion of that highway, bridge, or tunnel to a tolled facility, if the number of toll-free non-HOV lanes, excluding auxiliary lanes, after such construction is not less than the number of toll-free non-HOV lanes, excluding auxiliary lanes, before such construction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470429-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> reconstruction, resurfacing, restoration, rehabilitation, or replacement of a toll highway, bridge, or tunnel or approach to the highway, bridge, or tunnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47042a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> reconstruction or replacement of a toll-free bridge or tunnel and conversion of the bridge or tunnel to a toll facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47042b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> reconstruction of a toll-free Federal-aid highway (other than a highway on the Interstate System) and conversion of the highway to a toll facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47042c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> reconstruction, restoration, or rehabilitation of a highway on the Interstate System if the number of toll-free non-HOV lanes, excluding auxiliary lanes, after reconstruction, restoration, or rehabilitation is not less than the number of toll-free non-HOV lanes, excluding auxiliary lanes, before reconstruction, restoration, or rehabilitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47042d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> conversion of a high occupancy vehicle lane on a highway, bridge, or tunnel to a toll facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47042e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> preliminary studies to determine the feasibility of a toll facility for which Federal participation is authorized under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47042f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ownership</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each highway, bridge, tunnel, or approach to the highway, bridge, or tunnel constructed under this subsection shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470430-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be publicly owned; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470431-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be privately owned if the public authority with jurisdiction over the highway, bridge, tunnel, or approach has entered into a contract with 1 or more private persons to design, finance, construct, and operate the facility and the public authority will be responsible for complying with all applicable requirements of this title with respect to the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470432-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on use of revenues.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470433-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A public authority with jurisdiction over a toll facility shall ensure that all toll revenues received from operation of the toll facility are used only for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470434-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> debt service with respect to the projects on or for which the tolls are authorized, including funding of reasonable reserves and debt service on refinancing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470435-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a reasonable return on investment of any private person financing the project, as determined by the State or interstate compact of States concerned;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470436-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any costs necessary for the improvement and proper operation and maintenance of the toll facility, including reconstruction, resurfacing, restoration, and rehabilitation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470437-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> if the toll facility is subject to a public-private partnership agreement, payments that the party holding the right to toll revenues owes to the other party under the public-private partnership agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470438-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> if the public authority certifies annually that the tolled facility is being adequately maintained, any other purpose for which Federal funds may be obligated by a State under this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470439-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual audit.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47043a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>A public authority with jurisdiction over a toll facility shall conduct or have an independent auditor conduct an annual audit of toll facility records to verify adequate maintenance and compliance with subparagraph (A), and report the results of the audits, together with the results of the audit under paragraph (9)(C), to the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47043b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading><content>On reasonable notice, the public authority shall make all records of the public authority pertaining to the toll facility available for audit by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47043c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Noncompliance</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary concludes that a public authority has not complied with the limitations on the use of revenues described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary may require the public authority to discontinue collecting tolls until an agreement with the Secretary is reached to achieve compliance with the limitation on the use of revenues described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47043d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for funding.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47043e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a toll facility under the jurisdiction of a public authority of a State (other than the State transportation department), on request of the State transportation department and subject to such terms and conditions as the department and public authority may agree, the Secretary, working through the State department of transportation, shall reimburse the public authority for the Federal share of the costs of construction of the project carried out on the toll facility under this subsection in the same manner and to the same extent as the department would be reimbursed if the project was being carried out by the department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47043f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Source</inline>.—</heading><content>The reimbursement of funds under this paragraph shall be from sums apportioned to the State under this chapter and available for obligations on projects on the Federal-aid highways in the State on which the project is being carried out.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470440-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on federal share</inline>.—</heading><content>The Federal share payable for a project described in paragraph (1) shall be a percentage determined by the State, but not to exceed 80 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470441-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Modifications</inline>.—</heading><content>If a public authority (including a State transportation department) with jurisdiction over a toll facility subject to an agreement under this section or section 119(e), as in effect on the day before the effective date of title I of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (<ref href="/us/stat/105/1915">105 Stat. 1915</ref>), requests modification of the agreement, the Secretary shall modify the agreement to allow the continuation of tolls in accordance with paragraph (3) without repayment of Federal funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470442-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loans.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470443-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470444-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—</heading><content>Using amounts made available under this title, a State may loan to a public or private entity constructing or proposing to construct under this section a toll facility or non-toll facility with a dedicated revenue source an amount equal to all or part of the Federal share of the cost of the project if the project has a revenue source specifically dedicated to the project.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470445-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dedicated revenue sources</inline>.—</heading><content>Dedicated revenue sources for non-toll facilities include excise taxes, sales taxes, motor vehicle use fees, tax on real property, tax increment financing, and such other dedicated revenue sources as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470446-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance with federal laws</inline>.—</heading><content>As a condition of receiving a loan under this paragraph, the public or private entity that receives the loan shall ensure that the project will be carried out in accordance with this title and any other applicable Federal law, including any applicable provision of a Federal environmental law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470447-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subordination of debt</inline>.—</heading><content>The amount of any loan received for a project under this paragraph may be subordinated to any other debt financing for the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470448-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Obligation of funds loaned</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds loaned under this paragraph may only be obligated for projects under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470449-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repayment</inline>.—</heading><content>The repayment of a loan made under this paragraph shall commence not later than 5 years after date on which the facility that is the subject of the loan is open to traffic.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47044a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Term of loan</inline>.—</heading><content>The term of a loan made under this paragraph shall not exceed 30 years from the date on which the loan funds are obligated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47044b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interest</inline>.—</heading><content>A loan made under this paragraph shall bear interest at or below market interest rates, as determined by the State, to make the project that is the subject of the loan feasible.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47044c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reuse of funds</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Amounts repaid to a State from a loan made under this paragraph may be obligated—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47044d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for any purpose for which the loan funds were available under this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47044e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for the purchase of insurance or for use as a capital reserve for other forms of credit enhancement for project debt in order to improve credit market access or to lower interest rates for projects eligible for assistance under this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47044f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/7/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish procedures and guidelines for making loans under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470450-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State law permitting tolling</inline>.—</heading><content>If a State does not have a highway, bridge, or tunnel toll facility as of the date of enactment of the MAP–21, before commencing any activity authorized under this section, the State shall have in effect a law that permits tolling on a highway, bridge, or tunnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470451-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Equal access for over-the-road buses.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470452-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>An over-the-road bus that serves the public shall be provided access to a toll facility under the same rates, terms, and conditions as public transportation vehicles.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470453-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470454-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, a public authority that operates a toll facility shall report to the Secretary any rates, terms, or conditions for access to the toll facility by public transportation vehicles that differ from the rates, terms, or conditions applicable to over-the-road buses.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470455-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updates</inline>.—</heading><content>A public authority that operates a toll facility shall report to the Secretary any change to the rates, terms, or conditions for access to the toll facility by public transportation vehicles that differ from the rates, terms, or conditions applicable to over-the-road buses by not later than 30 days after the date on which the change takes effect.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470456-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Publication</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall publish information reported to the Secretary under clauses (i) and (ii) on a publicly accessible internet website.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470457-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual audit.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470458-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A public authority (as defined in section 101(a)) with jurisdiction over a toll facility shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id2e470459-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> conduct or have an independent auditor conduct an annual audit of toll facility records to verify compliance with this paragraph; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id2e47045a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> report the results of the audit, together with the results of the audit under paragraph (3)(B), to the Secretary.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47045b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading><content>After providing reasonable notice, a public authority described in clause (i) shall make all records of the public authority pertaining to the toll facility available for audit by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47045c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/9/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Noncompliance</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary determines that a public authority described in clause (i) has not complied with this paragraph, the Secretary may require the public authority to discontinue collecting tolls until an agreement with the Secretary is reached to achieve compliance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47045d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">High occupancy vehicle use of certain toll facilities</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding section 102(a), in the case of a toll facility that is on the Interstate System and that is constructed or converted after the date of enactment of the Surface Transportation Reauthorization Act of 2021, the public authority with jurisdiction over the toll facility shall allow high occupancy vehicles, transit, and paratransit vehicles to use the facility at a discount rate or without charge, unless the public authority, in consultation with the Secretary, determines that the number of those vehicles using the facility reduces the travel time reliability of the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47045e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47045f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">High occupancy vehicle; hov</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “high occupancy vehicle” or “HOV” means a vehicle with not fewer than 2 occupants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470460-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial construction.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470461-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “initial construction” means the construction of a highway, bridge, tunnel, or other facility at any time before it is open to traffic.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470462-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusions</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “initial construction” does not include any improvement to a highway, bridge, tunnel, or other facility after it is open to traffic.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470463-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Over-the-road bus</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “over-the-road bus” has the meaning given the term in section 301 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12181">42 U.S.C. 12181</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470464-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “public authority” means a State, interstate compact of States, or public entity designated by a State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470465-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/a/11/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Toll facility</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “toll facility” means a toll highway, bridge, or tunnel or approach to the highway, bridge, or tunnel constructed under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e470466-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may permit Federal participation under this title in the construction of a project constituting an approach to a ferry, whether toll or free, the route of which is a public road and has not been designated as a route on the Interstate System. Such ferry may be either publicly or privately owned and operated, but the operating authority and the amount of fares charged for passage shall be under the control of a State agency or official, and all revenues derived from publicly owned or operated ferries shall be applied to payment of the cost of construction or acquisition thereof, including debt service, and to actual and necessary costs of operation, maintenance, repair, and replacement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e470467-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>, the Secretary may permit Federal participation under this title in the construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities (including ferry maintenance facilities), whether toll or free, and the procurement of transit vehicles used exclusively as an integral part of an intermodal ferry trip, subject to the following conditions:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470468-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It is not feasible to build a bridge, tunnel, combination thereof, or other normal highway structure in lieu of the use of such ferry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470469-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The operation of the ferry shall be on a route classified as a public road within the State and which has not been designated as a route on the Interstate System or on a public transit ferry eligible under chapter 53 of title 49. Projects under this subsection may be eligible for both ferry boats carrying cars and passengers and ferry boats carrying passengers only.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47046a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47046b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The ferry boat or ferry terminal facility shall be publicly owned or operated or majority publicly owned if the Secretary determines with respect to a majority publicly owned ferry or ferry terminal facility that such ferry boat or ferry terminal facility provides substantial public benefits.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47046c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any Federal participation shall not involve the construction or purchase, for private ownership, of a ferry boat, ferry terminal facility, or other eligible project under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47046d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The operating authority and the amount of fares charged for passage on such ferry shall be under the control of the State or other public entity, and all revenues derived therefrom shall be applied to actual and necessary costs of operation, maintenance, repair, debt service, negotiated management fees, and, in the case of a privately operated toll ferry, for a reasonable rate of return.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47046e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Such ferry may be operated only within the State (including the islands which comprise the State of Hawaii and the islands which comprise any territory of the United States) or between adjoining States or between a point in a State and a point in the Dominion of Canada. Except with respect to operations between the islands which comprise the State of Hawaii, operations between the islands which comprise any territory of the United States, operations between a point in a State and a point in the Dominion of Canada, and operations between any two points in Alaska and between Alaska and Washington, including stops at appropriate points in the Dominion of Canada, no part of such ferry operation shall be in any foreign or international waters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47046f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The ferry service shall be maintained in accordance with section 116.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470470-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470471-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> No ferry boat or ferry terminal with Federal participation under this title may be sold, leased, or otherwise disposed of, except in accordance with part 200 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470472-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/c/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Federal share of any proceeds from a disposition referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be used for eligible purposes under this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e470473-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congestion Relief Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470474-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470475-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible entity</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “eligible entity” means any of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470476-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> A State, for the purpose of carrying out a project in an urbanized area with a population of more than 1,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470477-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> A metropolitan planning organization, city, or municipality, for the purpose of carrying out a project in an urbanized area with a population of more than 1,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470478-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Integrated congestion management system</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “integrated congestion management system” means a system for the integration of management and operations of a regional transportation system that includes, at a minimum, traffic incident management, work zone management, traffic signal timing, managed lanes, real-time traveler information, and active traffic management, in order to maximize the capacity of all facilities and modes across the applicable region.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470479-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “program” means the congestion relief program established under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47047a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish a congestion relief program to provide discretionary grants to eligible entities to advance innovative, integrated, and multimodal solutions to congestion relief in the most congested metropolitan areas of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47047b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program goals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The goals of the program are to reduce highway congestion, reduce economic and environmental costs associated with that congestion, including transportation emissions, and optimize existing highway capacity and usage of highway and transit systems through—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47047c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> improving intermodal integration with highways, highway operations, and highway performance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47047d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> reducing or shifting highway users to off-peak travel times or to nonhighway travel modes during peak travel times; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47047e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> pricing of, or based on, as applicable—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47047f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> parking;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470480-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> use of roadways, including in designated geographic zones; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470481-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> congestion.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470482-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible projects</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Funds from a grant under the program may be used for a project or an integrated collection of projects, including planning, design, implementation, and construction activities, to achieve the program goals under paragraph (3), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470483-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> deployment and operation of an integrated congestion management system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470484-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> deployment and operation of a system that implements or enforces high occupancy vehicle toll lanes, cordon pricing, parking pricing, or congestion pricing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470485-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> deployment and operation of mobility services, including establishing account-based financial systems, commuter buses, commuter vans, express operations, paratransit, and on-demand microtransit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470486-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> incentive programs that encourage travelers to carpool, use nonhighway travel modes during peak period, or travel during nonpeak periods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470487-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application; selection.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470488-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading><content>To be eligible to receive a grant under the program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470489-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading><content>In providing grants under the program, the Secretary shall give priority to projects in urbanized areas that are experiencing a high degree of recurrent congestion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47048a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal share</inline>.—</heading><content>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out with a grant under the program shall not exceed 80 percent of the total project cost.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47048b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum award</inline>.—</heading><content>A grant provided under the program shall be not less than $10,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e47048c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of tolling.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47048d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1) and section 301 and subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the Secretary shall allow the use of tolls on the Interstate System as part of a project carried out with a grant under the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e47048e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may only approve the use of tolls under subparagraph (A) if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e47048f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the eligible entity has authority under State, and if applicable, local, law to assess the applicable toll;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470490-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the maximum toll rate for any vehicle class is not greater than the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id2e470491-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the toll rate for any other vehicle class; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id2e470492-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> 5;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470493-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the toll rates are not charged or varied on the basis of State residency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470494-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the Secretary determines that the use of tolls will enable the eligible entity to achieve the program goals under paragraph (3) without a significant impact to safety or mobility within the urbanized area in which the project is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e470495-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the use of toll revenues complies with subsection (a)(3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470496-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may not approve the use of tolls on the Interstate System under the program in more than 10 urbanized areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e470497-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Financial effects on low-income drivers</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A project under the program—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470498-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall include, if appropriate, an analysis of the potential effects of the project on low-income drivers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e470499-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s129/d/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may include mitigation measures to deal with any potential adverse financial effects on low-income drivers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id2e47049a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/767">Pub. L. 85–767</ref>, <date date="1958-08-27">Aug. 27, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/902">72 Stat. 902</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/657">Pub. L. 86–657</ref>, §§ 5, 8(a), <date date="1960-07-14">July 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/523">74 Stat. 523</ref>, 524; <ref href="/us/pl/90/495/s28">Pub. L. 90–495, § 28</ref>, <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/829">82 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/605/tI">Pub. L. 91–605, title I</ref>, §§ 133, 139, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1732">84 Stat. 1732</ref>, 1736; <ref href="/us/pl/92/434/s7">Pub. L. 92–434, § 7</ref>, <date date="1972-09-26">Sept. 26, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/732">86 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/tI">Pub. L. 93–87, title I</ref>, §§ 118, 132, 139, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/259">87 Stat. 259</ref>, 267, 270; <ref href="/us/pl/93/643/s108">Pub. L. 93–643, § 108</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2284">88 Stat. 2284</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/280/tI/s121">Pub. L. 94–280, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1976-05-05">May 5, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/438">90 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tI/s120">Pub. L. 95–599, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2700">92 Stat. 2700</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/tI/s120/a">Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 120(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/157">101 Stat. 157</ref>, 158; <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101</ref>(<i>l</i>) [title III, § 347(d)], <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-358">101 Stat. 1329–358</ref>, 1329–388; <ref href="/us/pl/100/457/tIII">Pub. L. 100–457, title III</ref>, §§ 326, 335, <date date="1988-09-30">Sept. 30, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2150">102 Stat. 2150</ref>, 2153; <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1012/a">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1012(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1936">105 Stat. 1936</ref>, 1938; <ref href="/us/pl/102/388/tIV/s410">Pub. L. 102–388, title IV, § 410</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1565">106 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s313/a">Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 313(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/585">109 Stat. 585</ref>, 586; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI">Pub. L. 105–178, title I</ref>, §§ 1106(c)(1)(C), 1207(a), 1211(f), formerly 1211(g), <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/136">112 Stat. 136</ref>, 185, 189; <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIX/s9003/d/5">Pub. L. 105–206, title IX, § 9003(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/840">112 Stat. 840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1801/f">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1801(f)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1456">119 Stat. 1456</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1512/a">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1512(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/567">126 Stat. 567</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 1112(c), 1411(a), <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1346">129 Stat. 1346</ref>, 1412; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 11117(a), 11404, 11523, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/483">135 Stat. 483</ref>, 558, 605.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id2e49749b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id2e49749c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id2e49749d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For the effective date of title I of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), see <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1100">section 1100 of Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1991 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104">section 104 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the MAP–21, referred to in subsec. (a)(8), is deemed to be <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this subparagraph and the date of enactment of the Surface Transportation Reauthorization Act of 2021, referred to in subsec. (a)(9)(B)(i), (10), is the date of enactment of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, which was approved <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id2e49749e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11523/1">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11523(1)</ref>, inserted “, together with the results of the audit under paragraph (9)(C),” after “the audits”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11523/2">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11523(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted heading, substituted “public transportation vehicles” for “public transportation buses”, and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10), (11). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11404/b">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11404(b)</ref>, added par. (10) and redesignated former par. (10) as (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11117/a">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11117(a)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “the construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities (including ferry maintenance facilities), whether toll or free, and the procurement of transit vehicles used exclusively as an integral part of an intermodal ferry trip,” for “the construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities, whether toll or free,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11404/a">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11404(a)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1411/a/1">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1411(a)(1)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “shall ensure that” for “shall use” and inserted “are used” before “only for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1411/a/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1411(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (4) and struck out former par. (4) which related to limitations on conversion of high occupancy vehicle facilities on interstate system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1411/a/3">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1411(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Federal-aid highways” for “Federal-aid system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1411/a/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1411(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated pars. (6) to (9) as (5) to (8), respectively. Former par. (5) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1411/a/4">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1411(a)(4)</ref>, added par. (9). Former par. (9) redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10)(C) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1411/a/5">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1411(a)(5)</ref>, added subpar. (C) and redesignated former subpars. (C) and (D) as (D) and (E), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1112/c/1">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1112(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “or on a public transit ferry eligible under chapter 53 of title 49” after “Interstate System”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1112/c/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1112(c)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), substituted “The ferry” for “Such ferry”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1112/c/3">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1112(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “repair,” for “and repair,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1112/c/4">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1112(c)(4)</ref>, added pars. (6) and (7) and struck out former par. (6) which read as follows: “No such ferry shall be sold, leased, or otherwise disposed of without the approval of the Secretary. The Federal share of any proceeds from such a disposition shall be credited to the unprogramed balance of Federal-aid highway funds of the same class last apportioned to such State. Any amount so credited shall be in addition to all other funds then apportioned to such State and available for expenditure in accordance with the provisions of this title.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) related to basic program and consisted of pars. (1) to (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59">Pub. L. 109–59</ref> substituted “any territory of the United States” for “the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1106/c/1/C">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1106(c)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “which is a public road and has not” for “which has been classified as a public road and has not” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1207/a">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1207(a)</ref>, substituted “owned or operated or majority publicly owned if the Secretary determines with respect to a majority publicly owned ferry or ferry terminal facility that such ferry boat or ferry terminal facility provides substantial public benefits.” for “owned.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1211/f">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1211(f)</ref>, formerly § 1211(g), as renumbered by <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s9003/d/5">Pub. L. 105–206, § 9003(d)(5)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which related to pilot toll collection program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s313/a">Pub. L. 104–59, § 313(a)</ref>, amended par. (5) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (5) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(5) <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on federal share</inline>.—Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the Federal share payable for construction of a highway, bridge, tunnel, or approach thereto or conversion of a highway, bridge, or tunnel to a toll facility under this subsection shall be such percentage as the State determines but not to exceed 50 percent. The Federal share payable for construction of a new bridge, tunnel, or approach thereto or for reconstruction or replacement of a bridge, tunnel, or approach thereto shall be such percentage as the Secretary determines but not to exceed 80 percent. In the case of a toll facility subject to an agreement under section 119 or 129, the Federal share payable on any project for resurfacing, restoring, rehabilitating, or reconstructing such facility shall be 80 percent until the scheduled expiration of such agreement (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s313/b">Pub. L. 104–59, § 313(b)</ref>, amended par. (7) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (7) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(7) <inline class="small-caps">Loans</inline>.—A State may loan all or part of the Federal share of a toll project under this section to a public or private agency constructing a toll facility. Such loan may be made only after all Federal environmental requirements have been complied with and permits obtained. The amount loaned shall be subordinated to other debt financing for the facility except for loans made by the State or any other public agency to the agency constructing the facility. Funds loaned pursuant to this section may be obligated for projects eligible under this section. The repayment of any such loan shall commence not more than 5 years after the facility has opened to traffic. Any such loan shall bear interest at the average rate the State’s pooled investment fund earned in the 52 weeks preceding the start of repayment. The term of any such loan shall not exceed 30 years from the time the loan was obligated. Amounts repaid to a State from any loan made under this section may be obligated for any purpose for which the loaned funds were available. The Secretary shall establish procedures and guidelines for making such loans.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s313/c">Pub. L. 104–59, § 313(c)</ref>, inserted before period at end of first sentence “or between a point in a State and a point in the Dominion of Canada” and in second sentence substituted “Hawaii,” for “Hawaii and” and inserted “, operations between a point in a State and a point in the Dominion of Canada,” after “Puerto Rico”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/388/s410/1">Pub. L. 102–388, § 410(1)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “classified as a public road” for “approved under section 103(b) or (b) of this title as a part of one of the Federal-aid systems”, was executed by making the substitution for “approved under section 103(b) or (c) of this title as a part of one of the Federal-aid systems” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/388/s410/2">Pub. L. 102–388, § 410(2)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “The operation of the ferry shall be on a route which has been approved under section 103(b) or (c) of this title as a part of one of the Federal-aid systems within the State and has not been designated as a route on the Interstate System.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/a">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally, substituting present provisions for provisions authorizing Federal participation in construction or acquisition of toll bridges, tunnels and approaches, provided that facility was publicly owned and operated by State or public authority, and State or authority agreed that all tolls, less those used to offset cost of operation and maintenance, were to be applied to repayment of State or authority for cost of construction or acquisition, that no tolls were to be charged after such repayment, and that facility was to be free of charge thereafter, except in case of bridge connecting United States with foreign country.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/1">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (f) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which authorized Secretary to approve toll roads, bridges and tunnels as part of Interstate System, authorized expenditure of Federal-aid highway funds on toll roads after they became toll-free, and required agreements between Secretary and State highway departments on construction of Interstate projects to forbid construction of toll roads, but not toll bridges and tunnels, on interstate highway route without official concurrence of Secretary, after <date date="1968-06-30">June 30, 1968</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (c), inserted “and ferry terminal facilities” after “boats” in introductory provisions, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “Such ferry shall be publicly owned and operated.”, in par. (4), inserted “or other public entity” after “State” and “, debt service, negotiated management fees, and, in the case of a privately operated toll ferry, for a reasonable rate of return” before period at end, and struck out former subsec. (c) which made available funds authorized for expenditure on Federal-aid highway systems for projects approaching toll roads, bridges or tunnels up to point where project had use irrespective of use for toll road, bridge or tunnel.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/1">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (j) as (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which made available funds authorized for expenditure on Interstate System for Interstate System projects approaching toll road and having no other use, if agreement was reached that section of toll road would become free to public upon collection of tolls sufficient to liquidate cost of road and outstanding bonds and cost of maintenance, operation and debt service during period of toll collection, and that there was a reasonably satisfactory alternative free route available to bypass toll section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/1">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which authorized Secretary to permit Federal participation in reconstruction and improvement of two-lane toll road designated as part of the Interstate System before <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, as necessary to bring such road to standards of Interstate System, provided that toll road authority agreed that no new indebtedness to be liquidated by tolls was to be incurred, that all tolls be used for operation and maintenance and to repay outstanding bonds, and that, upon liquidation of such bonds, the road was to become free to public.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/2">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (f) and (g) as (b) and (c), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/1">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (h) which provided that, in case of interstate toll bridge on Federal-aid primary system, except Interstate System, owned by State or political subdivision, that became toll-free by <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>, because of purchase or construction by State before <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>, funds would be made available under section 104(b)(1) and (3) of this title to pay Federal share of lesser of value of bridge (after deducting portion of value already attributable to Federal funds) or amount by which principal amount of outstanding unpaid bonds issued for construction or acquisition of bridge exceeded amount accumulated for their amortization, on date bridge became free to public.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/1">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (i) which authorized Secretary to permit Federal participation, through funds for Federal-aid highway system, other than Interstate System, in engineering and fiscal assessments, traffic analyses, network studies, etc., to determine whether privately owned toll bridges should be acquired by a State or subdivision.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/2">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (j) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1012/c/1">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1012(c)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (k) which required operators of toll roads, tunnels, ferries and bridges on Federal-aid highway system to biennially certify to Governor of State that facilities were adequately maintained and that operator had ability to fund such facilities that were not adequately maintained without using Federal-aid highway funds, and which required Governor of each State to report biennially to Secretary on facilities required to so certify.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (j)(1), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/457/s335">Pub. L. 100–457, § 335</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101</ref>(<i>l</i>) [title III, § 347(d)(1), (2)(A), (C)], see 1987 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/457/s326/1">Pub. L. 100–457, § 326(1)</ref>, inserted “(and, in the case of the State of Texas, the Texas Turnpike Authority)” after “State highway department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/100/457/s326/2">Pub. L. 100–457, § 326(2)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s120/a">Pub. L. 100–17, § 120(a)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101</ref>(<i>l</i>) [title III, § 347(d)(1)], as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/457/s335">Pub. L. 100–457, § 335</ref>, which directed the amendment of par. (1) by substituting “(9)” for “(9)” was executed by substituting “9” for “7” as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101</ref>(<i>l</i>) [title III, § 347(d)(2)(A)], as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/457/s335">Pub. L. 100–457, § 335</ref>, which directed the amendment of par. (3) by substituting “(9)” for “(7)” was executed by substituting “9” for “7” as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101</ref>(<i>l</i>) [title III, § 347(d)(2)(B)–(D)], as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/457/s335">Pub. L. 100–457, § 335</ref>, substituted “States of Pennsylvania and West Virginia” for “State of Pennsylvania” in two places and inserted “States of Georgia and West Virginia,” and “The toll facility in Orange County, California, may be located in more than 1 highway corridor to relieve congestion on existing interstate routes in such County.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/s120/b">Pub. L. 100–17, § 120(b)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/95/599">Pub. L. 95–599</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (g)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/94/280">Pub. L. 94–280</ref> authorized ferry operations within the islands which comprise the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and excepted ferry operations between the islands which comprise the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico from the prohibition of ferry operations in foreign or international waters.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (g)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/93/643">Pub. L. 93–643</ref> substituted “operations between the islands which comprise the State of Hawaii and operations between any two points in Alaska and between Alaska and Washington, including stops at appropriate points in the Dominion of Canada” for “operations between the islands which comprise the State of Hawaii and operations between the States of Alaska and Washington, or between any two points within the State of Alaska”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/s118/a">Pub. L. 93–87, § 118(a)</ref>, inserted third sentence providing that when any toll road which the Secretary has approved as a part of the Interstate System is made a toll-free facility, Federal-aid highway funds apportioned under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/5">section 104(b)(5) of this title</ref> may be expended for the construction, reconstruction, or improvement of that road to meet the standards adopted for the improvement of projects located on the Interstate System.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/s118/b">Pub. L. 93–87, § 118(b)</ref>, struck from first sentence “on the date of enactment of this subsection” before “as he may find necessary” and substituted in third sentence “1973” for “1968”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/s139">Pub. L. 93–87, § 139</ref>, redesignated the second subsec. (f) as (g) and in par. (5) substituted “may be operated” for “shall be operated”, inserted “(including the islands which comprise the State of Hawaii)” after “within the State”, and excepted operations between the islands which comprise the State of Hawaii and operations between the States of Alaska and Washington, or between any two points within the State of Alaska from the prohibition against ferry operations in foreign or international waters.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/s132">Pub. L. 93–87, § 132</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/92/434">Pub. L. 92–434</ref> substituted “or” for “and” making text read “maintained or operated”, and required domestic and foreign tolls for international bridges, and that the tolls be limited to amount necessary for maintenance, repair, and operation thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/605/s133">Pub. L. 91–605, § 133</ref>, added subsec. (e). Former subsec. (e), pertaining to ferry approaches, redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/91/605">Pub. L. 91–605</ref>, §§ 133, 139, redesignated subsec. (e), relating to ferry approaches, as (f) and added a second subsec. (f) relating to ferry boats.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/90/495">Pub. L. 90–495</ref> required that, after <date date="1968-06-30">June 30, 1968</date>, as a condition for the addition of toll highway facilities on the Interstate System, the approval of the Secretary is required, with an affirmative finding that the construction of the road as a toll facility rather than a toll-free facility is in the public interest, but with such limitation on the construction of toll facilities not to extend to toll bridges and tunnels.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/657/s5/b">Pub. L. 86–657, § 5(b)</ref>, included ferries in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/86/657/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–657, § 8(a)</ref>, struck out “under prior Acts” after “Funds authorized”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/86/657/s5/a">Pub. L. 86–657, § 5(a)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id2e49749f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e4974a0-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref> effective <date date="2021-10-01">Oct. 1, 2021</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s10003">section 10003 of Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e4974a1-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e4974a2-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e4974a3-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title IX of <ref href="/us/pl/105/206">Pub. L. 105–206</ref> effective simultaneously with enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref> and to be treated as included in <ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref> at time of enactment, and provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref>, as in effect on day before <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, that are amended by title IX of <ref href="/us/pl/105/206">Pub. L. 105–206</ref> to be treated as not enacted, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s9016">section 9016 of Pub. L. 105–206</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e4974a4-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> effective <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, and applicable to funds authorized to be appropriated or made available after <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, and, with certain exceptions, not applicable to funds appropriated or made available on or before <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1100">section 1100 of Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104">section 104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e4974a5-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/495">Pub. L. 90–495</ref> effective <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/495/s37">section 37 of Pub. L. 90–495</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4974a6-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Electronic Toll Collection Interoperability Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1512/b">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1512(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/572">126 Stat. 572</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1512/b">“Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act [see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>], all toll facilities on the Federal-aid highways shall implement technologies or business practices that provide for the interoperability of electronic toll collection programs.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4974a7-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Express Lanes Demonstration Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1604/b">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1604(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1250">119 Stat. 1250</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1419/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1419(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1423">129 Stat. 1423</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1419/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible toll facility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘eligible toll facility’ includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a facility in existence on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>] that collects tolls;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a facility in existence on the date of enactment of this Act that serves high occupancy vehicles;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> a facility modified or constructed after the date of enactment of this Act to create additional tolled lane capacity (including a facility constructed by a private entity or using private funds); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> in the case of a new lane added to a previously non-tolled facility, only the new lane.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonattainment area</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘nonattainment area’ has the meaning given that term in section 171 of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7501">42 U.S.C. 7501</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Demonstration program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding sections 129 and 301 of title 23, United States Code, the Secretary [of Transportation] shall carry out 15 demonstration projects during the period of fiscal years 2005 through 2009 to permit States, public authorities, or a [sic] public or private entities designated by States, to collect a toll from motor vehicles at an eligible toll facility for any highway, bridge, or tunnel, including facilities on the Interstate System—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to manage high levels of congestion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to reduce emissions in a nonattainment area or maintenance area; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to finance the expansion of a highway, for the purpose of reducing traffic congestion, by constructing one or more additional lanes (including bridge, tunnel, support, and other structures necessary for that construction) on the Interstate System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on use of revenues.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Toll revenues received under paragraph (2) shall be used by a State, public authority, or private entity designated by a State, for—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> debt service;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> a reasonable return on investment of any private financing;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="III">“(III)</num><content> the costs necessary for proper operation and maintenance of any facilities under paragraph (2) (including reconstruction, resurfacing, restoration, and rehabilitation); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="IV">“(IV)</num><content> if the State, public authority, or private entity annually certifies that the tolled facility is being adequately operated and maintained, any other purpose relating to a highway or transit project carried out under title 23 or 49, United States Code.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Variable price requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>A facility that charges tolls under this subsection may establish a toll that varies in price according to time of day or level of traffic, as appropriate to manage congestion or improve air quality.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> HOV <inline class="small-caps">variable pricing requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall require, for each high occupancy vehicle facility that charges tolls under this subsection, that the tolls vary in price according to time of day or level of traffic, as appropriate to manage congestion or improve air quality.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> HOV <inline class="small-caps">passenger requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s166">section 166 of title 23</ref>, United States Code, a State may permit motor vehicles with fewer than two occupants to operate in high occupancy vehicle lanes as part of a variable toll pricing program established under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreement.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Before the Secretary may permit a facility to charge tolls under this subsection, the Secretary and the applicable State, public authority, or private entity designated by a State shall enter into an agreement for each facility incorporating the conditions described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>An agreement under clause (i) shall terminate with respect to a facility upon the decision of the State, public authority, or private entity designated by a State to discontinue the variable tolling program under this subsection for the facility.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Debt</inline>.—</heading><content>If there is any debt outstanding on a facility at the time at which the decision is made to discontinue the program under this subsection with respect to the facility, the facility may continue to charge tolls in accordance with the terms of the agreement until such time as the debt is retired.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on federal share</inline>.—</heading><content>The Federal share of the cost of a project on a facility tolled under this subsection, including a project to install the toll collection facility shall be a percentage, not to exceed 80 percent, determined by the applicable State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To be eligible to participate in the program under this subsection, a State, public authority, or private entity designated by a State shall provide to the Secretary [of Transportation]—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a description of the congestion or air quality problems sought to be addressed under the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> a description of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the goals sought to be achieved under the program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the performance measures that would be used to gauge the success made toward reaching those goals; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Automation</inline>.—</heading><content>Fees collected from motorists using an express lane shall be collected only through the use of noncash electronic technology that optimizes the free flow of traffic on the tolled facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interoperability.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>], the Secretary [of Transportation] shall promulgate a final rule specifying requirements, standards, or performance specifications for automated toll collection systems implemented under this section [enacting provisions set out as a note under this section and amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s149">section 149 of this title</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing that rule, which shall be designed to maximize the interoperability of electronic collection systems, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> seek to accelerate progress toward the national goal of achieving a nationwide interoperable electronic toll collection system;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> take into account the use of noncash electronic technology currently deployed within an appropriate geographical area of travel and the noncash electronic technology likely to be in use within the next 5 years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> seek to minimize additional costs and maximize convenience to users of toll facility and to the toll facility owner or operator.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Transportation], in cooperation with State and local agencies and other program participants and with opportunity for public comment, shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> develop and publish performance goals for each express lane project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> establish a program for regular monitoring and reporting on the achievement of performance goals, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> effects on travel, traffic, and air quality;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> distribution of benefits and burdens;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="III">“(III)</num><content> use of alternative transportation modes; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="IV">“(IV)</num><content> use of revenues to meet transportation or impact mitigation needs.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1" status="repealed"><num value="B">“[(B)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1419/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1419(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1423">129 Stat. 1423</ref>.]”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4974a8-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interstate System Construction Toll Pilot Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1411/d">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1411(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1416">129 Stat. 1416</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1411/d">“The Secretary [of Transporation] may approve an application submitted under section 1604(c) of SAFETEA–LU (<ref href="/us/pl/109/59">Public Law 109–59</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/119/1253">119 Stat. 1253</ref>) [set out as a note below] if the application, or any part of the application, was submitted before the deadline specified in section 1604(c)(8) of that Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1604/c">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1604(c)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1253">119 Stat. 1253</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1604/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall establish and implement an Interstate System construction toll pilot program under which the Secretary, notwithstanding sections 129 and 301 of title 23, United States Code, may permit a State or an interstate compact of States to collect tolls on a highway, bridge, or tunnel on the Interstate System for the purpose of constructing Interstate highways.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on number of facilities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] may permit the collection of tolls under this section on three facilities on the Interstate System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To be eligible to participate in the pilot program, a State shall submit to the Secretary [of Transportation] an application that contains, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An identification of the facility on the Interstate System proposed to be a toll facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> In the case of a facility that affects a metropolitan area, an assurance that the metropolitan planning organization designated under section 134 or 135 for the area has been consulted concerning the placement and amount of tolls on the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> An analysis demonstrating that financing the construction of the facility with the collection of tolls under the pilot program is the most efficient and economical way to advance the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> A facility management plan that includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a plan for implementing the imposition of tolls on the facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a schedule and finance plan for the construction of the facility using toll revenues;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> a description of the public transportation agency that will be responsible for implementation and administration of the pilot program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> a description of whether consideration will be given to privatizing the maintenance and operational aspects of the facility, while retaining legal and administrative control of the portion of the Interstate route; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection criteria</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Transportation] may approve the application of a State under paragraph (3) only if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the State’s analysis under paragraph (3)(C) is reasonable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the State plan for implementing tolls on the facility takes into account the interests of local, regional, and interstate travelers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the State plan for construction of the facility using toll revenues is reasonable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the State will develop, manage, and maintain a system that will automatically collect the tolls; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the State has given preference to the use of a public toll agency with demonstrated capability to build, operate, and maintain a toll expressway system meeting criteria for the Interstate System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on noncompete agreements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Before the Secretary [of Transportation] may permit a State to participate in the pilot program, the State must enter into an agreement with the Secretary that provides that the State will not enter into an agreement with a private person under which the State is prevented from improving or expanding the capacity of public roads adjacent to the toll facility to address conditions resulting from traffic diverted to such roads from the toll facility, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> excessive congestion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> pavement wear; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> an increased incidence of traffic accidents, injuries, or fatalities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on use of revenues; audits</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Before the Secretary [of Transportation] may permit a State to participate in the pilot program, the State must enter into an agreement with the Secretary that provides that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> all toll revenues received from operation of the toll facility will be used only for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> debt service;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> reasonable return on investment of any private person financing the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> any costs necessary for the improvement of and the proper operation and maintenance of the toll facility, including reconstruction, resurfacing, restoration, and rehabilitation of the toll facility; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> regular audits will be conducted to ensure compliance with subparagraph (A) and the results of such audits will be transmitted to the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on use of interstate maintenance funds</inline>.—</heading><content>During the term of the pilot program, funds apportioned for Interstate maintenance under [former] <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/4">section 104(b)(4) of title 23</ref>, United States Code, may not be used on a facility for which tolls are being collected under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program term</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation] may approve an application of a State for permission to collect a toll under this section only if the application is received by the Secretary before the last day of the 10-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="9">“(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interstate system defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘Interstate System’ has the meaning such term has under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of title 23</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4974a9-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Ferry Database</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1801/e">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1801(e)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1456">119 Stat. 1456</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1121/b">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1121(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/494">126 Stat. 494</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1112/b">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1112(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1346">129 Stat. 1346</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1112/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Transportation], acting through the Bureau of Transportation Statistics, shall establish and maintain a national ferry database.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><content>The database shall contain current information regarding ferry systems, including information regarding routes, vessels, passengers and vehicles carried, funding sources, including any Federal, State, and local government funding sources, and such other information as the Secretary considers useful.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Update report</inline>.—</heading><content>Using information collected through the database, the Secretary shall periodically modify as appropriate the report submitted under section 1207(c) of the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century [<ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t23/s129">23 U.S.C. 129</ref> note; <ref href="/us/stat/112/185-186">112 Stat. 185–186</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> compile the database not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>] and update the database every 2 years thereafter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> ensure that the database is easily accessible to the public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> ensure that the database is consistent with the national transit database maintained by the Federal Transit Administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> make available, from the amounts made available for each fiscal year to carry out chapter 63 of title 49, not more than $500,000 to maintain the database.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4974aa-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Ferry Transportation Study</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1207/c">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1207(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/185">112 Stat. 185</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1207/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall conduct a study of ferry transportation in the United States and its possessions—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> to identify existing ferry operations, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the locations and routes served; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the source and amount, if any, of funds derived from Federal, State, or local government sources supporting ferry construction or operations;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to identify potential domestic ferry routes in the United States and its possessions and to develop information on those routes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to identify the potential for use of high-speed ferry services and alternative-fueled ferry services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall submit a report on the results of the study to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4974ab-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interstate System Reconstruction and Rehabilitation Pilot Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1216/b">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1216(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/212">112 Stat. 212</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1411/c">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1411(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1415">129 Stat. 1415</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1411/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish and implement an Interstate System reconstruction and rehabilitation pilot program under which the Secretary, notwithstanding sections 129 and 301 of title 23, United States Code, may permit a State to collect tolls on a highway, bridge, or tunnel on the Interstate System for the purpose of reconstructing and rehabilitating Interstate highway corridors that could not otherwise be adequately maintained or functionally improved without the collection of tolls.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on number of facilities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may permit the collection of tolls under this subsection on 3 facilities on the Interstate System. Each of such facilities shall be located in a different State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To be eligible to participate in the pilot program, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application that contains, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An identification of the facility on the Interstate System proposed to be a toll facility, including the age, condition, and intensity of use of the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> In the case of a facility that affects a metropolitan area, an assurance that the metropolitan planning organization established under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s134">section 134 of title 23</ref>, United States Code, for the area has been consulted concerning the placement and amount of tolls on the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> An analysis demonstrating that the facility could not be maintained or improved to meet current or future needs from the State’s apportionments and allocations made available by this Act [see Tables for classification] (including amendments made by this Act) and from revenues for highways from any other source without toll revenues.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> A facility management plan that includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a plan for implementing the imposition of tolls on the facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a schedule and finance plan for the reconstruction or rehabilitation of the facility using toll revenues;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> a description of the public transportation agency that will be responsible for implementation and administration of the pilot program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> a description of whether consideration will be given to privatizing the maintenance and operational aspects of the facility, while retaining legal and administrative control of the portion of the Interstate route; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection criteria</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may approve the application of a State under paragraph (3) only if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the State is unable to reconstruct or rehabilitate the proposed toll facility using existing apportionments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the facility has a sufficient intensity of use, age, or condition to warrant the collection of tolls;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the State plan for implementing tolls on the facility takes into account the interests of local, regional, and interstate travelers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the State plan for reconstruction or rehabilitation of the facility using toll revenues is reasonable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the State has given preference to the use of a public toll agency with demonstrated capability to build, operate, and maintain a toll expressway system meeting criteria for the Interstate System; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> the State has the authority required for the project to proceed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on use of revenues; audits</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Before the Secretary may permit a State to participate in the pilot program, the State must enter into an agreement with the Secretary that provides that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> all toll revenues received from operation of the toll facility will be used only for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> debt service;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> reasonable return on investment of any private person financing the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> any costs necessary for the improvement of and the proper operation and maintenance of the toll facility, including reconstruction, resurfacing, restoration, and rehabilitation of the toll facility; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> regular audits will be conducted to ensure compliance with subparagraph (A) and the results of such audits will be transmitted to the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for project completion.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General term for expiration of provisional application</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An application provisionally approved by the Secretary under this subsection shall expire 3 years after the date on which the application was provisionally approved if the State has not—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> submitted a complete application to the Secretary that fully satisfies the eligibility criteria under paragraph (3) and the selection criteria under paragraph (4);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> completed the environmental review and permitting process under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) for the pilot project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> executed a toll agreement with the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions to expiration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Secretary may extend the provisional approval for not more than 1 additional year if the State demonstrates material progress toward implementation of the project as evidenced by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> substantial progress in completing the environmental review and permitting process for the pilot project under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> funding and financing commitments for the pilot project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> expressions of support for the pilot project from State and local governments, community interests, and the public; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> submission of a facility management plan pursuant to paragraph (3)(D).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions for previously provisionally approved applications</inline>.—</heading><content>A State with a provisionally approved application for a pilot project as of the date of enactment of the FAST Act [<date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>] shall have 1 year after that date of enactment to meet the requirements of subparagraph (A) or receive an extension from the Secretary under subparagraph (B), or the application will expire.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘provisional approval’ or ‘provisionally approved’ means the approval by the Secretary of a partial application under this subsection, including the reservation of a slot in the pilot program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on use of interstate maintenance funds</inline>.—</heading><content>During the term of the pilot program, funds apportioned for Interstate maintenance under [former] <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/4">section 104(b)(4) of title 23</ref>, United States Code, may not be used on a facility for which tolls are being collected under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="9">“(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program term</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall conduct the pilot program under this subsection for a term to be determined by the Secretary, but not less than 10 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="10">“(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interstate system defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘Interstate System’ has the meaning such term has under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of title 23</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4be5ac-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continuation of Existing Agreements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1012/d">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1012(d)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1939">105 Stat. 1939</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1012/d">“Unless modified under section 129(a)(6) [now 129(a)(5)] of such title [this title], as amended by subsection (a) of this section, agreements entered into under section 119(e) or 129 of such title before the effective date of this title [<date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>] and in effect on the day before such effective date shall continue in effect on and after such effective date in accordance with the provisions of such agreement and such section 119(e) or 129.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4be5ad-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of Ferry Boats and Ferry Terminal Facilities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1064">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1064</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2005">105 Stat. 2005</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/388/tIII/s332">Pub. L. 102–388, title III, § 332</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1550">106 Stat. 1550</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1207/b">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1207(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/185">112 Stat. 185</ref>, which directed the Secretary to carry out a program for construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s129/c">section 129(c) of this title</ref>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1801/c">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1801(c)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1456">119 Stat. 1456</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s147">section 147 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4be5ae-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study To Determine Extent of Bonded Indebtedness of States for Construction of Toll Roads Incorporated Into Interstate System</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tI/s164">Pub. L. 95–599, title I, § 164</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2721">92 Stat. 2721</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/106/s16">Pub. L. 96–106, § 16</ref>, <date date="1979-11-19">Nov. 19, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/798">93 Stat. 798</ref>, directed Secretary of Transportation to report not later than <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, respecting extent of outstanding bonded indebtedness for each State as of <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, incurred by each State or public authority prior to <date date="1956-06-29">June 29, 1956</date>, for road construction or portions incorporated within Interstate System, and methods of allocating bonded indebtedness and removal of toll provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e4be5af-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Richmond-Petersburg Turnpike</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/605/tI/s131">Pub. L. 91–605, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1732">84 Stat. 1732</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/605/tI/s131">“The Secretary of Transportation is authorized to amend any agreement heretofore entered into under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s129/d">section 129(d) of title 23</ref>, United States Code, in order to permit the continuation of tolls on the existing Richmond-Petersburg Turnpike to finance the construction within the existing termini of such turnpike of two lanes thereon in addition to the lanes in existence on the date of enactment of this section [<date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>] necessary to meet traffic and highway safety requirements. Any amended agreement entered into for such purposes shall provide assurances that the existing turnpike (including the additional lanes) shall become free to the public upon the collection of tolls sufficient to liquidate all construction costs, and the costs of maintenance, operation, and debt service during the period of toll collections to liquidate such construction costs, but in no event shall tolls be collected after date of maturity of those bonds outstanding on the date of enactment of this section [<date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>] issued for construction of such turnpike having the latest maturity date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
