<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id2e61433a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s140"><num value="140">§ 140.</num><heading> Nondiscrimination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e61433b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s140/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Prior to approving any programs for projects as provided for in section 135, the Secretary shall require assurances from any State desiring to avail itself of the benefits of this chapter that employment in connection with proposed projects will be provided without regard to race, color, creed, national origin, or sex. The Secretary shall require that each State shall include in the advertised specifications, notification of the specific equal employment opportunity responsibilities of the successful bidder. In approving programs for projects on any of the Federal-aid systems, the Secretary, if necessary to ensure equal employment opportunity, shall require certification by any State desiring to avail itself of the benefits of this chapter that there are in existence and available on a regional, statewide, or local basis, apprenticeship, skill improvement or other upgrading programs, registered with the Department of Labor or the appropriate State agency, if any, which provide equal opportunity for training and employment without regard to race, color, creed, national origin, or sex. In implementing such programs, a State may reserve training positions for persons who receive welfare assistance from such State; except that the implementation of any such program shall not cause current employees to be displaced or current positions to be supplanted or preclude workers that are participating in an apprenticeship, skill improvement, or other upgrading program registered with the Department of Labor or the appropriate State agency from being referred to, or hired on, projects funded under this title without regard to the length of time of their participation in such program. The Secretary shall periodically obtain from the Secretary of Labor and the respective State transportation departments information which will enable the Secretary to judge compliance with the requirements of this section and the Secretary of Labor shall render to the Secretary such assistance and information as the Secretary of Transportation shall deem necessary to carry out the equal employment opportunity program required hereunder.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e61433c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s140/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary, in cooperation with any other department or agency of the Government, State agency, authority, association, institution, Indian tribal government, corporation (profit or nonprofit), or any other organization or person, is authorized to develop, conduct, and administer surface transportation and technology training, including skill improvement programs, and to develop and fund summer transportation institutes. From administrative funds made available under section 104(a), the Secretary shall deduct such sums as necessary, not to exceed $10,000,000 per fiscal year, for the administration of this subsection. Such sums so deducted shall remain available until expended. The provisions of section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41 shall not be applicable to contracts and agreements made under the authority herein granted to the Secretary. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not to exceed ½ of 1 percent of funds apportioned to a State for the surface transportation block grant program under section 104(b) may be available to carry out this subsection upon request of the State transportation department to the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e61433d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s140/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary, in cooperation with any other department or agency of the Government, State agency, authority, association, institution, Indian tribal government, corporation (profit or nonprofit), or any other organization or person, is authorized to develop, conduct, and administer training programs and assistance programs in connection with any program under this title in order that minority businesses may achieve proficiency to compete, on an equal basis, for contracts and subcontracts. From administrative funds made available under section 104(a), the Secretary shall deduct such sums as necessary, not to exceed $10,000,000 per fiscal year, for the administration of this subsection. The provisions of section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41 shall not be applicable to contracts and agreements made under the authority herein granted to the Secretary notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s3106">section 3106 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e61433e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s140/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Indian Employment</inline>.—</heading><content>Consistent with section 703(i) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000e–2/i">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2(i)</ref>), nothing in this section shall preclude the preferential employment of Indians living on or near a reservation on projects and contracts on Indian reservation roads. States may implement a preference for employment of Indians on projects carried out under this title near Indian reservations. The Secretary shall cooperate with Indian tribal governments and the States to implement this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id2e61433f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/90/495/s22/a">Pub. L. 90–495, § 22(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/826">82 Stat. 826</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/605/tI/s110">Pub. L. 91–605, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1719">84 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/tI/s120">Pub. L. 93–87, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/259">87 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/280/tI/s126">Pub. L. 94–280, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="1976-05-05">May 5, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/440">90 Stat. 440</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/424/tI/s119">Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2110">96 Stat. 2110</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/tI/s122">Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/160">101 Stat. 160</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1026">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1026</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1965">105 Stat. 1965</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/388/tIV/s412">Pub. L. 102–388, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1565">106 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI">Pub. L. 105–178, title I</ref>, §§ 1208, 1212(a)(2)(A), <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/186">112 Stat. 186</ref>, 193; <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1922">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1922</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1481">119 Stat. 1481</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/e/1">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3847">124 Stat. 3847</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1109">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1109</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/444">126 Stat. 444</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 1109(c)(5), 1446(d)(1), <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1343">129 Stat. 1343</ref>, 1438; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11525/i">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11525(i)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/607">135 Stat. 607</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id2e614340-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id2e614341-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id2e614342-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref> substituted “Secretary, if necessary” for “Secretary if necessary” in third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1446/d/1">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1446(d)(1)</ref>, amended directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1109/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1109(a)(2)</ref>. See 2012 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1109/c/5">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1109(c)(5)</ref>, substituted “surface transportation block grant program” for “surface transportation program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1109/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1109(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “From administrative funds made available under section 104(a),” for “Whenever apportionments are made under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/3">section 104(b)(3) of this title</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1109/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1109(a)(2)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1446/d/1">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1446(d)(1)</ref>, struck out “and the bridge program under section 144” after “section 104(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1109/b">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1109(b)</ref>, substituted “From administrative funds made available under section 104(a),” for “Whenever apportionments are made under section 104(b)(3),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/e/1/A">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(e)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41” for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/e/1/B">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(e)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41” for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>),” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s3106">section 3106 of title 41</ref>” for “section 302(e) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s252/e">41 U.S.C. 252(e)</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1922/a">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1922(a)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “section 135” for “subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s105">section 105 of this title</ref>”, in second sentence, substituted “The Secretary” for “He”, in third sentence, substituted “if necessary to ensure” for “shall, where he considers it necessary to assure” and inserted “shall” before “require”, and, in last sentence, substituted “the Secretary to” for “him to” and “the Secretary of Transportation” for “he”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1922/b">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1922(b)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “surface transportation” for “highway construction” and, in second sentence, struck out “he may deem” before “necessary” and “not to exceed $2,500,000 for the transition quarter ending <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>, and” before “not to exceed $10,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1922/c">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1922(c)</ref>, substituted “section 104(b)(3)” for “sub<ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/3">section 104(b)(3) of this title</ref>” and struck out “he may deem” before “necessary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1922/d">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1922(d)</ref>, struck out “<inline class="small-caps">and Contracting</inline>” after “<inline class="small-caps">Employment</inline>” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref>, §§ 1208(a), 1212(a)(2)(A)(ii), inserted “In implementing such programs, a State may reserve training positions for persons who receive welfare assistance from such State; except that the implementation of any such program shall not cause current employees to be displaced or current positions to be supplanted or preclude workers that are participating in an apprenticeship, skill improvement, or other upgrading program registered with the Department of Labor or the appropriate State agency from being referred to, or hired on, projects funded under this title without regard to the length of time of their participation in such program.” after third sentence and substituted “State transportation departments” for “State highway departments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref>, §§ 1208(b), 1212(a)(2)(A)(i), inserted “and technology” after “highway construction” and “, and to develop and fund summer transportation institutes” after “skill improvement programs” and substituted “section 104(b)(3)” for “section 104(b)” and “State transportation department” for “State highway department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1208/c">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1208(c)</ref>, substituted “104(b)(3)” for “104(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/388">Pub. L. 102–388</ref> substituted “½ of 1 percent” for “¼ of 1 percent” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1026/a">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1026(a)</ref>, (b), inserted “Indian tribal government,” after “institution,” and inserted at end “Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not to exceed ¼ of 1 percent of funds apportioned to a State for the surface transportation program under section 104(b) and the bridge program under section 144 may be available to carry out this subsection upon request of the State highway department to the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1026/b">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1026(b)</ref>, inserted “Indian tribal government,” after “institution,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1026/c">Pub. L. 102–240, § 1026(c)</ref>, inserted after first sentence “States may implement a preference for employment of Indians on projects carried out under this title near Indian reservations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/17">Pub. L. 100–17</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/97/424/s119/c">Pub. L. 97–424, § 119(c)</ref>, substituted “Nondiscrimination” for “Equal employment opportunity” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/424/s119/a">Pub. L. 97–424, § 119(a)</ref>, substituted “, national origin, or sex” for “or national origin” after “color, creed”, in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/424/s119/b">Pub. L. 97–424, § 119(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/280">Pub. L. 94–280</ref> substituted second sentence “Whenever apportionments are made under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b">section 104(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall deduct such sums as he may deem necessary, not to exceed $2,500,000 for the transition quarter ending <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>, and not to exceed $10,000,000 per fiscal year, for the administration of this subsection.” for “Whenever an apportionment is made under subsections 104(b)(1), (b)(2), (b)(3), (b)(5), and (b)(6) of this title of the sums authorized to be appropriated for expenditure upon the Federal-aid primary and secondary systems, and their extensions within urban areas, the Interstate System, and the Federal-aid urban system for the fiscal years 1972, 1973, 1974, 1975, and 1976, the Secretary shall deduct such sums as he may deem necessary not to exceed $5,000,000 per fiscal year for the fiscal years 1972 and 1973, and $10,000,000 per fiscal year for the fiscal years 1974, 1975 and 1976, for administering the provisions of this subsection to be financed from the appropriation for the Federal-aid systems.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/87">Pub. L. 93–87</ref> included apportionment of appropriated moneys for administration of subsec. (b) provisions for fiscal years 1974, 1975, and 1976, and substituted provisions which made available for such administration $5,000,000 per fiscal year for fiscal years 1972, and 1973, and $10,000,000 per fiscal year for fiscal years 1974, 1975, and 1976, for prior provision making available $5,000,000 per fiscal year for such administration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/605">Pub. L. 91–605</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id2e63b343-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e63b344-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref> effective <date date="2021-10-01">Oct. 1, 2021</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s10003">section 10003 of Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e63b345-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI/s1446/d">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I, § 1446(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1438">129 Stat. 1438</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1446(d)(1) is effective as of <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e63b346-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e63b347-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> effective <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, and applicable to funds authorized to be appropriated or made available after <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, and, with certain exceptions, not applicable to funds appropriated or made available on or before <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1100">section 1100 of Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104">section 104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id2e63b348-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/495/s37">section 37 of Pub. L. 90–495</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1968 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
