<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id2e686e39-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s146"><num value="146">§ 146.</num><heading> Carpool and vanpool projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e686e3a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s146/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In order to conserve fuel, decrease traffic congestion during rush hours, improve air quality, and enhance the use of existing highways and parking facilities, the Secretary may approve for Federal financial assistance from funds apportioned under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/2">section 104(b)(2) of this title</ref>, projects designed to encourage the use of carpools and vanpools. (As used hereafter in this section, the term “carpool” includes a vanpool.) Such a project may include, but is not limited to, such measures as providing carpooling opportunities to the elderly and handicapped, systems for locating potential riders and informing them of convenient carpool opportunities, acquiring vehicles appropriate for carpool use, designating existing highway lanes as preferential carpool highway lanes, providing related traffic control devices, and designating existing facilities for use as preferential parking for carpools.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e686e3b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s146/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A project authorized by this section shall be subject to and carried out in accordance with all provisions of this title, except those provisions which the Secretary determines are inconsistent with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id2e686e3c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tI/s126/a">Pub. L. 95–599, title I, § 126(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2705">92 Stat. 2705</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1103">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1103</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/125">112 Stat. 125</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1105/b">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1105(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/432">126 Stat. 432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id2e686e3d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id2e686e3e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id2e686e3f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 146, <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/tI/s125/a">Pub. L. 93–87, title I, § 125(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/262">87 Stat. 262</ref>, related to a special urban high density traffic program, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/94/280/tI/s128/a">Pub. L. 94–280, title I, § 128(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-05">May 5, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/440">90 Stat. 440</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id2e686e40-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> substituted “section 104(b)(2)” for “sections 104(b)(1) and 104(b)(3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref> substituted “sections 104(b)(1) and 104(b)(3)” for “sections 104(b)(1), 104(b)(2), and 104(b)(6)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id2e686e41-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e686e42-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e686e43-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of High Occupancy Lanes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/424/tI/s163">Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 163</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2136">96 Stat. 2136</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/17/tI/s133/a/4">Pub. L. 100–17, title I, § 133(a)(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/170">101 Stat. 170</ref>, 171; <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1056">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1056</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2002">105 Stat. 2002</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1056">“Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act or any other law, no funds apportioned or allocated to a State for Federal-aid highways shall be obligated for a project for constructing, resurfacing, restoring, rehabilitating, or reconstructing a Federal-aid highway which has a lane designated as a carpool lane unless the use of such lane includes use by motorcycles. Upon certification by the State to the Secretary of Transportation, after notice in the Federal Register and an opportunity for public comment, and acceptance of such certification by the Secretary, the State may restrict such use by motorcycles if such use would create a safety hazard. Any certification made before the date of the enactment of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 [<date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>] shall not be recognized by the Secretary until the Secretary publishes notice of such certification in the Federal Register and provides an opportunity for public comment on such certification.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e686e44-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expenditure of Administrative Funds for Carpooling and Vanpooling Programs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/424/tI/s123/b">Pub. L. 97–424, title I, § 123(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2113">96 Stat. 2113</ref>, directed the Secretary of Transportation to expend necessary sums out of the administrative funds authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/a">section 104(a) of this title</ref> to carry out <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/s126/d">section 126(d) of Pub. L. 95–599</ref>, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e686e45-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Grants to States, Counties, etc., To Promote Carpooling and Vanpooling Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tI/s126/d">Pub. L. 95–599, title I, § 126(d)</ref>–(h), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2706">92 Stat. 2706</ref>, 2707, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tIII/s3004/b">Pub. L. 102–240, title III, § 3004(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2088">105 Stat. 2088</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/240/tIII/s3004/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> It is hereby declared to be national policy that special effort should be made to promote commuter modes of transportation which conserve energy, reduce pollution, and reduce traffic congestion. The Secretary is directed to assist both public and private employers and employees who wish to establish carpooling and vanpooling programs where they are needed and desired, and to assist local and State governments, and their instrumentalities, in encouraging such modes by removing legal and regulatory barriers to such programs, supporting existing carpooling and vanpooling programs, and providing technical assistance, for the purpose of increasing participation in such modes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> The Secretary of Transportation is authorized to make grants and loans to States, counties, municipalities, metropolitan planning organizations, and other units of local and regional government consistent with the policy of subsection (d) of this section. Such grants and loans shall be awarded in a manner which emphasizes energy conservation, although the Secretary may use other factors as he deems appropriate. The Federal share of the costs of any project approved under this subsection shall not exceed 75 per centum. No grant awarded under this subsection may be used for the purchase or lease of vehicles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> There is hereby authorized to be appropriated, out of the Highway Trust Fund, not to exceed $1,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, $1,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, and $1,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, for expenditures incurred by the Secretary of Transportation in carrying out the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, and $3,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, and $9,000,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, for the purpose of carrying out the program described in subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><content> The Secretary of Transportation shall not approve any project under subsection (d) or (e) of this section or under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s146">section 146 of title 23</ref>, United States Code; which will have an adverse effect on any mass transportation system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><content> The Secretary of Transportation is directed to study the administrative effectiveness of carpooling and vanpooling programs within the Department of Transportation, including programs of the Federal Highway Administration, the Federal Transit Administration, and the Office of the Secretary. Such study shall be completed no later than <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>. Upon completion of such study, the Secretary shall propose a plan to centralize or modify such programs to make delivery of services and grants more efficient, more cost-effective, and to avoid duplication of effort. Such plan shall list statutory changes needed to implement such a plan, which shall be sent to Congress no later than <date date="1980-03-30">March 30, 1980</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“Federal Transit Administration” substituted for “Urban Mass Transit Administration” in <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/s126/h">section 126(h) of Pub. L. 95–599</ref>, set out above, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s3004/a">section 3004(a) of Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s107">section 107 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e686e46-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Federal Facility Ridesharing Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to the Federal Facilities Ridesharing Program, see Ex. Ord. No. 12191, <date date="1980-02-01">Feb. 1, 1980</date>, 45 F.R. 7997, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6361">section 6361 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
