<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id2e6ae05f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149"><num value="149">§ 149.</num><heading> Congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6ae060-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish and implement a congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6ae061-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Projects</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsections (d) and (m)(1)(B)(ii), a State may obligate funds apportioned to it under section 104(b)(4) for the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program only for a transportation project or program if the project or program is for an area in the State that is or was designated as a nonattainment area for ozone, carbon monoxide, or particulate matter under section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)</ref>) and classified pursuant to section 181(a), 186(a), 188(a), or 188(b) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511/a">42 U.S.C. 7511(a)</ref>, 7512(a), 7513(a), or 7513(b)) or is or was designated as a nonattainment area under such section 107(d) after <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, or is required to prepare, and file with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, maintenance plans under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.) and—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6ae062-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6ae063-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6ae064-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> if the Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator determines, on the basis of information published by the Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to section 108(f)(1)(A) of the Clean Air Act (other than clause (xvi)) that the project or program is likely to contribute to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6ae065-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/1/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the attainment of a national ambient air quality standard in the designated nonattainment area; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6ae066-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/1/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the maintenance of a national ambient air quality standard in a maintenance area; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6ae067-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a high level of effectiveness in reducing air pollution, in cases of projects or programs where sufficient information is available in the database established pursuant to subsection (h) to determine the relative effectiveness of such projects or programs; or,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6ae068-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in any case in which such information is not available, if the Secretary, after such consultation, determines that the project or program is part of a program, method, or strategy described in such section 108(f)(1)(A);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2959-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the project or program is included in a State implementation plan that has been approved pursuant to the Clean Air Act and the project will have air quality benefits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d295a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, determines that the project or program is likely to contribute to the attainment or maintenance of a national ambient air quality standard, whether through reductions in vehicle miles traveled, fuel consumption, or through other factors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d295b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to establish or operate a traffic monitoring, management, and control facility or program, including advanced truck stop electrification systems, if the Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, determines that the facility or program is likely to contribute to the attainment or maintenance in the area of a national ambient air quality standard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d295c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> if the program or project improves traffic flow, including projects to improve signalization, construct high occupancy vehicle lanes, improve intersections, add turning lanes, improve transportation systems management and operations that mitigate congestion and improve air quality, and implement intelligent transportation system strategies and such other projects that are eligible for assistance under this section on the day before the date of enactment of this paragraph, including programs or projects to improve incident and emergency response or improve mobility, such as through real-time traffic, transit, and multimodal traveler information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d295d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> if the project or program involves the purchase of integrated, interoperable emergency communications equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d295e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> if the project or program shifts traffic demand to nonpeak hours or other transportation modes, increases vehicle occupancy rates, or otherwise reduces demand for roads through such means as telecommuting, ridesharing, carsharing, shared micromobility (including bikesharing and shared scooter systems), alternative work hours, and pricing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d295f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> if the project or program is for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2960-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the purchase of diesel replacements or retrofits that are—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d2961-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> verified technologies (as defined in section 791 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s16131">42 U.S.C. 16131</ref>)) for motor vehicles (as defined in section 216 of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7550">42 U.S.C. 7550</ref>)); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d2962-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> verified technologies (as defined in section 791 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s16131">42 U.S.C. 16131</ref>)) for non-road vehicles and non-road engines (as defined in section 216 of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7550">42 U.S.C. 7550</ref>)) that are used in construction projects or port-related freight operations that are—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id2e6d2963-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> located in nonattainment or maintenance areas for ozone, PM<sub>10</sub>, or PM<sub>2.5</sub> (as defined under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.)); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id2e6d2964-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> funded, in whole or in part, under this title or chapter 53 of title 49;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2965-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the conduct of outreach activities that are designed to provide information and technical assistance to the owners and operators of diesel equipment and vehicles regarding the purchase and installation of diesel replacements or retrofits; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2966-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the purchase of medium- or heavy-duty zero emission vehicles and related charging equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2967-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> if the project or program is for the installation of vehicle-to-infrastructure communication equipment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2968-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><chapeau> if the project is for the modernization or rehabilitation of a lock and dam that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2969-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is functionally connected to the Federal-aid highway system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d296a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary determines is likely to contribute to the attainment or maintenance of a national ambient air quality standard; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d296b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><chapeau> if the project is on a marine highway corridor, connector, or crossing designated by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s55601/c">section 55601(c) of title 46</ref> (including an inland waterway corridor, connector, or crossing) that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d296c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is functionally connected to the Federal-aid highway system; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d296d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/b/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary determines is likely to contribute to the attainment or maintenance of a national ambient air quality standard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d296e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Rules.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d296f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Projects for pm–10 nonattainment areas</inline>.—</heading><content>A State may obligate funds apportioned to the State under section 104(b)(4) for a project or program for an area that is nonattainment for ozone or carbon monoxide, or both, and for PM–10 resulting from transportation activities, without regard to any limitation of the Department of Transportation relating to the type of ambient air quality standard such project or program addresses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2970-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Electric vehicle and natural gas vehicle infrastructure</inline>.—</heading><content>A State may obligate funds apportioned under section 104(b)(4) for a project or program to establish electric vehicle charging stations or natural gas vehicle refueling stations for the use of battery powered or natural gas fueled trucks or other motor vehicles at any location in the State (giving priority to corridors designated under section 151) except that such stations may not be established or supported where commercial establishments serving motor vehicle users are prohibited by <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s111">section 111 of title 23</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2971-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">HOV facilities</inline>.—</heading><content>No funds may be provided under this section for a project which will result in the construction of new capacity available to single occupant vehicles unless the project consists of a high occupancy vehicle facility available to single occupant vehicles only at other than peak travel times.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2972-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Locks and dams; marine highways</inline>.—</heading><content>For each fiscal year, a State may not obligate more than 10 percent of the funds apportioned to the State under section 104(b)(4) for projects described in paragraphs (10) and (11) of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d2973-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">States Flexibility.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2974-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">States without a nonattainment area</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If a State does not have, and never has had, a nonattainment area designated under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.), the State may use funds apportioned to the State under section 104(b)(4) for any project in the State that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2975-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> would otherwise be eligible under subsection (b) as if the project were carried out in a nonattainment or maintenance area; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2976-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is eligible under the surface transportation block grant program under section 133.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2977-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">States with a nonattainment area.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2978-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If a State has a nonattainment area or maintenance area and received funds in fiscal year 2009 under section 104(b)(2)(D), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the MAP–21, above the amount of funds that the State would have received based on the nonattainment and maintenance area population of the State under subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 104(b)(2), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the MAP–21, the State may use for any project that would otherwise be eligible under subsection (b) if the project were carried out in a nonattainment or maintenance area or is eligible under the surface transportation block grant program under section 133 an amount of funds apportioned to such State under section 104(b)(4) that is equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d2979-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount apportioned to such State under section 104(b)(4) (excluding the amount of funds reserved under subsection (k)(1)); by</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d297a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the ratio calculated under subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d297b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ratio</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this paragraph, the ratio shall be calculated as the proportion that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d297c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount for fiscal year 2009 such State was permitted by section 149(c)(2), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the MAP–21, to obligate in any area of the State for projects eligible under section 133, as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the MAP–21; bears to</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d297d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the total apportionment to such State for fiscal year 2009 under section 104(b)(2), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the MAP–21.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d297e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Changes in designation</inline>.—</heading><content>If a new nonattainment area is designated or a previously designated nonattainment area is redesignated as an attainment area in a State under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.), the Secretary shall modify, in a manner consistent with the approach that was in effect on the day before the date of enactment of MAP–21, the amount such State is permitted to obligate in any area of the State for projects eligible under section 133.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d297f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Planning Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Programming and expenditure of funds for projects under this section shall be consistent with the requirements of sections 134 and 135 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d2980-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Partnerships With Nongovernmental Entities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2981-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title and in accordance with this subsection, a metropolitan planning organization, State transportation department, or other project sponsor may enter into an agreement with any public, private, or nonprofit entity to cooperatively implement any project carried out under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2982-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Forms of participation by entities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Participation by an entity under paragraph (1) may consist of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2983-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> ownership or operation of any land, facility, vehicle, or other physical asset associated with the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2984-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> cost sharing of any project expense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2985-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> carrying out of administration, construction management, project management, project operation, or any other management or operational duty associated with the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2986-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any other form of participation approved by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2987-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocation to entities</inline>.—</heading><content>A State may allocate funds apportioned under section 104(b)(4) to an entity described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2988-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternative fuel projects</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of a project that will provide for the use of alternative fuels by privately owned vehicles or vehicle fleets, activities eligible for funding under this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2989-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may include the costs of vehicle refueling infrastructure, including infrastructure that would support the development, production, and use of emerging technologies that reduce emissions of air pollutants from motor vehicles and nonroad vehicles and nonroad engines used in construction projects or port-related freight operations, and other capital investments associated with the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d298a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall include only the incremental cost of an alternative fueled vehicle, as compared to a conventionally fueled vehicle, that would otherwise be borne by a private party; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d298b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall apply other governmental financial purchase contributions in the calculation of net incremental cost.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d298c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on federal participation with respect to required activities</inline>.—</heading><content>A Federal participation payment under this subsection may not be made to an entity to fund an obligation imposed under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.) or any other Federal law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d298d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cost-Effective Emission Reduction Guidance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d298e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d298f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrator</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2990-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Diesel replacement or retrofit</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “diesel replacement or retrofit” means a replacement or retrofit, repowering, rebuilding, after treatment, or other technology, as determined by the Administrator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2991-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emission reduction guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall publish a list of diesel replacement or retrofit technologies and supporting technical information for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2992-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> diesel emission reduction technologies certified or verified by the Administrator, the California Air Resources Board, or any other entity recognized by the Administrator for the same purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2993-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> diesel emission reduction technologies identified by the Administrator as having an application and approvable test plan for verification by the Administrator or the California Air Resources Board that is submitted not later than 18 months of the date of enactment of this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d2994-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> available information regarding the emission reduction effectiveness and cost effectiveness of technologies identified in this paragraph, taking into consideration air quality and health effects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2995-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority consideration</inline>.—</heading><content>States and metropolitan planning organizations shall give priority in areas designated as nonattainment or maintenance for PM2.5 under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.) in distributing funds received for congestion mitigation and air quality projects and programs from apportionments under section 104(b)(4) to projects that are proven to reduce PM2.5, including diesel replacements or retrofits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2996-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No effect on authority or restrictions</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection modifies or otherwise affects any authority or restriction established under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.) or any other law (other than provisions of this title relating to congestion mitigation and air quality).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d2997-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interagency Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall encourage States and metropolitan planning organizations to consult with State and local air quality agencies in nonattainment and maintenance areas on the estimated emission reductions from proposed congestion mitigation and air quality improvement programs and projects.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d2998-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation and Assessment of Projects.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d2999-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Database.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d299a-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Using appropriate assessments of projects funded under the congestion mitigation and air quality program and results from other research, the Secretary shall maintain and disseminate a cumulative database describing the impacts of the projects, including specific information about each project, such as the project name, location, sponsor, cost, and, to the extent already measured by the project sponsor, cost-effectiveness, based on reductions in congestion and emissions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d299b-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>The database shall be published or otherwise made readily available by the Secretary in electronically accessible format and means, such as the Internet, for public review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d299c-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cost effectiveness.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d299d-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall evaluate projects on a periodic basis and develop a table or other similar medium that illustrates the cost-effectiveness of a range of project types eligible for funding under this section as to how the projects mitigate congestion and improve air quality.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d299e-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><content>The table described in subparagraph (A) shall show measures of cost-effectiveness, such as dollars per ton of emissions reduced, and assess those measures over a variety of timeframes to capture impacts on the planning timeframes outlined in section 134.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d299f-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of table</inline>.—</heading><content>States and metropolitan planning organizations shall consider the information in the table when selecting projects or developing performance plans under subsection (<i>l</i>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d29a0-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Optional Programmatic Eligibility.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29a1-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>At the discretion of a metropolitan planning organization, a technical assessment of a selected program of projects may be conducted through modeling or other means to demonstrate the emissions reduction projection required under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29a2-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>If an assessment described in paragraph (1) successfully demonstrates an emissions reduction, all projects included in such assessment shall be eligible for obligation under this section without further demonstration of emissions reduction of individual projects included in such assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d29a3-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority for Use of Funds in PM</inline>2.5 <inline class="small-caps">Areas.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29a4-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For any State that has a nonattainment or maintenance area for fine particulate matter, an amount equal to 25 percent of the funds apportioned to each State under section 104(b)(4) for a nonattainment or maintenance area that are based all or in part on the weighted population of such area in fine particulate matter nonattainment shall be obligated to projects that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29a5-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reduce such fine particulate matter emissions in such area, including diesel replacements or retrofits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29a6-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to the extent practicable, prioritize benefits to disadvantaged communities or low-income populations living in, or immediately adjacent to, such area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29a7-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction equipment and vehicles</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to meet the requirements of paragraph (1), a State or metropolitan planning organization may elect to obligate funds to install diesel emission control technology on nonroad diesel equipment or on-road diesel equipment that is operated on a highway construction project within a PM2.5 nonattainment or maintenance area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29a8-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">PM</inline>2.5<inline class="small-caps"> nonattainment and maintenance in low population density states.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29a9-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In any State with a population density of 80 or fewer persons per square mile of land area, based on the most recent decennial census, the requirements under subsection (g)(3) and paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall not apply to a nonattainment or maintenance area in the State if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29aa-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the nonattainment or maintenance area does not have projects that are part of the emissions analysis of a metropolitan transportation plan or transportation improvement program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29ab-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> regional motor vehicle emissions are an insignificant contributor to the air quality problem for PM2.5 in the nonattainment or maintenance area.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29ac-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Calculation</inline>.—</heading><content>If subparagraph (A) applies to a nonattainment or maintenance area in a State, the percentage of the PM2.5 set-aside under paragraph (1) shall be reduced for that State proportionately based on the weighted population of the area in fine particulate matter nonattainment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29ad-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Port-related equipment and vehicles</inline>.—</heading><content>To meet the requirements under paragraph (1), a State or metropolitan planning organization may elect to obligate funds to the most cost-effective projects to reduce emissions from port-related landside nonroad or on-road equipment that is operated within the boundaries of a PM2.5 nonattainment or maintenance area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d29ae-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Performance Plan.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29af-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each metropolitan planning organization serving a transportation management area (as defined in section 134) with a population over 1,000,000 people representing a nonattainment or maintenance area shall develop a performance plan that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29b0-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> includes an area baseline level for traffic congestion and on-road mobile source emissions for which the area is in nonattainment or maintenance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29b1-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> describes progress made in achieving the air quality and traffic congestion performance targets described in section 150(d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29b2-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> includes a description of projects identified for funding under this section and how such projects will contribute to achieving emission and traffic congestion reduction targets.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29b3-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updated plans</inline>.—</heading><content>Performance plans shall be updated biennially and include a separate report that assesses the progress of the program of projects under the previous plan in achieving the air quality and traffic congestion targets of the previous plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29b4-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance to metropolitan planning organizations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29b5-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>On the request of a metropolitan planning organization, the Secretary may assist the metropolitan planning organization tracking progress made in minority or low-income populations as part of a performance plan under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29b6-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings provision</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this paragraph provides the Secretary the authority—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29b7-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to change the performance measures under section 150(c)(5) or the performance targets established under section 134(h)(2) or 150(d); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29b8-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/l/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to establish any other Federal requirement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id2e6d29b9-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Operating Assistance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29ba-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State may obligate funds apportioned under section 104(b)(4) in an area of the State that is otherwise eligible for obligations of such funds for operating costs—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29bb-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> under chapter 53 of title 49; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29bc-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29bd-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a system for which CMAQ funding was eligible, made available, obligated, or expended in fiscal year 2012; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29be-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a State-supported Amtrak route with a valid cost-sharing agreement under section 209 of the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s24101">49 U.S.C. 24101</ref> note; <ref href="/us/pl/110/432">Public Law 110–432</ref>) and no current nonattainment areas under subsection (d).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id2e6d29bf-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No time limitation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Operating assistance provided under paragraph (1) shall have no imposed time limitation if the operating assistance is for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29c0-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a route described in subparagraph (B) of that paragraph; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id2e6d29c1-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> a transit system that is located in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29c2-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a non-urbanized area; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id2e6d29c3-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79" identifier="/us/usc/t23/s149/m/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an urbanized area with a population of 200,000 or fewer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id2e6d29c4-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/93/87/tI/s142/a">Pub. L. 93–87, title I, § 142(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-13">Aug. 13, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/272">87 Stat. 272</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1008/a">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1008(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1932">105 Stat. 1932</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/388/tIII/s380">Pub. L. 102–388, title III, § 380</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1562">106 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s319/a/1">Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 319(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/588">109 Stat. 588</ref>, 589; <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tIV/s405/a/2">Pub. L. 104–88, title IV, § 405(a)(2)</ref>, (b), <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/956">109 Stat. 956</ref>, 957; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1110/a">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1110(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/142">112 Stat. 142</ref>, 143; <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1808/a">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1808(a)</ref>–(f), <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1461-1463">119 Stat. 1461–1463</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dA/tI/s1113/a">Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1113(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/460">126 Stat. 460</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dL/tI/s125">Pub. L. 113–76, div. L, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/587">128 Stat. 587</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/dA/tI">Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 1109(c)(5), 1114, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1343">129 Stat. 1343</ref>, 1348; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dL/tIV/s421">Pub. L. 115–141, div. L, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1045">132 Stat. 1045</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11115">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11115</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/480">135 Stat. 480</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id2e6d29c5-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id2e6d29c6-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id2e6d29c7-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Clean Air Act, referred to in subsecs. (b), (d)(1), (3), (f)(5), and (g)(3), (4), is <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-14/ch360">act July 14, 1955, ch. 360</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/322">69 Stat. 322</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 85 (§ 7401 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Section 108(f)(1)(A) of the Act is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7408/f/1/A">section 7408(f)(1)(A) of Title 42</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">section 7401 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this paragraph, referred to in subsec. (b)(5), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/105/178">Pub. L. 105–178</ref>, which was approved <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 104(b)(2), 133, and 149(c)(2), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the MAP–21, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), mean <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/2">section 104(b)(2) of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s133">section 133 of this title</ref>, and subsec. (c)(2) of this section, respectively, as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, which amended section 104 generally, made numerous amendments to section 133, and redesignated subsec. (c) of this section as (d) and struck it out. The date of enactment of the MAP–21 is deemed to be <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see section 3(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The day before the date of enactment of MAP–21, referred to in subsec. (d)(3), means the day before the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref>. See note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this subsection, referred to in subsec. (g)(2)(B), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/109/59">Pub. L. 109–59</ref>, which was approved <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 209 of the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008, referred to in subsec. (m), is <ref href="/us/pl/110/432/dB/s209">section 209 of div. B of Pub. L. 110–432</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s24101">section 24101 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id2e6d29c8-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/1/A">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsections (d) and (m)(1)(B)(ii)” for “subsection (d)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/1/B">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “shared micromobility (including bikesharing and shared scooter systems),” after “carsharing,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/1/C/i/I">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(1)(C)(i)(I)</ref>, inserted “replacements or” before “retrofits” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/1/C/i/II">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(1)(C)(i)(II)</ref>, added cl. (i) and struck out former cl. (i) which read as follows: “for motor vehicles (as defined in section 216 of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7550">42 U.S.C. 7550</ref>)); or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/1/C/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(1)(C)(ii)</ref>, inserted “replacements or” before “retrofits”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/1/C/i/III">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(1)(C)(i)(III)</ref>, (iii), added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10), (11). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/1/D">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(1)(D)</ref>, (E), added pars. (10) and (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/2">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/3">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(3)</ref>, inserted “and nonroad vehicles and nonroad engines used in construction projects or port-related freight operations” after “motor vehicles”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/4/A">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(4)(A)</ref>, in heading, inserted “replacement or” before “retrofit” and, in text, substituted “The term ‘diesel replacement or retrofit’ means” for “The term ‘diesel retrofit’ means” and inserted “or retrofit” after “replacement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/4/B">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(4)(B)</ref>, inserted “replacement or” before “retrofit” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/4/C">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(4)(C)</ref>, inserted “replacements or” before “retrofits”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/5">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(5)</ref>, substituted “that—” and subpars. (A) and (B) for “that reduce such fine particulate matter emissions in such area, including diesel retrofits.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/6">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(6)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s11115/7">Pub. L. 117–58, § 11115(7)</ref>, added subsec. (m) and struck out former subsec. (m). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “A State may obligate funds apportioned under section 104(b)(4) in an area of such State that is otherwise eligible for obligations of such funds for operating costs under chapter 53 of title 49 or on a system for which CMAQ funding was made available, obligated or expended in fiscal year 2012, or on a State-Supported Amtrak route with a valid cost-sharing agreement under section 209 of the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 and no current nonattainment areas under subsection (d), and shall have no imposed time limitation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> inserted “or on a State-Supported Amtrak route with a valid cost-sharing agreement under section 209 of the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 and no current nonattainment areas under subsection (d),” after “2012,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(i)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/1/A">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “in the designated nonattainment area” after “air quality standard”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/1/B">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “or maintenance” after “likely to contribute to the attainment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/1/C">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “attainment or maintenance in the area of” for “attainment of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/1/E/i/I">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(1)(E)(i)(I)</ref>, inserted “or port-related freight operations” after “construction projects” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8)(A)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/1/E/i/II">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(1)(E)(i)(II)</ref>, inserted “or chapter 53 of title 49” after “this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/1/D">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(1)(D)</ref>, (E)(ii), (F), added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/2">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(2)</ref>, inserted “(giving priority to corridors designated under section 151)” after “at any location in the State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/3/A">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(3)(A)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “is eligible under the surface transportation program under section 133.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/3/B/i/I">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(3)(B)(i)(I)</ref>, inserted “would otherwise be eligible under subsection (b) if the project were carried out in a nonattainment or maintenance area or” after “may use for any project that” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1109/c/5">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1109(c)(5)</ref>, substituted “surface transportation block grant program” for “surface transportation program” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/3/B/i/II">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(3)(B)(i)(II)</ref>, substituted “subsection (k)(1)” for “paragraph (l)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/3/B/ii">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(3)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “MAP–21” for “MAP–21t”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/3/C">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(3)(C)</ref>, inserted “, in a manner consistent with the approach that was in effect on the day before the date of enactment of MAP–21,” after “the Secretary shall modify”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/4">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(4)</ref>, substituted “not later than” for “not later that”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/5">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(5)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/6">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(6)</ref>, inserted “air quality and traffic congestion” before “performance targets”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1114/7">Pub. L. 114–94, § 1114(7)</ref>, substituted “section 104(b)(4)” for “section 104(b)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/113/76">Pub. L. 113–76</ref> substituted “for which CMAQ funding was made available, obligated or expended in fiscal year 2012, and shall have no imposed time limitation” for “that was previously eligible under this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/a/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(a)(1)</ref>, (5), in introductory provisions, substituted “in subsection (d)” for “in subsection (c)” and “section 104(b)(4)” for “section 104(b)(2)” and struck out concluding provisions which read as follows: “No funds may be provided under this section for a project which will result in the construction of new capacity available to single occupant vehicles unless the project consists of a high occupancy vehicle facility available to single occupant vehicles only at other than peak travel times. In areas of a State which are nonattainment for ozone or carbon monoxide, or both, and for PM–10 resulting from transportation activities, the State may obligate such funds for any project or program under paragraph (1) or (2) without regard to any limitation of the Department of Transportation relating to the type of ambient air quality standard such project or program addresses.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/a/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “add turning lanes,” after “improve intersections,” and substituted “paragraph, including programs or projects to improve incident and emergency response or improve mobility, such as through real-time traffic, transit, and multimodal traveler information;” for “paragraph;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/a/3">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(a)(3)</ref>, (7), added par. (7). Former par. (7) redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/a/4">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “verified technologies (as defined in section 791 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s16131">42 U.S.C. 16131</ref>))” for “published in the list under subsection (f)(2)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/a/6">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(a)(6)</ref>, redesignated par. (7) as (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/2">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/3">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which related to states receiving minimum apportionment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(1)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (e) as (f) and substituted “104(b)(4)” for “104(b)(2)” in par. (3). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(1)</ref>, (5), redesignated subsec. (f) as (g), added par. (3), and struck out former par. (3) which related to priority. Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (h). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/6">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(6)</ref>, added subsec. (i) and struck out former subsec. (i) which related to evaluation and assessment of projects.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/1">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j) to (m). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s1113/b/6">Pub. L. 112–141, § 1113(b)(6)</ref>, added subsecs. (j) to (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/a">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(a)</ref>, inserted “or is required to prepare, and file with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, maintenance plans under the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</ref> et seq.)” after “1997,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/b/1">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) if the Secretary, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, determines, on the basis of information published by the Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to section 108(f)(1)(A) of the Clean Air Act (other than clause (xvi) of such section), that the project or program is likely to contribute to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the attainment of a national ambient air quality standard; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the maintenance of a national ambient air quality standard in a maintenance area; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) in any case in which such information is not available, if the Secretary, after such consultation, determines that the project or program is part of a program, method, or strategy described in such section;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/b/2/A">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “, including advanced truck stop electrification systems,” after “control facility or program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/b/3/A">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(b)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “improve transportation systems management and operations that mitigate congestion and improve air quality,” after “intersections,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/b/2/B">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(b)(2)(B)</ref>, (3)(B), (4), which directed addition of pars. (6) and (7) at end of subsec. (b), was executed by adding pars. (6) and (7) after par. (5) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/c/1">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “for any project in the State that—” and subpars. (A) and (B) for “for any project eligible under the surface transportation program under section 133.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/c/2">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “for any project in the State that—” and subpars. (A) and (B) for “for any project in the State eligible under section 133.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/s1808/d">Pub. L. 109–59, § 1808(d)</ref>–(f), added subsecs. (f) to (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1110/a">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1110(a)</ref>, substituted “shall establish and implement” for “shall establish”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1110/b/1">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1110(b)(1)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “that is or was designated as a nonattainment area for ozone, carbon monoxide, or particulate matter under section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)</ref>) and classified pursuant to section 181(a), 186(a), 188(a), or 188(b) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7511/a">42 U.S.C. 7511(a)</ref>, 7512(a), 7513(a), or 7513(b)) or is or was designated as a nonattainment area under such section 107(d) after <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>,” for “that was designated as a nonattainment area under section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)</ref>) during any part of fiscal year 1994”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1110/b/2">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1110(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “clause (xvi) of such section” for “clauses (xii) and (xvi) of such section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1110/b/3">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1110(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “a maintenance area” for “an area that was designated as a nonattainment area but that was later redesignated by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency as an attainment area under section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1110/b/4">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1110(b)(4)</ref>–(6), added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1110/c">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1110(c)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “If a State does not have a nonattainment area for ozone or carbon monoxide under the Clean Air Act located within its borders, the State may use funds apportioned to it under section 104(b)(2) for any project eligible for assistance under the surface transportation program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/s1110/d/1">Pub. L. 105–178, § 1110(d)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s319/a/1/A">Pub. L. 104–59, § 319(a)(1)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted “if the project or program is for an area in the State that was designated as a nonattainment area under section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7407/d">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)</ref>) during any part of fiscal year 1994 and” after “project or program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s319/a/1/B">Pub. L. 104–59, § 319(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “contribute to—” and cls. (i) and (ii) for “contribute to the attainment of a national ambient air quality standard; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s319/b/1">Pub. L. 104–59, § 319(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “or” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s405/b/1">Pub. L. 104–88, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “or” after semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s319/b/2">Pub. L. 104–59, § 319(b)(2)</ref>, substituted a semicolon for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s405/b/2">Pub. L. 104–88, § 405(b)(2)</ref>, substituted a period for “; or” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s319/b/3">Pub. L. 104–59, § 319(b)(3)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s405/a/2">Pub. L. 104–88, § 405(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/388">Pub. L. 102–388</ref> inserted at end “In areas of a State which are nonattainment for ozone or carbon monoxide, or both, and for PM–10 resulting from transportation activities, the State may obligate such funds for any project or program under paragraph (1) or (2) without regard to any limitation of the Department of Transportation relating to the type of ambient air quality standard such project or program addresses.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> substituted section catchline for one which read: “Truck lanes” and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary may approve as a project on any Federal-aid system the construction of exclusive or preferential truck lanes.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id2e6d29c9-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e6d29ca-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/58">Pub. L. 117–58</ref> effective <date date="2021-10-01">Oct. 1, 2021</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s10003">section 10003 of Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e6d29cb-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/94">Pub. L. 114–94</ref> effective <date date="2015-10-01">Oct. 1, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/94/s1003">section 1003 of Pub. L. 114–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e6d29cc-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> effective <date date="2012-10-01">Oct. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2012 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e6d29cd-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1995 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s405/b">section 405(b) of Pub. L. 104–88</ref> effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tIV/s405/a">Pub. L. 104–88, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/956">109 Stat. 956</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 405(a)(2) is effective <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id2e6d29ce-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> effective <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, and applicable to funds authorized to be appropriated or made available after <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, and, with certain exceptions, not applicable to funds appropriated or made available on or before <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/s1100">section 1100 of Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104">section 104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e6d29cf-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reduction of Truck Emissions at Port Facilities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11402">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11402</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/553">135 Stat. 553</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11402">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall establish a program to reduce idling at port facilities, under which the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> study how ports and intermodal port transfer facilities would benefit from increased opportunities to reduce emissions at ports, including through the electrification of port operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> study emerging technologies and strategies that may help reduce port-related emissions from idling trucks; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> coordinate and provide funding to test, evaluate, and deploy projects that reduce port-related emissions from idling trucks, including through the advancement of port electrification and improvements in efficiency, focusing on port operations, including heavy-duty commercial vehicles, and other related projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the program under this subsection, the Secretary may consult with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grants.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out subsection (a)(1)(C), the Secretary shall award grants to fund projects that reduce emissions at ports, including through the advancement of port electrification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cost share</inline>.—</heading><content>A grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall not exceed 80 percent of the total cost of the project funded by the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the grant program under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to the maximum extent practicable, leverage existing resources and programs of the Department [of Transportation] and other relevant Federal agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> coordinate with other Federal agencies, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application; selection.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall solicit applications for grants under paragraph (1) at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall make grants under paragraph (1) by not later than April 1 of each fiscal year for which funding is made available.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any project funded by a grant under this subsection shall be treated as a project on a Federal-aid highway under chapter 1 of title 23, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date on which all of the projects funded with a grant under subsection (b) are completed, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the findings of the studies described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the results of the projects that received a grant under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any recommendations for workforce development and training opportunities with respect to port electrification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> any policy recommendations based on the findings and results described in paragraphs (1) and (2).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e6d29d0-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Healthy Streets Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11406">Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11406</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/575">135 Stat. 575</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dA/tI/s11406">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cool pavement</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘cool pavement’ means a pavement with reflective surfaces with higher albedo to decrease the surface temperature of that pavement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible entity</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘eligible entity’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a metropolitan planning organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a unit of local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a Tribal government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> a nonprofit organization working in coordination with an entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Low-income community</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘low-income community’ means a census block group in which not less than 30 percent of the population lives below the poverty line (as defined in section 673 of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9902">42 U.S.C. 9902</ref>)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Porous pavement</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘porous pavement’ means a paved surface with a higher than normal percentage of air voids to allow water to pass through the surface and infiltrate into the subsoil.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘program’ means the Healthy Streets program established under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 23</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tribal government</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Tribal government’ means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>] pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of Transportation] shall establish a discretionary grant program, to be known as the ‘Healthy Streets program’, to provide grants to eligible entities—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to deploy cool pavements and porous pavements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to expand tree cover.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Goals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The goals of the program are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to mitigate urban heat islands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to improve air quality; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> to reduce—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the extent of impervious surfaces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> stormwater runoff and flood risks; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> heat impacts to infrastructure and road users.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>To be eligible to receive a grant under the program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The application submitted by an eligible entity under paragraph (1) shall include a description of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> how the eligible entity would use the grant funds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the contribution that the projects intended to be carried out with grant funds would make to improving the safety, health outcomes, natural environment, and quality of life in low-income communities and disadvantaged communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An eligible entity that receives a grant under the program may use the grant funds for 1 or more of the following activities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Conducting an assessment of urban heat islands to identify hot spot areas of extreme heat or elevated air pollution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Conducting a comprehensive tree canopy assessment, which shall assess the current tree locations and canopy, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an inventory of the location, species, condition, and health of existing tree canopies and trees on public facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> an identification of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the locations where trees need to be replaced;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> empty tree boxes or other locations where trees could be added; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> flood-prone locations where trees or other natural infrastructure could mitigate flooding.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> Conducting an equity assessment by mapping tree canopy gaps, flood-prone locations, and urban heat island hot spots as compared to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> pedestrian walkways and public transportation stop locations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> low-income communities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> disadvantaged communities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Planning activities, including developing an investment plan based on the results of the assessments carried out under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Purchasing and deploying cool pavements to mitigate urban heat island hot spots.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><chapeau> Purchasing and deploying porous pavement to mitigate flooding and stormwater runoff in—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> pedestrian-only areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> areas of low-volume, low-speed vehicular use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><chapeau> Purchasing of trees, site preparation, planting of trees, ongoing maintenance and monitoring of trees, and repairing of storm damage to trees, with priority given to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to the extent practicable, the planting of native species; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> projects located in a neighborhood with lower tree cover or higher maximum daytime summer temperatures compared to surrounding neighborhoods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> Assessing underground infrastructure and coordinating with local transportation and utility providers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> Hiring staff to conduct any of the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (8).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In awarding grants to eligible entities under the program, the Secretary shall give priority to an eligible entity—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> proposing to carry out an activity or project in a low-income community or a disadvantaged community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that has entered into a community benefits agreement with representatives of the community; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> that is partnering with a qualified youth or conservation corps (as defined in section 203 of the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1722">16 U.S.C. 1722</ref>)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Distribution Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the amounts made available to carry out the program for each fiscal year, not less than 80 percent shall be provided for projects in urbanized areas (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 23</ref>, United States Code).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal Share.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided under paragraph (2), the Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the program shall be 80 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may increase the Federal share requirement under paragraph (1) to 100 percent for projects carried out by an eligible entity that demonstrates economic hardship, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maximum Grant Amount</inline>.—</heading><content>An individual grant under this section shall not exceed $15,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Projects</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a project assisted under this section shall be treated as a project on a Federal-aid highway under chapter 1 of title 23, United States Code.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e6f99d1-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Determination by Secretary; Water-Phased Hydrocarbon Fuel Emulsion Technologies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1110/d/2">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1110(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/144">112 Stat. 144</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIX/s9002/g">Pub. L. 105–206, title IX, § 9002(g)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/836">112 Stat. 836</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/206/tIX/s9002/g">“For the purposes of section 149(e) [now 149(f)] of title 23, United States Code, the Secretary shall determine in accordance with the procedures specified in section 149(b) of such title whether water-phased hydrocarbon fuel emulsion technologies that consist of a hydrocarbon base and water in an amount not less than 20 percent by volume reduce emissions of hydrocarbon, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, or nitrogen oxide from motor vehicles.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e6f99d2-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of CMAQ Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1110/e">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1110(e)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/144">112 Stat. 144</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1110/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall enter into arrangements with the National Academy of Sciences to complete, by not later than <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, a study of the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s149">section 149 of title 23</ref>, United States Code. The study shall, at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> evaluate the air quality impacts of emissions from motor vehicles;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> evaluate the negative effects of traffic congestion, including the economic effects of time lost due to congestion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> determine the amount of funds obligated under the program and make a comprehensive analysis of the types of projects funded under the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> evaluate the emissions reductions attributable to projects of various types that have been funded under the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> assess the effectiveness, including the quantitative and nonquantitative benefits, of projects funded under the program and include, in the assessment, an estimate of the cost per ton of pollution reduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> assess the cost effectiveness of projects funded under the program with respect to congestion mitigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="G">“(G)</num><chapeau> compare—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the costs of achieving the air pollutant emissions reductions achieved under the program; to</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the costs that would be incurred if similar reductions were achieved by other measures, including pollution controls on stationary sources;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> include recommendations on improvements, including other types of projects, that will increase the overall effectiveness of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> include recommendations on expanding the scope of the program to address traffic-related pollutants that, as of the date of the study, are not addressed by the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>, the National Academy of Sciences shall transmit to the Secretary, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report on the results of the study with recommendations for modifications to the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program in light of the results of the study.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Before making the apportionment of funds under [former] <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/2">section 104(b)(2) of title 23</ref>, United States Code, for each of fiscal years 1999 and 2000, the Secretary shall deduct from the amount to be apportioned under such section for such fiscal year, and make available, $500,000 for such fiscal year to carry out this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e6f99d3-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect of Limitation on Apportionment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for each of fiscal years 1996 and 1997, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s319/a/1">section 319(a)(1) of Pub. L. 104–59</ref> not to affect any apportionment adjustments under section 1015 of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991, <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/s319/c">section 319(c) of Pub. L. 104–59</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104">section 104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id2e6f99d4-3a70-11f1-8334-895c8eef5d79"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Value Pricing Pilot Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tI/s1012/b">Pub. L. 102–240, title I, § 1012(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1938">105 Stat. 1938</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/59/tIII/s325/e">Pub. L. 104–59, title III, § 325(e)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-28">Nov. 28, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/592">109 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tI/s1216/a">Pub. L. 105–178, title I, § 1216(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/211">112 Stat. 211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIX/s9006/b">Pub. L. 105–206, title IX, § 9006(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/848">112 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1604/a">Pub. L. 109–59, title I, § 1604(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1249">119 Stat. 1249</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/59/tI/s1604/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall solicit the participation of State and local governments and public authorities for one or more value pricing pilot programs. The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with as many as 15 such State or local governments or public authorities to establish, maintain, and monitor value pricing programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s129">section 129 of title 23</ref>, United States Code, the Federal share payable for such programs shall be 80 percent. The Secretary shall fund all preimplementation costs and project design, and all of the development and other start up costs of such projects, including salaries and expenses, for a period of at least 1 year, and thereafter until such time that sufficient revenues are being generated by the program to fund its operating costs without Federal participation, except that the Secretary may not fund the preimplementation or implementation costs of any project for more than 3 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Revenues generated by any pilot project under this subsection must be applied to projects eligible under such title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Notwithstanding sections 129 and 301 of title 23, United States Code, the Secretary shall allow the use of tolls on the Interstate System as part of any value pricing pilot program under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The Secretary shall monitor the effect of such programs for a period of at least 10 years, and shall report to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives every 2 years on the effects such programs are having on driver behavior, traffic volume, transit ridership, air quality, and availability of funds for transportation programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">HOV passenger requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s102/a">section 102(a) of title 23</ref>, United States Code, a State may permit vehicles with fewer than 2 occupants to operate in high occupancy vehicle lanes if the vehicles are part of a value pricing pilot program under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Financial effects on low-income drivers</inline>.—</heading><content>Any value pricing pilot program under this subsection shall include, if appropriate, an analysis of the potential effects of the pilot program on low-income drivers and may include mitigation measures to deal with any potential adverse financial effects on low-income drivers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary from the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) to carry out this subsection—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> for fiscal year 2005, $11,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2009, $12,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Set-aside for projects not involving highway tolls</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the amounts made available to carry out this subsection, $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2009 shall be available only for congestion pricing pilot projects that do not involve highway tolls.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds allocated by the Secretary to a State under this subsection shall remain available for obligation by the State for a period of 3 years after the last day of the fiscal year for which the funds are authorized.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of unallocated funds</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the total amount of funds made available from the Highway Trust Fund to carry out this subsection for fiscal year 1998 and fiscal years thereafter but not allocated exceeds $8,000,000 as of September 30 of any year, the excess amount—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> shall be apportioned in the following fiscal year by the Secretary to all States in accordance with [former] <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s104/b/3">section 104(b)(3) of title 23</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> shall be considered to be a sum made available for expenditure on the surface transportation program, except that the amount shall not be subject to section 133(d) of such title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> shall be available for any purpose eligible for funding under section 133 of such title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> [probably should be (E)] <inline class="small-caps">Contract authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds authorized to carry out this subsection shall be available for obligation in the same manner as if the funds were apportioned under chapter 1 of title 23, United States Code; except that the Federal share of the cost of any project under this subsection and the availability of funds authorized to carry out this subsection shall be determined in accordance with this subsection.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
