<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb92e299d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102"><num value="10102">§ 10102.</num><heading> Strategic human capital plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb92e299e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Development</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this chapter, the Administrator shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a strategic human capital plan to shape and improve the workforce of the Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb92e299f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The strategic human capital plan shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb92e29a0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> a workforce gap analysis, including an assessment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29a1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the critical skills and competencies that will be needed in the workforce of the Agency to support the mission and responsibilities of, and effectively manage, the Agency during the 10-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29a2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the skills and competencies of the workforce of the Agency on the day before the date of enactment of this chapter and projected trends in that workforce, based on expected losses due to retirement and other attrition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29a3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the staffing levels of each category of employee, including gaps in the workforce of the Agency on the day before the date of enactment of this chapter and in the projected workforce of the Agency that should be addressed to ensure that the Agency has continued access to the critical skills and competencies described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb92e29a4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> a plan of action for developing and reshaping the workforce of the Agency to address the gaps in critical skills and competencies identified under paragraph (1)(C), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29a5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> specific recruitment and retention goals, including the use of the bonus authorities under this chapter as well as other bonus authorities (including the program objective of the Agency to be achieved through such goals);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29a6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> specific strategies for developing, training, deploying, compensating, and motivating and retaining the Agency workforce and its ability to fulfill the Agency’s mission and responsibilities (including the program objectives of the Department and the Agency to be achieved through such strategies);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29a7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> specific strategies for recruiting individuals who have served in multiple State agencies with emergency management responsibilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29a8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> specific strategies for the development, training, and coordinated and rapid deployment of the Surge Capacity Force; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb92e29a9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> a discussion that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29aa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> details the number of employees of the Department not employed by the Agency serving in the Surge Capacity Force and the qualifications or credentials of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29ab-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> details the number of individuals not employed by the Department serving in the Surge Capacity Force and the qualifications or credentials of such individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29ac-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> describes the training given to the Surge Capacity Force during the calendar year preceding the year of submission of the plan under subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29ad-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> states whether the Surge Capacity Force is able to adequately prepare for, respond to, and recover from natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters, including catastrophic incidents; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb92e29ae-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> describes any additional authorities or resources necessary to address any deficiencies in the Surge Capacity Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb92e29af-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s10102/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Updates</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2007-05-01">May 1, 2007</date>, and May 1st of each of the next 5 succeeding years, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an update of the strategic human capital plan, including an assessment by the Administrator, using results-oriented performance measures, of the progress of the Department and the Agency in implementing the strategic human capital plan.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb92e29b0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/tVI/s621/a">Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 621(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1412">120 Stat. 1412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb92e29b1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb92e29b2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb92e29b3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b)(1), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/109/295">Pub. L. 109–295</ref>, which was approved <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
