<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb7ec32f6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221"><num value="1221">§ 1221.</num><heading> Individual right of action in certain reprisal cases</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32f7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section and subsection 1214(a)(3), an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment may, with respect to any personnel action taken, or proposed to be taken, against such employee, former employee, or applicant for employment, as a result of a prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D), seek corrective action from the Merit Systems Protection Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32f8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> This section may not be construed to prohibit any employee, former employee, or applicant for employment from seeking corrective action from the Merit Systems Protection Board before seeking corrective action from the Special Counsel, if such employee, former employee, or applicant for employment has the right to appeal directly to the Board under any law, rule, or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32f9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32fa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any employee, former employee, or applicant for employment seeking corrective action under subsection (a) may request that the Board order a stay of the personnel action involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32fb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any stay requested under paragraph (1) shall be granted within 10 calendar days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after the date the request is made, if the Board determines that such a stay would be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32fc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32fd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Board shall allow any agency which would be subject to a stay under this subsection to comment to the Board on such stay request.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32fe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (C), a stay granted under this subsection shall remain in effect for such period as the Board determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec32ff-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Board may modify or dissolve a stay under this subsection at any time, if the Board determines that such a modification or dissolution is appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3300-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3301-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> At the request of an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment seeking corrective action under subsection (a), the Board shall issue a subpoena for the attendance and testimony of any person or the production of documentary or other evidence from any person if the Board finds that the testimony or production requested is not unduly burdensome and appears reasonably calculated to lead to the discovery of admissible evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3302-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A subpoena under this subsection may be issued, and shall be enforced, in the same manner as applies in the case of subpoenas under section 1204.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3303-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3304-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), in any case involving an alleged prohibited personnel practice as described under section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D), the Board shall order such corrective action as the Board considers appropriate if the employee, former employee, or applicant for employment has demonstrated that a disclosure or protected activity described under section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) was a contributing factor in the personnel action which was taken or is to be taken against such employee, former employee, or applicant. The employee may demonstrate that the disclosure or protected activity was a contributing factor in the personnel action through circumstantial evidence, such as evidence that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7ec3305-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the official taking the personnel action knew of the disclosure or protected activity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7ec3306-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the personnel action occurred within a period of time such that a reasonable person could conclude that the disclosure or protected activity was a contributing factor in the personnel action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3307-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Corrective action under paragraph (1) may not be ordered if, after a finding that a protected disclosure was a contributing factor, the agency demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that it would have taken the same personnel action in the absence of such disclosure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3308-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3309-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A final order or decision shall be rendered by the Board as soon as practicable after the commencement of any proceeding under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec330a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A decision to terminate an investigation under subchapter II may not be considered in any action or other proceeding under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec330b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If, based on evidence presented to it under this section, the Merit Systems Protection Board determines that there is reason to believe that a current employee may have committed a prohibited personnel practice, the Board shall refer the matter to the Special Counsel to investigate and take appropriate action under section 1215.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec330c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec330d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec330e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If the Board orders corrective action under this section, such corrective action may include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7ec330f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that the individual be placed, as nearly as possible, in the position the individual would have been in had the prohibited personnel practice not occurred; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7ec3310-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> back pay and related benefits, medical costs incurred, travel expenses, any other reasonable and foreseeable consequential damages, and compensatory damages (including interest, reasonable expert witness fees, and costs).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3311-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Corrective action shall include attorney’s fees and costs as provided for under paragraphs (2) and (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3312-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment is the prevailing party before the Merit Systems Protection Board, and the decision is based on a finding of a prohibited personnel practice, the agency involved shall be liable to the employee, former employee, or applicant for reasonable attorney’s fees and any other reasonable costs incurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3313-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If an employee, former emloyee,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002035">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002035"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “employee,”.</note> or applicant for employment is the prevailing party in an appeal from the Merit Systems Protection Board, the agency involved shall be liable to the employee, former employee, or applicant for reasonable attorney’s fees and any other reasonable costs incurred, regardless of the basis of the decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3314-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any corrective action ordered under this section to correct a prohibited personnel practice may include fees, costs, or damages reasonably incurred due to an agency investigation of the employee, if such investigation was commenced, expanded, or extended in retaliation for the disclosure or protected activity that formed the basis of the corrective action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3315-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3316-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An employee, former employee, or applicant for employment adversely affected or aggrieved by a final order or decision of the Board under this section may obtain judicial review of the order or decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3317-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A petition for review under this subsection shall be filed with such court, and within such time, as provided for under section 7703(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3318-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Subsections (a) through (h) shall apply in any proceeding brought under section 7513(d) if, or to the extent that, a prohibited personnel practice as defined in section 2302(b)(8) or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) is alleged.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec3319-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> In determining the appealability of any case involving an allegation made by an individual under the provisions of this chapter, neither the status of an individual under any retirement system established under a Federal statute nor any election made by such individual under any such system may be taken into account.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7ec331a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s1221/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> If the Board grants a stay under subsection (c) and the employee who is the subject of the action is in probationary status, the head of the agency employing the employee shall give priority to a request for a transfer submitted by the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb7ec331b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/12/s3/a/13">Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/29">103 Stat. 29</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/424">Pub. L. 103–424</ref>, §§ 4, 8(b), <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4363">108 Stat. 4363</ref>, 4365; <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/tI">Pub. L. 112–199, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b)(1)(A), (2)(A), 104(c)(2), 107(b), 114(b), <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1465">126 Stat. 1465</ref>, 1468, 1469, 1472; <ref href="/us/pl/115/73/tI/s102/b">Pub. L. 115–73, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-10-26">Oct. 26, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1236">131 Stat. 1236</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tX/s1097/c/3/B">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1097(c)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1619">131 Stat. 1619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb7ec331c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb7ec331d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb7ec331e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Pub. L. 115–91</ref> added subsec. (k) and struck out former subsec. (k) which read as follows: “If the Merit Systems Protection Board grants a stay to an employee in probationary status under subsection (c), the head of the agency employing the employee shall give priority to a request for a transfer submitted by the employee.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/73">Pub. L. 115–73</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/s101/b/1/A">Pub. L. 112–199, § 101(b)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D)” after “section 2302(b)(8)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/s101/b/1/A">Pub. L. 112–199, § 101(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(A), inserted “or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D)” after “section 2302(b)(8)” in two places and inserted “or protected activity” after “disclosure” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/s114/b">Pub. L. 112–199, § 114(b)</ref>, inserted “, after a finding that a protected disclosure was a contributing factor,” after “ordered if”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/s107/b">Pub. L. 112–199, § 107(b)</ref>, substituted “any other reasonable and foreseeable consequential damages, and compensatory damages (including interest, reasonable expert witness fees, and costs).” for “and any other reasonable and foreseeable consequential changes.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/s104/c/2">Pub. L. 112–199, § 104(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/s101/b/1/A">Pub. L. 112–199, § 101(b)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “or section 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D)” after “section 2302(b)(8)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s4/a">Pub. L. 103–424, § 4(a)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “At the request of an employee, former employee, or applicant for employment seeking corrective action under subsection (a), the Board may issue a subpoena for the attendance and testimony of any person or the production of documentary or other evidence from any person if the Board finds that such subpoena is necessary for the development of relevant evidence.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s4/b">Pub. L. 103–424, § 4(b)</ref>, which directed the amendment of section 1221(e)(1), without specifying the Code title to be amended, by inserting at end “The employee may demonstrate that the disclosure was a contributing factor in the personnel action through circumstantial evidence, such as evidence that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the official taking the personnel action knew of the disclosure; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the personnel action occurred within a period of time such that a reasonable person could conclude that the disclosure was a contributing factor in the personnel action.”, was executed to subsec. (e)(1) of this section to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s4/c">Pub. L. 103–424, § 4(c)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s8/b">Pub. L. 103–424, § 8(b)</ref>, added par. (1) and redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as (2) and (3), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb7ec331f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb7ec3320-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/199">Pub. L. 112–199</ref> effective 30 days after <date date="2012-11-27">Nov. 27, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/199/s202">section 202 of Pub. L. 112–199</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1204">section 1204 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb7ec3321-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter effective 90 days following <date date="1989-04-10">Apr. 10, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/12/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 101–12</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1989 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1201">section 1201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
