<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb78a8b65-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322"><num value="322">§ 322.</num><heading> Federal Government service delivery</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb78a8b66-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002007">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002007"><num>1</num> So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted.</note> <inline class="small-caps">Federal Government Service Delivery Lead</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director shall designate or appoint a senior official as the Federal Government Service Delivery Lead within the Office of Management and Budget whose responsibility is to coordinate governmentwide efforts to improve Government service delivery by agencies. The individual shall have the following duties and authorities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b67-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Facilitate and coordinate governmentwide efforts to improve Government service delivery provided by agencies, particularly with respect to high impact service providers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b68-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b69-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Serve as the lead, governmentwide official responsible for supporting Government service delivery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b6a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Advise the Director concerning the improvement of Government service delivery provided by agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b6b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> In consultation with each lead agency service delivery official and any other agency stakeholder as appropriate, develop and oversee the implementation of governmentwide Government service delivery standards, policies, and guidelines for services and programs provided by agencies, including standards, policies, and guidelines to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb78a8b6c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> understand the needs of an individual, business, or organization interacting with an agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb78a8b6d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> solicit and consider voluntary feedback on the Government service delivery by the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb78a8b6e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> assess Government service delivery processes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb78a8b6f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> consider the factors of ease, efficiency, transparency, accessibility, fairness, burden (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s3502">section 3502 of title 44</ref>), and duration, including wait and processing times, with respect to Government service delivery; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb78a8b70-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> encourage the adoption of commercial products and services in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s3307">section 3307 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b71-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Collect and report qualitative and quantitative information or data on Government service delivery through existing reporting mechanisms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b72-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Evaluate the quality of Government service delivery, including through the establishment of performance metrics developed using the standards, policies, and guidelines developed pursuant to paragraph (5) and the information or data collected and reported pursuant to paragraph (6).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b73-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Engage with stakeholders to identify leading practices in service design and delivery that would improve Government service delivery across and within agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b74-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Ensure agency service delivery initiatives, including those related to the 21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3501">15 U.S.C. 3501</ref> note; <ref href="/us/pl/115/336">Public Law 115–336</ref>), are identified in agency congressional budget justifications.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b75-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Coordinate with Office of Management and Budget stakeholders and other agency stakeholders on Government service delivery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb78a8b76-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s322/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> In collaboration with relevant agency officials as appropriate, and in coordination with relevant Office of Management and Budget stakeholders, ensure that websites of agencies, including those associated with high impact service providers, are consistent with the objectives of this subchapter, the 21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act, and any other applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb78a8b77-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/118/231/s2/a">Pub. L. 118–231, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2830">138 Stat. 2830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
