<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb81bf5d4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372"><num value="3372">§ 3372.</num><heading> General provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81bf5d5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> On request from or with the concurrence of a State or local government, and with the consent of the employee concerned, the head of a Federal agency may arrange for the assignment of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5d6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an employee of his agency, other than a noncareer appointee, limited term appointee, or limited emergency appointee (as such terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3132/a">section 3132(a) of this title</ref>) in the Senior Executive Service and an employee in a position which has been excepted from the competitive service by reason of its confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character, to a State or local government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5d7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an employee of a State or local government to his agency;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for work of mutual concern to his agency and the State or local government that he determines will be beneficial to both. The period of an assignment under this subchapter may not exceed two years. However, the head of a Federal agency may extend the period of assignment for not more than two additional years. In the case of assignments made to Indian tribes or tribal organizations as defined in section 3371(2)(C) of this subchapter, the head of an executive agency may extend the period of assignment for any period of time where it is determined that this will continue to benefit both the executive agency and the Indian tribe or tribal organization. If the assigned employee fails to complete the period of assignment and there is another employee willing and available to do so, the Secretary may assign the employee to complete the period of assignment and may execute an agreement with the tribal organization with respect to the replacement employee. That agreement may provide for a different period of assignment as may be agreed to by the Secretary and the tribal organization.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81bf5d8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> This subchapter is authority for and applies to the assignment of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5d9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an employee of a Federal agency to an institution of higher education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5da-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an employee of an institution of higher education to a Federal agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5db-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an employee of a Federal agency to any other organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5dc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an employee of an other organization to a Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81bf5dd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81bf5de-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An employee of a Federal agency may be assigned under this subchapter only if the employee agrees, as a condition of accepting an assignment under this subchapter, to serve in the civil service upon the completion of the assignment for a period equal to the length of the assignment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81bf5df-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each agreement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall provide that in the event the employee fails to carry out the agreement (except for good and sufficient reason, as determined by the head of the Federal agency from which assigned) the employee shall be liable to the United States for payment of all expenses (excluding salary) of the assignment. The amount shall be treated as a debt due the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81bf5e0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Where the employee is assigned to a tribal organization, the employee shall be eligible for promotions, periodic step-increases, and additional step-increases, as defined in chapter 53 of this title, on the same basis as other Federal employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81bf5e1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3376">section 3376 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5e2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an assignment of an employee of a Federal agency to an other organization or an institution of higher education, and an employee so assigned, shall be treated in the same way as an assignment of an employee of a Federal agency to a State or local government, and an employee so assigned, is treated under the provisions of this subchapter governing an assignment of an employee of a Federal agency to a State or local government, except that the rate of pay of an employee assigned to a federally funded research and development center may not exceed the rate of pay that such employee would be paid for continued service in the position in the Federal agency from which assigned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb81bf5e3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3372/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an assignment of an employee of an other organization or an institution of higher education to a Federal agency, and an employee so assigned, shall be treated in the same way as an assignment of an employee of a State or local government to a Federal agency, and an employee so assigned, is treated under the provisions of this subchapter governing an assignment of an employee of a State or local government to a Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb81bf5e4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/91/648/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 91–648, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1921">84 Stat. 1921</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/tI/s104/k">Pub. L. 93–638, title I, § 104(k)</ref>, (<i>l</i>), as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/472/tII/s203/f">Pub. L. 100–472, title II, § 203(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-05">Oct. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2290">102 Stat. 2290</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tVI/s603/b">Pub. L. 95–454, title VI, § 603(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1190">92 Stat. 1190</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/146/tII">Pub. L. 98–146, title II</ref>, <date date="1983-11-04">Nov. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/946">97 Stat. 946</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/89/s3/b/1/A">Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/981">107 Stat. 981</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tX/s1068/b">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1068(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2852">108 Stat. 2852</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb81bf5e5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb81bf5e6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb81bf5e7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/89">Pub. L. 103–89</ref> substituted “and additional step-increases, as defined in chapter 53” for “additional step-increases, merit pay, and cash awards, as defined in chapters 53 and 54”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsecs. (a), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/472">Pub. L. 100–472</ref> added <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s104/k">Pub. L. 93–638, § 104(k)</ref>, (<i>l</i>). See 1975 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/146">Pub. L. 98–146</ref> inserted sentence providing that, in the case of assignments made to Indian tribes or tribal organizations as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3371/2/C">section 3371(2)(C) of this title</ref>, the head of an executive agency may extend the period of assignment for any period of time where it is determined that this will continue to benefit both the executive agency and the Indian tribe or tribal organization.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s603/b">Pub. L. 95–454, § 603(b)</ref>, (c)(1), substituted “a Federal” for “an executive” wherever appearing, and in cl. (1) inserted provisions relating to a noncareer appointee, limited term appointee, or limited emergency appointee, and an employee excepted from the competitive service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s603/b">Pub. L. 95–454, § 603(b)</ref>, (c)(2)–(4), in cls. (1) and (2) substituted “a Federal” for “an executive”, and added cls. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s603/c/5">Pub. L. 95–454, § 603(c)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s104/k">Pub. L. 93–638, § 104(k)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/100/472">Pub. L. 100–472</ref>, inserted at end “If the assigned employee fails to complete the period of assignment and there is another employee willing and available to do so, the Secretary may assign the employee to complete the period of assignment and may execute an agreement with the tribal organization with respect to the replacement employee. That agreement may provide for a different period of assignment as may be agreed to by the Secretary and the tribal organization.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s104">Pub. L. 93–638, § 104</ref>(<i>l</i>), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/100/472">Pub. L. 100–472</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb81bf5e8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb81bf5e9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/89/s3/c">Pub. L. 103–89, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/983">107 Stat. 983</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/89/s3/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 4501, 4502, 5302, 5332, 5334 to 5336, 5361 to 5363, 5948, and 8473 of this title, sections 1602, 1732, and 1733 of Title 10, Armed Forces, and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s731">section 731 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, repealing sections 4302a and 5401 to 5410 of this title, and amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5304">section 5304 of this title</ref>] shall take effect as of <date date="1993-11-01">November 1, 1993</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb81bf5ea-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb81bf5eb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective sixty days after <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/648/s404">section 404 of Pub. L. 91–648</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3371">section 3371 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
