<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb823226a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s3584"><num value="3584">§ 3584.</num><heading> Regulations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may prescribe regulations necessary to carry out this subchapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3343">section 3343 of this title</ref> and to protect and assure the retirement, insurance, leave, and reemployment rights and such other similar civil service employment rights as he finds appropriate. The regulations may provide for the exclusion of employees from the application of this subchapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3343">section 3343 of this title</ref> on the basis of the nature and type of employment including excepted appointments of a confidential or policy-determining character, or conditions pertaining to the employment including short-term appointments, seasonal or intermittent employment, and part-time employment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb823226b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/431">80 Stat. 431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb823226c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb823226d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb823226e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Derivation</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>U.S. Code</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised Statutes and</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Statutes at Large</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> </html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s2334">5 U.S.C. 2334</html:a>.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 28, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/795/s5">Pub. L. 85–795, § 5</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/72/961">72 Stat. 961</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “civil service employment rights” are substituted for “Federal employment rights”. The word “including” is substituted for “such as, but not limited to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb823226f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb8232270-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 10804</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10804, <date date="1959-02-12">Feb. 12, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 1147, which delegated to the United States Civil Service Commission the authority vested in the President by section 5 of the Federal Employees International Organization Service Act (<ref href="/us/stat/72/961">72 Stat. 961</ref>) [now this section], was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 11552, <date date="1970-08-24">Aug. 24, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 13569, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb8232271-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11552. Providing for Details and Transfers of Federal Employees to International Organizations</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11552, <date date="1970-08-24">Aug. 24, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 13569, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12107, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1055, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3584">section 3584 of title 5</ref> [this section], United States Code, and as President of the United States, it is ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Leadership and coordination</i>. The Secretary of State shall provide leadership and coordination for the effort of the Federal Government to increase and improve its participation in international organizations through transfers and details of well-qualified Federal employees, and shall develop policies, procedures, and programs consistent with this order to advance and encourage such participation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Federal agency cooperation</i>. Each agency in the executive branch of the Federal Government shall to the maximum extent feasible and with due regard to its manpower requirements assist and encourage details and transfers of employees to international organizations by observing the following policies and procedures:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Vacancies in international organizations shall be brought to the notice of well-qualified agency employees whose abilities and levels of responsibility in the Federal service are commensurate with those required to fill such vacancies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Subject to prior approval of his agency, no leave shall be charged an employee who is absent for a maximum of three days for interview for a proposed detail or transfer at the formal request of an international organization of a Federal official; an agency may approve official travel for necessary travel within the United States in connection with such an interview.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) An agency, upon request of an appropriate authority, shall provide international organizations with detailed assessments of the technical or professional qualifications of individual employees being formally considered for details and transfers to specific positions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) Upon return of an employee to his agency, the agency shall give due consideration to the employee’s overall qualifications, including those which may have been acquired during his service with the international organization, in determining the position and grade in which he is reemployed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Delegations</i>. (a) Except as otherwise provided in this order, there is hereby delegated to the Office of Personnel Management the authority vested in the President by sections 3582(b) and 3584 of title 5, United States Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The following are hereby delegated to the Secretary of State:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) The authority vested in the President by sections 3343 and 3581 of title 5, United States Code, to determine whether it is in the national interest to extend a detail or transfer of an employee beyond five years.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) The authority vested in the President by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3582/b">section 3582(b) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, to define and specify “pay, allowances, post differential, and other monetary benefits” to be paid by the agency upon reemployment, disability, or death.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Revocation</i>. Executive Order No. 10804 of <date date="1959-02-12">February 12, 1959</date>, is hereby revoked.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
