<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb79400bf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408"><num value="408">§ 408.</num><heading> Additional provisions with respect to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400c0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inspector General</inline>.—</heading><content>A member of the Armed Forces, active or reserve, shall not be appointed Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400c1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary of Defense.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400c2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the last two sentences of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s403/a">section 403(a) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, which require access to information concerning—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400c3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> sensitive operational plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400c4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> intelligence matters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400c5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> counterintelligence matters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400c6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> ongoing criminal investigations by other administrative units of the Department of Defense related to national security; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400c7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> other matters the disclosure of which would constitute a serious threat to national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400c8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to prohibit audit or investigation</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to the information described in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may prohibit the Inspector General from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation, from accessing information described in paragraph (1), or from issuing any subpoena, after the Inspector General has decided to initiate, carry out, or complete such audit or investigation, access such information, or to issue such subpoena, if the Secretary determines that such prohibition is necessary to preserve the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400c9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement concerning exercise of power</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary of Defense exercises any power under paragraph (1) or (2), the Inspector General shall submit a statement concerning that exercise of power within 30 days to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400ca-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement of reasons for exercise of power</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall, within 30 days after submission of a statement under paragraph (3), transmit a statement of the reasons for the exercise of power under paragraph (1) or (2) to the congressional committees specified in paragraph (3) and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400cb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Duties and Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In addition to the other duties and responsibilities specified in this chapter, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400cc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be the principal adviser to the Secretary of Defense for matters relating to the prevention and detection of fraud, waste, and abuse in the programs and operations of the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400cd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> initiate, conduct, and supervise such audits and investigations in the Department of Defense (including the military departments) as the Inspector General considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400ce-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide policy direction for audits and investigations relating to fraud, waste, and abuse and program effectiveness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400cf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> investigate fraud, waste, and abuse uncovered as a result of other contract and internal audits, as the Inspector General considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400d0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> develop policy, monitor and evaluate program performance, and provide guidance with respect to all Department activities relating to criminal investigation programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400d1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> monitor and evaluate the adherence of Department auditors to internal audit, contract audit, and internal review principles, policies, and procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400d2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> develop policy, evaluate program performance, and monitor actions taken by all components of the Department in response to contract audits, internal audits, internal review reports, and audits conducted by the Comptroller General of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400d3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> request assistance as needed from other audit, inspection, and investigative units of the Department of Defense (including military departments);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400d4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> give particular regard to the activities of the internal audit, inspection, and investigative units of the military departments with a view toward avoiding duplication and ensuring effective coordination and cooperation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400d5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> conduct, or approve arrangements for the conduct of, external peer reviews of Department of Defense audit agencies in accordance with, and in such frequency as provided by, Government auditing standards as established by the Comptroller General of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400d6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting Violations of Chapter</inline> 47 <inline class="small-caps">of Title</inline> 10.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s404/d">section 404(d) of this title</ref>, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall expeditiously report suspected or alleged violations of chapter 47 of title 10 (Uniform Code of Military Justice), to the Secretary of the military department concerned or the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400d7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Member of Armed Forces Deemed To Be Employee</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s407">section 407 of this title</ref>, a member of the Armed Forces shall be deemed to be an employee of the Department of Defense, except that, when the Coast Guard operates as a service of another department or agency of the Federal Government, a member of the Coast Guard shall be deemed to be an employee of that department or agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400d8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400d9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports transmitted to congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each semiannual report prepared by the Inspector General of the Department of Defense under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s405/b">section 405(b) of this title</ref> shall be transmitted by the Secretary of Defense to the Committees on Armed Services and on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Armed Services and on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of Congress. Each report shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400da-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> information concerning the numbers and types of contract audits conducted by the Department during the reporting period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400db-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information concerning any Department of Defense audit agency that, during the reporting period, has either received a failed opinion from an external peer review or is overdue for an external peer review required to be conducted in accordance with subsection (c)(10).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400dc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional reports transmitted to congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><content>Any report required to be transmitted by the Secretary of Defense to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s405/e">section 405(e) of this title</ref> shall also be transmitted, within the 7-day period specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s405/e">section 405(e) of this title</ref>, to the congressional committees specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400dd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-Applicability of Section</inline> 1385 <inline class="small-caps">of Title</inline> 18.—</heading><content>The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1385">section 1385 of title 18</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002009">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002009"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> shall not apply to audits and investigations conducted by, under the direction of, or at the request of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400de-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Counsel to Inspector General of Department of Defense.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400df-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>There is a General Counsel to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, who shall be appointed by the Inspector General of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400e0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties and functions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400e1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s140/b">section 140(b) of title 10</ref>, the General Counsel is the chief legal officer of the Office of the Inspector General.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400e2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Inspector General is the exclusive legal client of the General Counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400e3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The General Counsel shall perform such functions as the Inspector General may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb79400e4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The General Counsel shall serve at the discretion of the Inspector General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400e5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Office of general counsel</inline>.—</heading><content>There is an Office of the General Counsel to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense. The Inspector General may appoint to the Office to serve as staff of the General Counsel such legal counsel as the Inspector General considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb79400e6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Require Attendance and Testimony of Witnesses.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400e7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subpoena</inline>.—</heading><content>The Inspector General of the Department of Defense is authorized to require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses as necessary in the performance of functions assigned to the Inspector General by this chapter, except that the Inspector General shall use procedures other than subpoenas to obtain attendance and testimony from Federal employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400e8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement</inline>.—</heading><content>A subpoena issued under this subsection, in the case of contumacy or refusal to obey, shall be enforceable by order of any appropriate United States district court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb79400e9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s408/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><content>The Inspector General shall notify the Attorney General 7 days before issuing any subpoena under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb79400ea-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s3/b">Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4224">136 Stat. 4224</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb79400eb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="idb79400ec-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendments Not Shown in Text</heading><p>This section was derived from section 8 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/452">Pub. L. 95–452</ref>, which was set out in the former Appendix to this title, and as it existed as of <date date="2021-10-19">Oct. 19, 2021</date>. <ref href="/us/pl/95/452/s8">Section 8 of Pub. L. 95–452</ref> was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLII/s5272/3">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LII, § 5272(3)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3239">136 Stat. 3239</ref>, prior to being repealed and reenacted as this section by <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref>, §§ 3(b), 7, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4224">136 Stat. 4224</ref>, 4361. For applicability of those amendments to this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s5/b">section 5(b) of Pub. L. 117–286</ref>, set out in a Transitional and Savings Provisions note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/95/452/s8">Section 8 of Pub. L. 95–452</ref> was amended as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(1) in subsection (b)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(A) in paragraph (3), by striking “the Committees on Armed Services and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight of the House of Representatives and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress” and inserting “the appropriate congressional committees, including the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(B) in paragraph (4), by striking “and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(2) in subsection (f)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(A) in paragraph (1), by striking “the Committees on Armed Services and on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Armed Services and on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and to other appropriate committees or subcommittees of Congress” and inserting “the appropriate congressional committees, including the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(B) in paragraph (2), by striking “committees or subcommittees of the Congress” and inserting “congressional committees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">The text directed to be stricken in subsections (b)(3) and (f)(1) did not appear exactly as quoted in the text enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref>. See Historical and Revision notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For definition of “appropriate congressional committees” as seen in the above amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, see Amendments Not Shown in Text note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb79400ed-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90; " id="idb79400ee-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:68pt ; max-width:68pt;" />
<html:col style="width:94pt ; max-width:94pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:68.0pt ; max-width:68.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:94.0pt ; max-width:94.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>408</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 U.S.C. App. (IGA § 8)</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/pl/95/452/s8">Pub. L. 95–452, § 8</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Oct. 12, 1978</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/92/1105">92 Stat. 1105</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/97/252/tXI/s1117/b">Pub. L. 97–252, title XI, § 1117(b)</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Sept. 8, 1982</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/96/751">96 Stat. 751</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/100/504/tI/s110/b">Pub. L. 100–504, title I, § 110(b)</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Oct. 18, 1988</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/102/2529">102 Stat. 2529</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1502/f/6">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(f)(6)</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Feb. 10, 1996</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/110/510">110 Stat. 510</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/17">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(17)</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Oct. 5, 1999</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/113/775">113 Stat. 775</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</html:a>, [div. A], title IX, § 907, <html:span class="date">Oct. 14, 2008</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/122/4569">122 Stat. 4569</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tX/s1042">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1042</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Oct. 28, 2009</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/123/2455">123 Stat. 2455</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXVI/s1614">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1614</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Jan. 2, 2013</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/126/2066">126 Stat. 2066</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/114/317/s6/1">Pub. L. 114–317, § 6(1)</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Dec. 16, 2016</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/130/1604">130 Stat. 1604</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b)(3), the words “Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate” are substituted for “[Committee on] Governmental Affairs of the Senate” on authority of Senate Resolution No. 445, 108th Congress, <date date="2004-10-09">October 9, 2004</date> (effective <date date="2005-01-04">January 4, 2005</date>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b)(3), the words “Committee on Oversight and Reform” are substituted for “Committee on Government Reform and Oversight” on authority of House Resolution No. 5 (106th Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">January 6, 1999</date>), House Resolution No. 6 (110th Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">January 5, 2007</date>), and rule X(1)(n) of the Rules of the House of Representatives, adopted by House Resolution No. 6 (116th Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">January 9, 2019</date>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c)(9), the word “ensuring” is substituted for “insuring” for clarity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (f)(1) (matter before subparagraph (A)), the words “[Committee on] Oversight and Reform” are substituted for “[Committee on] Oversight and Government Reform” on authority of rule X(1)(n) of the Rules of the House of Representatives, adopted by House Resolution No. 6 (116th Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">January 9, 2019</date>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb79400ef-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb79400f0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
