<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb859e9c1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347"><num value="5347">§ 5347.</num><heading> Federal Prevailing Rate Advisory Committee</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9c2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> There is established a Federal Prevailing Rate Advisory Committee composed of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb859e9c3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Chairman, who shall not hold any other office or position in the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia, and who shall be appointed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management for a 4-year term;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb859e9c4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> one member from the Office of the Secretary of Defense, designated by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb859e9c5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> two members from the military departments, designated by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb859e9c6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> one member, designated by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management from time to time from an agency (other than the Department of Defense, a military department, and the Office of Personnel Management);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb859e9c7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> an employee of the Office of Personnel Management, designated by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb859e9c8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> five members, designated by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, from among the employee organizations representing, under exclusive recognition of the Government of the United States, the largest numbers of prevailing rate employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9c9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In designating members from among employee organizations under subsection (a)(6) of this section, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall designate, as nearly as practicable, a number of members from a particular employee organization in the same proportion to the total number of employee representatives appointed to the Committee under subsection (a)(6) of this section as the number of prevailing rate employees represented by such organization is to the total number of prevailing rate employees. However, there shall not be more than two members from any one employee organization nor more than four members from a single council, federation, alliance, association, or affiliation of employee organizations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9ca-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Every 2 years the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall review employee organization representation to determine adequate or proportional representation under the guidelines of subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9cb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The members from the employee organizations serve at the pleasure of the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9cc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The Committee shall study the prevailing rate system and other matters pertinent to the establishment of prevailing rates under this subchapter and, from time to time, advise the Office of Personnel Management thereon. Conclusions and recommendations of the Committee shall be formulated by majority vote. The Chairman of the Committee may vote only to break a tie vote of the Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9cd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chairman. However, a special meeting shall be called by the Chairman if 5 members make a written request to the Chairman to call a special meeting to consider matters within the purview of the Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9ce-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9cf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), members of the Committee described in paragraphs (2)–(5) of subsection (a) of this section serve without additional pay. Members who represent employee organizations are not entitled to pay from the Government of the United States for services rendered to the Committee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9d0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The position of Chairman shall be considered to be a Senior Executive Service position within the meaning of section 3132(a), and shall be subject to all provisions of this title relating to Senior Executive Service positions, including section 5383.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859e9d1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5347/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The Office of Personnel Management shall provide such clerical and professional personnel as the Chairman of the Committee considers appropriate and necessary to carry out its functions under this subchapter. Such personnel shall be responsible to the Chairman of the Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb859e9d2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/92/392/s1/a">Pub. L. 92–392, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-19">Aug. 19, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/571">86 Stat. 571</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tIX/s906/a/1">Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1224">92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/54/s2/a/15">Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/382">93 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/30">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(30)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1350">106 Stat. 1350</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tII/s2181/d">Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2181(d)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/732">109 Stat. 732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb859e9d3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb859e9d4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb859e9d5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out at end “The Committee shall make an annual report to the Office and the President for transmittal to Congress, including recommendations and other matters considered appropriate. Any member of the Committee may include in the annual report recommendations and other matters he considers appropriate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378">Pub. L. 102–378</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (2), members” for “Members”, struck out second sentence which read as follows: “The Chairman is entitled to a rate of pay equal to the maximum rate currently paid, from time to time, under the General Schedule.”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/54">Pub. L. 96–54</ref> substituted “Office” for “Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (a) to (e), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> substituted “Director of the Office of Personnel Management” for “Chairman of the Civil Service Commission” and “Office of Personnel Management” for “Civil Service Commission”, wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb859e9d6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb859e9d7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/54">Pub. L. 96–54</ref> effective <date date="1979-07-12">July 12, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/54/s2/b">section 2(b) of Pub. L. 96–54</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s305">section 305 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb859e9d8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb859e9d9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on first day of first applicable pay period beginning on or after 90th day after <date date="1972-08-19">Aug. 19, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/392/s15/a">section 15(a) of Pub. L. 92–392</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5341">section 5341 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
