<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8611496-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5382"><num value="5382">§ 5382.</num><heading> Establishment of rates of pay for the Senior Executive Service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8611497-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5382/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Subject to regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, there shall be established a range of rates of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service, and each senior executive shall be paid at one of the rates within the range, based on individual performance, contribution to the agency’s performance, or both, as determined under a rigorous performance management system. The lowest rate of the range shall not be less than the minimum rate of basic pay payable under section 5376, and the highest rate, for any position under this system or an equivalent system as determined by the President’s Pay Agent designated under section 5304(d), shall not exceed the rate for level III of the Executive Schedule. The payment of the rates shall not be subject to the pay limitation of section 5306(e) or 5373.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8611498-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5382/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a), the applicable maximum shall be level II of the Executive Schedule for any agency that is certified under section 5307 as having a performance appraisal system which, as designed and applied, makes meaningful distinctions based on relative performance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8611499-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5382/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> No employee may suffer a reduction in pay by reason of transfer from an agency with an applicable maximum rate of pay prescribed under subsection (b) to an agency with an applicable maximum rate of pay prescribed under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb861149a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tIV/s407/a">Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1171">92 Stat. 1171</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/509/tV/s529/tI/s101/b/4/B">Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 101(b)(4)(B), (6)(A), (9)(I)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1427">104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1439, 1440, 1442; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tXI/s1125/a/2">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1125(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1638">117 Stat. 1638</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb861149b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb861149c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb861149d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Level III of the Executive Schedule, referred to in subsec. (a), is set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5314">section 5314 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Level II of the Executive Schedule, referred to in subsec. (b), is set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb861149e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—<ref href="/us/pl/108/136">Pub. L. 108–136</ref> substituted “Establishment of rates of pay for the Senior Executive Service” for “Establishment and adjustment of rates of pay for the Senior Executive Service” in section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) There shall be 5 or more rates of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service, and each senior executive shall be paid at one of the rates. The rates of basic pay shall be initially established and thereafter adjusted by the President subject to subsection (b) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) In setting rates of basic pay, the lowest rate for the Senior Executive Service shall not be less than the minimum rate of basic pay payable under section 5376 and the highest rate shall not exceed the rate for level IV of the Executive Schedule. The payment of the rates shall not be subject to the pay limitation of section 5306(e) or 5373 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) Subject to subsection (b) of this section, effective at the beginning of the first applicable pay period commencing on or after the first day of the month in which an adjustment takes effect under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5303">section 5303 of this title</ref> in the rates of pay under the General Schedule, each rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service shall be adjusted by an amount determined by the President to be appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(d) The rates of basic pay that are established and adjusted under this section shall be printed in the Federal Register and shall supersede any prior rates of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/509/s529/tI/s101/b/6/A">Pub. L. 101–509, § 529 [title I, § 101(b)(6)(A), (9)(I)]</ref>, substituted “under section 5376” for “for GS–16 of the General Schedule” and “5306(e)” for “5308”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/509/s529/tI/s101/b/4/B">Pub. L. 101–509, § 529 [title I, § 101(b)(4)(B)]</ref>, substituted “5303” for “5305” and struck out at end “The adjusted rates of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service shall be included in the report transmitted to the Congress by the President under section 5305(a)(3) or (c)(1) of this title.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb861149f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb86114a0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136">Pub. L. 108–136</ref> effective on first day of first pay period beginning on or after <date date="2004-01-01">Jan. 1, 2004</date>, but not to result in reduction in rate of basic pay for any senior executive during first year after effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s1125/c">section 1125(c) of Pub. L. 108–136</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5304">section 5304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb86114a1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref> effective on such date as the President shall determine, but not earlier than 90 days, and not later than 180 days, after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see section 529 [title III, § 305] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb86114a2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 9 months after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, and congressional review of provisions of sections 401 through 412 of <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, see section 415(a)(1), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3131">section 3131 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb86114a3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pay Increases</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For adjustment of rates of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service under this section, see the executive order detailing the adjustment of certain rates of pay set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For miscellaneous provisions dealing with adjustments of pay and limitations on use of funds to pay salaries in prior years, see notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5318">section 5318 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb86114a4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb86114a5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 12592</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12592, <date date="1987-04-10">Apr. 10, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 13417, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12609, <date date="1987-09-23">Sept. 23, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 36211, which related to the establishment, functions, administration, and termination of the President’s Commission on Compensation of Career Federal Executives, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12692, <date date="1989-09-29">Sept. 29, 1989</date>, 54 F.R. 40627, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
