<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb865d044-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a"><num value="5520a">§ 5520a.</num><heading> Garnishment of pay</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d045-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d046-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> “agency” means each agency of the Federal Government, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d047-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an executive agency, except for the Government Accountability Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d048-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d049-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any agency of the judicial branch of the Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d04a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any agency of the legislative branch of the Government, including the Government Accountability Office, each office of a Member of Congress, a committee of the Congress, or other office of the Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d04b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “employee” means an employee of an agency (including a Member of Congress as defined under section 2106);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d04c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> “legal process” means any writ, order, summons, or other similar process in the nature of garnishment, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d04d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is issued by a court of competent jurisdiction within any State, territory, or possession of the United States, or an authorized official pursuant to an order of such a court or pursuant to State or local law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d04e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> orders the employing agency of such employee to withhold an amount from the pay of such employee, and make a payment of such withholding to another person, for a specifically described satisfaction of a legal debt of the employee, or recovery of attorney’s fees, interest, or court costs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d04f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> “pay” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d050-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> basic pay, premium pay paid under subchapter V, any payment received under subchapter VI, VII, or VIII, severance and back pay paid under subchapter IX, sick pay, incentive pay, and any other compensation paid or payable for personal services, whether such compensation is denominated as wages, salary, commission, bonus pay or otherwise; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d051-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not include awards for making suggestions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d052-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of this section and the provisions of section 303 of the Consumer Credit Protection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1673">15 U.S.C. 1673</ref>) pay from an agency to an employee is subject to legal process in the same manner and to the same extent as if the agency were a private person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d053-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d054-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Service of legal process to which an agency is subject under this section may be accomplished by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, or by personal service, upon—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d055-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the appropriate agent designated for receipt of such service of process pursuant to the regulations issued under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d056-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the head of such agency, if no agent has been so designated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d057-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such legal process shall be accompanied by sufficient information to permit prompt identification of the employee and the payments involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d058-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Whenever any person, who is designated by law or regulation to accept service of process to which an agency is subject under this section, is effectively served with any such process or with interrogatories, such person shall respond thereto within thirty days (or within such longer period as may be prescribed by applicable State law) after the date effective service thereof is made, and shall, as soon as possible but not later than fifteen days after the date effective service is made, send written notice that such process has been so served (together with a copy thereof) to the affected employee at his or her duty station or last-known home address.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d059-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> No employee whose duties include responding to interrogatories pursuant to requirements imposed by this section shall be subject to any disciplinary action or civil or criminal liability or penalty for, or on account of, any disclosure of information made by such employee in connection with the carrying out of any of such employee’s duties which pertain directly or indirectly to the answering of any such interrogatory.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d05a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Agencies affected by legal process under this section shall not be required to vary their normal pay and disbursement cycles in order to comply with any such legal process.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d05b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> Neither the United States, an agency, nor any disbursing officer shall be liable with respect to any payment made from payments due or payable to an employee pursuant to legal process regular on its face, provided such payment is made in accordance with this section and the regulations issued to carry out this section. In determining the amount of any payment due from, or payable by, an agency to an employee, there shall be excluded those amounts which would be excluded under section 462(g) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s662/g">42 U.S.C. 662(g)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d05c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d05d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), if an agency is served under this section with more than one legal process with respect to the same payments due or payable to an employee, then such payments shall be available, subject to section 303 of the Consumer Credit Protection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1673">15 U.S.C. 1673</ref>), to satisfy such processes in priority based on the time of service, with any such process being satisfied out of such amounts as remain after satisfaction of all such processes which have been previously served.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d05e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A legal process to which an agency is subject under section 459 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s659">42 U.S.C. 659</ref>) for the enforcement of the employee’s legal obligation to provide child support or make alimony payments, shall have priority over any legal process to which an agency is subject under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d05f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The provisions of this section shall not modify or supersede the provisions of section 459 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s659">42 U.S.C. 659</ref>) concerning legal process brought for the enforcement of an individual’s legal obligations to provide child support or make alimony payments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d060-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d061-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Regulations implementing the provisions of this section shall be promulgated—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d062-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> by the President or his designee for each executive agency, except with regard to employees of the United States Postal Service, the President or, at his discretion, the Postmaster General shall promulgate such regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d063-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> jointly by the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, or their designee, for the legislative branch of the Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d064-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/j/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> by the Chief Justice of the United States or his designee for the judicial branch of the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d065-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such regulations shall provide that an agency’s administrative costs in executing a garnishment action may be added to the garnishment, and that the agency may retain costs recovered as offsetting collections.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d066-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d067-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries of the Executive departments concerned shall promulgate regulations to carry out the purposes of this section with regard to members of the uniformed services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d068-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Such regulations shall include provisions for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d069-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the involuntary allotment of the pay of a member of the uniformed services for indebtedness owed a third party as determined by the final judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction, and as further determined by competent military or executive authority, as appropriate, to be in compliance with the procedural requirements of the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 App. U.S.C. 501 et seq.); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002104">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002104"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d06a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> consideration for the absence of a member of the uniformed service from an appearance in a judicial proceeding resulting from the exigencies of military duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d06b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretaries of the Executive departments concerned shall promulgate regulations under this subsection that are, as far as practicable, uniform for all of the uniformed services. The Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security with regard to the promulgation of such regulations that might affect members of the Coast Guard when the Coast Guard is operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb865d06c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/94/s9/a">Pub. L. 103–94, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1007">107 Stat. 1007</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tVI/s643">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VI, § 643</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/368">110 Stat. 368</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tIII/s362/b/2">Pub. L. 104–193, title III, § 362(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2246">110 Stat. 2246</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tXI/s1105">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1923">111 Stat. 1923</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/189/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 108–189, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2865">117 Stat. 2865</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/241/tIX/s902/a/3">Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 902(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/566">120 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/tVI/s604/f">Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3242">120 Stat. 3242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb865d06d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb865d06e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb865d06f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of this Act, referred to in subsec. (k)(1), probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/103/94">Pub. L. 103–94</ref>, which enacted this section and was approved <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Servicemembers Civil Relief Act, referred to in subsec. (k)(2)(A), is <ref href="/us/act/1940-10-17/ch888">act Oct. 17, 1940, ch. 888</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1178">54 Stat. 1178</ref>, which was classified to section 501 et seq. of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as chapter 50 (§ 3901 et seq.) of Title 50. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb865d070-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/435">Pub. L. 109–435</ref> substituted “Postal Regulatory Commission” for “Postal Rate Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/241">Pub. L. 109–241</ref> substituted “Secretary of Homeland Security” for “Secretary of Transportation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(1)(A), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/108/271">Pub. L. 108–271</ref> substituted “Government Accountability Office” for “General Accounting Office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (k)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/189">Pub. L. 108–189</ref> substituted “Servicemembers Civil Relief Act” for “Soldiers’ and Sailors’ Civil Relief Act of 1940”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s1105/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 1105(1)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Such regulations shall provide that an agency’s administrative costs incurred in executing legal process to which the agency is subject under this section shall be deducted from the amount withheld from the pay of the employee concerned pursuant to the legal process.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s1105/2">Pub. L. 105–85, § 1105(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “Regulations under this subsection may also provide that the administrative costs incurred in establishing and maintaining an involuntary allotment be deducted from the amount withheld from the pay of the member of the uniformed services concerned pursuant to such regulations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s1105/3">Pub. L. 105–85, § 1105(3)</ref>, struck out subsec. (<i>l</i>) which read as follows: “The amount of an agency’s administrative costs deducted under regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (j)(2) or (k)(3) shall be credited to the appropriation, fund, or account from which such administrative costs were paid.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (h)(2), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> substituted “section 459 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s659">42 U.S.C. 659</ref>)” for “sections 459, 461, and 462 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s659">42 U.S.C. 659</ref>, 661, and 662)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s643/a">Pub. L. 104–106, § 643(a)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Such regulations shall provide that an agency’s administrative costs in executing a garnishment action may be added to the garnishment, and that the agency may retain costs recovered as offsetting collections.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s643/b">Pub. L. 104–106, § 643(b)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s643/c">Pub. L. 104–106, § 643(c)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb865d071-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb865d072-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> effective six months after <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s362/d">section 362(d) of Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s659">section 659 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to effective date of title III of <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, see section 395(a)–(c) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s654">section 654 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb865d073-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 120 days after <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, and not to affect any proceedings with respect to which charges were filed on or before 120 days after <date date="1993-10-06">Oct. 6, 1993</date>, with orders to be issued in such proceedings and appeals taken therefrom as if <ref href="/us/pl/103/94">Pub. L. 103–94</ref> had not been enacted, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/94/s12">section 12 of Pub. L. 103–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7321">section 7321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb865d074-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb865d075-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review and Update of Regulations Governing Debt Collectors Interactions With Unit Commanders of Members of the Armed Forces</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVI/s634">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 634</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1431">131 Stat. 1431</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVI/s634">“Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall review and update Department of Defense Directive 1344.09 and any associated regulations to ensure that such regulations comply with Federal consumer protection laws with respect to the collection of debt.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb865d076-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Alternative Notice of Receipt of Legal Process for Garnishment of Federal Pay for Child Support and Alimony</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tX/s1061">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1061</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2128">112 Stat. 2128</ref>, authorized the Secretary of Defense to conduct a pilot program on alternative notice procedures for withholding or garnishment of pay for the payment of child support and alimony under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s659">section 659 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, required the Secretary to submit to Congress, not later than <date date="2001-01-01">Jan. 1, 2001</date>, a report describing the experience of the Department of Defense under the authority provided for the program, and provided for termination of pilot program on <date date="2001-09-30">Sept. 30, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb865d077-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb865d078-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12897. Garnishment of Federal Employees’ Pay</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12897, <date date="1994-02-03">Feb. 3, 1994</date>, 59 F.R. 5517, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5520a/j/1/A">section 5520a(j)(1)(A) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/103/94/s9">section 9 of Public Law 103–94</ref>, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. The Office of Personnel Management, in consultation with the Attorney General, is designated to promulgate regulations for the implementation of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5520a">section 5520a of title 5</ref>, United States Code, with respect to civilian employees and agencies in the executive branch, except as provided in section 2 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. The Postmaster General is designated to promulgate regulations for the implementation of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5520a">section 5520a of title 5</ref>, United States Code, with respect to employees of the United States Postal Service.</p>
<signature>
<name>William J. Clinton.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
