<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb865d024-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520"><num value="5520">§ 5520.</num><heading> Withholding of city or county income or employment taxes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d025-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> When a city or county ordinance—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d026-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provides for the collection of a tax by imposing on employers generally the duty of withholding sums from the pay of employees and making returns of the sums to a designated city or county officer, department, or instrumentality; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d027-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> imposes the duty to withhold generally on the payment of compensation earned within the jurisdiction of the city or county in the case of employees whose regular place of employment is within such jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary of the Treasury, under regulations prescribed by the President, shall enter into an agreement with the city or county within 120 days of a request for agreement by the proper city or county official. The agreement shall provide that the head of each agency of the United States shall comply with the requirements of the city or county ordinance in the case of any employee of the agency who is subject to the tax and (i) whose regular place of Federal employment is within the jurisdiction of the city or county with which the agreement is made or (ii) is a resident of such city or county. The agreement may not apply to pay for service as a member of the Armed Forces (other than service described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5517/d">section 5517(d) of this title</ref>). The agreement may not permit withholding of a city or county tax from the pay of an employee who is not a resident of, or whose regular place of Federal employment is not within, the State in which that city or county is located unless the employee consents to the withholding.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d028-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> This section does not give the consent of the United States to the application of an ordinance which imposes more burdensome requirements on the United States than on other employers or which subjects the United States or its employees to a penalty or liability because of this section. An agency of the United States may not accept pay from a city or county for services performed in withholding city or county income or employment taxes from the pay of employees of the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb865d029-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d02a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> “city” means any unit of general local government which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d02b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is classified as a municipality by the Bureau of the Census, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d02c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> is a town or township which, in the determination of the Secretary of the Treasury—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb865d02d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> possesses powers and performs functions comparable to those associated with municipalities,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb865d02e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is closely settled, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb865d02f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> contains within its boundaries no incorporated places, as defined by the Bureau of the Census,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">within the political boundaries of which 500 or more persons are regularly employed by all agencies of the Federal Government;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d030-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “county” means any unit of local general government which is classified as a county by the Bureau of the Census and within the political boundaries of which 500 or more persons are regularly employed by all agencies of the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d031-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “ordinance” means an ordinance, order, resolution, or similar instrument which is duly adopted and approved by a city or county in accordance with the constitution and statutes of the State in which it is located and which has the force of law within such city or county; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb865d032-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> “agency” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d033-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an Executive agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d034-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the judicial branch; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb865d035-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5520/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the United States Postal Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb865d036-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/93/340/s1/a">Pub. L. 93–340, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-07-10">July 10, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/294">88 Stat. 294</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/358/s1">Pub. L. 94–358, § 1</ref>, <date date="1976-07-12">July 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/910">90 Stat. 910</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/30/tIV/s408/a">Pub. L. 95–30, title IV, § 408(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-05-23">May 23, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/157">91 Stat. 157</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/365/s1">Pub. L. 95–365, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-09-15">Sept. 15, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/599">92 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tV/s505/2">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title V, § 505(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1086">101 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb865d037-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb865d038-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb865d039-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/180">Pub. L. 100–180</ref> inserted “(other than service described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5517/d">section 5517(d) of this title</ref>)” after “Armed Forces” in penultimate sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/365">Pub. L. 95–365</ref> designated existing provisions as cl. (i), inserted “, or whose regular place of Federal employment is not within,” after “not a resident of”, and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/30/s408/a/1">Pub. L. 95–30, § 408(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “or county” after “city” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/30/s408/a/2">Pub. L. 95–30, § 408(a)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “city or county” for “city” in introductory provisions preceding par. (1), in par. (2), and in provisions following par. (2), and, in par. (1), substituted “a designated city or county officer, department, or instrumentality” for “the city”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/30/s408/a/2">Pub. L. 95–30, § 408(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “city or county” for “city”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/30/s408/a/4">Pub. L. 95–30, § 408(a)(4)</ref>, (5), added pars. (2) and (3) and redesignated former par. (2) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/358">Pub. L. 94–358</ref> substituted provision defining a city, for purposes of this section, as any unit of general local government which is classified a municipality by the Bureau of the Census, or is a town or township which in the opinion of the Secretary of the Treasury possesses powers and performs functions comparable to those associated with municipalities, is closely settled, and contains within its boundaries no incorporated places, as defined by the Bureau of the Census, within the political boundaries of which five hundred or more persons are regularly employed by all agencies of the Federal Government, for provision defining a city, for purposes of this section, as a city which is duly incorporated under the laws of a State and within the political boundaries of which five hundred or more persons are regularly employed by all agencies of the Federal Government.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb865d03a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb865d03b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/365/s2">Pub. L. 95–365, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-09-15">Sept. 15, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/599">92 Stat. 599</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/365/s2">“The amendments made by the first section of this Act [amending this section] shall take effect on the 90th day after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-09-15">Sept. 15, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb865d03c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/30/tIV/s408/c">Pub. L. 95–30, title IV, § 408(c)</ref>, <date date="1977-05-23">May 23, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/157">91 Stat. 157</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/30/tIV/s408/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1977-05-23">May 23, 1977</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb865d03d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/358/s2">Pub. L. 94–358, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-07-12">July 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/910">90 Stat. 910</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/358/s2">“The amendment made by the first section of this Act [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1976-07-12">July 12, 1976</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb865d03e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/340/s3">Pub. L. 93–340, § 3</ref>, <date date="1974-07-10">July 10, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/295">88 Stat. 295</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/340/s3">“This section shall become effective on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1974-07-10">July 10, 1974</date>]. The provisions of the first section and section 2 of this Act [enacting this section and amending <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s410">section 410 of Title 39</ref>, Postal Service] shall become effective on the ninetieth day following the date of enactment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb865d03f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb865d040-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11833</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11833, <date date="1975-01-13">Jan. 13, 1975</date>, 40 F.R. 2673, which related to the withholding of city income or employment taxes by Federal agencies, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 11863, <date date="1975-06-12">June 12, 1975</date>, 40 F.R. 25413, formerly set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb865d041-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11863</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11863, <date date="1975-06-12">June 12, 1975</date>, 40 F.R. 25431, which related to the withholding of city income or employment taxes by Federal agencies, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 11968, <date date="1977-01-31">Jan. 31, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 6787, formerly set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb865d042-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11968</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11968, <date date="1977-01-31">Jan. 31, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 6787, which related to the withholding of District of Columbia, State and city income or employment taxes, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 11997, <date date="1977-06-22">June 22, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 31759, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb865d043-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11997. Withholding of District of Columbia, State, City and County Income or Employment Taxes</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11997, <date date="1977-06-22">June 22, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 31759, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by Sections 5516, 5517 and 5520 of Title 5 of the United States Code, and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">Section 301 of Title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and as President of the United States of America, in order to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to provide for the withholding of county income or employment taxes as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5520">Section 5520 of Title 5</ref> of the United States Code as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/30/s408">Section 408 of Public Law 95–30</ref>, as well as to provide for the withholding of District of Columbia, State and city income or employment taxes, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. Whenever the Secretary of the Treasury enters into an agreement pursuant to Sections 5516, 5517 or 5520 of Title 5 of the United States Code, with the District of Columbia, a State, a city or a county, as the case may be, with regard to the withholding, by an agency of the United States, hereinafter referred to as an agency, of income or employment taxes from the pay of Federal employees or members of the Armed Forces, the Secretary of the Treasury shall ensure that each agreement is consistent with those sections and regulations, including this Order, issued thereunder.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. Each agreement shall provide (a) when tax withholding shall begin, (b) that the head of an agency may rely on the withholding certificate of an employee or a member of the Armed Forces in withholding taxes, (c) that the method for calculating the amount to be withheld for District of Columbia, State, city or county income or employment taxes shall produce approximately the tax required to be withheld by the District of Columbia or State law; or city or county ordinance, whichever is applicable, and (d) that procedures for the withholding, filing of returns, and payment of the withheld taxes to the District of Columbia, a State, a city or a county shall conform to the usual fiscal practices of agencies. Any agreement affecting members of the Armed Forces shall also provide that the head of an agency may rely on the certificate of legal residence of a member of the Armed Forces in determining his or her residence for tax withholding purposes. No agreement shall require the collection by an agency of delinquent tax liabilities of an employee or a member of the Armed Forces.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. The head of each agency shall designate, or provide for the designation of, the officers or employees whose duty it shall be to withhold taxes, file required returns, and direct payment of the taxes withheld, in accordance with this Order, any regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury, and the new applicable agreement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to prescribe additional regulations to implement Sections 5516, 5517 and 5520 of Title 5 of the United States Code, and this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. Executive Order No. 11968 of <date date="1977-01-31">January 31, 1977</date>, is hereby revoked. However, all actions heretofore taken by the President or his delegates in respect of the matters affected by this Order and in force at the time of the issuance of this Order, including any regulations prescribed or approved by the President or his delegates in respect of such matters and any existing agreements approved by his delegates, shall, except as they may be inconsistent with the provisions of this Order, remain in effect until amended, modified, or revoked pursuant to the authority conferred by this Order, unless sooner terminated by operation of law.</p>
<signature>
<name>Jimmy Carter.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
