<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb86ab231-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5534a"><num value="5534a">§ 5534a.</num><heading> Dual employment and pay during terminal leave from uniformed services</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A member of a uniformed service who has performed active service and who is on terminal leave pending separation from, or release from active duty in, that service under honorable conditions may accept a civilian office or position in the Government of the United States, its territories or possessions, or the government of the District of Columbia, and he is entitled to receive the pay of that office or position in addition to pay and allowances from the uniformed service for the unexpired portion of the terminal leave. Such a member also is entitled to accrue annual leave with pay in the manner specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s6303/a">section 6303(a) of this title</ref> for a retired member of a uniformed service.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb86ab232-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/90/83/s1/22">Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(22)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/199">81 Stat. 199</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tXI/s1101">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title XI, § 1101</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2407">120 Stat. 2407</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb86ab233-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb86ab234-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section amends chapter 55 of title 5, United States Code, by inserting a new section 5534a. This section is based on subsections (a) and (f) of former <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s61a–1">5 U.S.C. 61a–1</ref> the source statute for which (<ref href="/us/act/1945-11-21/ch489">act of Nov. 21, 1945, ch. 489</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/584">59 Stat. 584</ref>) was repealed by the act of <date date="1966-09-06">September 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Public Law 89–554</ref> (sec. 8, <ref href="/us/stat/80/653">80 Stat. 653</ref>). Senate Report 1380, 89th Congress, second session, pages 449, 511, explains that the source was repealed since it had been rendered obsolete by section 4(c) of the Armed Forces Leave Act of 1946, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t37/s501">37 U.S.C. 501</ref>), and section 219(c) of the Public Health Service Act, as added <date date="1950-08-09">August 9, 1950</date> (ch. 654, sec. 2, <ref href="/us/stat/64/426">64 Stat. 426</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s210–1/c">42 U.S.C. 210–1(c)</ref>), and that any existing rights are preserved by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8">section 8 of Public Law 89–554</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">At the time of enactment of the act of <date date="1945-11-21">November 21, 1945</date>, there was no authority to make lump-sum leave payments to members of the uniformed services who were being separated from or released from active duty in the uniformed services. Accordingly, they were placed on terminal leave until the expiration of the unused portion of their accumulated and current accrued leave, and only then separated or released. The act of <date date="1945-11-21">November 21, 1945</date>, in part, authorized the employment of these members during terminal leave and provided they were entitled to receive, in addition to the payment from the employment, military pay and allowances for the unexpired portion of the terminal leave. The Armed Forces Leave Act of 1946 authorized lump-sum leave payments of unused accumulated and current accrued leave. Generally, thereafter, members of the uniformed services were not placed on terminal leave, but were separated and paid a lump-sum leave payment. However, in certain instances a member may be placed on terminal leave. Such a case was considered recently by the Comptroller General of the United States (see B–157500, <date date="1965-10-13">Oct. 13, 1965</date>, 45 Comp. Gen. 180. In view of the foregoing, it is concluded that subsection (a) of former <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s61a–1">5 U.S.C. 61a–1</ref> had prospective effect and should have been reenacted in title 5, U.S.C., by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Public Law 89–554</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In section 5534a, the words “A member of a uniformed service who has performed active service” are substituted for “Any person, who, shall have performed active service in the Armed Forces” to conform to the style of title 5 and the definition of “uniformed services” in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2101">5 U.S.C. 2101</ref> which is coextensive with the definition of “armed forces” in subsection (f) of former <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s61a–1">5 U.S.C. 61a–1</ref>. Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1965 (<ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>), effective <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, consolidated the Coast and Geodetic Survey and the Weather Bureau to form a new agency in the Department of Commerce to be known as the Environmental Science Services Administration. The words “subsequent to <date date="1940-05-01">May 1, 1940</date>” are omitted as executed. The word “territories” is substituted for “Territories” inasmuch as there now are no incorporated territories. The words “(including any corporation created under authority of an act of Congress which is either wholly controlled or wholly owned by the Government of the United States, or any department, agency, or establishment thereof, whether or not the employees thereof are paid from funds appropriated by Congress)” are omitted as included in “a civilian office or position in the Government of the United States”. The word “pay” is substituted for “compensation.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb86ab235-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb86ab236-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> inserted at end “Such a member also is entitled to accrue annual leave with pay in the manner specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s6303/a">section 6303(a) of this title</ref> for a retired member of a uniformed service.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb86ab237-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb86ab238-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, for all purposes, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/83/s9/h">section 9(h) of Pub. L. 90–83</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1967 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5102">section 5102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
