<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb7bc978f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573"><num value="573">§ 573.</num><heading> Neutrals</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7bc9790-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> A neutral may be a permanent or temporary officer or employee of the Federal Government or any other individual who is acceptable to the parties to a dispute resolution proceeding. A neutral shall have no official, financial, or personal conflict of interest with respect to the issues in controversy, unless such interest is fully disclosed in writing to all parties and all parties agree that the neutral may serve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7bc9791-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A neutral who serves as a conciliator, fa­cilitator, or mediator serves at the will of the parties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7bc9792-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> The President shall designate an agency or designate or establish an interagency committee to facilitate and encourage agency use of dispute resolution under this subchapter. Such agency or interagency committee, in consultation with other appropriate Federal agencies and professional organizations experienced in matters concerning dispute resolution, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7bc9793-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> encourage and facilitate agency use of alternative means of dispute resolution; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb7bc9794-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> develop procedures that permit agencies to obtain the services of neutrals on an expedited basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7bc9795-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> An agency may use the services of one or more employees of other agencies to serve as neutrals in dispute resolution proceedings. The agencies may enter into an interagency agreement that provides for the reimbursement by the user agency or the parties of the full or partial cost of the services of such an employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb7bc9796-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s573/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Any agency may enter into a contract with any person for services as a neutral, or for training in connection with alternative means of dispute resolution. The parties in a dispute resolution proceeding shall agree on compensation for the neutral that is fair and reasonable to the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb7bc9797-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/552/s4/b">Pub. L. 101–552, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2739">104 Stat. 2739</ref>, § 583; renumbered § 573, <ref href="/us/pl/102/354/s3/b/2">Pub. L. 102–354, § 3(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-08-26">Aug. 26, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/944">106 Stat. 944</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s7/b">Pub. L. 104–320, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3872">110 Stat. 3872</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb7bc9798-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb7bc9799-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb7bc979a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 573 of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees, was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2258">section 2258 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb7bc979b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 573 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s593">section 593 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb7bc979c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s7/b/1">Pub. L. 104–320, § 7(b)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which related to power of Administrative Conference of the United States to establish and utilize standards for neutrals and to enter into contracts for services of neutrals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s7/b/2">Pub. L. 104–320, § 7(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “on a roster established under subsection (c)(2) or a roster maintained by other public or private organizations, or individual” after “contract with any person”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/354">Pub. L. 102–354</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s583">section 583 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
