<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8873b3d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5732"><num value="5732">§ 5732.</num><heading> General average contribution; payment or reimbursement</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under such regulations as the President may prescribe, appropriations chargeable for the transportation of baggage and household goods and personal effects of employees of the Government, volunteers as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8142/a">section 8142(a) of this title</ref>, and members of the uniformed services are available for the payment or reimbursement of general average contributions required. Appropriations are not available for the payment or reimbursement of general average contributions—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8873b3e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5732/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> required in connection with and applicable to quantities of baggage and household goods and personal effects in excess of quantities authorized by statute or regulation to be transported;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8873b3f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5732/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> when the individual concerned is allowed under statute or regulation a commutation instead of actual transportation expenses; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8873b40-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5732/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> when the individual concerned selected the means of shipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idb8873b41-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/506">80 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/264/s6/11">Pub. L. 105–264, § 6(11)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-19">Oct. 19, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2356">112 Stat. 2356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8873b42-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8873b43-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb8873b44-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Derivation</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>U.S. Code</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised Statutes and</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Statutes at Large</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> </html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s73b–5">5 U.S.C. 73b–5</html:a>.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1954-06-04/ch264/s4">June 4, 1954, ch. 264, § 4</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/68/176">68 Stat. 176</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> </html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t22/s2504/h">22 U.S.C. 2504(h)</html:a> (as applicable to <html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s73b–5">5 U.S.C. 73b–5</html:a>).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Dec. 13, 1963</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/88/200/s2/e">Pub. L. 88–200, § 2(e)</html:a> (as applicable to the <html:a href="/us/act/1954-06-04/ch264/s4">Act of June 4, 1954, ch. 264, § 4</html:a> (<html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s73b–5">5 U.S.C. 73b–5</html:a>)), <html:a href="/us/stat/77/360">77 Stat. 360</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The word “personal” is added before the word “effects” for clarity and to preserve consistency throughout this subchapter. The words “employees of the United States . . . and members of the uniformed services” are substituted for “military personnel and civilian employees of departments and agencies of the Federal Government”. The words “a volunteer as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8142/a">section 8142(a) of this title</ref>” are based on sections 2504(a), 2505, and 2507 (a) of title 22. The words “pursuant to law” are omitted as unnecessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8873b45-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8873b46-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/264">Pub. L. 105–264</ref> substituted “Government” for “United States” in introductory provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb8873b47-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb8873b48-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 10614. Payment of General-Average Contributions in Connection With Transportation of Effects</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10614, <date date="1955-05-25">May 25, 1955</date>, 20 F.R. 3699, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Definitions</i>. As used in these regulations:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) The term “military personnel” means members and former and deceased members of the uniformed services as defined in section 102 of the Career Compensation Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/stat/63/804">63 Stat. 804</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t37/s101">37 U.S.C. 101</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The term “civilian employees” means civilian officers and employees of a department, including Foreign Service personnel, and former and deceased civilian officers and employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The terms “military personnel” and “civilian employees” shall also include those individuals enumerated under the term “person” as defined in section 1 of the Missing Persons Act, as amended [now <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5561">section 5561 of this title</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The term “department” means an executive department, independent establishment, or other agency of the Federal Government, including wholly-owned or controlled Government corporations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The term “general-average contribution” means the contribution by all parties to a sea venture (1) to make good the loss sustained by any one of their number on account of voluntary sacrifices made of part of the ship or cargo to save the residue or the lives of those on board from impending peril, or (2) for extraordinary expenses necessarily incurred for the common benefit and safety of all.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) The term “household goods” means such baggage, household goods, and effects, including privately-owned automobiles and professional books, papers, and equipment, of military personnel and civilian employees as are authorized to be transported at Government expense by law or regulations pursuant to law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Allowance of general-average contributions</i>. Whenever military personnel or civilian employees of a department are liable for general-average contributions arising out of shipments of household goods (as defined in section 1 (f) hereof), authorized or approved under law or regulations pursuant to law, disbursements shall be made, under rules and regulations prescribed by the head of the department concerned, from appropriations chargeable for the transportation of baggage and household goods and effects (a) for the payment of the general-average contributions for which such military personnel or civilian employees are liable, or (b) for the reimbursement of such military personnel or civilian employees in the amounts of their general-average liability paid by them and for which receipts are furnished, subject to the limitations set forth in section 3 hereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Limitations</i>. The provisions of section 2 hereof shall not apply:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) In case the shipment of household goods is made under law or regulation pursuant to law which provides for reimbursement to the military person or civilian employee concerned on a commuted basis in lieu of payment by the Government of the actual costs of the shipment; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) In case the military person or civilian employee concerned has himself selected the means of shipment; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) To quantities of household goods (excluding automobiles) shipped in excess of quantities authorized to be transported by law or regulation pursuant to law. In any case of such excess shipment, the liability of the Government for the employee’s general-average contribution shall not exceed the proportion that the applicable limitation, by weight or volume, bears to the total quantity, by weight or volume, of the household goods shipped.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Effective date</i>. This order shall be effective in any case in which the loss involved occurs, or has occurred, on or after <date date="1954-06-04">June 4, 1954</date>.</p>
<signature>
<name>Dwight D. Eisenhower.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
