<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb88e6678-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s5928"><num value="5928">§ 5928.</num><heading> Danger pay allowance</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An employee serving in a foreign area may be granted a danger pay allowance on the basis of civil insurrection, civil war, terrorism, or wartime conditions which threaten physical harm or imminent danger to the health or well-being of the employee. A danger pay allowance may not exceed 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee, except that if an employee is granted an additional differential under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5925/b">section 5925(b) of this title</ref> with respect to an assignment, the sum of that additional differential and any danger pay allowance granted to the employee with respect to that assignment may not exceed 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee. The presence of nonessential personnel or dependents shall not preclude payment of an allowance under this section. In each instance where an allowance under this section is initiated or terminated, the Secretary of State shall inform the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate of the action taken and the circumstances justifying it.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb88e6679-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2311/a">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2311(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2166">94 Stat. 2166</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/164/tI/s131">Pub. L. 98–164, title I, § 131</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1028">97 Stat. 1028</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dD/tV/s591/b">Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title V, § 591(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/207">118 Stat. 207</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/140/s4/c">Pub. L. 109–140, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-22">Dec. 22, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2651">119 Stat. 2651</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb88e667a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb88e667b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb88e667c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—<ref href="/us/pl/109/140">Pub. L. 109–140</ref> substituted “35 percent of the basic pay of the employee” for “25 percent of the basic pay of the employee or 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee in the case of an employee of the United States Agency for International Development” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—<ref href="/us/pl/108/199">Pub. L. 108–199</ref> inserted “or 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee in the case of an employee of the United States Agency for International Development” after “25 percent of the basic pay of the employee” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/164">Pub. L. 98–164</ref> inserted provision that presence of nonessential personnel or dependents shall not preclude payment of an allowance under this section, and that each instance where an allowance under this section is initiated or terminated, the Secretary of State shall inform the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate of action taken and circumstances justifying it.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb88e667d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb88e667e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-02-15">Feb. 15, 1981</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2403">section 2403 of Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb88e667f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Danger Pay Allowance; DEA or FBI Employee</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s151">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 151</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/42">104 Stat. 42</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tI/s11005">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11005</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1817">116 Stat. 1817</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dB/tII/s221">Pub. L. 116–260, div. B, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1266">134 Stat. 1266</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dB/tII/s221">“The Secretary of State may not deny a request by the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the United States Marshals Service to authorize a danger pay allowance (under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5928">section 5928 of title 5</ref>, United States Code) for any employee of such agency.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb88e6680-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Greater Utilization of Danger Pay Allowance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/533/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 98–533, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2711">98 Stat. 2711</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/533/tIII/s304">“In recognition of the current epidemic of worldwide terrorist activity and the courage and sacrifice of employees of United States agencies overseas, civilian as well as military, it is the sense of Congress that the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5928">section 5928 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, relating to the payment of danger pay allowance, should be more extensively utilized at United States missions abroad.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
