<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8ab167e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120"><num value="7120">§ 7120.</num><heading> Standards of conduct for labor organizations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab167f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> An agency shall only accord recognition to a labor organization that is free from corrupt influences and influences opposed to basic democratic principles. Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an organization is not required to prove that it is free from such influences if it is subject to governing requirements adopted by the organization or by a national or international labor organization or federation of labor organizations with which it is affiliated, or in which it participates, containing explicit and detailed provisions to which it subscribes calling for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab1680-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the maintenance of democratic procedures and practices including provisions for periodic elections to be conducted subject to recognized safeguards and provisions defining and securing the right of individual members to participate in the affairs of the organization, to receive fair and equal treatment under the governing rules of the organization, and to receive fair process in disciplinary proceedings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab1681-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the exclusion from office in the organization of persons affiliated with communist or other totalitarian movements and persons identified with corrupt influences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab1682-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the prohibition of business or financial interests on the part of organization officers and agents which conflict with their duty to the organization and its members; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab1683-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the maintenance of fiscal integrity in the conduct of the affairs of the organization, including provisions for accounting and financial controls and regular financial reports or summaries to be made available to members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1684-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding the fact that a labor organization has adopted or subscribed to standards of conduct as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the organization is required to furnish evidence of its freedom from corrupt influences or influences opposed to basic democratic principles if there is reasonable cause to believe that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab1685-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the organization has been suspended or expelled from, or is subject to other sanction, by a parent labor organization, or federation of organizations with which it had been affiliated, because it has demonstrated an unwillingness or inability to comply with governing requirements comparable in purpose to those required by subsection (a) of this section; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab1686-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the organization is in fact subject to influences that would preclude recognition under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1687-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A labor organization which has or seeks recognition as a representative of employees under this chapter shall file financial and other reports with the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Labor Management Relations, provide for bonding of officials and employees of the organization, and comply with trusteeship and election standards.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1688-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Assistant Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. Such regulations shall conform generally to the principles applied to labor organizations in the private sector. Complaints of violations of this section shall be filed with the Assistant Secretary. In any matter arising under this section, the Assistant Secretary may require a labor organization to cease and desist from violations of this section and require it to take such actions as he considers appropriate to carry out the policies of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1689-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> This chapter does not authorize participation in the management of a labor organization or acting as a representative of a labor organization by a management official, a supervisor, or a confidential employee, except as specifically provided in this chapter, or by an employee if the participation or activity would result in a conflict or apparent conflict of interest or would otherwise be incompatible with law or with the official duties of the employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab168a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> In the case of any labor organization which by omission or commission has willfully and intentionally, with regard to any strike, work stoppage, or slowdown, violated <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7116/b/7">section 7116(b)(7) of this title</ref>, the Authority shall, upon an appropriate finding by the Authority of such violation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab168b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> revoke the exclusive recognition status of the labor organization, which shall then immediately cease to be legally entitled and obligated to represent employees in the unit; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab168c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7120/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> take any other appropriate disciplinary action.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8ab168d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1210">92 Stat. 1210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8ab168e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8ab168f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb8ab1690-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
