<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8ab1695-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121"><num value="7121">§ 7121.</num><heading> Grievance procedures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1696-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1697-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any collective bargaining agreement shall provide procedures for the settlement of grievances, including questions of arbitrability. Except as provided in subsections (d), (e), and (g) of this section, the procedures shall be the exclusive administrative procedures for resolving grievances which fall within its coverage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1698-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any collective bargaining agreement may exclude any matter from the application of the grievance procedures which are provided for in the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab1699-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab169a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any negotiated grievance procedure referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab169b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be fair and simple,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab169c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide for expeditious processing, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab169d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> include procedures that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8ab169e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> assure an exclusive representative the right, in its own behalf or on behalf of any employee in the unit represented by the exclusive representative, to present and process grievances;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8ab169f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> assure such an employee the right to present a grievance on the employee’s own behalf, and assure the exclusive representative the right to be present during the grievance proceeding; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8ab16a0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> provide that any grievance not satisfactorily settled under the negotiated grievance procedure shall be subject to binding arbitration which may be invoked by either the exclusive representative or the agency.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16a1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16a2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The provisions of a negotiated grievance procedure providing for binding arbitration in accordance with paragraph (1)(C)(iii) shall, if or to the extent that an alleged prohibited personnel practice is involved, allow the arbitrator to order—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16a3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a stay of any personnel action in a manner similar to the manner described in section 1221(c) with respect to the Merit Systems Protection Board; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16a4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the taking, by an agency, of any disciplinary action identified under section 1215(a)(3) that is otherwise within the authority of such agency to take.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16a5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any employee who is the subject of any disciplinary action ordered under subparagraph (A)(ii) may appeal such action to the same extent and in the same manner as if the agency had taken the disciplinary action absent arbitration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16a6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> The preceding subsections of this section shall not apply with respect to any grievance concerning—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16a7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any claimed violation of subchapter III of chapter 73 of this title (relating to prohibited political activities);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16a8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> retirement, life insurance, or health insurance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16a9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a suspension or removal under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7532">section 7532 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16aa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any examination, certification, or appointment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16ab-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the classification of any position which does not result in the reduction in grade or pay of an employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16ac-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> An aggrieved employee affected by a prohibited personnel practice under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2302/b/1">section 2302(b)(1) of this title</ref> which also falls under the coverage of the negotiated grievance procedure may raise the matter under a statutory procedure or the negotiated procedure, but not both. An employee shall be deemed to have exercised his option under this subsection to raise the matter under either a statutory procedure or the negotiated procedure at such time as the employee timely initiates an action under the applicable statutory procedure or timely files a grievance in writing, in accordance with the provisions of the parties’ negotiated procedure, whichever event occurs first. Selection of the negotiated procedure in no manner prejudices the right of an aggrieved employee to request the Merit Systems Protection Board to review the final decision pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7702">section 7702 of this title</ref> in the case of any personnel action that could have been appealed to the Board, or, where applicable, to request the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to review a final decision in any other matter involving a complaint of discrimination of the type prohibited by any law administered by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16ad-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16ae-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Matters covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which also fall within the coverage of the negotiated grievance procedure may, in the discretion of the aggrieved employee, be raised either under the appellate procedures of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7701">section 7701 of this title</ref> or under the negotiated grievance procedure, but not both. Similar matters which arise under other personnel systems applicable to employees covered by this chapter may, in the discretion of the aggrieved employee, be raised either under the appellate procedures, if any, applicable to those matters, or under the negotiated grievance procedure, but not both. An employee shall be deemed to have exercised his option under this subsection to raise a matter either under the applicable appellate procedures or under the negotiated grievance procedure at such time as the employee timely files a notice of appeal under the applicable appellate procedures or timely files a grievance in writing in accordance with the provisions of the parties’ negotiated grievance procedure, whichever event occurs first.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16af-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In matters covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which have been raised under the negotiated grievance procedure in accordance with this section, an arbitrator shall be governed by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7701/c/1">section 7701(c)(1) of this title</ref>, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16b0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> In matters covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which have been raised under the negotiated grievance procedure in accordance with this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref> pertaining to judicial review shall apply to the award of an arbitrator in the same manner and under the same conditions as if the matter had been decided by the Board. In matters similar to those covered under sections 4303 and 7512 of this title which arise under other personnel systems and which an aggrieved employee has raised under the negotiated grievance procedure, judicial review of an arbitrator’s award may be obtained in the same manner and on the same basis as could be obtained of a final decision in such matters raised under applicable appellate procedures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16b1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16b2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> This subsection applies with respect to a prohibited personnel practice other than a prohibited personnel practice to which subsection (d) applies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16b3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An aggrieved employee affected by a prohibited personnel practice described in paragraph (1) may elect not more than one of the remedies described in paragraph (3) with respect thereto. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a determination as to whether a particular remedy has been elected shall be made as set forth under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16b4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The remedies described in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16b5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16b6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A negotiated grievance procedure under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16b7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Procedures for seeking corrective action under subchapters II and III of chapter 12.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16b8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> For the purpose of this subsection, a person shall be considered to have elected—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16b9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the remedy described in paragraph (3)(A) if such person has timely filed a notice of appeal under the applicable appellate procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16ba-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the remedy described in paragraph (3)(B) if such person has timely filed a grievance in writing, in accordance with the provisions of the parties’ negotiated procedure; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8ab16bb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/g/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the remedy described in paragraph (3)(C) if such person has sought corrective action from the Office of Special Counsel by making an allegation under section 1214(a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8ab16bc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s7121/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> Settlements and awards under this chapter shall be subject to the limitations in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5596/b/4">section 5596(b)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8ab16bd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1211">92 Stat. 1211</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s9">Pub. L. 103–424, § 9</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4365">108 Stat. 4365</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tXI/s1104/b">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title XI, § 1104(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2142">112 Stat. 2142</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8ab16be-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8ab16bf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8ab16c0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261">Pub. L. 105–261</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s9/c">Pub. L. 103–424, § 9(c)</ref>, substituted “(d), (e), and (g)” for “(d) and (e)” and inserted “administrative” after “exclusive”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s9/a">Pub. L. 103–424, § 9(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and redesignated former pars. (1) to (3) as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, and subpars. (A) to (C) of former par. (3) as cls. (i) to (iii) of subpar. (a)(1)(C), respectively, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s9/b">Pub. L. 103–424, § 9(b)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8ab16c1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb8ab16c2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8ab16c3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Partial Suspension of Federal Service Labor-Management Relations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(C) of this section suspended with respect to any grievance involving the implementation by the United States Forces of any treaty or agreement, including any minutes or understandings thereto, between the United States and the Government of the host nation, see section 1(d) of Ex. Ord. No. 12391, <date date="1982-11-04">Nov. 4, 1982</date>, 47 F.R. 50457, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7103">section 7103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
