<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8c52eb9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8191"><num value="8191">§ 8191.</num><heading> Determination of eligibility</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The benefits of this subchapter are available as provided in this subchapter to eligible law enforcement officers (referred to in this subchapter as “eligible officers”) and their survivors. For the purposes of this subchapter, an eligible officer is any person who is determined by the Secretary of Labor in his discretion to have been on any given occasion—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8c52eba-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8191/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> a law enforcement officer and to have been engaged on that occasion in the apprehension or attempted apprehension of any person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8c52ebb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8191/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for the commission of a crime against the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8c52ebc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8191/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> who at that time was sought by a law enforcement authority of the United States for the commission of a crime against the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8c52ebd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8191/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> who at that time was sought as a material witness in a criminal proceeding instituted by the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8c52ebe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8191/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a law enforcement officer and to have been engaged on that occasion in protecting or guarding a person held for the commission of a crime against the United States or as a material witness in connection with such a crime; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8c52ebf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8191/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a law enforcement officer and to have been engaged on that occasion in the lawful prevention of, or lawful attempt to prevent, the commission of a crime against the United States;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and to have been on that occasion not an employee as defined in section 8101(1), and to have sustained on that occasion a personal injury for which the United States would be required under subchapter I of this chapter to pay compensation if he had been on that occasion such an employee engaged in the performance of his duty. No person otherwise eligible to receive a benefit under this subchapter because of the disability or death of an eligible officer shall be barred from the receipt of such benefit because the person apprehended or attempted to be apprehended by such officer was then sought for the commission of a crime against a sovereignty other than the United States.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="idb8c52ec0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/90/291/s1/a">Pub. L. 90–291, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-04-19">Apr. 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/98">82 Stat. 98</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/623/s1/20">Pub. L. 90–623, § 1(20)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1313">82 Stat. 1313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8c52ec1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8c52ec2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8c52ec3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/623">Pub. L. 90–623</ref> substituted “For the purposes of this subchapter” for “For the purposes of this Act”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8c52ec4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8c52ec5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/623">Pub. L. 90–623</ref> intended to restate without substantive change the law in effect on <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/623/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 90–623</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5334">section 5334 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb8c52ec6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/90/291/s2">Section 2 of Pub. L. 90–291</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/90/291/s2">“The amendments made by section 1 of this Act [enacting this section and sections 8192 and 8193 of this title] are effective only with respect to personal injuries sustained on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1968-04-19">Apr. 19, 1968</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
