<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8e44ea7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341"><num value="8341">§ 8341.</num><heading> Survivor annuities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ea8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> For the purpose of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ea9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> “widow” means the surviving wife of an employee or Member who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eaa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> was married to him for at least 9 months immediately before his death; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eab-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is the mother of issue by that marriage;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eac-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> “widower” means the surviving husband of an employee or Member who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44ead-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> was married to her for at least 9 months immediately before her death; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eae-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is the father of issue by that marriage;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eaf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “dependent”, in the case of any child, means that the employee or Member involved was, at the time of the employee or Member’s death, either living with or contributing to the support of such child, as determined in accordance with such regulations as the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eb0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> “child” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eb1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an unmarried dependent child under 18 years of age, including (i) an adopted child, and (ii) a stepchild but only if the stepchild lived with the employee or Member in a regular parent-child relationship, and (iii) a recognized natural child, and (iv) a child who lived with and for whom a petition of adoption was filed by an employee or Member, and who is adopted by the surviving spouse of the employee or Member after his death;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eb2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such unmarried dependent child regardless of age who is incapable of self-support because of mental or physical disability incurred before age 18; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eb3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such unmarried dependent child between 18 and 22 years of age who is a student regularly pursuing a full-time course of study or training in residence in a high school, trade school, technical or vocational institute, junior college, college, university, or comparable recognized educational institution.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For the purpose of this paragraph and subsection (e) of this section, a child whose 22nd birthday occurs before July 1 or after August 31 of a calendar year, and while he is regularly pursuing such a course of study or training, is deemed to have become 22 years of age on the first day of July after that birthday. A child who is a student is deemed not to have ceased to be a student during an interim between school years if the interim is not more than 5 months and if he shows to the satisfaction of the Office of Personnel Management that he has a bona fide intention of continuing to pursue a course of study or training in the same or different school during the school semester (or other period into which the school year is divided) immediately after the interim.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44eb4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44eb5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if an employee or Member dies after having retired under this subchapter and is survived by a widow or widower, the widow or widower is entitled to an annuity equal to 55 percent (or 50 percent if retired before <date date="1962-10-11">October 11, 1962</date>) of an annuity computed under section 8339(a)–(i), (n), (p), (q), (r), and (s) as may apply with respect to the annuitant, or of such portion thereof as may have been designated for this purpose under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/1">section 8339(j)(1) of this title</ref>, unless the right to a survivor annuity was waived under such section 8339(j)(1) or, in the case of remarriage, the employee or Member did not file an election under section 8339(j)(5)(C) or <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/k/2">section 8339(k)(2) of this title</ref>, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44eb6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If an annuitant—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eb7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who retired before <date date="1948-04-01">April 1, 1948</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eb8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> who elected a reduced annuity provided in paragraph (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/k">section 8339(k) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">dies and is survived by a widow or widower, the widow or widower is entitled to an annuity in an amount which would have been paid had the annuitant been married to the widow or widower at the time of retirement.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44eb9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A spouse acquired after retirement is entitled to a survivor annuity under this subsection only upon electing this annuity instead of any other survivor benefit to which he may be entitled under this subchapter or another retirement system for Government employees. The annuity of the widow or widower under this subsection commences on the day after the annuitant dies. This annuity and the right thereto terminate on the last day of the month before the widow or widower—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eba-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> dies; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ebb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (k), remarries before becoming 55 years of age.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ebc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this subsection, the annuity payable under this subsection to the widow or widower of a retired employee or Member may not exceed the difference between—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ebd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount which would otherwise be payable to such widow or widower under this subsection (determined without regard to any waiver or designation under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/1">section 8339(j)(1) of this title</ref> or a prior similar provision of law), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ebe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of the survivor annuity payable to any former spouse of such employee or Member under subsection (h) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ebf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The annuity of a survivor named under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/k/1">section 8339(k)(1) of this title</ref> is 55 percent of the reduced annuity of the retired employee or Member. The annuity of the survivor commences on the day after the retired employee or Member dies. This annuity and the right thereto terminate on the last day of the month before the survivor dies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ec0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> If an employee or Member dies after completing at least 18 months of civilian service, his widow or widower is entitled to an annuity equal to 55 percent of an annuity computed under section 8339(a)–(f), (i), (n), (p), (q), (r), and (s) as may apply with respect to the employee or Member, except that, in the computation of the annuity under such section, the annuity of the employee or Member shall be at least the smaller of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ec1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 40 percent of his average pay; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ec2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the sum obtained under such section after increasing his service of the type last performed by the period elapsing between the date of death and the date he would have become 60 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the annuity payable under this subsection to the widow or widower of an employee or Member may not exceed the difference between—</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ec3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/d/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount which would otherwise be payable to such widow or widower under this subsection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ec4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/d/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of the survivor annuity payable to any former spouse of such employee or Member under subsection (h) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The annuity of the widow or widower commences on the day after the employee or Member dies. This annuity and the right thereto terminate on the last day of the month before the widow or widower—</continuation>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ec5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/d/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> dies; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ec6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/d/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (k), remarries before becoming 55 years of age.</content>
</clause>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ec7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ec8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the purposes of this subsection, “former spouse” includes a former spouse who was married to an employee or Member for less than 9 months and a former spouse of an employee or Member who completed less than 18 months of service covered by this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ec9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If an employee or Member dies after completing at least 18 months of civilian service, or an employee or Member dies after retiring under this subchapter, and is survived by a spouse or a former spouse who is the natural or adoptive parent of a surviving child of the employee or Member, that surviving child is entitled to an annuity equal to the smallest of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eca-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 60 percent of the average pay of the employee or Member divided by the number of children;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ecb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> $900; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ecc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> $2,700 divided by the number of children;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340">section 8340 of this title</ref>. If the employee or Member is not survived by a spouse or a former spouse who is the natural or adoptive parent of a surviving child of the employee or Member, that surviving child is entitled to an annuity equal to the smallest of—</continuation>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ecd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/2/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 75 percent of the average pay of the employee or Member divided by the number of children;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ece-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/2/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> $1,080; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ecf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/2/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> $3,240 divided by the number of children;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340">section 8340 of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ed0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The annuity of a child under this subchapter or under the Act of <date date="1930-05-29">May 29, 1930</date>, as amended from and after <date date="1948-02-28">February 28, 1948</date>, commences on the day after the employee or Member dies, or commences or resumes on the first day of the month in which the child later becomes or again becomes a student as described by subsection (a)(3) of this section, if any lump sum paid is returned to the Fund. This annuity and the right thereto terminate on the last day of the month before the child—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ed1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> becomes 18 years of age unless he is then a student as described or incapable of self-support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ed2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> becomes capable of self-support after becoming 18 years of age unless he is then such a student;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ed3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> becomes 22 years of age if he is then such a student and capable of self-support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ed4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> ceases to be such a student after becoming 18 years of age unless he is then incapable of self-support; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ed5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> dies or marries;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever first occurs. On the death of the surviving spouse or former spouse or termination of the annuity of a child, the annuity of any other child or children shall be recomputed and paid as though the spouse, former spouse, or child had not survived the employee or Member.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ed6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> If the annuity of a child under this subchapter terminates under paragraph (3)(E) because of marriage, then, if such marriage ends, such annuity shall resume on the first day of the month in which it ends, but only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ed7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any lump sum paid is returned to the Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ed8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that individual is not otherwise ineligible for such annuity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ed9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> If a Member heretofore or hereafter separated from the service with title to deferred annuity from the Fund hereafter dies before having established a valid claim for annuity and is survived by a spouse to whom married at the date of separation, the surviving spouse—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eda-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is entitled to an annuity equal to 55 percent of the deferred annuity of the Member commencing on the day after the Member dies and terminating on the last day of the month before the surviving spouse dies or remarries; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44edb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may elect to receive the lump-sum credit instead of annuity if the spouse is the individual who would be entitled to the lump-sum credit and files application therefor with the Office before the award of the annuity.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, an annuity payable under this subsection to the surviving spouse of a Member may not exceed the difference between—</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44edc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/f/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the annuity which would otherwise be payable to such surviving spouse under this subsection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44edd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/f/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of the survivor annuity payable to any former spouse of such Member under subsection (h) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ede-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><chapeau> In the case of a surviving spouse whose annuity under this section is terminated because of remarriage before becoming 55 years of age, annuity at the same rate shall be restored commencing on the day the remarriage is dissolved by death, annulment, or divorce, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44edf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the surviving spouse elects to receive this annuity instead of a survivor benefit to which he may be entitled, under this subchapter or another retirement system for Government employees, by reason of the remarriage; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ee0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any lump sum paid on termination of the annuity is returned to the Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ee1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ee2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraphs (2) through (5) of this subsection, a former spouse of a deceased employee, Member, annuitant, or former Member who was separated from the service with title to a deferred annuity under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8338/b">section 8338(b) of this title</ref> is entitled to a survivor annuity under this subsection, if and to the extent expressly provided for in an election under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/3">section 8339(j)(3) of this title</ref>, or in the terms of any decree of divorce or annulment or any court order or court-approved property settlement agreement incident to such decree.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ee3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ee4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The annuity payable to a former spouse under this subsection may not exceed the difference between—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ee5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount applicable in the case of such former spouse, as determined under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ee6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount of any annuity payable under this subsection to any other former spouse of the employee, Member, or annuitant, based on an election previously made under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/3">section 8339(j)(3) of this title</ref>, or a court order previously issued.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ee7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The applicable amount, for purposes of subparagraph (A)(i) of this paragraph in the case of a former spouse, is the amount which would be applicable—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ee8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> under subsection (b)(4)(A) of this section in the case of a widow or widower, if the deceased was an employee or Member who died after retirement;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ee9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> under subparagraph (A) of subsection (d) of this section in the case of a widow or widower, if the deceased was an employee or Member described in the first sentence of such subsection; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eea-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> under subparagraph (A) of subsection (f) of this section in the case of a surviving spouse, if the deceased was a Member described in the first sentence of such subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44eeb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The commencement and termination of an annuity payable under this subsection shall be governed by the terms of the applicable order, decree, agreement, or election, as the case may be, except that any such annuity—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eec-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> shall not commence before—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eed-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the day after the employee, Member, or annuitant dies, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44eee-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the first day of the second month beginning after the date on which the Office receives written notice of the order, decree, agreement, or election, as the case may be, together with such additional information or documentation as the Office may prescribe,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">whichever is later, and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44eef-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> shall terminate—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44ef0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (k), in the case of an annuity computed by reference to clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection, no later than the last day of the month before the former spouse remarries before becoming 55 years of age or dies; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8e44ef1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of an annuity computed by reference to clause (iii) of such paragraph, no later than the last day of the month before the former spouse remarries or dies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ef2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subchapter, a modification in a decree, order, agreement, or election referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be effective—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ef3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if such modification is made after the retirement or death of the employee or Member concerned, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ef4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to the extent that such modification involves an annuity under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ef5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For purposes of this subchapter, a decree, order, agreement, or election referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be effective, in the case of a former spouse, to the extent that it is inconsistent with any joint designation or waiver previously executed with respect to such former spouse under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/1">section 8339(j)(1) of this title</ref> or a similar prior provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ef6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Any payment under this subsection to a person bars recovery by any other person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ef7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> As used in this subsection, “court” means any court of any State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands, and any Indian court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44ef8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> The requirement in subsections (a)(1)(A) and (a)(2)(A) of this section that the surviving spouse of an employee or Member have been married to such employee or Member for at least 9 months immediately before the employee or Member’s death in order to qualify as the widow or widower of such employee or Member shall be deemed satisfied in any case in which the employee or Member dies within the applicable 9-month period, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44ef9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the death of the employee or Member was accidental; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8e44efa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the surviving spouse of such individual had been previously married to the individual and subsequently divorced, and the aggregate time married is at least 9 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44efb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44efc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002169">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002169"><num>1</num> So in original. No subsec. (j) has been enacted.</note> Subsections (b)(3)(B), (d)(ii), and (h)(3)(B)(i) (to the extent that they provide for termination of a survivor annuity because of a remarriage before age 55) shall not apply if the widow, widower, or former spouse was married for at least 30 years to the individual on whose service the survivor annuity is based.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8e44efd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8341/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A remarriage described in paragraph (1) shall not be taken into account for purposes of section 8339(j)(5)(B) or (C) or any other provision of this chapter which the Office may by regulation identify in order to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8e44efe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/577">80 Stat. 577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/83/s1/80">Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(80)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/216">81 Stat. 216</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/tII/s206">Pub. L. 91–93, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1969-10-20">Oct. 20, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/140">83 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/658/s3">Pub. L. 91–658, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-01-08">Jan. 8, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1961">84 Stat. 1961</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/243/s1">Pub. L. 92–243, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-03-09">Mar. 9, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/56">86 Stat. 56</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/297/s7/4">Pub. L. 92–297, § 7(4)</ref>, <date date="1972-05-16">May 16, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/145">86 Stat. 145</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/260/s1/a">Pub. L. 93–260, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-04-09">Apr. 9, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/76">88 Stat. 76</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/183/s2/36">Pub. L. 94–183, § 2(36)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1058">89 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/317/s1/b">Pub. L. 95–317, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-07-10">July 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/382">92 Stat. 382</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/318/s2">Pub. L. 95–318, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-07-10">July 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/384">92 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tIX/s906/a/2">Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1224">92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/tIII/s338/c">Pub. L. 95–598, title III, § 338(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2681">92 Stat. 2681</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/179/s1">Pub. L. 96–179, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1299">93 Stat. 1299</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tI/s112">Pub. L. 98–353, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/343">98 Stat. 343</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3199">98 Stat. 3199</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/tII">Pub. L. 99–251, title II</ref>, §§ 205–207, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/25">100 Stat. 25</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXV/s15204/a/2">Pub. L. 99–272, title XV, § 15204(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/335">100 Stat. 335</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/428/s2/d/7">Pub. L. 101–428, § 2(d)(7)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-15">Oct. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/929">104 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/63">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(63)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1354">106 Stat. 1354</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/f/tVI/s633/a/1">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 633(a)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-314">110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–362; <ref href="/us/pl/105/61/tV">Pub. L. 105–61, title V</ref>, §§ 516(a)(4), 518(a), <date date="1997-10-10">Oct. 10, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1306">111 Stat. 1306</ref>, 1307; <ref href="/us/pl/106/553/s1/a/2/tIII/s308/h/7">Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title III, § 308(h)(7)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2762">114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–89.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8e44eff-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8e44f00-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb8e44f01-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style="">1966 <html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Act</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Derivation</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>U.S. Code</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised Statutes and</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Statutes at Large</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>(a)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s2251/h">5 U.S.C. 2251(h)</html:a>–(j).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1956-07-31/ch804/s401">July 31, 1956, ch. 804, § 401</html:a> “Sec. 1(h)–(j)”, <html:a href="/us/stat/70/744">70 Stat. 744</html:a>.</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-top:0em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 11, 1962</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/87/793/s1103/f/A">Pub. L. 87–793, § 1103(f)(A)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/76/871">76 Stat. 871</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>(b)–(f)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s2260">5 U.S.C. 2260</html:a>.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1956-07-31/ch804/s401">July 31, 1956, ch. 804, § 401</html:a> “Sec. 10”, <html:a href="/us/stat/70/754">70 Stat. 754</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 27, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/772/s1/b">Pub. L. 85–772, § 1(b)</html:a>, (c), <html:a href="/us/stat/72/930">72 Stat. 930</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Sept. 6, 1960</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/86/713/s1/a">Pub. L. 86–713, § 1(a)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/74/813">74 Stat. 813</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 11, 1962</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/87/793/s1103">Pub. L. 87–793, § 1103</html:a> (less (a) and (f)(A)), <html:a href="/us/stat/76/870">76 Stat. 870</html:a>, 871.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b), the words “designated for this purpose under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/i">section 8339(i) of this title</ref>” are substituted for “designated in writing for such purpose by the employee or Member at the time of retirement” in view of the provisions of section 8339(i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (f), the words “heretofore or hereafter” are substituted “either prior to, on, or after the effective date of the Civil Service Retirement Act Amendments of 1956”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.</p>
</note>
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8e44f02-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb8e44f03-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style="">1967 <html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Act</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Section of title 5</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>8341(a)(4)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 App.: 2251(j) (less last sentence).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:span class="date">Apr. 25, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/407/s1">Pub. L. 89–407, § 1</html:a> (words before 1st comma), <html:a href="/us/stat/80/131">80 Stat. 131</html:a>.</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-top:0em;"><html:span class="date">July 18, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/504/s502">Pub. L. 89–504, § 502</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/300">80 Stat. 300</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">8341(b) (last sentence)</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 App.: 2260(a)(2).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">July 18, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/504/s506/a">Pub. L. 89–504, § 506(a)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/301">80 Stat. 301</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">8341(d) (last sentence)</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 App.: 2260(c) (last sentence).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">July 18, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/504/s506/b">Pub. L. 89–504, § 506(b)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/301">80 Stat. 301</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>8341(e)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 App.: 2260(d).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">July 18, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/504/s506/c">Pub. L. 89–504, § 506(c)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/301">80 Stat. 301</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>8341(g)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 App.: 2260(f).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">July 18, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/504/s506/d">Pub. L. 89–504, § 506(d)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/302">80 Stat. 302</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(4), the words “for the purposes of section 10(d)” are omitted as covered by the words “For the purpose of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In clause (2) of the last sentence of subsection (b), the word “retired” is inserted before “Member” for clarity and to conform to the penultimate sentence and clause (1) of the last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (e), the words “any lump sum paid” are substituted for “the lump-sum credit, if paid” for clarity and consistency with subsection (g)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (e)(2)(C), the words “capable of self-support” are substituted for “not incapable of self-support.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (g), the words “after <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>” are substituted for “hereafter.” In clause (1), the word “he” is substituted for “he or she” on authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s1">1 U.S.C. 1</ref>. The words “another retirement system for Government employees” are substituted for “any other retirement system established for employees of the Government” for consistency with section 8101(1)(ii).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8e44f04-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb8e44f05-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1930-05-29">May 29, 1930</date>, as amended from and after <date date="1948-02-28">February 28, 1948</date>, referred to in subsec. (e)(3), is the predecessor of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8338">section 8338 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8e44f06-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (b)(1), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref> substituted “(q), (r), and (s)” for “(q), and (r)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/61/s516/a/4">Pub. L. 105–61, § 516(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “(q), and (r)” for “and (q) of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/61/s518/a/2/A">Pub. L. 105–61, § 518(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “except as provided in subsection (k), remarries” for “remarries”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/61">Pub. L. 105–61</ref>, §§ 516(a)(4), 518(a)(2)(A), substituted “(q), and (r)” for “and (q) of this title” in introductory provisions and “except as provided in subsection (k), remarries” for “remarries” in cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/61/s518/a/2/B">Pub. L. 105–61, § 518(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “except as provided in subsection (k), in” for “in”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/105/61/s518/a/1">Pub. L. 105–61, § 518(a)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsecs. (b)(1), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378">Pub. L. 102–378</ref> substituted “(p),” for “(<i>o</i>),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsecs. (b)(1), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/428">Pub. L. 101–428</ref> substituted “(n), (<i>o</i>), and (q)” for “(n), and (<i>o</i>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (b)(1), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> substituted “, (n) and (<i>o</i>)” for “and (n)” in subsec. (b)(1), and “(n), and (<i>o</i>)” for “and (n)” in subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/s205">Pub. L. 99–251, § 205</ref>, added par. (1), redesignated existing pars. (1) and (2) as (2) and (3), respectively, and in par. (2) as redesignated substituted “that surviving child” for “each surviving child” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/s206">Pub. L. 99–251, § 206</ref>, substituted “annuitant, or former Member who was separated from the service with title to a deferred annuity under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8338/b">section 8338(b) of this title</ref>” for “or annuitant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/s207">Pub. L. 99–251, § 207</ref>, inserted “or death” after “retirement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(1)(A), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/A">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “9 months” for “1 year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/B/i">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “by a widow or widower, the widow or widower is entitled to an annuity equal to 55 percent (or 50 percent if retired before <date date="1962-10-11">October 11, 1962</date>)” for “by a spouse to whom he was married at the time of retirement, or by a widow or widower whom he married after retirement, the spouse, widow, or widower is entitled to an annuity equal to 55 percent, or 50 percent if retired before <date date="1962-10-11">October 11, 1962</date>” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/1">section 8339(j)(1) of this title</ref>, unless the right to a survivor annuity was waived under such section 8339(j)(1) or, in the case of remarriage, the employee or Member did not file an election under section 8339(j)(5)(C) or <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/k/2">section 8339(k)(2) of this title</ref>, as the case may be” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j">section 8339(j) of this title</ref>, unless the employee or Member has notified the Office in writing at the time of retirement that he does not desire any spouse surviving him to receive his annuity, or in the case of remarriage, he did not file an election under the third sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j">section 8339(j) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> substituted “and (n)” for “and (<i>o</i>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/B/ii">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “widow or widower” for “spouse, widow, or widower” wherever appearing in provisions preceding subpar. (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/B/iii">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(B)(iii)</ref>, substituted “55 years of age” for “60 years of age”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/B/iv">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(B)(iv)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/C/i">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(C)(i)</ref>, inserted provision that the annuity payable under this subsection to the widow or widower of an employee or Member may not exceed the difference between the amount which would otherwise be payable to such widow or widower under this subsection and the amount of the survivor annuity payable to any former spouse of such employee or Member under subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> substituted “and (n)” for “and (<i>o</i>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/C/ii">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(C)(ii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (A) as cl. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/C/ii">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(C)(ii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (B) as cl. (ii) and substituted “55 years of age” for “60 years of age”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/D/i">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(D)(i)</ref>, inserted “or a former spouse who is the natural or adoptive parent of a surviving child of the employee or Member” in provisions preceding subpar. (A) and following subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/D/ii">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(D)(ii)</ref>, substituted “surviving spouse or former spouse” for “surviving spouse” and “spouse, former spouse, or child” for “spouse or child” in provisions following subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/E">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(E)</ref>, inserted provision that an annuity payable under this subsection to the surviving spouse of a Member may not exceed the difference between the annuity which would otherwise be payable to such surviving spouse under this subsection and the amount of the survivor annuity payable to any former spouse of such Member under subsec. (h) of this section in provisions following par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/F">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(F)</ref>, substituted “55 years of age” for “60 years of age” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/4/G">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(4)(G)</ref>, added subsecs. (h) and (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/96/179/s1/1">Pub. L. 96–179, § 1(1)</ref>, struck out “and” after “marriage;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/179/s1/2">Pub. L. 96–179, § 1(2)</ref>, added par. (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/96/179/s1/3">Pub. L. 96–179, § 1(3)</ref>, redesignated former par. (3) as (4), substituted “unmarried dependent child” for “unmarried child” wherever appearing in subpars. (A), (B), and (C), substituted “but only if the stepchild” for “or recognized natural child who” in subpar. (A)(ii), and inserted “a recognized natural child, and (iv)” after “(iii)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/2">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Office of Personnel Management” for “Civil Service Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s338/c/1">Pub. L. 95–598, § 338(c)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to subsec. (<i>o</i>) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339">section 8339 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/3">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Office” for “Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/317">Pub. L. 95–317</ref> inserted provisions relating to failure to file an election under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j">section 8339(j) of this title</ref> in the case of remarriage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s338/c/2">Pub. L. 95–598, § 338(c)(2)</ref>, inserted reference to subsec. (<i>o</i>) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339">section 8339 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/3">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Office” for “Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/318">Pub. L. 95–318</ref> struck out “after <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>,” after “terminated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/183">Pub. L. 94–183</ref> substituted “8339(k)(1)” for “8339(k)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a)(1)(A), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/93/260">Pub. L. 93–260</ref> substituted “1 year” for “2 years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/92/243">Pub. L. 92–243</ref> added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/297/s7/4/i">Pub. L. 92–297, § 7(4)(i)</ref>, substituted “section 8339(a)–(i)”, “section 8339(j)”, and “section 8339(k)” for “section 8339(a)–(h)”, “section 8339(i)”, and “section 8339(j)”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/92/297/s7/4/ii">Pub. L. 92–297, § 7(4)(ii)</ref>, substituted “section 8339(k)” for “section 8339(j)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/92/297/s7/4/iii">Pub. L. 92–297, § 7(4)(iii)</ref>, substituted “section 8339(a)–(f) and (i)” for “section 8339(a)–(e) and (h)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/91/658/s3/a">Pub. L. 91–658, § 3(a)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which defined “dependent widower”, and redesignated par. (4) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/658/s3/b">Pub. L. 91–658, § 3(b)</ref>, designated existing first sentence as par. (1), and inserted exception phrase, provision for survival by widow or widower whom employee or Member marries after retirement, entitlement of widow or widower to 55 percent annuity (limited to 50 percent where retirement before <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>), and substituted “any spouse surviving him” for “his spouse”; added par. (2); and added par. (3), first sentence, respecting entitlement to survivor annuity by a spouse acquired after retirement upon election from available survivor benefits, and designated as second and third sentences former second and third sentences, providing for widows and widowers and substituting “annuitant” for “retired employee or member”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/658/s3/c">Pub. L. 91–658, § 3(c)</ref>, substituted “his widow or widower” for “the widow or dependent widower of the employee or Member” in first sentence, struck out “or dependent” before “widower” in second sentence, and substituted in third sentence provision for termination of annuity where widow or widower dies or remarries before becoming 60 years of age for prior termination of annuity before widow or dependent widower dies, the dependent widower becomes capable of self-support, the widow or dependent widower of an employee remarries before becoming 60 years of age, or the widow or dependent widower of a member remarries.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/658/s3/d">Pub. L. 91–658, § 3(d)</ref>, substituted reference to “subsection (a)(3)” for “subsection (a)(4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s206/a">Pub. L. 91–93, § 206(a)</ref>, provided for entitlement to a survivor annuity after an 18 month rather than a 5 year period of civilian service and prescribed as the annuity the smaller of two computations when computing the annuity under section 8399 (a) to (e) and (h) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s206/b">Pub. L. 91–93, § 206(b)</ref>, increased annuity of a surviving child, substituting “eighteen months” for “five years” of civilian service in par. (1), “60 percent”, “$900”, and “$2,700” for “40 percent”, “$600”, and “$1,800” in cls. (A), (B), and (C), respectively, and “75 percent”, “$1,080”, and “$3,240”, for “50 percent”, “$720”, and “$2,160” in cls. (i), (ii), and (iii), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8e698f7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698f8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref> effective on the first day of the first applicable pay period that begins on <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, and applicable only to an individual who is employed as a member of the Supreme Court Police after <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, see section 1(a)(2) [title III, § 308(i), (j)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/553">Pub. L. 106–553</ref>, set out in a Supreme Court Police Retirement note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8331">section 8331 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698f9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/61/s516/a">section 516(a) of Pub. L. 105–61</ref> applicable to any annuity commencing before, on, or after <date date="1997-10-10">Oct. 10, 1997</date>, and effective with regard to any payment made after the first month following <date date="1997-10-10">Oct. 10, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/61/s516/b">section 516(b) of Pub. L. 105–61</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334">section 8334 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/61/s518/c">Section 518(c) of Pub. L. 105–61</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/61/s518/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 8442 and 8445 of this title] shall apply with respect to remarriages occurring on or after <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698fa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p>Section 101(f) [title VI, § 633(b)] of <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section and sections 8443 and 8908 of this title] shall apply with respect to any termination of marriage taking effect before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>], except that benefits shall be payable only with respect to amounts accruing for periods beginning on the first day of the month beginning after the later of such termination of marriage or such date of enactment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698fb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> effective with respect to service performed on or after <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s15204/b">section 15204(b) of Pub. L. 99–272</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339">section 8339 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698fc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s4">Pub. L. 98–615, § 4</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3204">98 Stat. 3204</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 99–251, title II, § 201(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/20">100 Stat. 20</ref>, 22; <ref href="/us/pl/99/549/s9/a">Pub. L. 99–549, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3065">100 Stat. 3065</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/556/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 99–556, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3139">100 Stat. 3139</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/238/tI/s127">Pub. L. 100–238, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="1988-01-08">Jan. 8, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1758">101 Stat. 1758</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/238/tI/s127">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) and subsections (b) and (c), the amendments made by section 2 of this Act [amending this section and sections 8331, 8334, 8339, 8342, 8345, and 8348 of this title] shall take effect <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, and shall apply—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to any individual who, on or after such date, is married to an employee or Member who, on or after such date, retires, dies, or applies for a refund of contributions under subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5, United States Code, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to any individual who, as of such date, is married to a retired employee or Member,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless (i) such employee or Member has waived, under the first sentence of section 8339(j)(1) of such title (or a similar prior provision of law), the right of that individual’s spouse to receive a survivor annuity, or (ii) in the case of a post-retirement marriage or remarriage, an election has not been made before such date by such employee or Member with respect to such individual under the applicable provisions of section 8339(j)(1) or 8339(k)(2) of such title, as the case may be (or a similar prior provision of law).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Except as provided in subsection (f), the amendments made by section 3 of this Act [amending sections 8901 to 8903, 8905, 8907, 8909, and 8913 of this title] shall take effect <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, and shall apply to any individual who, on or after such date, is married to an employee or annuitant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> The amendments made by subparagraphs (B)(iii) and (C)(ii) of section 2(4) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of this title</ref>] (relating to the termination of survivor benefits for a widow or widower who remarries before age 55) and the amendments made by subparagraph (F) of such section 2(4) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of this title</ref>] (relating to the restoration of a survivor annuity upon the dissolution of such a remarriage) shall apply—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> in the case of a remarriage occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with respect to periods beginning on or after such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the amendment made by section 2(3)(A) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339">section 8339 of this title</ref>] (but only to the extent that it amends title 5, United States Code, by adding a new section 8339(j)(5)(C)) and the amendment made by section 2(3)(C) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339">section 8339 of this title</ref>] (which relate to the election of a survivor annuity for a spouse in the case of a post-retirement marriage or remarriage) shall apply—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to an employee or Member who retires before, on, or after <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> in the case of a marriage occurring on or after <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The amendments referred to in subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of a marriage of an employee or Member retiring before <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, if the marriage occurred after <date date="1985-05-06">May 6, 1985</date>, and before the date of the enactment of the Federal Employees Benefits Improvement Act of 1986 [<date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Any election by an employee or Member described in subparagraph (B) to provide a survivor annuity for that individual’s spouse by a marriage described in such subparagraph shall be effective if made in accordance with the applicable provisions of section 8339(j)(1) or 8339(k)(2) of title 5, United States Code, as the case may be, as in effect on <date date="1985-05-06">May 6, 1985</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Paragraphs (3), (4), and (5)(B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j">section 8339(j) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (as added by section 2(3)(A) of this Act), shall apply in the case of a former spouse of an employee or Member whose marriage to such employee or Member terminated before <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, if such employee or Member retires on or after such date. The paragraphs referred to in the preceding sentence shall so apply only insofar as they relate to an election to provide a survivor annuity for a former spouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The requirement described in clause (ii) shall not apply to an election made by an employee or Member under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/3">section 8339(j)(3) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (as amended by section 2(3)(A) of this Act), in order to provide a survivor annuity under section 8341(h) of such title (as amended by section 2(4)(G) of this Act) in the case of a former spouse referred to in subparagraph (A) if the election meets the requirements of clause (iii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The requirement referred to in clause (i) is the requirement prescribed in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j/3">section 8339(j)(3) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, for an employee or Member to make an election in the case of a former spouse under such section 8339(j)(3) at the time of retirement or, if later, within 2 years after the date on which the marriage of the former spouse to the employee or Member is dissolved.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Clause (i) applies to an election which is made by an employee or Member who retires on or after <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, and before the date of the enactment of the Federal Employees Benefits Improvement Act of 1986 [<date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>], and is received by the Office of Personnel Management within the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of such Act.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A survivor annuity shall be paid a former spouse as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341/h">section 8341(h) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (as amended by section 2(4)(G) of this Act), pursuant to an election made in the case of such former spouse under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The amendments made by paragraphs (6) and (7) of section 2 of this Act [amending sections 8345 and 8348 of this title] shall apply in the case of survivor annuities and elections authorized by this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The amendment made by section 2(4)(A) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of this title</ref>] (relating to the definition of a widow or widower) and the amendment made by section 2(4)(G) of this Act (but only to the extent that it amends title 5, United States Code, by adding a new section 8341(i)) shall apply with respect to any marriage occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1) of this section, a former spouse of an employee or Member who retired before <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, or who died after becoming eligible to retire and before such date, is entitled to a survivor annuity under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b">section 8341(b) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the retired employee or Member elects, in writing, within eighteen months after the date of enactment of this Act, according to procedures prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, to have the annuity of such employee or Member reduced under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/j">section 8339(j) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act, and, except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, to deposit in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund an amount determined by the Office, as nearly as may be administratively feasible, to reflect the amount by which such employee or Member’s annuity would have been reduced had the reduction been in effect since such employee or Member’s annuity commenced, plus interest computed at the annual rate of six percent for each year during which the annuity would have been reduced if the election had been in effect on and after the date the annuity commenced; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> where the employee or Member dies or died on or before the one hundred and eightieth day after the date of enactment of this Act or does not make the election described in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the former spouse’s marriage to the employee or Member was dissolved after <date date="1978-09-14">September 14, 1978</date>, and before <date date="1987-05-08">May 8, 1987</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the former spouse was married to the employee or Member for at least ten years during periods of creditable service under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of title 5</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the former spouse has not remarried before age fifty-five after <date date="1978-09-14">September 14, 1978</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> the former spouse files an application for the survivor annuity with the Office on or before <date date="1989-05-07">May 7, 1989</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> the former spouse is at least fifty years of age on <date date="1987-05-07">May 7, 1987</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">A survivor annuity under subparagraph (B) shall commence on the day after the employee or Member dies or the first day of the second month after the former spouse’s application is received by the Office, whichever occurs later.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), if a retired employee or Member who makes an election under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) does not make the deposit required by such subparagraph, the Office shall collect the amount of the deposit by offset against the employee or Member’s annuity, up to a maximum of 25 per centum of the net annuity otherwise payable to the employee or Member, and the employee or Member is deemed to consent to such offset.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> An election made by an individual under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) of this subsection to provide a survivor annuity for any person prospectively voids any election previously made by such individual with respect to such person under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339/k/1">section 8339(k)(1) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act, or any similar prior provision of law. Notwithstanding the provisions of such subparagraph (A), an individual who made such an election under such section 8339(k)(1) (or prior provision) shall not be required to make the deposit described in such subparagraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A former spouse of an employee or Member referred to in the matter before subparagraph (A) in paragraph (1) of this section shall be entitled to a survivor annuity under subparagraph (B) of such paragraph if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the former spouse satisfies the requirements of clauses (ii) through (v) of such subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> there is no surviving spouse of the employee or Member and no other former spouse of such employee or Member who is entitled to receive a survivor annuity under subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5, United States Code, based on the service of such employee or Member which is creditable under such subchapter and there is no other person who has been designated to receive a survivor annuity under such subchapter by reason of an insurable interest in such employee or Member.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> For the purposes of this paragraph, the term ‘surviving spouse’ means a widow or a widower as defined in paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341/a">section 8341(a) of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><chapeau> A survivor annuity provided under this subsection shall be 55 per centum of the annuity of the retired employee or Member (or of that portion of the annuity which such employee or Member may have designated for this purpose under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection), as determined under section 8339(a)–(i) and (n) of title 5, United States Code, increased by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the total percent increase the retired employee or Member was receiving under section 8340 of such title at death, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in the case of a retired employee or Member whose date of death precedes the one hundred and eightieth day after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>], the total percent increase the retired employee or Member would have received under such section 8340 had such individual died on the one hundred and eightieth day after such date of enactment,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and shall not be subject to reduction under section 8341(h)(2) of such title, as amended by this Act.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1) of this section, an employee or Member who retired before the one hundred and eightieth day after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>] and who is married to a spouse acquired after retirement for whom such employee or Member was unable to provide a survivor annuity because—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the employee or Member was married at the time of retirement and elected not to provide a survivor annuity for the employee or Member’s spouse at the time of retirement, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the employee or Member failed to notify the Office of the employee or Member’s post-retirement marriage within one year after the marriage,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may elect in writing, within one year after the date of enactment of this Act, in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Office, to provide for a survivor annuity for such spouse under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341/b">section 8341(b) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act, to have the retired employee or Member’s annuity reduced under section 8339(j) of such title, as so amended, and to deposit in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund an amount determined by the Office, as nearly as may be administratively feasible, to reflect the amount by which such employee or Member’s annuity would have been reduced had the election been continuously in effect since the annuity commenced, plus interest. For the purposes of the preceding sentence, the annual rate of interest for each year during which the annuity would have been reduced if the election had been in effect on and after the date the annuity commenced shall be 6 percent. If the retired employee or Member does not make such deposit, the Office shall collect such amount by offset against such employee or Member’s annuity, up to a maximum of 25 percent of the net annuity otherwise payable to such employee or Member, and such employee or Member is deemed to consent to such offset. The Office shall provide for general public notice of the right to make an election under this subsection. In cases to which paragraph (2) of this subsection applies, the retired employee or Member shall provide the Office with such documentation as the Office shall decide is appropriate, that such employee or Member attempted to elect a reduced annuity with survivor benefit for such employee or Member’s current spouse and that such employee or Member’s election was rejected by the Office because it was untimely filed.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> A deposit required by subsection (b)(1)(A) or (c) of this section may be made by the surviving former spouse or spouse, as applicable, of the retired employee or Member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><chapeau> The Office shall determine at the end of each fiscal year—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the cost of survivor annuities provided under subsections (b) and (c) of this section, less an amount determined appropriate by the Office to reflect the value of any deposits made under subsection (b)(1)(A), (c), or (d), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the cost of administering subsections (b) and (c).</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Office shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury of the amounts so determined. The Secretary of the Treasury, before closing the account for the fiscal year in question, shall credit to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts, which shall be available in the same manner as provided under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a/1">section 8348(a)(1) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><chapeau> Any individual—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> who is entitled to a survivor annuity under subsection (b) of this section or pursuant to an election authorized by reason of the application of subsection (a)(5) of this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> as to whom a court order or decree referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8345/j">section 8345(j) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (or similar provision of law under a retirement system for Government employees other than the Civil Service Retirement System) has been issued before <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> who is entitled (other than as described in paragraph (2)) to an annuity or any portion of an annuity as a former spouse under a retirement system for Government employees as of <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be considered to have satisfied <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8901/10/C">section 8901(10)(C) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act. Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2) of this section, any such individual who otherwise meets the definition of a former spouse under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8901">section 8901 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as so amended, may, within 12 months after the date of the enactment of the Federal Employees Benefits Improvement Act of 1986 [<date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>], enroll in an approved health benefits plan described by section 8903 of such title, under the conditions set forth in section 8905(c) of such title, as so amended (other than the conditions prescribed in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) of such section 8905(c)).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For purposes of subsections (a)(1), (b), (c), (d), and (e), ‘employee’, ‘Member’, and ‘former spouse’ each has the meaning given that term under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8331">section 8331 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> For purposes of subsection (a)(2), ‘employee’ and ‘annuitant’ each has the meaning given that term under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8901">section 8901 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><content> Section 827 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4067">22 U.S.C. 4067</ref>] and section 292 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees [former <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403">50 U.S.C. 403</ref> note] shall not apply with respect to either the amendments made by section 2 [amending sections 8331, 8334, 8339, 8341, 8342, 8345, and 8348 of this title] or the preceding provisions of this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/99/556/s501/b">Section 501(b) of Pub. L. 99–556</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/556/s501/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending note above] shall be effective as of <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/99/549/s9/b">Section 9(b) of Pub. L. 99–549</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/549/s9/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending note above] shall be effective as of <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[The Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees, referred to in <ref href="/us/pl/98/615">Pub. L. 98–615</ref>, set out above, is <ref href="/us/pl/88/643">Pub. L. 88–643</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1043">78 Stat. 1043</ref>, which was revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/tVIII/s802">Pub. L. 102–496, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3196">106 Stat. 3196</ref>, is known as the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act and is classified generally to chapter 38 (§ 2001 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s122/a">section 122(a) of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s151">section 151 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698fd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/179/s5/a">Section 5(a) of Pub. L. 96–179</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/179/s5/a">“The amendments made by the first section [amending this section] and section 2 of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8901">section 8901 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>], except that no benefits under chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, made available by reason of such amendments shall be payable for any period before <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698fe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref> effective <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s402/d">section 402(d) of Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of Title 11</ref>, Bankruptcy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/95/318/s3">Section 3 of Pub. L. 95–318</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/318/s3">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“The foregoing provisions of this Act [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] shall take effect on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the first day of the month following the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-07-10">July 10, 1978</date>], or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> <date date="1978-10-01">October 1, 1978</date>,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever date is later.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e698ff-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment; Survivor Annuities Subject to Reduction, Etc.</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/317">Pub. L. 95–317</ref> as first day of first month which begins on or after date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/95/317">Pub. L. 95–317</ref>, which was approved <date date="1978-07-10">July 10, 1978</date>, or <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, whichever is later, and provisions respecting eligibility of an individual to a survivor annuity, or the reduction therefor, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/317/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 95–317</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339">section 8339 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e69900-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/260/s1/b">Section 1(b) of Pub. L. 93–260</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/260/s1/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) of this section [amending this section] shall not apply in the cases of employees, Members, or annuitants who died before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1974-04-09">Apr. 9, 1974</date>]. The rights of such individuals and their survivors shall continue in the same manner and to the same extent as if such amendments had not been enacted.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e69901-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/297">Pub. L. 92–297</ref> effective on 90th day after <date date="1972-05-16">May 16, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/297/s10">section 10 of Pub. L. 92–297</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3381">section 3381 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/92/243/s2">Section 2 of Pub. L. 92–243</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/243/s2">“The amendment made by the first section of this Act [amending this section] is effective upon enactment [<date date="1972-03-09">Mar. 9, 1972</date>]. Upon application to the Civil Service Commission, it also applies to a child of an employee or Member who died or retired before such date of enactment [<date date="1972-03-09">Mar. 9, 1972</date>] but no annuity shall be paid by reason of the amendment for any period prior to the date of enactment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e69902-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/189/s2">Section 2 of Pub. L. 91–189</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/189/s2">“The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e">section 8341(e) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s206/b">section 206(b) of Public Law 91–93</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/83/140">83 Stat. 140</ref>), shall be effective as of <date date="1969-10-20">October 20, 1969</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/93">Pub. L. 91–93</ref> inapplicable in cases of persons retired or otherwise separated prior to <date date="1969-10-20">Oct. 20, 1969</date>, their rights and of their survivors continued as if such amendment had not been enacted, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s207/a">section 207(a) of Pub. L. 91–93</ref> set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8331">section 8331 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8e69903-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment; Recomputation and Reduction of Survivor Annuities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s207/c">Section 207(c) of Pub. L. 91–93</ref> provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/93/s207/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The amendment made by section 206(b) of this Act [amending this section] shall become effective on the first day of the first month which begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1969-10-20">Oct. 20, 1969</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The annuity of each surviving child who, immediately prior to the effective date of such amendment [amending this section] is receiving an annuity under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341/e">section 8341(e) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, or under a comparable provision of any prior law, or who hereafter becomes entitled to receive annuity under the Act of <date date="1930-05-29">May 29, 1930</date>, as amended from and after <date date="1948-02-28">February 28, 1948</date>, shall be recomputed effective on such date, or computed from commencing date if later, in accordance with such amendment. No increase allowed and in force prior to such date shall be included in the computation or recomputation of any such annuity. This paragraph shall not operate to reduce any annuity.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8e69904-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Additional Elections Under Civil Service Retirement Spouse Equity Act of 1984</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/251/s201/d">Section 201(d) of Pub. L. 99–251</ref> provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/251/s201/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding the time limitation prescribed in subparagraph (A) of section 4(b)(1) of the Civil Service Retirement Spouse Equity Act of 1984 [<ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s4/b/1/A">Pub. L. 98–615, § 4(b)(1)(A)</ref>, set out as a note above], an election may be made under such subparagraph before the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the regulations under paragraph (3) of this subsection first take effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any retired employee or Member who has made an election under section 4(b)(1)(A) of the Civil Service Retirement Spouse Equity Act of 1984 [set out as a note above] (as in effect at the time of such election) before the regulations under paragraph (3) of this subsection become effective may modify such election by designating, in writing, that only a portion of such employee or Member’s annuity is to be used as the base for the survivor annuity for the former spouse for whom the election was made. A modification under this subparagraph shall be subject to the deadline under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection, including regulations under which an appropriate refund shall be made in the case of a modification under paragraph (2) of this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8e69905-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Restoration of Survivor Annuities for Certain Widows and Widowers Remarrying Before <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, and Where Member Died Before <date date="1971-01-08">January 8, 1971</date></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/318/s1">Section 1 of Pub. L. 95–318</ref>, eff. <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/318/s1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> Upon application to the Civil Service Commission, the annuity of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a surviving spouse of an employee which was terminated under the provisions of section 8341 (b) or (d) of title 5, United States Code, or of any prior applicable law, because of the remarriage of such spouse before <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a surviving spouse of a Member who died before <date date="1971-01-08">January 8, 1971</date>, which was terminated under any such provision, because of the remarriage of such spouse,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be restored in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of a remarriage occurring after the surviving spouse became sixty years of age, the annuity shall be restored to such spouse under subsection (a) of this section only if any lump sum paid on termination of the annuity is returned to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund. If such amount is paid, the annuity shall be so restored commencing on the effective date of this section at the rate which would have been in effect if the annuity had not been terminated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> In the case of a remarriage occurring before the surviving spouse became sixty years of age, the annuity shall be restored to such spouse under subsection (a) of this section only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> such spouse elects to receive this annuity instead of a survivor benefit to which the spouse may be entitled under subchapter III of chapter 83 of such title 5 or under another retirement system for Government employees by reason of the marriage; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any lump sum paid on termination of the annuity is returned to such fund.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the requirements of the preceding sentence are satisfied, such annuity shall be so restored commencing on the effective date of this section or on the first day of the month following the date the remarriage is dissolved by death, annulment, or divorce, whichever date is later, at the rate which was in effect when the annuity was terminated.”</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8e69906-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Increase in Annuity Payable to Surviving Spouses of Members, Employees, of Annuities Based on Separation Occurring Prior to <date date="1969-10-20">Oct. 20, 1969</date></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/273/s2/b">Section 2(b) of Pub. L. 93–273</ref>, <date date="1974-04-26">Apr. 26, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/93">88 Stat. 93</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/273/s2/b">“In lieu of any increase based on an increase under subsection (a) of this section, an annuity payable from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund to the surviving spouse of an employee, Member, or annuitant, which is based on a separation occurring prior to <date date="1969-10-20">October 20, 1969</date> shall be increased by $132.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/273/s3">Section 3 of Pub. L. 93–273</ref>, <date date="1974-04-26">Apr. 26, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/93">88 Stat. 93</ref> provided in part that annuity increases under this pension shall apply to annuities which commence before, on, or after <date date="1974-04-26">Apr. 26, 1974</date>, but that no increase in annuity shall be paid for any period prior to the first day of the first month which begins on or after the ninetieth day after <date date="1974-04-26">Apr. 26, 1974</date>, or the date on which the annuity commences, whichever is later. See <ref href="/us/pl/93/273/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 93–273</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8345">section 8345 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8e69907-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Remarriage Provisions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s205">Section 205 of Pub. L. 91–93</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/93/s205">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“The provisions of subsection (b)(1), (d)(3), and (g) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, also shall apply in the case of any widow or widower—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> of an employee who died, retired, or was otherwise finally separated before <date date="1966-07-18">July 18, 1966</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> who shall have remarried on or after such date; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> who, immediately before such remarriage, was receiving annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that no annuity shall be paid by reason of this section for any period prior to the enactment of this section. No annuity shall be terminated solely by reason of the enactment of this section. Notwithstanding the prohibition contained in the first sentence of this section on the payment of annuity for any period prior to the enactment of this section, in any case in which the Civil Service Commission determines that—</continuation>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the remarriage of any widow or widower described in such sentence was entered into by the widow or widower in good faith and in reliance on erroneous information provided by Government authority prior to that remarriage that the then existing survivor annuity of the widow or widower would not be terminated because of the remarriage; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> such annuity was terminated by law because of that remarriage;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then payment of annuity may be made by reason of this section in such case, beginning as of the effective date of the termination because of the remarriage.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
