<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8eb7b2e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347"><num value="8347">§ 8347.</num><heading> Administration; regulations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b2f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Office of Personnel Management shall administer this subchapter. Except as otherwise specifically provided herein, the Office shall perform, or cause to be performed, such acts and prescribe such regulations as are necessary and proper to carry out this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b30-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Applications under this subchapter shall be in such form as the Office prescribes. Agencies shall support the applications by such certificates as the Office considers necessary to the determination of the rights of applicants. The Office shall adjudicate all claims under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b31-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Office shall determine questions of disability and dependency arising under this subchapter. Except to the extent provided under subsection (d) of this section, the decisions of the Office concerning these matters are final and conclusive and are not subject to review. The Office may direct at any time such medical or other examinations as it considers necessary to determine the facts concerning disability or dependency of an individual receiving or applying for annuity under this subchapter. The Office may suspend or deny annuity for failure to submit to examination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b32-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b33-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an administrative action or order affecting the rights or interests of an individual or of the United States under this subchapter may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board under procedures prescribed by the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b34-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of any individual found by the Office to be disabled in whole or in part on the basis of the individual’s mental condition, and that finding was made pursuant to an application by an agency for purposes of disability retirement under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8337/a">section 8337(a) of this title</ref>, the procedures under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7701">section 7701 of this title</ref> shall apply and the decision of the Board shall be subject to judicial review under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b35-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The Office shall fix the fees for examinations made under this subchapter by physicians or surgeons who are not medical officers of the United States. The fees and reasonable traveling and other expenses incurred in connection with the examinations are paid from appropriations for the cost of administering this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b36-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Office shall select three actuaries, to be known as the Board of Actuaries of the Civil Service Retirement System. The Office shall fix the pay of the members of the Board, except members otherwise in the employ of the United States. The Board shall report annually on the actuarial status of the System and furnish its advice and opinion on matters referred to it by the Office. The Board may recommend to the Office and to Congress such changes as in the Board’s judgment are necessary to protect the public interest and maintain the System on a sound financial basis. The Office shall keep, or cause to be kept, such records as it considers necessary for making periodic actuarial valuations of the System. The Board shall make actuarial valuations every 5 years, or oftener if considered necessary by the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b37-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The Office may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee or group of employees in or under an Executive agency whose employment is temporary or intermittent. However, the Office may not exclude any employee who occupies a position on a part-time career employment basis (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3401/2">section 3401(2) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b38-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The Office, on recommendation by the Mayor of the District of Columbia, may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an individual or group of individuals employed by the government of the District of Columbia whose employment is temporary or intermittent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b39-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Architect of the Capitol may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee under the Office of the Architect of the Capitol whose employment is temporary or of uncertain duration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b3a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> The Librarian of Congress may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee under the Library of Congress whose employment is temporary or of uncertain duration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b3b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> The Secretary of Agriculture shall prescribe regulations to effect the application and operation of this subchapter to an individual named by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8331/1/F">section 8331(1)(F) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b3c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> The Director or Acting Director of the Botanic Garden may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee under the Botanic Garden whose employment is temporary or of uncertain duration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b3d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the purpose of ensuring the accuracy of information used in the administration of this chapter, at the request of the Director of the Office of Personnel Management—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b3e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary’s designee shall provide information on retired or retainer pay provided under title 10;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b3f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide information on pensions or compensation provided under title 38;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b40-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary’s <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002170">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002170"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Commissioner’s”.</note> designee shall provide information contained in the records of the Social Security Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b41-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/m/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Secretary of Labor or the Secretary’s designee shall provide information on benefits paid under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Director shall request only such information as the Director determines is necessary. The Director, in consultation with the officials from whom information is requested, shall establish, by regulation and otherwise, such safeguards as are necessary to ensure that information made available under this subsection is used only for the purpose authorized.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b42-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b43-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Director of Central Intelligence shall, in a manner consistent with the administration of this subchapter by the Office, and to the extent considered appropriate by the Director of Central Intelligence—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b44-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> determine entitlement to benefits under this subchapter based on the service of employees of the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b45-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> maintain records relating to the service of such employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b46-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> compute benefits under this subchapter based on the service of such employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b47-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> collect deposits to the Fund made by such employees, their spouses, and their former spouses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b48-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> authorize and direct disbursements from the Fund to the extent based on service of such employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b49-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> perform such other functions under this subchapter as the Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b4a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall furnish such information and, on a reimbursable basis, such services to the Director of Central Intelligence as the Director of Central Intelligence requests to carry out paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b4b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b4c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall by regulation prescribe appropriate procedures to carry out this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b4d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The regulations shall provide procedures for the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to inspect and audit disbursements from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b4e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Director of Central Intelligence shall submit the regulations prescribed under subparagraph (A) to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives before the regulations take effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b4f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b50-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Section 201(c) of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act shall apply in the administration of this subchapter to the extent that the provisions of this subchapter are administered under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b51-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/n/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8347/d">section 8347(d) of this title</ref> shall apply with respect to employees of the Central Intelligence Agency who are subject to the Civil Service Retirement System.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b52-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content> Any provision of law outside of this subchapter which provides coverage, service credit, or any other benefit under this subchapter to any individuals who (based on their being employed by an entity other than the Government) would not otherwise be eligible for any such coverage, credit, or benefit, shall not apply with respect to any individual appointed, transferred, or otherwise commencing that type of employment on or after <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b53-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content> The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the Federal Judicial Center, or a court named by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s610">section 610 of title 28</ref>, whose employment is temporary or of uncertain duration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b54-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b55-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, an employee who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b56-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has not previously made an election under this subsection or had an opportunity to make an election under this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b57-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> moves, without a break in service of more than 1 year, to employment in a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, described in section 2105(c),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be given the opportunity to elect irrevocably, within 30 days after such move, to remain covered as an employee under this subchapter during any employment described in section 2105(c) after such move.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8eb7b58-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, an employee of a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, described in section 2105(c), who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b59-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has not previously made an election under this subsection or had an opportunity to make an election under this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b5a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is a participant in a retirement system established for employees described in section 2105(c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b5b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> moves, without a break in service of more than 1 year, to a position that is not described in section 2105(c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8eb7b5c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8347/q/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> is excluded from coverage under chapter 84 by section 8402(b),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be given the opportunity to elect irrevocably, within 30 days after such move, to remain covered, during any subsequent employment as an employee as defined in section 2105(a) or section 2105(c), by the retirement system applicable to such employee’s current or most recent employment described in section 2105(c) rather than be subject to this subchapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8eb7b5d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/583">80 Stat. 583</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/83/s1/84">Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(84)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/218">81 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/623/s1/22">Pub. L. 90–623, § 1(22)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1313">82 Stat. 1313</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/437/s4/a">Pub. L. 95–437, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1058">92 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tIX/s906/a/2">Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), (9), (c)(2)(F), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1224">92 Stat. 1224</ref>, 1225, 1227; <ref href="/us/pl/96/54/s2/a/50">Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(50)</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/384">93 Stat. 384</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/499/tIV/s404/b">Pub. L. 96–499, title IV, § 404(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2606">94 Stat. 2606</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/500/s1">Pub. L. 96–500, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2696">94 Stat. 2696</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 97–253, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/793">96 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tII/s207/i">Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(i)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/596">100 Stat. 596</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/238/tI/s108/a/1">Pub. L. 100–238, title I, § 108(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-01-08">Jan. 8, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1747">101 Stat. 1747</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/474/s5/n">Pub. L. 101–474, § 5(n)</ref>, <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1100">104 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII/s7202/j/2">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7202(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-337">104 Stat. 1388–337</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/54/s13/b/5">Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/274">105 Stat. 274</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/64">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(64)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1354">106 Stat. 1354</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/tVIII/s803/c">Pub. L. 102–496, title VIII, § 803(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3253">106 Stat. 3253</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s108/e/5">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(e)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1486">108 Stat. 1486</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tX/s1043/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1043(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/434">110 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tXI/s1131/a">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XI, § 1131(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1242">115 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8eb7b5e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8eb7b5f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb8eb7b60-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style="">1966 <html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Act</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Derivation</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>U.S. Code</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised Statutes and</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Statutes at Large</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>(a)–(f)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s2266">5 U.S.C. 2266</html:a> (less (f)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1956-07-31/ch804/s401">July 31, 1956, ch. 804, § 401</html:a> “Sec. 16 (less (f))”, <html:a href="/us/stat/70/758">70 Stat. 758</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>(g)–(k)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s2252/e">5 U.S.C. 2252(e)</html:a>, (f) (words after semicolon), (h) (1).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1956-07-31/ch804/s401">July 31, 1956, ch. 804, § 401</html:a> “Sec. 2(e), (f) (words after semicolon)”, <html:a href="/us/stat/70/745">70 Stat. 745</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">July 1, 1960</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/86/568/s115/b/1">Pub. L. 86–568, § 115(b)(1)</html:a> “(h) (1)”, <html:a href="/us/stat/74/302">74 Stat. 302</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), the words “to carry out this subchapter” are substituted for “for the purpose of carrying the provisions of this chapter into full force and effect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.</p>
</note>
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8eb7b61-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb8eb7b62-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style="">1967 <html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Act</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Section of title 5</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>8347(<html:i>l</html:i>)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 App.: 2252(f).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Sept. 26, 1966</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/604/s1/c">Pub. L. 89–604, § 1(c)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/80/847">80 Stat. 847</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8eb7b63-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb8eb7b64-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 201(c) of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act, referred to in subsec. (n)(4)(A), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2011/c">section 2011(c) of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8eb7b65-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (q)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s1131/a/1">Pub. L. 107–107, § 1131(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and” after semicolon in subpar. (A), redesignated subpar. (C) as (B), and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “has 5 or more years of civilian service creditable under this subchapter; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s1131/a/2">Pub. L. 107–107, § 1131(a)(2)</ref>, struck out “vested” before “participant in a retirement system” and struck out “, as the term ‘vested participant’ is defined by such system” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (q)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1043/a/1/A">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1043(a)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard” after “an employee” in introductory provisions and substituted “1 year” for “3 days” in subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1043/a/1/B">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1043(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “1 year” for “3 days” and struck out “in the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively,” after “to a position”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (m)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary of Health and Human Services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (n)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/496">Pub. L. 102–496</ref> substituted “the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act” for “the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/64/A">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(64)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (p), relating to employees of Department of Defense and Coast Guard, as (q).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/64/A">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(64)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (p), relating to employees of Department of Defense and Coast Guard, as (q).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q)(1)(A), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/64/B">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(64)(B)</ref>, amended subpars. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpars. (A) read as follows: “has not previously made or had an opportunity to make an election under this subsection;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (m)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/54">Pub. L. 102–54</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> added subsec. (p) relating to elections by employees of Department of Defense, Coast Guard, or a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of Department of Defense or Coast Guard.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/474">Pub. L. 101–474</ref> added subsec. (p) relating to Director of Administrative Office of United States Courts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/100/238">Pub. L. 100–238</ref> added subsec. (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (m)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/253">Pub. L. 97–253</ref> added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/500/s1/a">Pub. L. 96–500, § 1(a)</ref>, substituted “Except to the extent provided under subsection (d) of this section, the decisions of the Office concerning” for “The decisions of the Office concerning”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/500/s1/b">Pub. L. 96–500, § 1(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), made such par. (1) subject to the provisions of par. (2), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/96/499">Pub. L. 96–499</ref> added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/54">Pub. L. 96–54</ref> substituted “Mayor” for “Commissioner”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (a) to (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/2">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “Office of Personnel Management” and “Office” for “Civil Service Commission” and “Commission”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/9">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(9)</ref>, substituted “Merit Systems Protection Board” for “Commission”, and “Board” for “Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/3">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Office” for “Commission” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/3">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(3)</ref>, (c)(2)(F), substituted “Office” for “Commission” wherever appearing, and “3401” for “3391”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/437">Pub. L. 95–437</ref> inserted provision prohibiting the Commission from excluding any employee who occupies a position on a part-time career employment basis, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3391/2">section 3391(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s906/a/3">Pub. L. 95–454, § 906(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Office” for “Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/90/623">Pub. L. 90–623</ref> substituted “Commissioner” for “Commissioners”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8eb7b66-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb8eb7b67-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b68-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref>, see Regulations; Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b69-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b6a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/496">Pub. L. 102–496</ref> effective on first day of fourth month beginning after <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s805">section 805 of Pub. L. 102–496</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2001">section 2001 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/64">section 2(64) of Pub. L. 102–378</ref> effective <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s9/b/6">section 9(b)(6) of Pub. L. 102–378</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s6303">section 6303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b6b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable with respect to any individual who, on or after <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, moves from employment in nonappropriated fund instrumentality of Department of Defense or Coast Guard, that is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105/c">section 2105(c) of this title</ref>, to employment in Department or Coast Guard, that is not described in section 2105(c), or who moves from employment in Department or Coast Guard, that is not described in section 2105(c), to employment in nonappropriated fund instrumentality of Department or Coast Guard, that is described in section 2105(c), see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s7202/m/1">section 7202(m)(1) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105">section 2105 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b6c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> effective <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/s702/a">section 702(a) of Pub. L. 99–335</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401">section 8401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b6d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/253">Pub. L. 97–253</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/s302/c/1">section 302(c)(1) of Pub. L. 97–253</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/97/346/s3/i">section 3(i) of Pub. L. 97–346</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8337">section 8337 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b6e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/500/s2">Section 2 of Pub. L. 96–500</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/500/s2">“The amendments made by the first section of this Act [amending this section] shall apply with respect to determinations made by the Office of Personnel Management on or after the first day of the first month beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/499">Pub. L. 96–499</ref> effective <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/499/s404/c">section 404(c) of Pub. L. 96–499</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8339">section 8339 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b6f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/54">Pub. L. 96–54</ref> effective <date date="1979-07-12">July 12, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/54/s2/b">section 2(b) of Pub. L. 96–54</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s305">section 305 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b70-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8eb7b71-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/623">Pub. L. 90–623</ref> intended to restate without substantive change the law in effect on <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/623/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 90–623</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5334">section 5334 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8eb7b72-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations; Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p>Section 1043(b), (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/106">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>], the Office of Personnel Management (and each of the other administrative authorities, within the meaning of subsection (c)(2)(C)(iii)) shall prescribe any regulations (or make any modifications in existing regulations) necessary to carry out this section [amending this section and sections 3502 and 8461 of this title and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3502">section 3502 of this title</ref>] and the amendments made by this section, including regulations to provide for the notification of individuals who may be affected by the enactment of this section. All regulations (and modifications to regulations) under the preceding sentence shall take effect on the same date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability; Related Provisions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prospective rules</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 3502 and 8461 of this title] shall apply with respect to moves occurring on or after the effective date of the regulations under subsection (b). Moves occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>] and before the effective date of such regulations shall be subject to applicable provisions of title 5, United States Code, disregarding the amendments made by this section, except that any individual making an election pursuant to this sentence shall be ineligible to make an election otherwise allowable under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retroactive rules.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The regulations under subsection (b) shall include provisions for the application of sections 8347(q) and 8461(n) of title 5, United States Code, as amended by this section, with respect to any individual who, at any time after <date date="1965-12-31">December 31, 1965</date>, and before the effective date of such regulations, moved between positions in circumstances that would have qualified such individual to make an election under the provisions of such section 8347(q) or 8461(n), as so amended, if such provisions had then been in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline; related provisions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An election pursuant to this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> shall be made within 1 year after the effective date of the regulations under subsection (b), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> shall have the same force and effect as if it had been timely made at the time of the move,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I26" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">  except that no such election may be made by any individual—</continuation>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> who has previously made, or had an opportunity to make, an election under section 8347(q) or 8461(n) of title 5, United States Code (as in effect before being amended by this section); however, this subclause shall not be considered to render an individual ineligible, based on an opportunity arising out of a move occurring during the period described in the second sentence of paragraph (1), if no election has in fact been made by such individual based on such move;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> who has not, since the move on which eligibility for the election is based, remained continuously subject (disregarding any break in service of less than 3 days) to CSRS or FERS or both seriatim (if the move was from a NAFI position) or any retirement system (or 2 or more such systems seriatim) established for employees described in section 2105(c) of such title (if the move was to a NAFI position); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="III">“(III)</num><content> if such election would be based on a move to the Civil Service Retirement System from a retirement system established for employees described in section 2105(c) of such title.</content>
</subclause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfers of contributions.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>If an individual makes an election under this paragraph to be transferred back to a retirement system in which such individual previously participated (in this section referred to as the ‘previous system’), all individual contributions (including interest) and Government contributions to the retirement system in which such individual is then currently participating (in this section referred to as the ‘current system’), excluding those made to the Thrift Savings Plan or any other defined contribution plan, which are attributable to periods of service performed since the move on which the election is based, shall be paid to the fund, account, or other repository for contributions made under the previous system. For purposes of this section, the term ‘current system’ shall be considered also to include any retirement system (besides the one in which the individual is participating at the time of making the election) in which such individual previously participated since the move on which the election is based.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Condition subsequent relating to repayment of lump-sum credit</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of an individual who has received such individual’s lump-sum credit (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401/19">section 8401(19) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, or a similar payment) from such individual’s previous system, the payment described in clause (i) shall not be made (and the election to which it relates shall be ineffective) unless such lump-sum credit is redeposited or otherwise paid at such time and in such manner as shall be required under applicable regulations. Regulations to carry out this clause shall include provisions for the computation of interest (consistent with section 8334(e)(2) and (3) of title 5, United States Code), if no provisions for such computation otherwise exist.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Condition subsequent relating to deficiency in payments relative to amounts needed to ensure that benefits are fully funded.—</inline></heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subclause (II), the payment described in clause (i) shall not be made (and the election to which it relates shall be ineffective) if the actuarial present value of the future benefits that would be payable under the previous system with respect to service performed by such individual after the move on which the election under this paragraph is based and before the effective date of the election, exceeds the total amounts required to be transferred to the previous system under the preceding provisions of this subparagraph with respect to such service, as determined by the authority administering such previous system (in this section referred to as the ‘administrative authority’).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment of deficiency</inline>.—</heading><content>A determination of a deficiency under this clause shall not render an election ineffective if the individual pays or arranges to pay, at a time and in a manner satisfactory to such administrative authority, the full amount of the deficiency described in subclause (I).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternative election for an individual then participating in fers.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>This subparagraph applies with respect to any individual who—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> is then currently participating in FERS; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> would then otherwise be eligible to make an election under subparagraphs (A) through (C) of this paragraph, determined disregarding the matter in subclause (I) of subparagraph (B) before the first semicolon therein.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Election</inline>.—</heading><content>An individual described in clause (i) may, instead of making an election for which such individual is otherwise eligible under this paragraph, elect to have all prior qualifying NAFI service of such individual treated as creditable service for purposes of any annuity under FERS payable out of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualifying nafi service</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term ‘qualifying NAFI service’ means any service which, but for this subparagraph, would be creditable for purposes of any retirement system established for employees described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105/c">section 2105(c) of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Service ceases to be creditable for nafi retirement system purposes</inline>.—</heading><content>Any qualifying NAFI service that becomes creditable for FERS purposes by virtue of an election made under this subparagraph shall not be creditable for purposes of any retirement system referred to in clause (iii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An election under this subparagraph shall be subject to requirements, similar to those set forth in subparagraph (C), to ensure that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> appropriate transfers of individual and Government contributions are made to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> the actuarial present value of future benefits under FERS attributable to service made creditable by such election is fully funded.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternative election for an individual then participating in a nafi retirement system.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>This subparagraph applies with respect to any individual who—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> is then currently participating in any retirement system established for employees described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105/c">section 2105(c) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (in this subparagraph referred to as a ‘NAFI retirement system’); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> would then otherwise be eligible to make an election under subparagraphs (A) through (C) of this paragraph (determined disregarding the matter in subclause (I) of subparagraph (B) before the first semicolon therein) based on a move from FERS.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Election</inline>.—</heading><content>An individual described in clause (i) may, instead of making an election for which such individual is otherwise eligible under this paragraph, elect to have all prior qualifying FERS service of such individual treated as creditable service for purposes of determining eligibility for benefits under a NAFI retirement system, but not for purposes of computing the amount of any such benefits except as provided in clause (v)(II).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualifying fers service</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term ‘qualifying FERS service’ means any service which, but for this subparagraph, would be creditable for purposes of the Federal Employees’ Retirement System.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Service ceases to be creditable for purposes of fers</inline>.—</heading><content>Any qualifying FERS service that becomes creditable for NAFI purposes by virtue of an election made under this subparagraph shall not be creditable for purposes of the Federal Employees’ Retirement System.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding requirements.—</inline></heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subclause (II), nothing in this section or in any other provision of law or any other authority shall be considered to require any payment or transfer of monies in order for an election under this subparagraph to be effective.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contribution required only if individual elects to have service made creditable for computation purposes as well</inline>.—</heading><content>Under regulations prescribed by the appropriate administrative authority, an individual making an election under this subparagraph may further elect to have the qualifying FERS service made creditable for computation purposes under a NAFI retirement system, but only if the individual pays or arranges to pay, at a time and in a manner satisfactory to such administrative authority, the amount necessary to fully fund the actuarial present value of future benefits under the NAFI retirement system attributable to the qualifying FERS service.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The regulations under subsection (b) shall include provisions under which any individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> shall, upon request, be provided information or assistance in determining whether such individual is eligible to make an election under paragraph (2) and, if so, the exact amount of any payment which would be required of such individual in connection with any such election; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> may seek any other information or assistance relating to any such election.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8edc463-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which the report required by subsec. (f) of this section is listed on page 187), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb8edc464-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8edc465-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Treatment of Individuals Electing To Remain Subject to Their Former Retirement System</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to the deductions and contributions required with respect to individuals electing under section 8347(q) or 8461(n) of this title to remain covered under subchapter III of chapter 83 of this title, chapter 84 of this title, or a retirement system for employees described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105/c">section 2105(c) of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s7202/n">section 7202(n) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105">section 2105 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
