<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8edc466-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348"><num value="8348">§ 8348.</num><heading> Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc467-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> There is a Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund. The Fund—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc468-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> is appropriated for the payment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8edc469-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> benefits as provided by this subchapter or by the provisions of chapter 84 of this title which relate to benefits payable out of the Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8edc46a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> administrative expenses incurred by the Office of Personnel Management in placing in effect each annuity adjustment granted under section 8340 or 8462 of this title, in administering survivor annuities and elections providing therefor under sections 8339 and 8341 of this title or subchapters II and IV of chapter 84 of this title, in administering alternative forms of annuities under sections 8343a and 8420a (and related provisions of law), in making an allotment or assignment made by an individual under section 8345(h) or 8465(b) of this title, in administering fraud prevention under sections 8345, 8345a, 8466, and 8466a of this title, and in withholding taxes pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3405">section 3405 of title 26</ref> or section 8345(k) or 8469 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc46b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is made available, subject to such annual limitation as the Congress may prescribe, for any expenses incurred by the Office in connection with the administration of this chapter, chapter 84 of this title, and other retirement and annuity statutes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc46c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> is made available, subject to such annual limitation as the Congress may prescribe, for any expenses incurred by the Merit Systems Protection Board in the administration of appeals authorized under sections 8347(d) and 8461(e) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc46d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury may accept and credit to the Fund money received in the form of a donation, gift, legacy, or bequest, or otherwise contributed for the benefit of civil-service employees generally.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc46e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary shall immediately invest in interest-bearing securities of the United States such currently available portions of the Fund as are not immediately required for payments from the Fund. The income derived from these investments constitutes a part of the Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc46f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are extended to authorize the issuance at par of public-debt obligations for purchase by the Fund. The obligations issued for purchase by the Fund shall have maturities fixed with due regard for the needs of the Fund and bear interest at a rate equal to the average market yield computed as of the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of the issue, borne by all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt which are not due or callable until after the expiration of 4 years from the end of that calendar month. If the average market yield is not a multiple of ⅛ of 1 percent, the rate of interest on the obligations shall be the multiple of ⅛ of 1 percent nearest the average market yield.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc470-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The Secretary may purchase other interest-bearing obligations of the United States, or obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States, on original issue or at the market price only if he determines that the purchases are in the public interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc471-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> Any statute which authorizes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc472-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> new or liberalized benefits payable from the Fund, including annuity increases other than under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340">section 8340 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc473-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> extension of the coverage of this subchapter to new groups of employees; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc474-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> increases in pay on which benefits are computed;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">is deemed to authorize appropriations to the Fund to finance the unfunded liability created by that statute, in 30 equal annual installments with interest computed at the rate used in the then most recent valuation of the Civil Service Retirement System and with the first payment thereof due as of the end of the fiscal year in which each new or liberalized benefit, extension of coverage, or increase in pay is effective.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc475-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> At the end of each fiscal year, the Office shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury of the amount equivalent to (1) interest on the unfunded liability computed for that year at the interest rate used in the then most recent valuation of the System, and (2) that portion of disbursement for annuities for that year which the Office estimates is attributable to credit allowed for military service, less an amount determined by the Office to be appropriate to reflect the value of the deposits made to the credit of the Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/j">section 8334(j) of this title</ref>. Before closing the accounts for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall credit to the Fund, as a Government contribution, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, the following percentages of such amounts: 10 percent for 1971; 20 percent for 1972; 30 percent for 1973; 40 percent for 1974; 50 percent for 1975; 60 percent for 1976; 70 percent for 1977; 80 percent for 1978; 90 percent for 1979; and 100 percent for 1980 and for each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc476-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc477-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In this subsection, the term “Postal surplus or supplemental liability” means the estimated difference, as determined by the Office, between—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc478-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the actuarial present value of all future benefits payable from the Fund under this subchapter to current or former employees of the United States Postal Service and attributable to civilian employment with the United States Postal Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc479-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8edc47a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the actuarial present value of deductions to be withheld from the future basic pay of employees of the United States Postal Service currently subject to this subchapter under section 8334;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8edc47b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> that portion of the Fund balance, as of the date the Postal surplus or supplemental liability is determined, attributable to payments to the Fund by the United States Postal Service and its employees, minus benefit payments attributable to civilian employment with the United States Postal Service, plus the earnings on such amounts while in the Fund; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8edc47c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any other appropriate amount, as determined by the Office in accordance with generally accepted actuarial practices and principles.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc47d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc47e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than <date date="2007-06-15">June 15, 2007</date>, the Office shall determine the Postal surplus or supplemental liability, as of <date date="2006-09-30">September 30, 2006</date>. If that result is a surplus, the amount of the surplus shall be transferred to the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund established under section 8909a by <date date="2007-06-30">June 30, 2007</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc47f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Office shall redetermine the Postal surplus or supplemental liability as of the close of the fiscal year, for each fiscal year beginning after <date date="2007-09-30">September 30, 2007</date>, through the fiscal year ending <date date="2038-09-30">September 30, 2038</date>. If the result is a surplus, that amount shall remain in the Fund until distribution is authorized under subparagraph (C). Beginning <date date="2017-06-15">June 15, 2017</date>, if the result is a supplemental liability, the Office shall establish an amortization schedule, including a series of annual installments commencing on September 30 of the subsequent fiscal year, which provides for the liquidation of such liability by <date date="2043-09-30">September 30, 2043</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc480-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> As of the close of the fiscal years ending <date date="2015-09-30">September 30, 2015</date>, 2025, 2035, and 2039, if the result is a surplus, that amount shall be transferred to the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund, and any prior amortization schedule for payments shall be terminated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc481-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Amortization schedules established under this paragraph shall be set in accordance with generally accepted actuarial practices and principles, with interest computed at the rate used in the most recent valuation of the Civil Service Retirement System.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc482-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The United States Postal Service shall pay the amounts so determined to the Office, with payments due not later than the date scheduled by the Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc483-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in computing the amount of any payment under any other subsection of this section that is based upon the amount of the unfunded liability, such payment shall be computed disregarding that portion of the unfunded liability that the Office determines will be liquidated by payments under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc484-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc485-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Panama Canal Commission shall be liable for that portion of any estimated increase in the unfunded liability of the fund which is attributable to any benefits payable from the Fund to or on behalf of employees and their survivors to the extent attributable to the amendments made by sections 1241 and 1242, and the provisions of sections 1231(b) and 1243(a)(1), of the Panama Canal Act of 1979, and the amendments made by section 3506 of the Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc486-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The estimated increase in the unfunded liability referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be determined by the Office of Personnel Management. The Panama Canal Commission shall pay to the Fund from funds available to it for that purpose the amount so determined in annual installments with interest computed at the rate used in the most recent valuation of the Civil Service Retirement System.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc487-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc488-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury may suspend additional investment of amounts in the Fund if such additional investment could not be made without causing the public debt of the United States to exceed the public debt limit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc489-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any amounts in the Fund which, solely by reason of the public debt limit, are not invested shall be invested by the Secretary of the Treasury as soon as such investments can be made without exceeding the public debt limit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc48a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon expiration of the debt issuance suspension period, the Secretary of the Treasury shall immediately issue to the Fund obligations under chapter 31 of title 31 that (notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section) bear such interest rates and maturity dates as are necessary to ensure that, after such obligations are issued, the holdings of the Fund will replicate to the maximum extent practicable the obligations that would then be held by the Fund if the suspension of investment under paragraph (1) of this subsection, and any redemption or disinvestment under subsection (k) of this section for the purpose described in such paragraph, during such period had not occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc48b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> On the first normal interest payment date after the expiration of any debt issuance suspension period, the Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to the Fund, from amounts in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, an amount determined by the Secretary to be equal to the excess of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc48c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the net amount of interest that would have been earned by the Fund during such debt issuance suspension period if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8edc48d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> amounts in the Fund that were not invested during such debt issuance suspension period solely by reason of the public debt limit had been invested, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8edc48e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> redemptions and disinvestments with respect to the Fund which occurred during such debt issuance suspension period solely by reason of the public debt limit had not occurred, over</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc48f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the net amount of interest actually earned by the Fund during such debt issuance suspension period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc490-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection and subsections (k) and (<i>l</i>) of this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc491-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “public debt limit” means the limitation imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3101/b">section 3101(b) of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8edc492-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/j/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “debt issuance suspension period” means any period for which the Secretary of the Treasury determines for purposes of this subsection that the issuance of obligations of the United States may not be made without exceeding the public debt limit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc493-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc494-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary of the Treasury may sell or redeem securities, obligations, or other invested assets of the Fund before maturity in order to prevent the public debt of the United States from exceeding the public debt limit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc495-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may sell or redeem securities, obligations, or other invested assets of the Fund under paragraph (1) of this subsection only during a debt issuance suspension period, and only to the extent necessary to obtain any amount of funds not exceeding the amount equal to the total amount of the payments authorized to be made from the Fund under the provisions of this subchapter or chapter 84 of this title or related provisions of law during such period. A sale or redemption may be made under this subsection even if, before the sale or redemption, there is a sufficient amount in the Fund to ensure that such payments are made in a timely manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc496-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc497-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall report to Congress on the operation and status of the Fund during each debt issuance suspension period for which the Secretary is required to take action under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (j) of this section. The report shall be submitted as soon as possible after the expiration of such period, but not later than the date that is 30 days after the first normal interest payment date occurring after the expiration of such period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8edc498-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8348/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Whenever the Secretary of the Treasury determines that, by reason of the public debt limit, the Secretary will be unable to fully comply with the requirements of subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary shall immediately notify Congress of the determination. The notification shall be made in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8edc499-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/584">80 Stat. 584</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/83/s1/85">Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(85)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/218">81 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 91–93, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1969-10-20">Oct. 20, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/137">83 Stat. 137</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/349/s1">Pub. L. 93–349, § 1</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/354">88 Stat. 354</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/183/s2/37">Pub. L. 94–183, § 2(37)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1058">89 Stat. 1058</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tIX/s906/a/2">Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1224">92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/70/tI/s1244">Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1244</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/474">93 Stat. 474</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/tIII/s306/f">Pub. L. 97–253, title III, § 306(f)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/797">96 Stat. 797</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/346/s3/g">Pub. L. 97–346, § 3(g)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1648">96 Stat. 1648</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/216/s3/a/5">Pub. L. 98–216, § 3(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1984-02-14">Feb. 14, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/6">98 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s2/7">Pub. L. 98–615, § 2(7)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3202">98 Stat. 3202</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tII/s207/j">Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(j)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/597">100 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tVI/s6002">Pub. L. 99–509, title VI, § 6002</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1931">100 Stat. 1931</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tV/s5428/d">Pub. L. 100–203, title V, § 5428(d)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-274">101 Stat. 1330–274</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tIV/s4002/a">Pub. L. 101–239, title IV, § 4002(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2133">103 Stat. 2133</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII</ref>, §§ 7001(a)(3), 7101(a), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-328">104 Stat. 1388–328</ref>, 1388–331; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dC/tXXXV/s3506/c">Pub. L. 101–510, div. C, title XXXV, § 3506(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1847">104 Stat. 1847</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/424/s10">Pub. L. 103–424, § 10</ref>, <date date="1994-10-29">Oct. 29, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4366">108 Stat. 4366</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/52/tIV/s2">Pub. L. 104–52, title IV, § 2</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/490">109 Stat. 490</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/tI/s103/h">Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 103(h)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3829">110 Stat. 3829</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tXIII/s1302/c">Pub. L. 105–362, title XIII, § 1302(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3293">112 Stat. 3293</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/18/s2/c">Pub. L. 108–18, § 2(c)</ref>, (d)(1)(A), <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/625">117 Stat. 625</ref>, 626; <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/tVIII/s802/a/2">Pub. L. 109–435, title VIII, § 802(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3249">120 Stat. 3249</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/126/s3/a">Pub. L. 116–126, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-18">Mar. 18, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/176">134 Stat. 176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8edc49a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8edc49b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb8edc49c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style="">1966 <html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Act</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Derivation</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>U.S. Code</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised Statutes and</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Statutes at Large</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>(a)–(f)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s2267">5 U.S.C. 2267</html:a>.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1956-07-31/ch804/s401">July 31, 1956, ch. 804, § 401</html:a> “Sec. 17”, <html:a href="/us/stat/70/759">70 Stat. 759</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Oct. 4, 1961</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/87/350/s1/a">Pub. L. 87–350, § 1(a)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/75/770">75 Stat. 770</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>(g)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">[Uncodified].</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Aug. 28, 1958</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/85/844/s101">Pub. L. 85–844, § 101</html:a> (par. under “Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund”), <html:a href="/us/stat/72/1064">72 Stat. 1064</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), the first sentence is based on former section 2251(f), which is carried into section 8331.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (f), the words “to carry out this subchapter” are substituted for “to continue this chapter in full force and effect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (g), the words “after the enactment of this Act” are omitted as executed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.</p>
</note>
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb8edc49d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb8edc49e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style="">1967 <html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Act</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Section of title 5</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>8348(a)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">5 App.: 2267(a).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Sept. 27, 1965</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/89/205/s1/b">Pub. L. 89–205, § 1(b)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/79/840">79 Stat. 840</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The change in subsection (f) is made for uniformity in style and because the full title of the Commission appears in subsection (a).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8edc49f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb8edc4a0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1241 and 1242 of the Panama Canal Act of 1979 [<ref href="/us/pl/96/70">Pub. L. 96–70</ref>], referred to in subsec. (i)(1), amended sections 8336 and 8339 of this title, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1231(b) and 1243(a)(1) of the Panama Canal Act of 1979 [<ref href="/us/pl/96/70">Pub. L. 96–70</ref>], referred to in subsec. (i)(1), are classified to sections 3671(b) and 3681(a)(1) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 3506 of the Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dC/tXXXV">Pub. L. 101–510, div. C, title XXXV</ref>], referred to in subsec. (i)(1), amended sections 8336, 8339, and 8348 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8edc4a1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/126">Pub. L. 116–126</ref> inserted “in administering fraud prevention under sections 8345, 8345a, 8466, and 8466a of this title,” after “8465(b) of this title,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/435">Pub. L. 109–435</ref> amended subsec. (h) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (h) related to postal supplemental liability.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/18/s2/c">Pub. L. 108–18, § 2(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (h) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (h) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(h)(1) Notwithstanding any other statute, the United States Postal Service shall be liable for that portion of any estimated increase in the unfunded liability of the Fund which is attributable to any benefits payable from the Fund to active and retired Postal Service officers and employees, and to their survivors, when the increase results from an employee-management agreement under title 39, or any administrative action by the Postal Service taken pursuant to law, which authorizes increases in pay on which benefits are computed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) The estimated increase in the unfunded liability, referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall be determined by the Office of Personnel Management. The United States Postal Service shall pay the amount so determined to the Office in 30 equal annual installments with interest computed at the rate used in the most recent valuation of the Civil Service Retirement System, with the first payment thereof due at the end of the fiscal year in which an increase in pay becomes effective.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/108/18/s2/d/1/A">Pub. L. 108–18, § 2(d)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out subsec. (m) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(m)(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the United States Postal Service shall be liable for that portion of any estimated increase in the unfunded liability of the Fund which is attributable to any benefits payable from the Fund to former employees of the Postal Service who first become annuitants by reason of separation from the Postal Service on or after <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, or to their survivors, or to the survivors of individuals who die on or after <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, while employed by the Postal Service, when the increase results from a cost-of-living adjustment under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340">section 8340 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) The estimated increase in the unfunded liability referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be determined by the Office after consultation with the Postal Service. The Postal Service shall pay the amount so determined to the Office in 15 equal annual installments with interest computed at the rate used in the most recent valuation of the Civil Service Retirement System, and with the first payment thereof due at the end of the fiscal year in which the cost-of-living adjustment with respect to which the payment relates becomes effective.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) In determining any amount for which the Postal Service is liable under this subsection, the amount of the liability shall be prorated to reflect only that portion of total service (used in computing the benefits involved) which is attributable to civilian service performed after <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, as estimated by the Office.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> struck out at end “The Office shall report to the President and to the Congress the sums credited to the Fund under this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/316">Pub. L. 104–316</ref> struck out at end “The Secretary shall concurrently transmit a copy of such report to the Comptroller General of the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/52">Pub. L. 104–52</ref> inserted “in making an allotment or assignment made by an individual under section 8345(h) or 8465(b) of this title,” after “of law),” and “or section 8345(k) or 8469 of this title” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/424">Pub. L. 103–424</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s7001/a/3">Pub. L. 101–508, § 7001(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “in administering alternative forms of annuities under sections 8343a and 8420a (and related provisions of law),” before “and in withholding”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Pub. L. 101–510</ref> substituted “1979, and the amendments made by section 3506 of the Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991” for “1979”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s7101/a">Pub. L. 101–508, § 7101(a)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>” for “<date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> substituted “The Panama Canal Commission shall pay to the Fund from funds available to it” for “The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to the Fund from appropriations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> inserted reference to provisions of chapter 84 of this title which relate to benefits payable out of the Fund in par. (1)(A), inserted “or 8462” and reference to subchapters II and IV of chapter 84 of this title in par. (1)(B), and inserted reference to chapter 84 of this title in par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/99/509">Pub. L. 99–509</ref> added subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615">Pub. L. 98–615</ref> inserted “, in administering survivor annuities and elections providing therefor under sections 8339 and 8341 of this title,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/216">Pub. L. 98–216</ref> substituted “chapter 31 of title 31” for “the Second Liberty Bond Act, as amended,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/97/346">Pub. L. 97–346</ref> inserted “and in withholding taxes pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3405">section 3405 of title 26</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/s306/f">Pub. L. 97–253, § 306(f)</ref>, inserted “, less an amount determined by the Office to be appropriate to reflect the value of the deposits made to the credit of the Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/j">section 8334(j) of this title</ref>” after “allowed for military service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/96/70">Pub. L. 96–70</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (a), (g), (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> substituted “Office of Personnel Management” and “Office” for “Civil Service Commission” and “Commission”, respectively, wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/183">Pub. L. 94–183</ref> substituted “30” for “thirty”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/93/349">Pub. L. 93–349</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s103/a/1">Pub. L. 91–93, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1)(A) and (B) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s103/a/2">Pub. L. 91–93, § 103(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f) and struck out former subsec. (f) which required the Commission to submit estimates of appropriations necessary to finance the Fund on a normal cost plus interest basis and to carry out this subchapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s103/a/2">Pub. L. 91–93, § 103(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g) and struck out former subsec. (g) which contained restriction against use of Fund money to pay an increase in annuity benefits or a new annuity benefit under this subchapter or an earlier statute without an appropriation being made to the Fund in a sufficient amount to prevent an immediate increase in the unfunded accrued liability of the Fund.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8edc4a2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4a3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/435">Pub. L. 109–435</ref> effective <date date="2006-10-01">Oct. 1, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/s805/a">section 805(a) of Pub. L. 109–435</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334">section 8334 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4a4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/18/s2/d/2">Pub. L. 108–18, § 2(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/627">117 Stat. 627</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/18/s2/d/2">“Nothing in this subsection [repealing subsec. (m) of this section and provisions set out as a note under this section] shall be considered to affect any payments made before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>] under either of the provisions of law repealed by paragraph (1).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4a5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s7101/d">Section 7101(d) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/s7101/d">“This section and the amendments made by this section [amending this section, enacting provisions set out as a note under this section, and repealing provisions set out as notes under this section] shall take effect on <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4a6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s4002/b/1">Section 4002(b)(1) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, which provided that <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s4002">section 4002 of Pub. L. 101–239</ref> (amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section) be effective as of <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII/s7101/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7101(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-331">104 Stat. 1388–331</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4a7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> effective <date date="1988-01-01">Jan. 1, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s5429">section 5429 of Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3712">section 3712 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4a8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> effective <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/s702/a">section 702(a) of Pub. L. 99–335</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401">section 8401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4a9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/615">Pub. L. 98–615</ref> effective <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, with enumerated exceptions and specific applicability provisions, see section 4(a)(1), (5)(D) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/615">Pub. L. 98–615</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4aa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/346">Pub. L. 97–346</ref> effective <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/346/s3/n">section 3(n) of Pub. L. 97–346</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/253">Pub. L. 97–253</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, except that any employee or Member who retired after <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, and before <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, or is entitled to an annuity under chapter 83 of this title based on a separation from service occurring during such period, or a survivor of such individual, may make a payment under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/j/1">section 8334(j)(1) of this title</ref>, and regulations required to be issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/j/1">section 8334(j)(1) of this title</ref>, to be issued by the Office of Personnel Management within 90 days after such effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/s306/g">section 306(g) of Pub. L. 97–253</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8331">section 8331 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4ab-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/70">Pub. L. 96–70</ref> effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/70/s3304">section 3304 of Pub. L. 96–70</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3601">section 3601 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4ac-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4ad-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/349">Pub. L. 93–349</ref> effective <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, except that the Postal Service shall not be required to make (1) the payments due <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, and <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, attributable to pay increases granted by the Postal Service prior to <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, until such time as funds are appropriated to the Postal Service for that purpose, and (2) the transfer to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund required by title II of the Treasury, Postal Service, and General Government Appropriation Act, 1974, <ref href="/us/pl/93/143">Public Law 93–143</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/349/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 93–349</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s1005">section 1005 of Title 39</ref>, Postal Service.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8edc4ae-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s103/b/1">Section 103(b)(1) of Pub. L. 91–93</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/93/s103/b/1">“The provisions of subsection (g) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348">section 8348 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as contained in the amendment made by subsection (a)(2) of this section, shall become effective at the beginning of the fiscal year which ends on <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8edc4af-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review by Postal Regulatory Commission</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/435/tVIII/s802/c">Pub. L. 109–435, title VIII, § 802(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3250">120 Stat. 3250</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/435/tVIII/s802/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Request for review</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334">section 8334 of this title</ref>] (including any amendment made by this section), any determination or redetermination made by the Office of Personnel Management under this section (including any amendment made by this section) shall, upon request of the United States Postal Service, be subject to a review by the Postal Regulatory Commission under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon receiving a request under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall promptly procure the services of an actuary, who shall hold membership in the American Academy of Actuaries and shall be qualified in the evaluation of pension obligations, to conduct a review in accordance with generally accepted actuarial practices and principles and to provide a report to the Commission containing the results of the review. The Commission, upon determining that the report satisfies the requirements of this paragraph, shall approve the report, with any comments it may choose to make, and submit it with any such comments to the Postal Service, the Office of Personnel Management, and Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reconsideration</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon receiving the report from the Commission under paragraph (1), the Office of Personnel Management shall reconsider its determination or redetermination in light of such report, and shall make any appropriate adjustments. The Office shall submit a report containing the results of its reconsideration to the Commission, the Postal Service, and Congress.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8edc4b0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Payments To Reimburse Fund for Increase in Unfunded Liability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dC/tXXXI/s3154">Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXI, § 3154</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2256">112 Stat. 2256</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/stat/112/2256">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Department of Energy shall pay into the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund an amount determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to be necessary to reimburse the Fund for any estimated increase in the unfunded liability of the Fund resulting from the amendments related to the Civil Service Retirement System under this section [amending sections 3307, 8331, 8334 to 8336, 8401, 8412, 8415, 8422, 8423, and 8425 of this title], and for any estimated increase in the supplemental liability of the Fund resulting from the amendments related to the Federal Employees Retirement System under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Department shall pay the amount so determined in five equal annual installments with interest computed at the rate used in the most recent valuation of the Federal Employees Retirement System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Department shall make payments under this subsection from amounts available for weapons activities of the Department.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Payments by Postal Service Relating to Corrected Calculations for Past Retirement COLAs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/66/tXI/s11101/a">Pub. L. 103–66, title XI, § 11101(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/413">107 Stat. 413</ref>, required the United States Postal Service to pay into the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund a total of $693,000,000 not later than <date date="1998-09-30">September 30, 1998</date>, in addition to other payments required by law.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Timely Processing of Retirement Benefits</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIV/s4436/d">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4436(d)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2724">106 Stat. 2724</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tIII/s341/b/2">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 341(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2720">108 Stat. 2720</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tXI/s1106/b/2">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title XI, § 1106(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1924">111 Stat. 1924</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tXI/s1106/b/2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> In order to ensure the timely processing of applications for retirement benefits, under the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees’ Retirement System, for civilian employees of the Department of Defense and other employees who retire when their agency is undergoing a major reorganization, a major reduction in force, or a major transfer of function, the costs incurred by the Office of Personnel Management in processing any such application shall be deemed to be an administrative expense described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348/a/1/B">section 8348(a)(1)(B) of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> This subsection shall apply with respect to applications for retirement benefits based on separations occurring before <date date="2002-01-01">January 1, 2002</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pre-1991 Cost-of-Living Adjustments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII/s7101/c">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7101(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-331">104 Stat. 1388–331</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s5/a/1">Pub. L. 102–378, § 5(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1358">106 Stat. 1358</ref>, related to pre-1991 cost-of-living adjustments, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/18/s2/d/1/B">Pub. L. 108–18, § 2(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2003-04-23">Apr. 23, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/627">117 Stat. 627</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Payments Relating to Amounts Which Would Have Been Due Before Fiscal Year 1987</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII/s7103">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7103</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-333">104 Stat. 1388–333</ref>, required the United States Postal Service to pay, not later than <date date="1995-09-30">Sept. 30, 1995</date>, into the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund and into the Employees Health Benefits Fund certain sums for retirement COLA and health benefits which would have been due in any pre-1987 fiscal year if certain amendments had been in effect as of <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Certain Postal Service Annuitants; Size of Annual Installments To Fund Previous Years’ COLAs</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s4002/b/2">Section 4002(b)(2) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, which provided that notwithstanding any provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348/m">section 8348(m) of this title</ref> the estimated increase in the unfunded liability referred to in section 8348(m)(1) was to be payable based on annual installments equal to specified amounts for fiscal years 1987 to 1989, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII/s7101/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7101(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-331">104 Stat. 1388–331</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Certain Postal Service Annuitants; Additional Amount Payable</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s4002/b/3">Section 4002(b)(3) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, which provided that first payment made under provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348/m">section 8348(m) of this title</ref> was to include, in addition to the amount which would otherwise have been payable at that time, an amount equal to the sum of any amounts which would have been due under those provisions in any prior year if this section had been enacted before <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, and which provided the method of computation, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII/s7101/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7101(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-331">104 Stat. 1388–331</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Status of Original Subsec. (g) Provisions During Period From <date date="1969-10-20">Oct. 20, 1969</date> to <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/93/s103/b/2">Section 103(b)(2) of Pub. L. 91–93</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/93/s103/b/2">“Paragraph (1) of this subsection [set out as Effective Date of 1969 Amendment note above], shall not be held or considered to continue in effect after the enactment of this Act [<date date="1969-10-20">Oct. 20, 1969</date>], the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348/g">section 8348(g) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, as in effect immediately prior to such enactment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inapplicability to Benefits Under <ref href="/us/pl/89/737">Pub. L. 89–737</ref> of Prohibition Against Payment of Increased Annuity Benefit Without Compensating Appropriation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/737/s3">Section 3 of Pub. L. 89–737</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1164">80 Stat. 1164</ref>, which provided that <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348/g">section 8348(g) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, does not apply with respect to annuity benefits resulting from the enactment of this Act [amending sections 8114, 8331, and 8704 of this title and section 1117 of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees], was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/90/83/s10/b">Pub. L. 90–83, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-09-11">Sept. 11, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/223">81 Stat. 223</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8f035b9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Redemption of Obligations Held Prior to <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>; Reinvestment of Proceeds</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/87/350/s1/b">Pub. L. 87–350, § 1(b)</ref> <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/770">75 Stat. 770</ref>, provided that all special issues in which the civil service retirement and disability fund was invested in accordance with subsecs. (d) and (e) of this section before <date date="1961-10-04">Oct. 4, 1961</date>, were to be redeemed and the moneys reinvested by the Secretary of the Treasury in equal annual amounts over the period of ten calendar years beginning with the calendar year 1962.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
