<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb900d7c1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435"><num value="8435">§ 8435.</num><heading> Protections for spouses and former spouses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7c2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7c3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7c4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A married employee or Member (or former employee or Member) may withdraw all or part of a Thrift Savings Fund account under subsection (b)(2), (3), or (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref> or change a withdrawal election only if the employee or Member (or former employee or Member) satisfies the requirements of subparagraph (B). A married employee or Member (or former employee or Member) may make a withdrawal from a Thrift Savings Fund account under subsection (c)(1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref> only if the employee or Member (or former employee or Member) satisfies the requirements of subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7c5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An employee or Member (or former employee or Member) may make an election or change referred to in subparagraph (A) if the employee or Member and the employee’s or Member’s spouse (or the former employee or Member and the former employee’s or Member’s spouse) jointly waive, by written election, any right which the spouse may have to a survivor annuity with respect to such employee or Member (or former employee or Member) under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8434">section 8434 of this title</ref> or subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7c6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an election or change of election by an employee or Member (or former employee or Member) who establishes to the satisfaction of the Executive Director (at the time of the election or change and in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Executive Director)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7c7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that the spouse’s whereabouts cannot be determined; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7c8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that, due to exceptional circumstances, requiring the spouse’s waiver would otherwise be inappropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7c9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7ca-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any election under subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8434">section 8434 of this title</ref>, the method described in subsection (a)(2)(B) of such section (or, if more than one form of such method is available, the form which the Board determines to be the one which provides for a surviving spouse a survivor annuity most closely approximating the annuity of a surviving spouse under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8442">section 8442 of this title</ref>) shall be deemed the applicable method under such subsection (b) in the case of an employee, Member, former employee, or former Member who is married on the date on which an annuity contract is purchased to provide for the employee’s, Member’s, former employee’s, or former Member’s annuity under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7cb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) shall not apply if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7cc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a joint waiver of such method is made, in writing, by the employee or Member and the spouse; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7cd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the employee or Member waives such method, in writing, after establishing to the satisfaction of the Executive Director that circumstances described under subsection (a)(2)(A) or (B) make the requirement of a joint waiver inappropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7ce-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7cf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An election or change of election shall not be effective under this subchapter to the extent that the election, change, or transfer conflicts with any court decree, order, or agreement described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7d0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A court decree, order, or agreement referred to in paragraph (1) is, with respect to an employee or Member (or former employee or Member), a court decree of divorce, annulment, or legal separation issued in the case of such employee or Member (or former employee or Member) and any former spouse of the employee or Member (or former employee or Member) or any court order or court-approved property settlement agreement incident to such decree if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7d1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the decree, order, or agreement expressly relates to any portion of the balance in the employee’s or Member’s (or former employee’s or Member’s) account; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7d2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> notice of the decree, order, or agreement was received by the Executive Director before—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb900d7d3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the date on which payment is made, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb900d7d4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of an annuity, the date on which an annuity contract is purchased to provide for the annuity,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">in accordance with the election, change, or contribution referred to in paragraph (1).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7d5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Executive Director shall prescribe regulations under which this subsection shall be applied in any case in which the Executive Director receives two or more decrees, orders, or agreements referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7d6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7d7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to paragraphs (2) through (7), a former spouse of a deceased employee or Member (or a deceased former employee or Member) who died after performing 18 or more months of service and a former spouse of a deceased former employee or Member who died entitled to an immediate or deferred annuity under subchapter II of this chapter is entitled to a survivor annuity under this subsection if and to the extent that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7d8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an election under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8434/a/2/E">section 8434(a)(2)(E) of this title</ref>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7d9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any court decree, order, or agreement (described in subsection (c)(2), without regard to subparagraph (B) of such subsection) which relates to such deceased individual and such former spouse,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">expressly provides for such survivor annuity.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7da-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) shall apply only to payments made by the Executive Director after the date on which the Executive Director receives written notice of the election, decree, order, or agreement, and such additional information and documentation as the Executive Director may require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7db-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The amount of the survivor annuity payable from the Thrift Savings Fund to a former spouse of a deceased employee, Member, former employee, or former Member under this section may not exceed the excess, if any, of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7dc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount of the survivor annuity determined for a surviving spouse of the deceased employee, Member, former employee, or former Member under the method described in subsection (b)(1), over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7dd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the total amount of all other survivor annuities payable under this subchapter to other former spouses of such deceased employee, Member, former employee, or former Member based on the order of precedence provided in paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7de-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If more than one former spouse of a deceased employee, Member, former employee, or former Member is entitled to a survivor annuity pursuant to this subsection, the amount of each such survivor annuity shall be limited appropriately to carry out paragraph (3) in the order of precedence established for the entitlements by the chronological order of the dates on which elections are properly made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8434/a/2/E">section 8434(a)(2)(E) of this title</ref> and the dates on which the court decrees, orders, or agreements applicable to the entitlement were issued, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7df-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Subsections (c) and (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8445">section 8445 of this title</ref> shall apply to an entitlement of a former spouse to a survivor annuity under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> For the purposes of this section, a court decree, order, or agreement or an election referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall not be effective, in the case of a former spouse, to the extent that the election is inconsistent with any joint waiver previously executed with respect to such former spouse under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Any payment under this subsection to any individual bars recovery by any other individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A loan or withdrawal may be made to a married employee or Member under section 8433(g) and (h) of this title only if the employee’s or Member’s spouse consents to such loan or withdrawal in writing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A consent under subparagraph (A) shall be irrevocable with respect to the loan or withdrawal to which the consent relates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a loan or withdrawal to an employee or Member who establishes to the satisfaction of the Executive Director (at the time the employee or Member applies for such loan or withdrawal and in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Executive Director)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7e7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that the spouse’s whereabouts cannot be determined; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d7e8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> that, due to exceptional circumstances, requiring the employee or Member to seek the spouse’s consent would otherwise be inappropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7e9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An application for a loan or withdrawal under section 8433(g) and (h) of this title shall not be approved if approval would have the result described under subsection (c)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7ea-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Waivers and notifications required by this section and waivers of the requirements for such waivers and notifications (as authorized by this section) may be made only in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Executive Director.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7eb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> Except with respect to the making of loans or withdrawals under section 8433(g) and (h), none of the provisions of this section requiring notification to, or the consent or waiver of, a spouse or former spouse of an employee, Member, former employee, or former Member shall apply in any case in which the nonforfeitable account balance of the employee, Member, former employee, or former Member is $3,500 or less.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d7ec-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8435/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The protections provided by this section are in addition to the protections provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8467">section 8467 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb900d7ed-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 99–335, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/547">100 Stat. 547</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/335">Pub. L. 101–335</ref>, §§ 5(c), 6(a)(3), <date date="1990-07-17">July 17, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/322">104 Stat. 322</ref>, 323; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIV/s4437/b">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4437(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2724">106 Stat. 2724</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)</ref>, (i)(9)–(15), <date date="1994-03-30">Mar. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/120">108 Stat. 120</ref>, 122; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204]</ref>], <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-314">110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–372, 3009–376.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb900d7ee-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb900d7ef-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb900d7f0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(1)]</ref>], substituted “may withdraw all or part of a Thrift Savings Fund account under subsection (b)(2), (3), or (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref> or change a withdrawal election” for “may make an election under subsection (b)(3) or (b)(4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref> or change an election previously made under subsection (b)(1) or (b)(2) of such section” and inserted at end “A married employee or Member (or former employee or Member) may make a withdrawal from a Thrift Savings Fund account under subsection (c)(1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref> only if the employee or Member (or former employee or Member) satisfies the requirements of subparagraph (B).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/2/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(2)(A)]</ref>], substituted “An election or change of election” for “An election, change of election, or modification of the commencement date of a deferred annuity” and “or transfer” for “modification, or transfer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/2/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(2)(B)]</ref>], struck out “modification,” after “change,” in closing provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/3/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(3)(A)]</ref>], in subpar. (A) inserted “or withdrawal” after “A loan”, “and (h)” after “8433(g)”, and “or withdrawal” after “such loan”, in subpar. (B) inserted “or withdrawal” after “loan”, and in subpar. (C) inserted “or withdrawal” after “to a loan” and after “for such loan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/3/B/i">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(3)(B)(i)]</ref>], inserted “or withdrawal” after “loan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/3/B/ii">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(3)(B)(ii)]</ref>], which directed insertion of “and (h)” after “8344(g)”, was executed by making the insertion after “8433(g)” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/4/A">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(4)(A)]</ref>], inserted “or withdrawals” after “loans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tII/s204/4/B">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 204(4)(B)]</ref>], which directed insertion of “and (h)” after “8344(g)” was executed by making the insertion after “8433(g)” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/1">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)(3) or (b)(4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref> or change an election previously made under subsection (b)(1) or (b)(2)” for “subsection (b)(3), (b)(4), (c)(3), or (c)(4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref> or change an election previously made under subsection (b)(1), (b)(2), (c)(1), or (c)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/i/9">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(i)(9)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)” for “subsection (c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/4">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(4)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “Paragraph (1) shall not apply—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) in the case of an employee or Member retiring under section 8412, 8413, 8414, or 8451 of this title, or who separates from Government employment pursuant to regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3502/a">section 3502(a) of this title</ref> or procedures under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3595/a">section 3595(a) of this title</ref> in a reduction in force, if—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(i) a joint waiver of such method is made, in writing, by the employee or Member and the spouse; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(ii) the employee or Member waives such method, in writing, after establishing to the satisfaction of the Executive Director that circumstances described in subsection (a)(2)(A) or (a)(2)(B) make the requirement of a joint waiver inappropriate; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) in the case of an employee or Member not covered by subparagraph (A), if the employee or Member waives such method after—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(i) having provided notification to the spouse of intent to waive; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(ii) establishing to the satisfaction of the Executive Director that the whereabouts of such spouse cannot be determined.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/2">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), a transfer may be made by an employee or Member (or former employee or Member) under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433/d">section 8433(d) of this title</ref> only after the Executive Director notifies any current spouse and each former spouse of the employee or Member (or former employee or Member), if any, that the transfer is to be made.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) Paragraph (1) may be waived with respect to a spouse or former spouse if the employee or Member (or former employee or Member) establishes to the satisfaction of the Executive Director that the whereabouts of such spouse or former spouse cannot be determined.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/3">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(3)</ref>, (5), redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and, in par. (1), struck out “and a transfer may not be made under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433/d">section 8433(d) of this title</ref>” after “effective under this subchapter”. Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/3">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/i/10">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(i)(10)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c)(2)” for “subsection (d)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/i/11">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(i)(11)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)(1)” for “subsection (c)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/i/12">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(i)(12)</ref>, substituted “or (b)(2)” for “or (c)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/3">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/i/13">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(i)(13)</ref>, substituted “section 8433(g)” for “section 8433(i)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/i/14">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(i)(14)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433/g">section 8433(g) of this title</ref> shall not be approved if approval would have the result described under subsection (c)(1)” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433/i">section 8433(i) of this title</ref> shall not be approved if approval would have the result described in subsection (d)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/3">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/3">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(3)</ref>, (i)(15), redesignated subsec. (h) as (g) and substituted “section 8433(g)” for “section 8433(i)”. Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/d/3">Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(d)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (h). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> inserted “, or who separates from Government employment pursuant to regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3502/a">section 3502(a) of this title</ref> or procedures under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3595/a">section 3595(a) of this title</ref> in a reduction in force,” after “8451 of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 101–335, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “an annuity contract is purchased to provide for” after “the date on which” and struck out “commences” after “former Member’s annuity”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s5/c/2">Pub. L. 101–335, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “an annuity contract is purchased to provide for the annuity” for “the annuity commences”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s6/a/3">Pub. L. 101–335, § 6(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (h) and redesignated former subsec. (h) as (i).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb900d7f1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb900d7f2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> effective <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, and withdrawals and elections as provided under such amendment to be made at earliest practicable date as determined by Executive Director in regulations, see section 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title II, § 207]] of <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5545a">section 5545a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb900d7f3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/226">Pub. L. 103–226</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-10">Mar. 10, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/226/s9/j">section 9(j) of Pub. L. 103–226</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8351">section 8351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb900d7f4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> applicable with respect to separations occurring after <date date="1993-12-31">Dec. 31, 1993</date>, or such earlier date as Executive Director (appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8474">section 8474 of this title</ref>) may by regulation prescribe, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4437/d">section 4437(d) of Pub. L. 102–484</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8351">section 8351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb900d7f5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s5/c">section 5(c) of Pub. L. 101–335</ref> effective <date date="1987-04-01">Apr. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s5/d">section 5(d) of Pub. L. 101–335</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8433">section 8433 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s6/a/3">section 6(a)(3) of Pub. L. 101–335</ref> effective as of second election period described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8432/b">section 8432(b) of this title</ref> beginning after <date date="1990-07-17">July 17, 1990</date>, or such earlier date as Executive Director may by regulation prescribe, and applicable with respect to separations occurring before, on, or after that effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s6/c">section 6(c) of Pub. L. 101–335</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8351">section 8351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
