<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb900d815-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438"><num value="8438">§ 8438.</num><heading> Investment of Thrift Savings Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb900d816-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d817-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “Common Stock Index Investment Fund” means the Common Stock Index Investment Fund established under subsection (b)(1)(C);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb900d818-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “equity capital” means common and preferred stock, surplus, undivided profits, contingency reserves, and other capital reserves;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9034819-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “Fixed Income Investment Fund” means the Fixed Income Investment Fund established under subsection (b)(1)(B);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903481a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “Government Securities Investment Fund” means the Government Securities Investment Fund established under subsection (b)(1)(A);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903481b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “International Stock Index Investment Fund” means the International Stock Index Investment Fund established under subsection (b)(1)(E);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903481c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the term “net worth” means capital, paid-in and contributed surplus, unassigned surplus, contingency reserves, group contingency reserves, and special reserves;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903481d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the term “plan” means an employee benefit plan, as defined in section 3(3) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/3">29 U.S.C. 1002(3)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903481e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> the term “qualified professional asset manager” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb903481f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> a bank, as defined in section 202(a)(2) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–2/a/2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2(a)(2)</ref>) which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9034820-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has the power to manage, acquire, or dispose of assets of a plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9034821-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has, as of the last day of its latest fiscal year ending before the date of a determination for the purpose of this clause, equity capital in excess of $1,000,000;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9034822-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> a savings and loan association, the accounts of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9034823-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has applied for and been granted trust powers to manage, acquire, or dispose of assets of a plan by a State or Government authority having supervision over savings and loan associations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9034824-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has, as of the last day of its latest fiscal year ending before the date of a determination for the purpose of this clause, equity capital or net worth in excess of $1,000,000;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9034825-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> an insurance company which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9034826-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is qualified under the laws of more than one State to manage, acquire, or dispose of any assets of a plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9034827-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has, as of the last day of its latest fiscal year ending before the date of a determination for the purpose of this clause, net worth in excess of $1,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9034828-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> is subject to supervision and examination by a State authority having supervision over insurance companies; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9034829-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> an investment adviser registered under section 203 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–3">15 U.S.C. 80b–3</ref>) if the investment adviser has, on the last day of its latest fiscal year ending before the date of a determination for the purpose of this subparagraph, total client assets under its management and control in excess of $50,000,000, and—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb903482a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the investment adviser has, on such day, shareholder’s or partner’s equity in excess of $750,000; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb903482b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> payment of all of the investment adviser’s liabilities, including any liabilities which may arise by reason of a breach or violation of a duty described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8477">section 8477 of this title</ref>, is unconditionally guaranteed by—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb903482c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a person (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8471/4">section 8471(4) of this title</ref>) who directly or indirectly, through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with the investment adviser and who has, on the last day of the person’s latest fiscal year ending before the date of a determination for the purpose of this clause, shareholder’s or partner’s equity in an amount which, when added to the amount of the shareholder’s or partner’s equity of the investment adviser on such day, exceeds $750,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb903482d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a qualified professional asset manager described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb903482e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/8/D/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> a broker or dealer registered under section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78">15 U.S.C. 78</ref><i>o</i>) that has, on the last day of the broker’s or dealer’s latest fiscal year ending before the date of a determination for the purpose of this clause, net worth in excess of $750,000;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903482f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> the term “shareholder’s or partner’s equity”, as used in paragraph (8)(D) with respect to an investment adviser or a person (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8471/4">section 8471(4) of this title</ref>) who is affiliated with the investment adviser in a manner described in clause (ii)(I) of such paragraph (8)(D), means the equity shown in the most recent balance sheet prepared for such investment adviser or affiliated person, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, within 2 years before the date on which the investment adviser’s status as a qualified professional asset manager is determined for the purposes of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9034830-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> the term “Small Capitalization Stock Index Investment Fund” means the Small Capitalization Stock Index Investment Fund established under subsection (b)(1)(D).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034831-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034832-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Board shall establish—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9034833-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a Government Securities Investment Fund under which sums in the Thrift Savings Fund are invested in securities of the United States Government issued as provided in subsection (e);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9034834-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> a Fixed Income Investment Fund under which sums in the Thrift Savings Fund are invested in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9034835-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> insurance contracts;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9034836-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> certificates of deposits; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9034837-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> other instruments or obligations selected by qualified professional asset managers,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">which return the amount invested and pay interest, at a specified rate or rates, on that amount during a specified period of time;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9034838-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a Common Stock Index Investment Fund as provided in paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9034839-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a Small Capitalization Stock Index Investment Fund as provided in paragraph (3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903483a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> an International Stock Index Investment Fund as provided in paragraph (4); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903483b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> a service that enables participants to invest in mutual funds, if the Board authorizes the mutual fund window under paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903483c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903483d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Board shall select an index which is a commonly recognized index comprised of common stock the aggregate market value of which is a reasonably complete representation of the United States equity markets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903483e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Common Stock Index Investment Fund shall be invested in a portfolio designed to replicate the performance of the index selected under subparagraph (A). The portfolio shall be designed such that, to the extent practicable, the percentage of the Common Stock Index Investment Fund that is invested in each stock is the same as the percentage determined by dividing the aggregate market value of all shares of that stock by the aggregate market value of all shares of all stocks included in such index.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903483f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034840-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Board shall select an index which is a commonly recognized index comprised of common stock the aggregate market value of which represents the United States equity markets excluding the common stocks included in the Common Stock Index Investment Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034841-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Small Capitalization Stock Index Investment Fund shall be invested in a portfolio designed to replicate the performance of the index in subparagraph (A). The portfolio shall be designed such that, to the extent practicable, the percentage of the Small Capitalization Stock Index Investment Fund that is invested in each stock is the same as the percentage determined by dividing the aggregate market value of all shares of that stock by the aggregate market value of all shares of all stocks included in such index.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034842-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034843-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Board shall select an index which is a commonly recognized index comprised of stock the aggregate market value of which is a reasonably complete representation of the international equity markets excluding the United States equity markets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034844-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The International Stock Index Investment Fund shall be invested in a portfolio designed to replicate the performance of the index in subparagraph (A). The portfolio shall be designed such that, to the extent practicable, the percentage of the International Stock Index Investment Fund that is invested in each stock is the same as the percentage determined by dividing the aggregate market value of all shares of that stock by the aggregate market value of all shares of all stocks included in such index.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034845-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034846-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Board may authorize the addition of a mutual fund window under the Thrift Savings Plan if the Board determines that such addition would be in the best interests of participants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034847-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Board shall ensure that any expenses charged for use of the mutual fund window are borne solely by the participants who use such window.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034848-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Board may establish such other terms and conditions for the mutual fund window as the Board considers appropriate to protect the interests of participants, including requirements relating to risk disclosure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034849-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Board shall consult with the Employee Thrift Advisory Council (established under section 8473) before authorizing the addition of a mutual fund window or establishing a service that enables participants to invest in mutual funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903484a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903484b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Executive Director shall invest the sums available in the Thrift Savings Fund for investment as provided in elections made under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903484c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an election has not been made with respect to any sums available for investment in the Thrift Savings Fund, the Executive Director shall invest such sums in an age-appropriate target date asset allocation investment fund, as determined by the Executive Director. Such investment fund shall consist of any of the funds described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903484d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903484e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> At least twice each year, an employee or Member (or former employee or Member) may elect the investment funds and options referred to in subsection (b) into which the sums in the Thrift Savings Fund credited to such individual’s account are to be invested or reinvested.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903484f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An election may be made under paragraph (1) only in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Executive Director and within such period as the Executive Director shall provide in such regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034850-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034851-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to issue special interest-bearing obligations of the United States for purchase by the Thrift Savings Fund for the Government Securities Investment Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034852-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034853-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Obligations issued for the purpose of this subsection shall have maturities fixed with due regard to the needs of such Fund as determined by the Executive Director, and shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average market yield (computed by the Secretary of the Treasury on the basis of market quotations as of the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of issue of such obligations) on all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt which are not due or callable earlier than 4 years after the end of such calendar month.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034854-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any average market yield computed under subparagraph (A) which is not a multiple of one-eighth of 1 percent, shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of one-eighth of 1 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034855-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Board, other Government agencies, the Executive Director, an employee, a Member, a former employee, and a former Member may not exercise voting rights associated with the ownership of securities by the Thrift Savings Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034856-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034857-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (e) of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury may suspend the issuance of additional amounts of obligations of the United States, if such issuances could not be made without causing the public debt of the United States to exceed the public debt limit, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034858-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any issuances of obligations to the Government Securities Investment Fund which, solely by reason of the public debt limit are not issued, shall be issued under subsection (e) by the Secretary of the Treasury as soon as such issuances can be issued without exceeding the public debt limit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034859-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon expiration of the debt issuance suspension period, the Secretary of the Treasury shall immediately issue to the Government Securities Investment Fund obligations under chapter 31 of title 31 that (notwithstanding subsection (e)(2) of this section) bear such interest rates and maturity dates as are necessary to ensure that, after such obligations are issued, the holdings of obligations of the United States by the Government Securities Investment Fund will replicate the obligations that would then be held by the Government Securities Investment Fund under the procedure set forth in paragraph (5), if the suspension of issuances under paragraph (1) of this subsection had not occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903485a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> On the first business day after the expiration of any debt issuance suspension period, the Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to the Government Securities Investment Fund, from amounts in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, an amount equal to the excess of the net amount of interest that would have been earned by the Government Securities Investment Fund from obligations of the United States during such debt issuance suspension period if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903485b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> amounts in the Government Securities Investment Fund that were available for investment in obligations of the United States and were not invested during such debt issuance suspension period solely by reason of the public debt limit had been invested under the procedure set forth in paragraph (5), over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903485c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the net amount of interest actually earned by the Government Securities Investment Fund from obligations of the United States during such debt issuance suspension period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903485d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> On each business day during the debt limit suspension period, the Executive Director shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury of the amounts, by maturity, that would have been invested or redeemed each day had the debt issuance suspension period not occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb903485e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection and subsection (h) of this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb903485f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “public debt limit” means the limitation imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3101/b">section 3101(b) of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9034860-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/g/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “debt issuance suspension period” means any period for which the Secretary of the Treasury determines for purposes of this subsection that the issuance of obligations of the United States may not be made without exceeding the public debt limit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034861-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034862-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall report to Congress on the operation and status of the Thrift Savings Fund during each debt issuance suspension period for which the Secretary is required to take action under paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (g) of this section. The report shall be submitted as soon as possible after the expiration of such period, but not later than 30 days after the first business day after the expiration of such period. The Secretary shall concurrently transmit a copy of such report to the Executive Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9034863-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8438/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Whenever the Secretary of the Treasury determines that, by reason of the public debt limit, the Secretary will be unable to fully comply with the requirements of subsection (e) of this section, the Secretary shall immediately notify Congress and the Executive Director of the determination. The notification shall be made in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9034864-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 99–335, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/551">100 Stat. 551</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/43/s2">Pub. L. 100–43, § 2</ref>, <date date="1987-05-22">May 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/315">101 Stat. 315</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/366/s2/a">Pub. L. 100–366, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-13">July 13, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/826">102 Stat. 826</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-07-17">July 17, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/320">104 Stat. 320</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/68">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(68)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1355">106 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/f/tVI/tI/s102">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title I, § 102]</ref>], <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-314">110 Stat. 3009–314</ref>, 3009–372; <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/tI/s103/i">Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 103(i)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3829">110 Stat. 3829</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/dB/tI/s104">Pub. L. 111–31, div. B, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2009-06-22">June 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1854">123 Stat. 1854</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/255/s2/a">Pub. L. 113–255, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2920">128 Stat. 2920</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tVI/s632/d">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VI, § 632(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/847">129 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9034865-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9034866-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9034867-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92">Pub. L. 114–92</ref> substituted “If an” for “(A) Consistent with the requirements of subparagraph (B), if an” and struck out subpar. (B) which read as follows: “If an election has not been made by an eligible member under section 8440e with respect to any sums available for investment in such member’s Thrift Savings Fund account, the Executive Director shall invest such sums in the Government Securities Investment Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/255">Pub. L. 113–255</ref> amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “If an election has not been made with respect to any sums in the Thrift Savings Fund available for investment, the Executive Director shall invest such sums in the Government Securities Investment Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (b)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s104/a">Pub. L. 111–31, § 104(a)</ref>, added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s104/b">Pub. L. 111–31, § 104(b)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/31/s104/c">Pub. L. 111–31, § 104(c)</ref>, inserted “and options” after “investment funds”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tI/s102/1">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title I, § 102(1)]</ref>], added par. (5), redesignated former pars. (5) to (8) as (6) to (9), respectively, in par. (9) substituted “paragraph (8)(D)” for “paragraph (7)(D)” in two places, and added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f/tVI/tI/s102/2">Pub. L. 104–208, § 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title I, § 102(2)]</ref>], in par. (1) added subpars. (D) and (E) and added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/316">Pub. L. 104–316</ref> struck out “and the Comptroller General of the United States” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(7)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378">Pub. L. 102–378</ref> substituted “Deposit” for “Savings and Loan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “subsection (e)” for “subsection (f)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a/3">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “The” for “Subject to subsection (e), the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a/4">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, struck out “and not subject to subsection (e)” after “individual’s account”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (e) and struck out former subsec. (e) which related to minimum percentages to be invested in Government Securities Investment Fund and limitations on reinvestment of sums invested in Government Securities Investment Fund prior to years 1992 and 1997.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, (5), (6), redesignated subsec. (h) as (g) and substituted “subsection (e)” for “subsection (f)” in pars. (1) and (2), “subsection (e)(2)” for “subsection (f)(2)” in par. (3), and “subsection (h)” for “subsection (i)” in par. (6). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, (7), redesignated subsec. (i) as (h) and substituted “subsection (g)” for “subsection (h)” in par. (1) and “subsection (e)” for “subsection (f)” in par. (2). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (e)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/366">Pub. L. 100–366</ref> struck out “and the earnings attributable to the investment of such sums” after “paragraph (1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/43">Pub. L. 100–43</ref> added subsecs. (h) and (i).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9034868-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9034869-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment; Implementation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/92">Pub. L. 114–92</ref> effective <date date="2018-01-01">Jan. 1, 2018</date>, with certain implementation requirements, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s635">section 635 of Pub. L. 114–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8432">section 8432 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb903486a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/255/s2/e">Pub. L. 113–255, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2920">128 Stat. 2920</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/255/s2/e">
<inline>“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8439">section 8439 of this title</ref>] shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> take effect on the date that the Executive Director issues guidance under subsection (d) [guidance published <date date="2015-08-28">Aug. 28, 2015</date>, effective <date date="2015-09-05">Sept. 5, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/255/s2/d">section 2(d) of Pub. L. 113–255</ref>, set out as a Guidance note below]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> apply to individuals enrolled in the Thrift Savings Plan on or after such date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb903486b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 101(f) [title VI, § 659 [title I, § 104]] provided that: “This title [title I (§§ 101–104) of section 659 of <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/s101/f">section 101(f) of Pub. L. 104–208</ref>, amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8439">section 8439 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401">section 8401 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>], and the Funds established under this title shall be offered for investment at the earliest practicable election period (described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8432/b">section 8432(b) of title 5</ref>, United States Code) as determined by the Executive Director in regulations.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb903486c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/335">Pub. L. 101–335</ref> effective as of second election period described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8432/b">section 8432(b) of this title</ref> beginning after <date date="1990-07-17">July 17, 1990</date>, or as of such earlier date as Executive Director may by regulation prescribe, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/c">section 3(c) of Pub. L. 101–335</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8351">section 8351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb903486d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/366/s2/b">Pub. L. 100–366, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-13">July 13, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/826">102 Stat. 826</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/366/s2/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to earnings attributable to contributions made to the Thrift Savings Fund on or after <date date="1987-04-01">April 1, 1987</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb903486e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/255/s2/d">Pub. L. 113–255, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2920">128 Stat. 2920</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/255/s2/d">“Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>], the Executive Director (as that term is defined under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401/13">section 8401(13) of title 5</ref>, United States Code) shall develop and issue guidance implementing the requirements of this Act [see <ref href="/us/pl/113/255/s1">section 1 of Pub. L. 113–255</ref>, set out as a Short Title of 2014 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Guidance issued in the form of a final rule published <date date="2015-08-28">Aug. 28, 2015</date>, effective <date date="2015-09-05">Sept. 5, 2015</date>, see 80 F.R. 52173.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb903486f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Removal of Investment Restrictions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/335/s3/b/4">Pub. L. 101–335, § 3(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1990-07-17">July 17, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/320">104 Stat. 320</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/335/s3/b/4">“Any other provision of law, in effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-07-17">July 17, 1990</date>], which provides that any amounts contributed to the Thrift Savings Fund, or earnings thereon, may be invested or reinvested only in the Government Securities Investment Fund established under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8438/b/1/A">section 8438(b)(1)(A) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, shall cease to be effective.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
