<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9080435-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461"><num value="8461">§ 8461.</num><heading> Authority of the Office of Personnel Management</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080436-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Office shall pay all benefits that are payable under subchapter II, IV, V, or VI of this chapter from the Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080437-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Office shall administer all provisions of this chapter not specifically required to be administered by the Board, the Executive Director, the Secretary of Labor, or any other officer or agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080438-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Office shall adjudicate all claims under the provisions of this chapter administered by the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080439-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Office shall determine questions of disability and dependency arising under the provisions of this chapter administered by the Office. Except to the extent provided under subsection (e), the decisions of the Office concerning these matters are final and conclusive and are not subject to review. The Office may direct at any time such medical or other examinations as it considers necessary to determine the facts concerning disability or dependency of an individual receiving or applying for annuity under the provisions of this chapter administered by the Office. The Office may suspend or deny annuity for failure to submit to examination.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908043a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908043b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (2), an administrative action or order affecting the rights or interests of an individual or of the United States under the provisions of this chapter administered by the Office may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board under procedures prescribed by the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908043c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of any individual found by the Office to be disabled in whole or in part on the basis of the individual’s mental condition, and that finding was made pursuant to an application by an agency for purposes of disability retirement under section 8451, the procedures under section 7701 shall apply and the decision of the Board shall be subject to judicial review under section 7703.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908043d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Office shall fix the fees for examinations made under subchapter V of this chapter by physicians or surgeons who are not medical officers of the United States. The fees and reasonable traveling and other expenses incurred in connection with the examinations are paid from appropriations for the cost of administering the provisions of this chapter administered by the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908043e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The Office may prescribe regulations to carry out the provisions of this chapter administered by the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908043f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080440-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each Government agency shall furnish the Director with such information as the Director determines necessary in order to administer this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080441-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director, in consultation with the officials from whom such information is requested, shall establish (by regulation or otherwise) such safeguards as are necessary to ensure that information made available under this subsection is used only for the purpose authorized.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080442-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In making a determination of “actuarial equivalence” under this chapter, the economic assumptions used shall be the same as the economic assumptions most recently used by the Office (before the determination of actuarial equivalence involved) in determining the normal-cost percentage of the System.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080443-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080444-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Director of Central Intelligence shall, in a manner consistent with the administration of this chapter by the Office, and to the extent considered appropriate by the Director of Central Intelligence—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080445-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> determine entitlement to benefits under this chapter based on the service of employees of the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080446-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> maintain records relating to the service of such employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080447-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> compute benefits under this chapter based on the service of such employees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080448-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> collect deposits to the Fund made by such employees, their spouses, their former spouses, and their survivors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080449-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> authorize and direct disbursements from the Fund to the extent based on service of such employees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb908044a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> perform such other functions under this chapter (other than under subchapters III and VII of this chapter) with respect to employees of the Central Intelligence Agency as the Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908044b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall furnish such information and, on a reimbursable basis, such services to the Director of Central Intelligence as the Director of Central Intelligence requests to carry out paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908044c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908044d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board, may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb908044e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> maintain exclusive records relating to elections, contributions, and accounts under the Thrift Savings Plan provided in subchapter III of this chapter in the case of employees of the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb908044f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide that contributions by, or on behalf of, such employees to the Thrift Savings Plan be accounted for by such Executive Director in aggregate amounts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080450-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> make the necessary disbursements from, and the necessary allocations of earnings, losses, and charges to, individual accounts of such employees under the Thrift Savings Plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080451-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> perform such other functions under subchapters III and VII of this chapter (but not including investing sums in the Thrift Savings Fund) with respect to employees of the Central Intelligence Agency as the Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board, determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080452-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board may not exercise authority under this chapter in the case of employees of the Central Intelligence Agency to the extent that the Director of Central Intelligence exercises authority provided in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080453-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board shall furnish such information and, on a reimbursable basis, such services to the Director of Central Intelligence as the Director of Central Intelligence determines necessary to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080454-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> Subsection (h)(1), and sections 8439(b) and 8474(c)(4), shall be applied with respect to information relating to employees of the Central Intelligence Agency in a manner that protects intelligence sources, methods, and activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080455-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080456-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board, shall by regulation prescribe appropriate procedures to carry out subsections (j), (k), and (<i>l</i>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080457-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The regulations shall provide procedures for the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to inspect and audit disbursements from the Fund under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080458-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Director of Central Intelligence shall submit the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives before the regulations take effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9080459-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908045a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Office, an employee who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb908045b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has not previously made an election under this subsection or had an opportunity to make an election under this paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb908045c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> moves, without a break in service of more than 1 year, to employment in a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, described in section 2105(c),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be given the opportunity to elect irrevocably, within 30 days after such move, to remain covered as an employee under this chapter during any employment described in section 2105(c) after such move.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb908045d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Office, an employee of a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard described in section 2105(c), who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb908045e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has not previously made an election under this subsection or had an opportunity to make an election under this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb908045f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is a participant in a retirement system established for employees described in section 2105(c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080460-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> moves, without a break in service of more than 1 year, to a position that is not described by section 2105(c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9080461-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8461/n/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> is not eligible to make an election under section 8347(q),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be given the opportunity to elect irrevocably, within 30 days after such move, to remain covered, during any subsequent employment as an employee as defined by section 2105(a) or section 2105(c), by the retirement system applicable to such employee’s current or most recent employment described by section 2105(c) rather than be subject to this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9080462-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 99–335, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/570">100 Stat. 570</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/556/tI/s102">Pub. L. 99–556, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3131">100 Stat. 3131</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVII/s7202/k/2">Pub. L. 101–508, title VII, § 7202(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-339">104 Stat. 1388–339</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/71">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(71)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1355">106 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tX/s1043/a/2">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1043(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/434">110 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tXI/s1131/b">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XI, § 1131(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1242">115 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9080463-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9080464-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9080465-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (n)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s1131/b/1">Pub. L. 107–107, § 1131(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “and” at end of subpar. (A), redesignated subpar. (C) as (B), and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “has 5 or more years of civilian service creditable under this chapter; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s1131/b/2">Pub. L. 107–107, § 1131(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “vested” before “participant in a retirement system” and struck out “, as the term ‘vested participant’ is defined by such system” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (n)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1043/a/2/A">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1043(a)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard” after “an employee” in introductory provisions and substituted “1 year” for “3 days” in subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1043/a/2/B">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1043(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “1 year” for “3 days” and struck out “in the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively,” after “to a position”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (n)(1)(A), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/71/A">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(71)(A)</ref>, amended subpars. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpars. (A) read as follows: “has not previously made or had an opportunity to make an election under this subsection;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/71/B">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(71)(B)</ref>, substituted “8347(q)” for “8347(p)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (m)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/556">Pub. L. 99–556</ref> struck out “, and from the Thrift Savings Fund,” after “from the Fund”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9080466-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb9080467-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9080468-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref>, see Regulations; Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9080469-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/378">Pub. L. 102–378</ref> effective <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s9/b/6">section 9(b)(6) of Pub. L. 102–378</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s6303">section 6303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb908046a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable with respect to any individual who, on or after <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, moves from employment in nonappropriated fund instrumentality of Department of Defense or Coast Guard, that is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105/c">section 2105(c) of this title</ref>, to employment in Department or Coast Guard, that is not described in section 2105(c), or who moves from employment in Department or Coast Guard, that is not described in section 2105(c), to employment in nonappropriated fund instrumentality of Department or Coast Guard, that is described in section 2105(c), see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s7202/m/1">section 7202(m)(1) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105">section 2105 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb908046b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations; Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to promulgation of regulations necessary to carry out amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref>, and effective date of such amendment in connection with those regulations, see section 1043(b), (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8347">section 8347 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb908046c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb908046d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Treatment of Individuals Electing To Remain Subject to Their Former Retirement System</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions relating to the deductions and contributions required with respect to individuals electing under section 8347(q) or 8461(n) of this title to remain covered under subchapter III of chapter 83 of this title, chapter 84 of this title, or a retirement system for employees described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105/c">section 2105(c) of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s7202/n">section 7202(n) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105">section 2105 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
