<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9165ae5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d"><num value="8714d">§ 8714d.</num><heading> Option to receive “living benefits”</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165ae6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> For the purpose of this section, an individual shall be considered to be “terminally ill” if such individual has a medical prognosis that such individual’s life expectancy is 9 months or less.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165ae7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations under which any individual covered by group life insurance under section 8704(a) may, if such individual is terminally ill, elect to receive a lump-sum payment equal to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9165ae8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the full amount of insurance under section 8704(a) (or portion thereof designated for this purpose under subsection (d)(4)) which would otherwise be payable under this chapter (on the establishment of a valid claim)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9165ae9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> computed based on a date determined under regulations of the Office (but not later than 30 days after the date on which the individual’s application for benefits under this section is approved or deemed approved under subsection (d)(3)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9165aea-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assuming continued coverage under this chapter at that time;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">reduced by</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9165aeb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an amount necessary to assure that there is no increase in the actuarial value of the benefit paid (as determined under regulations of the Office).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165aec-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165aed-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If a lump-sum payment is taken under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9165aee-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> no insurance under the provisions of section 8704(a) or (b) shall be payable based on the death or any loss of the individual involved, unless the lump-sum payment represents only a portion of the total benefits which could have been taken, in which case benefits under those provisions shall remain in effect, except that the basic insurance amount on which they are based—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9165aef-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall be reduced by the percentage which the designated portion comprised relative to the total benefits which could have been taken (rounding the result to the nearest multiple of $1,000 or, if midway between multiples of $1,000, to the next higher multiple of $1,000); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9165af0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall not be subject to further adjustment; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9165af1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> deductions and withholdings under section 8707, and contributions under section 8708, shall be terminated with respect to such individual (or reduced in a manner consistent with the percentage reduction in the individual’s basic insurance amount, if applicable), effective with respect to any amounts which would otherwise become due on or after the date of payment under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An individual who takes a lump-sum payment under this section (whether full or partial) remains eligible for optional benefits under sections 8714a–8714c (subject to payment of the full cost of those benefits in accordance with applicable provisions of the section or sections involved, to the same extent as if no election under this section had been made).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Office’s regulations shall include provisions regarding the form and manner in which an application under this section shall be made and the procedures in accordance with which any such application shall be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An application shall not be considered to be complete unless it includes such information and supporting evidence as the regulations require, including certification by an appropriate medical authority as to the nature of the individual’s illness and that the individual is not expected to live more than 9 months because of that illness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In order to ascertain the reliability of any medical opinion or finding submitted as part of an application under this section, the covered individual may be required to submit to a medical examination under the direction of the agency or entity considering the application. The individual shall not be liable for the costs associated with any examination required under this subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any decision by the reviewing agency or entity with respect to an application for benefits under this section (including one relating to an individual’s medical prognosis) shall not be subject to administrative review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165af9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165afa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An individual making an election under this section may designate that only a limited portion (expressed as a multiple of $1,000) of the total amount otherwise allowable under this section be paid pursuant to such election.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165afb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A designation under this paragraph may not be made by an individual described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 8706(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165afc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> An election to receive benefits under this section shall be irrevocable, and not more than one such election may be made by any individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9165afd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714d/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The regulations shall include provisions to address the question of how to apply section 8706(b)(3)(B) in the case of an electing individual who has attained 65 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9165afe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/409/s2/a">Pub. L. 103–409, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4230">108 Stat. 4230</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9165aff-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9165b00-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9165b01-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/409/s3/a">Pub. L. 103–409, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4232">108 Stat. 4232</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/409/s3/a">“The amendments made by section 2 [enacting this section] shall take effect 9 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
