<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb913ea7f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a"><num value="8714a">§ 8714a.</num><heading> Optional insurance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea80-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Under the conditions, directives, and terms specified in sections 8709–8712 of this title, the Office of Personnel Management, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, may purchase a policy which shall make available to each insured employee equal amounts of optional life insurance and accidental death and dismemberment insurance in addition to the amounts provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8704/a">section 8704(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea81-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea82-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An employee who is deployed in support of a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a/13">section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>) or an employee of the Department of Defense who is designated as emergency essential under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1580">section 1580 of title 10</ref> shall be insured under the policy of insurance under this section if the employee, within 60 days after the date of notification of deployment or designation, elects to be insured under the policy of insurance. An election under this paragraph shall be effective when provided to the Office in writing, in the form prescribed by the Office, within such 60-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea83-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The optional life insurance and accidental death and dismemberment insurance shall be made available to each insured employee under such conditions as the Office shall prescribe and in amounts approved by the Office but not more than the greater of $10,000 or an amount which, when added to the amount provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8704/a">section 8704(a) of this title</ref>, makes the sum of his insurance equal to his annual pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea84-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea85-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the optional insurance on an employee stops on his separation from service or 12 months after discontinuance of his pay, whichever is earlier, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea86-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea87-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> In the case of any employee who retires on an immediate annuity and has been insured under this section throughout—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb913ea88-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of such retirement, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb913ea89-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if less than 5 years,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the amount of optional life insurance only which has been in force throughout such period may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea8a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> In the case of any employee who becomes entitled to receive compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee and has been insured under this section throughout—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb913ea8b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date such employee becomes entitled to such compensation, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb913ea8c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if less than 5 years,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the amount of optional life insurance only which has been in force throughout such period may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office, during the period the employee is receiving such compensation for disease or injury and is held by the Secretary of Labor or his delegate to be unable to return to duty.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea8d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The amount of optional life insurance continued under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall be reduced by 2 percent at the end of each full calendar month after the date the employee becomes 65 years of age and is retired or is receiving compensation for disease or injury. The Office shall prescribe minimum amounts, not less than 25 percent of the amount of life insurance in force before the first reduction, to which the insurance may be reduced.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea8e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(1) of this section,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002187">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002187"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (1) of this subsection,”.</note> a justice or judge of the United States as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8701/a/5">section 8701(a)(5) of this title</ref> who resigns his office without meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s371/a">section 371(a) of title 28</ref>, United States Code, for continuation of the judicial salary shall have the right to convert regular optional life insurance coverage issued under this section during his judicial service to an individual policy of life insurance under the same conditions approved by the Office governing conversion of basic life insurance coverage for employees eligible as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8706/a">section 8706(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea8f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea90-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> During each period in which an employee has the optional insurance the full cost thereof shall be withheld from his pay. During each period in which an employee continues optional life insurance after retirement or while in receipt of compensation for work injuries, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8706/b">section 8706(b) of this title</ref>, the full cost thereof shall be withheld from his annuity or compensation, except that, at the end of the calendar month in which he becomes 65 years of age, the optional life insurance shall be without cost to him. Amounts so withheld shall be deposited, used, and invested as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8714">section 8714 of this title</ref> and shall be reported and accounted for separately from amounts withheld and contributed under sections 8707 and 8708 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea91-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an agency fails to withhold the proper cost of optional insurance from an individual’s salary, compensation, or retirement annuity, the collection of amounts properly due may be waived by the agency if, in the judgment of the agency, the individual is without fault and recovery would be against equity and good conscience. However, if the agency so waives the collection of any unpaid amount, the agency shall submit an amount equal to the uncollected amount to the Office for deposit to the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea92-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an employee who is subject to withholdings under this subsection and whose pay, annuity, or compensation is insufficient to cover such withholdings may nevertheless continue optional insurance if the employee arranges to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through the agency or retirement system which administers pay, annuity, or compensation, an amount equal to the withholdings that would otherwise be required under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea93-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The cost of the optional insurance shall be determined from time to time by the Office on the basis of such age groups as it considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb913ea94-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The amount of optional life, or life and accidental death, insurance in force on an employee at the date of his death shall be paid as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8705">section 8705 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb913ea95-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/90/206/tIV/s404/1">Pub. L. 90–206, title IV, § 404(1)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/647">81 Stat. 647</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tIX/s906/a/2">Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1224">92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/583/s1/c">Pub. L. 95–583, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2481">92 Stat. 2481</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/427/s6">Pub. L. 96–427, § 6</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1834">94 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tII/s206">Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/351">98 Stat. 351</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/336/s7/1">Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/639">100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tII/s207/k/3">Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/597">100 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/336/s7/1">Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-19">June 19, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/639">100 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/311/s6/2">Pub. L. 105–311, § 6(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2951">112 Stat. 2951</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title XI, § 1103(b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4616">122 Stat. 4616</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/a/12">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3841">124 Stat. 3841</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb913ea96-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb913ea97-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb913ea98-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref> substituted “section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">section 5 of title 41</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (2) and added par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/311">Pub. L. 105–311</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/336">Pub. L. 99–336</ref> amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s206">Pub. L. 98–353, § 206</ref>, generally. See 1984 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> amended par. (1) generally, effective <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>. Prior to such effective date, par. (1) read as follows: “The optional insurance on an employee stops on his separation from service, 12 months after discontinuance of his pay, or on his entry on active duty or active duty for training, as provided in sections 8706(a) and 8706(c) of this title. Justices and judges of the United States described in section 8701(a)(5)(ii) and (iii) of this chapter are deemed to continue in active employment for purposes of this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s206">Pub. L. 98–353, § 206</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/99/336">Pub. L. 99–336</ref>, inserted sentence which deemed justices and judges described in section 8701(a)(5)(ii) and (iii) of this chapter to continue in active employment for purposes of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s206">Pub. L. 98–353, § 206</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/96/427/s6/a">Pub. L. 96–427, § 6(a)</ref>, substituted provisions that the amount of optional life insurance shall be reduced by 2% at the end of each calendar month after the date the employee becomes 65 years of age and is retired or is receiving compensation for disease or injury and that the Office shall prescribe minimum amount of life insurance in force before the first reduction to which the insurance may be reduced for provisions that such optional insurance be subject to the same monthly reductions as required for regular life insurance under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8706/b/3">section 8706(b)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/427/s6/b">Pub. L. 96–427, § 6(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> substituted “Office of Personnel Management” for “Civil Service Commission” and “Office” for “Commission” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/583/s1/c/1">Pub. L. 95–583, § 1(c)(1)</ref>, substituted reference to section “8706(c)” for “8706(d)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/583/s1/c/2">Pub. L. 95–583, § 1(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “So much of the optional life insurance in force on an employee on the date he retires on an immediate annuity or becomes entitled to receive compensation for work injuries which has been in force for not less than—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the full period or periods of service during which the optional insurance was available to him; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the 12 years of service immediately preceding his retirement or beginning date of entitlement to compensation for work injuries and during which the optional insurance was available to him;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever is shorter, may be continued—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) after retirement, under the same conditions (except with respect to cost but including reduction of the amount continued) as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8706/b">section 8706(b) of this title</ref>; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) while in receipt of compensation for work injuries under the same conditions (except with respect to cost) as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8706/c">section 8706(c) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, which substituted “Office” for “Commission”, was executed to text of subsec. (c)(2) as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/583">Pub. L. 95–583</ref>. See Effective Date of 1978 Amendments note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/583/s1/c/3">Pub. L. 95–583, § 1(c)(3)</ref>, struck out “or 8706(c)” after “section 8706(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> substituted “Office” for “Commission”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb913ea99-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb913ea9a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/311">Pub. L. 105–311</ref> effective on the first day of the first applicable pay period beginning on or after <date date="1998-10-30">Oct. 30, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/311/s11/d">section 11(d) of Pub. L. 105–311</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb913ea9b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> effective <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/s702/a">section 702(a) of Pub. L. 99–335</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401">section 8401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb913ea9c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s206">Pub. L. 98–353, § 206</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/99/336/s7/1">Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(1)</ref>, applicable to any justice or judge who retires under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s371/a">28 U.S.C. 371(a)</ref> or (b) or 372(a) on or after <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/s207">section 207 of Pub. L. 98–353</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/99/336/s7/2">Pub. L. 99–336, § 7(2)</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8706">section 8706 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb913ea9d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/427">Pub. L. 96–427</ref> effective <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, with amendment to have no effect in case of an employee who died, was separated, or retired before <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/427/s10/a">section 10(a) of Pub. L. 96–427</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb913ea9e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/583">Pub. L. 95–583</ref> effective <date date="1978-11-02">Nov. 2, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/583/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 95–583</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8706">section 8706 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb913ea9f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/90/206/tIV/s405/b">Pub. L. 90–206, title IV, § 405(b)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/648">81 Stat. 648</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/90/206/tIV/s405/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The amendments made by section 404 of this Act [enacting this section and amending analysis preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the first day of the first pay period which begins on or after the one hundred and eightieth day following the date of enactment [<date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>], or on any earlier date that the Civil Service Commission may prescribe, which is at least sixty days after the date of enactment [<date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>]. In the case of an employee who dies during the period beginning on the date of enactment [<date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>] and ending on the effective date prescribed by or pursuant to this subsection, or during the sixty days immediately following such period if the Commission determines that he did not have a reasonable opportunity to elect the optional insurance made available by section 404, the insurance of such employee shall be determined as if the amendments made by section 404 had been in effect on the date of such death, and the employee had elected to receive the maximum amount of optional insurance available to him under such amendments. An employee who retires during the period beginning on the date of enactment and ending on the effective date prescribed by or pursuant to this subsection shall have an opportunity to elect the optional insurance made available by section 404.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In the case of an employee in the service on the effective date prescribed by or pursuant to this subsection, (i) the period during which such employee may elect to receive optional insurance under the amendment made by section 404 shall not expire prior to the sixtieth day after such effective date, and (ii) for the purpose of determining the amount of insurance to be continued after retirement, the period during which such optional insurance was available to such employee shall not be considered to have commenced prior to the expiration of sixty days following such effective date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="retroactiveDate" id="idb913eaa0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Retroactive Effect</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enactment of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/90/206">Pub. L. 90–206</ref> to have no effect in the case of an employee who died, was finally separated, or retired prior to <date date="1967-12-16">Dec. 16, 1967</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/206/s405/c">section 405(c) of Pub. L. 90–206</ref>, set out as an Retroactive Effect of 1967 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8704">section 8704 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb913eaa1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Availability of Certain Funds in Employees’ Life Insurance Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/427/s11">Pub. L. 96–427, § 11</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1838">94 Stat. 1838</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/427/s11">“Amounts credited to the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8714a/d">section 8714a(d) of title 5</ref>, United States Code shall be available for expenses incurred by the Office of Personnel Management in implementing the amendments made by sections 7 and 8 of this Act [enacting sections 8714b, 8714c, and 8701(d) of this title].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
