<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb91d86ba-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905"><num value="8905">§ 8905.</num><heading> Election of coverage</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86bb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> An employee may enroll in an approved health benefits plan described in section 8903 or 8903a—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86bc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> as an individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86bd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for self plus one; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86be-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> for self and family.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86bf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> An annuitant who at the time he becomes an annuitant was enrolled in a health benefits plan under this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86c0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> as an employee for a period of not less than—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91d86c1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the 5 years of service immediately before retirement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91d86c2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the full period or periods of service between the last day of the first period, as prescribed by regulations of the Office of Personnel Management, in which he is eligible to enroll in the plan and the date on which he becomes an annuitant; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91d86c3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the full period or periods of service beginning with the enrollment which became effective before <date date="1965-01-01">January 1, 1965</date>, and ending with the date on which he becomes an annuitant;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">whichever is shortest; or</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86c4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> as a member of the family of an employee or annuitant;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may continue his enrollment under the conditions of eligibility prescribed by regulations of the Office. The Office may, in its sole discretion, waive the requirements of this subsection in the case of an individual who fails to satisfy such requirements if the Office determines that, due to exceptional circumstances, it would be against equity and good conscience not to allow such individual to be enrolled as an annuitant in a health benefits plan under this chapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002191">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002191"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</note></continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86c5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86c6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A former spouse may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86c7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> within 60 days after the dissolution of the marriage, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86c8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a former spouse of a former employee whose marriage was dissolved after the employee’s retirement, within 60 days after the dissolution of the marriage or, if later, within 60 days after an election is made under section 8339(j)(3) or 8417(b) of this title for such former spouse by the retired employee,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">enroll in an approved health benefits plan described by section 8903 or 8903a of this title as an individual or for <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002192">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002192"><num>2</num> So in original. The word “for” probably should precede “self and family”.</note> for self plus one or self and family as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, subject to agreement to pay the full subscription charge of the enrollment, including the amounts determined by the Office to be necessary for administration and reserves pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8909/b">section 8909(b) of this title</ref>. The former spouse shall submit an enrollment application and make premium payments to the agency which, at the time of divorce or annulment, employed the employee to whom the former spouse was married or, in the case of a former spouse who is receiving annuity payments under section 8341(h), 8345(j), 8445, or 8467 of this title, to the Office of Personnel Management.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86c9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Coverage for self plus one or for self and family under this subsection shall be limited to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86ca-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the former spouse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86cb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> unmarried dependent natural or adopted children (or, in the case of self plus one coverage, not more than 1 such child) of the former spouse and the employee who are—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91d86cc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> under 22 years of age; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb91d86cd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> incapable of self-support because of mental or physical disability which existed before age 22.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86ce-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> An individual whom the Secretary of Defense determines is an eligible beneficiary under subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1108">section 1108 of title 10</ref> may enroll, as part of the demonstration project under such section, in a health benefits plan under this chapter in accordance with the agreement under subsection (a) of such section between the Secretary and the Office and applicable regulations under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86cf-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> If an employee, annuitant, or other individual eligible to enroll in a health benefits plan under this chapter has a spouse who is also eligible to enroll, either spouse, but not both, may enroll for self and family, or for a self plus one enrollment that covers the spouse, or each spouse may enroll as an individual or for a self plus one enrollment that does not cover the other spouse or a child who is covered under the enrollment of the other spouse. However, an individual may not be enrolled both as an employee, annuitant, or other individual eligible to enroll and as a member of the family.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86d0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> An employee, annuitant, former spouse, or person having continued coverage under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8905a">section 8905a of this title</ref> enrolled in a health benefits plan under this chapter may change his coverage or that of himself and members of his family by an application filed within 60 days after a change in family status or at other times and under conditions prescribed by regulations of the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86d1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86d2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Office, the Office shall, before the start of any contract term in which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86d3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an adjustment is made in any of the rates charged or benefits provided under a health benefits plan described by section 8903 or 8903a of this title,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86d4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a newly approved health benefits plan is offered, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb91d86d5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an existing plan is terminated,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">provide a period of not less than 3 weeks during which any employee, annuitant, former spouse, or person having continued coverage under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8905a">section 8905a of this title</ref> enrolled in a health benefits plan described by such section shall be permitted to transfer that individual’s enrollment to another such plan or to cancel such enrollment.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86d6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In addition to any opportunity afforded under paragraph (1) of this subsection, an employee, annuitant, former spouse, or person having continued coverage under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8905a">section 8905a of this title</ref> enrolled in a health benefits plan under this chapter shall be permitted to transfer that individual’s enrollment to another such plan, or to cancel such enrollment, at such other times and subject to such conditions as the Office may prescribe in regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86d7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86d8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In addition to any informational requirements otherwise applicable under this chapter, the regulations shall include provisions to ensure that each employee eligible to enroll in a health benefits plan under this chapter (whether actually enrolled or not) is notified in writing as to the rights afforded under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8905a">section 8905a of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86d9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notification under this paragraph shall be provided by employing agencies at an appropriate point in time before each period under paragraph (1) so that employees may be aware of their rights under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8905a">section 8905a of this title</ref> when making enrollment decisions during such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86da-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86db-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An unenrolled employee who is required by a court or administrative order to provide health insurance coverage for 1 or more children who meets the requirements of section 8901(5) may enroll for self plus one or self and family coverage, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in a health benefits plan under this chapter. If such employee fails to enroll for self plus one or self and family coverage, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in a health benefits plan that provides full benefits and services in the location in which the child or children reside, and the employee does not provide documentation showing that such coverage has been provided through other health insurance, the employing agency shall enroll the employee in a self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in the option which provides the lower level of coverage under the Service Benefit Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86dc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An employee who is enrolled as an individual in a health benefits plan under this chapter and who is required by a court or administrative order to provide health insurance coverage for 1 or more children who meets the requirements of section 8901(5) may change to a self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in the same or another health benefits plan under this chapter. If such employee fails to change to a self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, and the employee does not provide documentation showing that such coverage has been provided through other health insurance, the employing agency shall change the enrollment of the employee to a self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in the plan in which the employee is enrolled if that plan provides full benefits and services in the location where the child or children reside. If the plan in which the employee is enrolled does not provide full benefits and services in the location in which the child or children reside, or, if the employee fails to change to a self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in a plan that provides full benefits and services in the location where the child or children reside, the employing agency shall change the coverage of the employee to a self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in the option which provides the lower level of coverage under the Service Benefits Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86dd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The employee may not discontinue the self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order, in a plan that provides full benefits and services in the location in which the child or children reside for so long as the court or administrative order remains in effect and the child or children continue to meet the requirements of section 8901(5), unless the employee provides documentation showing that such coverage has been provided through other health insurance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb91d86de-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s8905/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any services by an officer or employee under this chapter relating to enrolling individuals in a health benefits plan under this chapter, or changing the enrollment of an individual already so enrolled, shall be deemed, for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1342">section 1342 of title 31</ref>, services for emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb91d86df-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/603">80 Stat. 603</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tIX/s906/a/2">Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1224">92 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s3/4">Pub. L. 98–615, § 3(4)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3203">98 Stat. 3203</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/53/s2/a">Pub. L. 99–53, § 2(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1985-06-17">June 17, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/94">99 Stat. 94</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/tI">Pub. L. 99–251, title I</ref>, §§ 103, 104(a), <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/14">100 Stat. 14</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tII/s207/m">Pub. L. 99–335, title II, § 207(m)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/598">100 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/654/tII">Pub. L. 100–654, title II</ref>, §§ 201(c), (d), 202(c), <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3845">102 Stat. 3845</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/77">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(77)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1355">106 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tVII/s721/b/1">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VII, § 721(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2065">112 Stat. 2065</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/394/s2">Pub. L. 106–394, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1629">114 Stat. 1629</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/dA/tVII/s706/a">Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title VII, § 706(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/1193">127 Stat. 1193</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXI/s1110/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XI, § 1110(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1600">133 Stat. 1600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb91d86e0-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idb91d86e1-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50,tp7,p6,6/7,xs37,xls66,r50; " id="idb91d86e2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:41pt ; max-width:41pt;" />
<html:col style="width:70pt ; max-width:70pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 95pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:41.0pt ; max-width:41.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Derivation</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:70.0pt ; max-width:70.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>U.S. Code</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 95.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised Statutes and</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Statutes at Large</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> </html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s3002/a">5 U.S.C. 3002(a)</html:a> (1st sentence, less words between 1st and 4th commas), (b)–(e).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Sept. 28, 1959</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/86/382/s3/a">Pub. L. 86–382, § 3(a)</html:a> (1st sentence, less words between 1st and 4th commas), (b)–(e), <html:a href="/us/stat/73/710">73 Stat. 710</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">Mar. 17, 1964</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/pl/88/284/s1/5">Pub. L. 88–284, § 1(5)</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/78/164">78 Stat. 164</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b)(1), the words “as an employee” are inserted for clarity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b)(1)(C), the words “before <date date="1965-01-01">January 1, 1965</date>” are substituted for “not later than <date date="1964-12-31">December 31, 1964</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb91d86e3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb91d86e4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/1">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which read as follows: “An employee may enroll in an approved health benefits plan described by section 8903 or 8903a of this title either as an individual or for self and family.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/2/A">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “for self plus one or” before “self and family as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/2/B/i">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “for self plus one or” before “for self and family” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “(or, in the case of self plus one coverage, not more than 1 such child)” after “adopted children”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/3">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “or for a self plus one enrollment that covers the spouse, or each spouse may enroll as an individual or for a self plus one enrollment that does not cover the other spouse or a child who is covered under the enrollment of the other spouse” for “or each spouse may enroll as an individual”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/4/A">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(4)(A)</ref>–(C), substituted “self plus one or self and family enrollment, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order,” for “self and family enrollment”, “1 or more children” for “a child”, and “the child or children reside” for “the child resides” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/4/D">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(4)(D)</ref>, substituted “self plus one or self and family coverage, as necessary to provide health insurance coverage for each child who is covered under the order,” for “self and family coverage” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s706/a/4/E">Pub. L. 113–67, § 706(a)(4)(E)</ref>, substituted “the child or children continue” for “the child continues”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/106/394">Pub. L. 106–394</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsecs. (d) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261">Pub. L. 105–261</ref> added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsecs. (d) to (f) as (e) to (g), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/77/A">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(77)(A)</ref>, substituted “this chapter” for “this subchapter.” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/378/s2/77/B">Pub. L. 102–378, § 2(77)(B)</ref>, inserted comma after “8341(h)” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/654/s202/c">Pub. L. 100–654, § 202(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “If an employee has a spouse who is an employee, either spouse, but not both, may enroll for self and family, or each spouse may enroll as an individual. However, an individual may not be enrolled both as an employee or annuitant and as a member of the family.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/654/s201/c">Pub. L. 100–654, § 201(c)</ref>, (d)(1), substituted “former spouse, or person having continued coverage under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8905a">section 8905a of this title</ref>” for “or former spouse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/654/s201/d/2">Pub. L. 100–654, § 201(d)(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/s103">Pub. L. 99–251, § 103</ref>, inserted last sentence relating to waiver of the requirements of this subsection if it would be against equity to prohibit enrollment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> inserted in subpar. (B) “or 8417(b)” and substituted in provision following subpar. (B) “8345(j), 8445, or 8467” for “or 8345(j)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/251/s104/a">Pub. L. 99–251, § 104(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (f) read as follows: “An employee, annuitant, or former spouse enrolled in a health benefits plan under this chapter may change his coverage or that of himself and members of his family by an application filed within 60 days after a change in family status or at other times and under conditions prescribed by regulations of the Office.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsecs. (a), (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/53/s2/a">Pub. L. 99–53, § 2(a)</ref>, inserted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8903a">section 8903a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/53/s2/a">Pub. L. 99–53, § 2(a)</ref>, (c), inserted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8903a">section 8903a of this title</ref> and substituted “such plan” for “plan described by that section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s3/4/A">Pub. L. 98–615, § 3(4)(A)</ref>, added subsec. (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s3/4/A">Pub. L. 98–615, § 3(4)(A)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s3/4">Pub. L. 98–615, § 3(4)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e) and substituted “An employee, annuitant, or former spouse” for “An employee or annuitant”. Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s3/4">Pub. L. 98–615, § 3(4)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (e) as (f) and substituted “An employee, annuitant, or former spouse” for “An employee or annuitant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (b), (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> substituted “Office of Personnel Management” and “Office” for “Civil Service Commission” and “Commission”, respectively, wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb91d86e5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb91d86e6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2019 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> applicable to any lapse in appropriations beginning on or after <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1110/d">section 1110(d) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8702">section 8702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb91d86e7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/654">Pub. L. 100–654</ref> applicable with respect to any calendar year beginning, and contracts entered into or renewed for any calendar year beginning, after end of 9-month period beginning <date date="1988-11-14">Nov. 14, 1988</date>, and with respect to any qualifying event occurring on or after first day of first calendar year beginning after end of such 9-month period, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/654/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 100–654</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8902">section 8902 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb91d86e8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> effective <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/s702/a">section 702(a) of Pub. L. 99–335</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401">section 8401 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/251/tI/s104/b">Pub. L. 99–251, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-02-27">Feb. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/15">100 Stat. 15</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/251/tI/s104/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall be effective with respect to contracts entered into or renewed for calendar years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb91d86e9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/615">Pub. L. 98–615</ref> effective <date date="1985-05-07">May 7, 1985</date>, with enumerated exceptions, and applicable to any individual who is married to an employee or annuitant on or after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/615/s4/a/2">section 4(a)(2) of Pub. L. 98–615</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb91d86ea-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb91d86eb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Regulations to carry out amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> to be prescribed no later than 90 days after <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, and to contain provision related to pay status for furloughed employees, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1110/c">section 1110(c) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8702">section 8702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb91d86ec-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">FEHB Improvements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/21/tIX/s90101/a">Pub. L. 119–21, title IX, § 90101(a)</ref>–(f), <date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/362">139 Stat. 362</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/21/tIX/s90101/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short Title</inline>.—</heading><content>This section may be cited as the ‘FEHB Protection Act of 2025’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Director’ means the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Health benefits plan; member of family</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘health benefits plan’ and ‘member of family’ have the meanings given those terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8901">section 8901 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Open season</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘open season’ means an open season described in section 890.301(f) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Program’ means the health insurance programs carried out under chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, including the program carried out under section 8903c of that title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualifying life event</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘qualifying life event’ has the meaning given the term in section 892.101 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Verification Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>], the Director shall issue regulations and implement a process to verify—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the veracity of any qualifying life event through which an enrollee in the Program seeks to add a member of family with respect to the enrollee to a health benefits plan under the Program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that, when an enrollee in the Program seeks to add a member of family with respect to the enrollee to the health benefits plan of the enrollee under the Program, including during any open season, the individual so added is a qualifying member of family with respect to the enrollee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fraud Risk Assessment</inline>.—</heading><content>In any fraud risk assessment conducted with respect to the Program on or after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall include an assessment of individuals who are enrolled in, or covered under, a health benefits plan under the Program even though those individuals are not eligible to be so enrolled or covered.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Family Member Eligibility Verification Audit.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>During the 3-year period beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall carry out a comprehensive audit regarding members of family who are covered under an enrollment in a health benefits plan under the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to the audit carried out under paragraph (1), the Director shall review marriage certificates, birth certificates, and other appropriate documents that are necessary to determine eligibility to enroll in a health benefits plan under the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disenrollment or Removal</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall develop a process by which any individual enrolled in, or covered under, a health benefits plan under the Program who is not eligible to be so enrolled or covered shall be disenrolled or removed from enrollment in, or coverage under, that health benefits plan.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb91d86ed-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Weighted Average for First Year</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/67/dA/tVII/s706/d">Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title VII, § 706(d)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/1194">127 Stat. 1194</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/67/dA/tVII/s706/d">“For the first contract year for which an employee may enroll for self plus one coverage under chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, the Office of Personnel Management shall determine the weighted average of the subscription charges that will be in effect for the contract year for enrollments for self plus one under such chapter based on an actuarial analysis.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb91d86ee-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Election of Health Benefits Coverage and Entitlement to Health Benefits Under this Chapter Rather Than Under Retired Federal Employees Health Benefits Act</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/246">Pub. L. 93–246</ref>, §§ 2, 4(b), <date date="1974-01-31">Jan. 31, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/4">88 Stat. 4</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/246">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="2">“Sec. 2.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an annuitant, as defined under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8901/3">section 8901(3) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, who is participating or who is eligible to participate in the health benefits program offered under the Retired Federal Employees Health Benefits Act (<ref href="/us/stat/74/849">74 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/724">Public Law 86–724</ref>), may elect, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the United States Civil Service Commission, to be covered under the provisions of chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, in lieu of coverage under such Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> An annuitant who elects to be covered under the provisions of chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, shall be entitled to the benefits under such chapter 89.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="4">“[Sec. 4]</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b"> (b)</num><content> Section 2 [set out above] shall take effect on the one hundred and eightieth day following the date of enactment [<date date="1974-01-01">Jan. 1, 1974</date>] or on such earlier date as the United States Civil Service Commission may prescribe.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
