<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb924b3f2-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008"><num value="9008">§ 9008.</num><heading> Administrative functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb924b3f3-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations necessary to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb924b3f4-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enrollment Periods</inline>.—</heading><content>The Office shall provide for periodic coordinated enrollment, promotion, and education efforts in consultation with the carriers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb924b3f5-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>Any regulations necessary to effect the application and operation of this chapter with respect to an eligible individual described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 9001, or a qualified relative thereof, shall be prescribed by the Office in consultation with the appropriate Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb924b3f6-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Informed Decisionmaking</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Office shall ensure that each eligible individual applying for long-term care insurance under this chapter is furnished the information necessary to enable that individual to evaluate the advantages and disadvantages of obtaining long-term care insurance under this chapter, including the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb924b3f7-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The principal long-term care benefits and coverage available under this chapter, and how those benefits and coverage compare to the range of long-term care benefits and coverage otherwise generally available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb924b3f8-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Representative examples of the cost of long-term care, and the sufficiency of the benefits available under this chapter relative to those costs. The information under this paragraph shall also include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb924b3f9-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the projected effect of inflation on the value of those benefits; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb924b3fa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a comparison of the inflation-adjusted value of those benefits to the projected future costs of long-term care.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb924b3fb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Any rights individuals under this chapter may have to cancel coverage, and to receive a total or partial refund of premiums. The information under this paragraph shall also include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb924b3fc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the projected number or percentage of individuals likely to fail to maintain their coverage (determined based on lapse rates experienced under similar group long-term care insurance programs and, when available, this chapter); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb924b3fd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb924b3fe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a summary description of how and when premiums for long-term care insurance under this chapter may be raised;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb924b3ff-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the premium history during the last 10 years for each qualified carrier offering long-term care insurance under this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb924b400-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> if cost increases are anticipated, the projected premiums for a typical insured individual at various ages.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb924b401-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9008/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The advantages and disadvantages of long-term care insurance generally, relative to other means of accumulating or otherwise acquiring the assets that may be needed to meet the costs of long-term care, such as through tax-qualified retirement programs or other investment vehicles.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb924b402-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/265/tI/s1002/a">Pub. L. 106–265, title I, § 1002(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-09-19">Sept. 19, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/768">114 Stat. 768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
