<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9296e2e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602"><num value="9602">§ 9602.</num><heading> Competitive service; time-limited appointments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296e2f-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding chapter 33 or any other provision of law relating to the examination, certification, and appointment of individuals in the competitive service, an employee of a land management agency serving under a time-limited appointment in the competitive service is eligible to compete for a permanent appointment in the competitive service at such land management agency when such agency is accepting applications from individuals within the agency’s workforce under merit promotion procedures, or any agency, including a land management agency, when the agency is accepting applications from individuals outside its own workforce under the merit promotion procedures of the applicable agency if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296e30-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the employee was appointed initially under open, competitive examination under subchapter I of chapter 33 to the time-limited appointment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296e31-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the employee has served under 1 or more time-limited appointments by a land management agency for a period or periods totaling more than 24 months without a break of 2 or more years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296e32-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the employee’s performance has been at an acceptable level of performance throughout the period or periods (as the case may be) referred to in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296e33-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In determining the eligibility of a time-limited employee under this section to be examined for or appointed in the competitive service, the Office of Personnel Management or other examining agency shall waive requirements as to age, unless the requirement is essential to the performance of the duties of the position.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296e34-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> An individual appointed under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296e35-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> becomes a career-conditional employee, unless the employee has otherwise completed the service requirements for career tenure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296e36-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> acquires competitive status upon appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296e37-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> A former employee of a land management agency who served under a time-limited appointment and who otherwise meets the requirements of this section shall be deemed a time-limited employee of the agency from which the former employee was most recently separated for purposes of this section if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296e38-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such employee applies for a position covered by this section within the period of 2 years after the most recent date of separation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296e39-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such employee’s most recent separation was for reasons other than misconduct or performance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296e3a-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9602/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9296e3b-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/114/47/s2/a">Pub. L. 114–47, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-08-07">Aug. 7, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/485">129 Stat. 485</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXI/s1135">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XI, § 1135</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2459">130 Stat. 2459</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9296e3c-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9296e3d-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9296e3e-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1135/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1135(1)</ref>, substituted in introductory provisions “such land management agency when such agency is accepting applications from individuals within the agency’s workforce under merit promotion procedures, or any agency, including a land management agency, when the agency is accepting applications from individuals outside its own workforce under the merit promotion procedures of the applicable agency” for “any land management agency or any other agency (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s101">section 101 of title 31</ref>) under the internal merit promotion procedures of the applicable agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1135/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1135(2)</ref>, inserted “of the agency from which the former employee was most recently separated” after “deemed a time-limited employee” in introductory provisions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
