<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9296efa-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806"><num value="9806">§ 9806.</num><heading> Term appointments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296efb-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Administrator may authorize term appointments within the Administration under subchapter I of chapter 33, for a period of not less than 1 year and not more than 6 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296efc-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding chapter 33 or any other provision of law relating to the examination, certification, and appointment of individuals in the competitive service, the Administrator may convert an employee serving under a term appointment to a permanent appointment in the competitive service within the Administration without further competition if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296efd-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such individual was appointed under open, competitive examination under subchapter I of chapter 33 to the term position;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296efe-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the announcement for the term appointment from which the conversion is made stated that there was potential for subsequent conversion to a career-conditional or career appointment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296eff-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the employee has completed at least 2 years of current continuous service under a term appointment in the competitive service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296f00-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the employee’s performance under such term appointment was at least fully successful or equivalent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9296f01-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the position to which such employee is being converted under this section is in the same occupational series, is in the same geographic location, and provides no greater promotion potential than the term position for which the competitive examination was conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296f02-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Notwithstanding chapter 33 or any other provision of law relating to the examination, certification, and appointment of individuals in the competitive service, the Administrator may convert an employee serving under a term appointment to a permanent appointment in the competitive service within the Administration through internal competitive promotion procedures if the conditions under paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b) are met.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296f03-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> An employee converted under this section becomes a career-conditional employee, unless the employee has otherwise completed the service requirements for career tenure.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9296f04-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea" identifier="/us/usc/t5/s9806/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> An employee converted to career or career-conditional employment under this section acquires competitive status upon conversion.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9296f05-5e84-11f1-a692-ec26948f6fea">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/108/201/s3/a">Pub. L. 108–201, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-02-24">Feb. 24, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/466">118 Stat. 466</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
