<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida1c642c8-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112"><num value="112">§ 112.</num><heading> Drug interdiction and counter-drug activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642c9-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding Assistance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may provide funds to the Governor of a State who submits to the Secretary a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan satisfying the requirements of subsection (c). Such funds shall be used for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642ca-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The pay, allowances, clothing, subsistence, gratuities, travel, and related expenses, as authorized by State law, of personnel of the National Guard of that State used, while not in Federal service, for the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642cb-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The operation and maintenance of the equipment and facilities of the National Guard of that State used for the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642cc-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The procurement of services and equipment, and the leasing of equipment, for the National Guard of that State used for the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities. However, the use of such funds for the procurement of equipment may not exceed $15,000 per item, unless approval for procurement of equipment in excess of that amount is granted in advance by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642cd-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Personnel Performing Full-Time National Guard Duty</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642ce-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, personnel of the National Guard of a State may, in accordance with the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan referred to in subsection (c), be ordered to perform full-time National Guard duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/f">section 502(f) of this title</ref> for the purpose of carrying out drug interdiction and counter-drug activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642cf-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642d0-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A member of the National Guard serving on full-time National Guard duty under orders authorized under paragraph (1) shall participate in the training required under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/a">section 502(a) of this title</ref> in addition to the duty performed for the purpose authorized under that paragraph. The pay, allowances, and other benefits of the member while participating in the training shall be the same as those to which the member is entitled while performing duty for the purpose of carrying out drug interdiction and counter-drug activities. The member is not entitled to additional pay, allowances, or other benefits for participation in training required under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/a/1">section 502(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642d1-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Appropriations available for the Department of Defense for drug interdiction and counter-drug activities may be used for paying costs associated with a member’s participation in training described in subparagraph (A). The appropriation shall be reimbursed in full, out of appropriations available for paying those costs, for the amounts paid. Appropriations available for paying those costs shall be available for making the reimbursements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642d2-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> To ensure that the use of units and personnel of the National Guard of a State pursuant to a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan does not degrade the training and readiness of such units and personnel, the following requirements shall apply in determining the drug interdiction and counter-drug activities that units and personnel of the National Guard of a State may perform:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642d3-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The performance of the activities may not adversely affect the quality of that training or otherwise interfere with the ability of a member or unit of the National Guard to perform the military functions of the member or unit.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642d4-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> National Guard personnel will not degrade their military skills as a result of performing the activities.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642d5-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The performance of the activities will not result in a significant increase in the cost of training.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642d6-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> In the case of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities performed by a unit organized to serve as a unit, the activities will support valid unit training requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642d7-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A unit or member of the National Guard of a State may be used, pursuant to a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan approved by the Secretary of Defense under this section, to provide services or other assistance (other than air transportation) to an organization eligible to receive services under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s508">section 508 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642d8-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan specifically recognizes the organization as being eligible to receive the services or assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642d9-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of services, the performance of the services meets the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s508">section 508 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642da-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the services or assistance is authorized under subsection (b) or (c) of such section or in the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642db-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642dc-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> specify how personnel of the National Guard of that State are to be used in drug interdiction and counter-drug activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642dd-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> certify that those operations are to be conducted at a time when the personnel involved are not in Federal service;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642de-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> certify that participation by National Guard personnel in those operations is service in addition to training required under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502">section 502 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642df-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> certify that any engineer-type activities (as defined by the Secretary of Defense) under the plan will be performed only by units and members of the National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642e0-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> include a certification by the Attorney General of the State (or, in the case of a State with no position of Attorney General, a civilian official of the State equivalent to a State attorney general) that the use of the National Guard of the State for the activities proposed under the plan is authorized by, and is consistent with, State law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642e1-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> certify that the Governor of the State or a civilian law enforcement official of the State designated by the Governor has determined that any activities included in the plan that are carried out in conjunction with Federal law enforcement agencies serve a State law enforcement purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642e2-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Examination of Plan</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642e3-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Before funds are provided to the Governor of a State under this section and before members of the National Guard of that State are ordered to full-time National Guard duty as authorized in subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense shall examine the adequacy of the plan submitted by the Governor under subsection (c). The plan as approved by the Secretary may provide for the use of personnel and equipment of the National Guard of that State to assist the Immigration and Naturalization Service in the transportation of aliens who have violated a Federal or State law prohibiting or regulating the possession, use, or distribution of a controlled substance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642e4-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall carry out paragraph (1) in consultation with the Director of National Drug Control Policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642e5-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (2) shall not apply if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642e6-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Governor of a State submits a plan under subsection (c) that is substantially the same as a plan submitted for that State for a previous fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642e7-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> pursuant to the plan submitted for a previous fiscal year, funds were provided to the State in accordance with subsection (a) or personnel of the National Guard of the State were ordered to perform full-time National Guard duty in accordance with subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642e8-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">End Strength Limitation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642e9-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), at the end of a fiscal year there may not be more than 4000 members of the National Guard—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642ea-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> on full-time National Guard duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/f">section 502(f) of this title</ref> to perform drug interdiction or counter-drug activities pursuant to an order to duty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642eb-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> on duty under State authority to perform drug interdiction or counter-drug activities pursuant to an order to duty with State pay and allowances being reimbursed with funds provided under subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642ec-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may increase the end strength authorized under paragraph (1) by not more than 20 percent for any fiscal year if the Secretary determines that such an increase is necessary in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642ed-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress an annual report regarding assistance provided and activities carried out under this section during the preceding fiscal year. The report shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642ee-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The number of members of the National Guard excluded under subsection (e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002001"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> from the computation of end strengths.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642ef-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description of the drug interdiction and counter-drug activities conducted under State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plans referred to in subsection (c) with funds provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642f0-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An accounting of the amount of funds provided to each State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642f1-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A description of the effect on military training and readiness of using units and personnel of the National Guard to perform activities under the State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642f2-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statutory Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as a limitation on the authority of any unit of the National Guard of a State, when such unit is not in Federal service, to perform law enforcement functions authorized to be performed by the National Guard by the laws of the State concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida1c642f3-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642f4-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “drug interdiction and counter-drug activities”, with respect to the National Guard of a State, means the use of National Guard personnel in drug interdiction and counter-drug law enforcement activities, including drug demand reduction activities, authorized by the law of the State and requested by the Governor of the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642f5-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Governor of a State” means, in the case of the District of Columbia, the Commanding General of the National Guard of the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1c642f6-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s112/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida1c642f7-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXII/s1207/a/1">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XII, § 1207(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1564">103 Stat. 1564</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/118">105 Stat. 118</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/396/tIX/s9099A">Pub. L. 102–396, title IX, § 9099A</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1926">106 Stat. 1926</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tX/s1021">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/426">110 Stat. 426</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dC/tVI/s660">Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title VI, § 660</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-720">110 Stat. 3009–720</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tX/s1031">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1880">111 Stat. 1880</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tX/s1022">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1022</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2120">112 Stat. 2120</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1021">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/746">113 Stat. 746</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s416/k">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(k)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1869">118 Stat. 1869</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tX/s1012">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1012</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/380">137 Stat. 380</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida1c642f8-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida1c642f9-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida1c642fa-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (e), referred to in subsec. (f)(1), was repealed and subsec. (f) was redesignated (e) by <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s416/k/1">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(k)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1869">118 Stat. 1869</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida1c642fb-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tXI/s1105">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2047">102 Stat. 2047</ref>, which was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s374">section 374 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s1207/b">Pub. L. 101–189, § 1207(b)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida1c642fc-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> substituted “$15,000” for “$5,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/k/1">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(k)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (f) as (e) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (e). Text read as follows: “Members of the National Guard on active duty or full-time National Guard duty for the purposes of administering (or during fiscal year 1993 otherwise implementing) this section shall not be counted toward the annual end strength authorized for reserves on active duty in support of the reserve components of the armed forces or toward the strengths authorized in sections 12011 and 12012 of title 10.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/k/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(k)(3)</ref>, struck out “for a period of more than 180 days” after “order to duty”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/k/2">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(k)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (g) to (i) as (f) to (h), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “per item” for “per purchase order” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1022/e/1">Pub. L. 105–261, § 1022(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “for the following:” for “for—” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1022/e/2">Pub. L. 105–261, § 1022(e)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “The pay” for “the pay” and “activities.” for “activities;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1022/e/2">Pub. L. 105–261, § 1022(e)(2)</ref>, (4), substituted “The operation” for “the operation” and “activities.” for “activities; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1022/a">Pub. L. 105–261, § 1022(a)</ref>, (e)(2), substituted “The procurement” for “the procurement” and “and equipment, and the leasing of equipment,” for “and leasing of equipment” and inserted at end “However, the use of such funds for the procurement of equipment may not exceed $5,000 per purchase order, unless approval for procurement of equipment in excess of that amount is granted in advance by the Secretary of Defense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1022/b">Pub. L. 105–261, § 1022(b)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “To ensure that the use of units and personnel of the National Guard of a State pursuant to a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan is not detrimental to the training and readiness of such units and personnel, the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2012/d">section 2012(d) of title 10</ref> shall apply in determining the drug interdiction and counter-drug activities that units and personnel of the National Guard of a State may perform.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1022/c">Pub. L. 105–261, § 1022(c)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “<ref href="/us/usc/t32/s508">Section 508 of this title</ref>, regarding the provision of assistance to certain specified youth and charitable organizations, shall apply in any case in which a unit or member of the National Guard of a State is proposed to be used pursuant to a State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan to provide to an organization specified in subsection (d) of such section any of the services described in subsection (b) of such section or services regarding counter-drug education.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1022/d">Pub. L. 105–261, § 1022(d)</ref>, inserted “, including drug demand reduction activities,” after “drug interdiction and counter-drug law enforcement activities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s1031/a">Pub. L. 105–85, § 1031(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s1031/b/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 1031(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (4) and redesignated former pars. (4) and (5) as (5) and (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s1031/d">Pub. L. 105–85, § 1031(d)</ref>, designated par. (1) as subsec. (e) and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives an annual report specifying for the period covered by the report the number of members of the National Guard excluded under paragraph (1) from the computation of end strengths.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s1031/c">Pub. L. 105–85, § 1031(c)</ref>, added subsec. (g) and redesignated former subsecs. (g) and (h) as (h) and (i), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/a">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense may provide to the Governor of a State who submits a plan to the Secretary under subsection (b) sufficient funds for—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the pay, allowances, clothing, subsistence, gratuities, travel, and related expenses of personnel of the National Guard of that State used for—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(A) the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(B) the operation and maintenance of the equipment and facilities of the National Guard of that State used for that purpose; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the procurement of services and leasing of equipment for the National Guard of that State used for the purpose of drug interdiction and counter-drug activities.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/e">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(e)</ref>, added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/c">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(c)</ref>, substituted “A State drug interdiction and counter-drug activities plan” for “A plan referred to in subsection (a)” in introductory provisions and “training” for “annual training” in par. (3) and added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/b/3">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(b)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b) as (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/b/3">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(b)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> inserted at end “The plan as approved by the Secretary may provide for the use of personnel and equipment of the National Guard of that State to assist the Immigration and Naturalization Service in the transportation of aliens who have violated a Federal or State law prohibiting or regulating the possession, use, or distribution of a controlled substance.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/d/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “and before members of the National Guard of that State are ordered to full-time National Guard duty as authorized in subsection (b)” after “under this section” and substituted “under subsection (c)” for “under subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/d/2/A">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c)” for “subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/d/2/B">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(d)(2)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “funds were provided to the State pursuant to such plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/h/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(h)(1)</ref>, substituted “sections 12011 and 12012” for “sections 517 and 524”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/h/2">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(h)(2)</ref>, substituted “the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/f">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(f)</ref>, added subsec. (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/b/2">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (g) and transferred it to appear before subsec. (h), as redesignated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/b/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1021/g">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1021(g)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The term ‘counter-drug activities’ includes the use of National Guard personnel, while not in Federal service, in any law enforcement activities authorized by State and local law and requested by the Governor.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/396">Pub. L. 102–396</ref> inserted “(or during fiscal year 1993 otherwise implementing)” after “administering”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/25">Pub. L. 102–25</ref> substituted “in consultation with the Director of National Drug Control Policy.” for “in consultation with—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the Attorney General of the United States in the case of a plan submitted for fiscal year 1990; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the Director of National Drug Control Policy in the case of a plan submitted for subsequent fiscal years.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida1c8b3fd-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida1c8b3fe-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2021-12-31">Dec. 31, 2021</date>, of provisions in subsec. (f) of this section requiring submittal of annual report to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1061">section 1061 of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">section 111 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida1c8b3ff-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of Title 8</ref>, Aliens and Nationality.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida1c8b400-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Guard Counterdrug Schools</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/469/tIX/s901">Pub. L. 109–469, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="2006-12-29">Dec. 29, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3536">120 Stat. 3536</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tX/s1008">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1008</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1905">126 Stat. 1905</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tX/s1012">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title X, § 1012</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2385">130 Stat. 2385</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tX/s1012">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Operate</inline>.—</heading><content>Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, the Chief of the National Guard Bureau may establish and operate, or provide financial assistance to the States to establish and operate, not more than 5 schools (to be known generally as ‘National Guard counterdrug schools’).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purpose of the National Guard counterdrug schools shall be the provision by the National Guard of training in drug interdiction and counterdrug activities and drug demand reduction activities to personnel of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Community-based organizations engaged in such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Other non-Federal governmental and private entities and organizations engaged in such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Counterdrug Schools Specified</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The National Guard counterdrug schools operated under the authority in subsection (a) are as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Multi-Jurisdictional Counterdrug Task Force Training (MCTFT), St. Petersburg, Florida.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Midwest Counterdrug Training Center (MCTC), Johnston, Iowa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Regional Counterdrug Training Academy (RCTA), Meridian, Mississippi.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The Northeast Regional Counterdrug Training Center (NCTC), Fort Indiantown Gap, Pennsylvania.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The Western Regional Counterdrug Training Center, Camp Murray, Washington.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of National Guard Personnel.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent provided for in the State drug interdiction and counterdrug activities plan of a State in which a National Guard counterdrug school is located, personnel of the National Guard of that State who are ordered to perform full-time National Guard duty authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s112/b">section 112(b) of title 32</ref>, United States Code, may provide training referred to in subsection (b) at that school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘State drug interdiction and counterdrug activities plan’, in the case of a State, means the current plan submitted by the Governor of the State to the Secretary of Defense under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s112">section 112 of title 32</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Curriculum Review</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall review the curriculum and program structure of each school established under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment Under Authority To Provide Counterdrug Support</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of section 1004 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s374">10 U.S.C. 374</ref> note) shall apply to any activities of a National Guard counterdrug school under this section that are for an agency referred to in subsection (a) of such section 1004 and for a purpose set forth in subsection (b) of such section 1004.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report on Activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than February 1 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the National Guard counterdrug schools during the preceding year. Each such report shall set forth a description of the activities of each National Guard counterdrug school for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year during which the report is submitted, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the amount of funding made available and the appropriation account for each National Guard counterdrug school during such fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the cumulative amount of funding made available for each National Guard counterdrug school during five fiscal years preceding such fiscal year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a description of the curriculum and training used at each National Guard counterdrug school;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> a description of how the activities conducted at each National Guard counterdrug school fulfilled Department of Defense counterdrug mission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> a list of the entities described in subsection (b) whose personnel received training at each National Guard counterdrug school; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> updates, if any, to the Department of Defense regulations prescribed under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not more than $30,000,000 may be expended by the Secretary of Defense for purposes of the National Guard counterdrug schools in any fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>The amount expended pursuant to paragraph (1) for a fiscal year is in addition to any other amount authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense for the National Guard for such fiscal year.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For termination, effective <date date="2021-12-31">Dec. 31, 2021</date>, of annual reporting provisions in <ref href="/us/pl/109/469/s901/g">section 901(g) of Pub. L. 109–469</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1061">section 1061 of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">section 111 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
