<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida1c8b411-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s114"><num value="114">§ 114.</num><heading> Funeral honors functions at funerals for veterans</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to such regulations and restrictions as may be prescribed by the Secretary concerned, the performance of funeral honors functions by members of the National Guard at funerals for veterans of the armed forces may be treated by the Secretary concerned as a Federal function for which appropriated funds may be used. Any such performance of funeral honors functions at such a funeral may not be considered to be a period of drill or training, but may be performed as funeral honors duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s115">section 115 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="ida1c8b412-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tV/s517/a/1">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 517(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1733">111 Stat. 1733</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tV/s567/d">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 567(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2031">112 Stat. 2031</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s578/g/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 578(g)(1)</ref>, (k)(3)(A), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/627">113 Stat. 627</ref>, 631.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida1c8b413-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida1c8b414-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida1c8b415-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref>, in section catchline, substituted “Funeral honors” for “Honor guard” and, in text, substituted “funeral honors functions” for “honor guard functions” in two places and “drill or training, but may be performed as funeral honors duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s115">section 115 of this title</ref>” for “drill or training otherwise required”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/261">Pub. L. 105–261</ref> designated subsec. (a) as entire section and struck out subsec. (b) which read as follows: “This section does not authorize additional appropriations for any fiscal year. Any expense of the National Guard that is incurred by reason of this section shall be paid from appropriations otherwise available for the National Guard.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
