<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida1de1108-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s901"><num value="901">§ 901.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1de1109-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s901/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “homeland defense activity” means an activity undertaken for the military protection of the territory or domestic population of the United States, or of infrastructure or other assets of the United States determined by the Secretary of Defense as being critical to national security, from a threat or aggression against the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida1de110a-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95" identifier="/us/usc/t32/s901/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or a territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="ida1de110b-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tV/s512/a/1">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1878">118 Stat. 1878</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida1de110c-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida1de110d-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida1de110e-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance for Use of Unmanned Aircraft Systems by National Guard</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tX/s1086">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1086</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/419">137 Stat. 419</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tX/s1086">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updated Guidance Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall issue updated guidance on the use of unmanned aircraft systems by the National Guard for covered activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary issues the updated guidance under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives. [sic] Such briefing shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an explanation of whether the updated guidance is more restrictive than guidance on the use of other types of aircraft for covered activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> if the updated guidance is more restrictive, an explanation for the reasons why such guidance is more restrictive.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Activities Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘covered activities’ means any of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Emergency operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Search and rescue operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Defense support to civil authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Support provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/f">section 502(f) of title 32</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida1de110f-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation of Certain Recommendations Regarding Use of Unmanned Aircraft Systems by the National Guard</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tV/s514">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 514</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1683">135 Stat. 1683</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tV/s514">“Not later than <date date="2022-09-30">September 30, 2022</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall implement recommendations of the Secretary described in section 519C(a)(2) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/134/3596">134 Stat. 3596</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida1de1110-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Remote Provision by National Guard to National Guards of Other States of Cybersecurity Technical Assistance in Training, Preparation, and Response to Cyber Incidents</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVII/s1725">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVII, § 1725</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4112">134 Stat. 4112</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVII/s1725">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program Authorized.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may conduct a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of the development of a capability in support of Department of Defense missions within the National Guard through which a National Guard of a State remotely provides National Guards of other States (whether or not in the same Armed Force as the providing National Guard) with cybersecurity technical assistance in training, preparation, and response to cyber incidents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The authorization under paragraph (1) to conduct the pilot program expires 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment Prior to Commencement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of the pilot program described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall, prior to commencing the pilot program, for purposes of evaluating existing platforms, technologies, and capabilities under subsection (c), and for establishing eligibility and participation requirements under such subsection—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> conduct an assessment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> existing cyber response capacities of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard, as applicable, in each State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any existing platform, technology, or capability of a National Guard that provides the capability described in subsection (a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> determine whether a platform, technology, or capability referred to in subparagraph (B) is suitable for expansion for purposes of the pilot program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> assess potential benefits or impact on the missions, the Total Force, the Cyber Operations Forces, and the cyber infrastructure of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The pilot program described in subsection (a) may include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A technical capability that enables the National Guard of a State to remotely provide cybersecurity technical assistance to National Guards of other States, without the need to deploy outside its home State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The development of policies, processes, procedures, and authorities for use of such a capability, including with respect to the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The roles and responsibilities of both requesting and deploying National Guards with respect to such technical assistance, taking into account the matters specified in subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Necessary updates to the Defense Cyber Incident Coordinating Procedure, or any other applicable Department of Defense instruction, for purposes of implementing such a capability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Program management and governance structures for deployment and maintenance of such a capability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Security when performing remote support, including in matters such as authentication and remote sensing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> The conduct, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the heads of other Federal agencies, and appropriate non-Federal entities, as appropriate, of at least one exercise to demonstrate such a capability, which exercise shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Participation of not fewer than the National Guards of two different States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Circumstances designed to test and validate the policies, processes, procedures, and authorities developed pursuant to paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Existing Technology</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may use an existing platform, technology, or capability to provide the technical capability described in subsection (a)(1) under the pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility and Participation Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, establish requirements with respect to eligibility and participation of National Guards in the pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> [sic] <inline class="small-caps">Construction With Certain Current Authorities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Command authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section may be construed as affecting or altering the command authorities otherwise applicable to any unit of the National Guard participating in the pilot program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency management assistance compact</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section may be construed as affecting or altering any current agreement under the Emergency Management Assistance Compact, or any other State agreements, or as determinative of the future content of any such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation Metrics</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish metrics to evaluate the effectiveness of the pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program under subsection (b) shall terminate not later than the date that is three years after the date of the commencement of the pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the commencement of the pilot program, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Secretary of Homeland Security an initial report setting forth a description of the pilot program and such other matters in connection with the pilot program as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the termination of the pilot program, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Secretary of Homeland Security a final report on the pilot program. The final report shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A description of the pilot program, including any partnerships entered into under the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A summary of the assessment performed prior to the commencement of the pilot program in accordance with subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A summary of the evaluation metrics established in accordance with subsection (h), including how the pilot program contributes directly to Department of Defense missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> An assessment of the effectiveness of the pilot program, and of the capability described in subsection (c)(1) under the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> A description of costs associated with the implementation and conduct of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> A recommendation as to the value of the pilot program, including whether to authorize a permanent program modeled on the pilot program, including whether the pilot program duplicates the remote operating concept and capabilities of active duty cyber operations forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> An estimate of the costs of making the pilot program permanent and expanding it nationwide in accordance with the recommendation in subparagraph (F).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> Such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Secretary considers appropriate in light of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘State’ means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida1de1111-2930-11f1-9ed5-c078b45cfa95"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Cyber Capabilities and Interoperability of the National Guard</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVII/s1729">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVII, § 1729</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4118">134 Stat. 4118</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVII/s1729">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives], the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives an evaluation of the statutes, rules, regulations and standards that pertain to the use of the National Guard for the response to and recovery from significant cyber incidents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration of inputs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the evaluation under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security and may solicit and consider inputs from the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The heads of Federal agencies determined appropriate by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> State governors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The heads of other non-Federal entities as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of Evaluation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The evaluation required under subsection (a) shall include review of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Regulations promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s903">section 903 of title 32</ref>, United States Code, to clarify when and under what conditions the National Guard could respond to a cyber attack as a homeland defense activity under section 902 of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Guidance promulgated regarding how units of the National Guard shall collaborate with relevant civil, law enforcement, and cybersecurity agencies when conducting a homeland defense activity under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s902">section 902 of title 32</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Update to Certain Regulations and Guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the Secretary of Defense determines such is appropriate based on the evaluation required under subsection (a) and the review described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall update—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the regulations referred to in subsection (b)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the guidance referred to in subsection (b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Update to the National Cyber Incident Response Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, may update the National Cyber Incident Response Plan to address any changes made by the Secretary of Defense to the roles and responsibilities of the National Guard for the response to and recovery from significant cyber incidents.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Joint Briefings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 300 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly brief the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives on the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The results of the evaluation required under subsection (a)(1), including the utilization of any input provided to the Secretary of Defense pursuant to subsection (a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any updated regulations or guidance in accordance with subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any update by the Secretary of Homeland Security to the National Cyber Incident Response Plan pursuant to subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> How the Department of Defense, including the National Guard, and the Department of Homeland Security, including the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency and the Federal Emergency Management Agency, will collaborate with each other and with relevant law enforcement, State governments, and other non-Federal entities when responding to and recovering from significant cyber incidents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘significant cyber incident’ means a cyber incident that results, or several related cyber incidents that result, in demonstrable harm to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the national security interests, foreign relations, or economy of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the public confidence, civil liberties, or public health and safety of the American people.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
