<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd10f2a3c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1541"><num value="1541">§ 1541.</num><heading> Purpose and policy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd10f2a3d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1541/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional declaration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this chapter to fulfill the intent of the framers of the Constitution of the United States and insure that the collective judgment of both the Congress and the President will apply to the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, and to the continued use of such forces in hostilities or in such situations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd10f2a3e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1541/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional legislative power under necessary and proper clause</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under article I, section 8, of the Constitution, it is specifically provided that the Congress shall have the power to make all laws necessary and proper for carrying into execution, not only its own powers but also all other powers vested by the Constitution in the Government of the United States, or in any department or officer thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd10f2a3f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1541/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential executive power as Commander-in-Chief; limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The constitutional powers of the President as Commander-in-Chief to introduce United States Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, are exercised only pursuant to (1) a declaration of war, (2) specific statutory authorization, or (3) a national emergency created by attack upon the United States, its territories or possessions, or its armed forces.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd10f2a40-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/148/s2">Pub. L. 93–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/555">87 Stat. 555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd10f2a41-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd10f2a42-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd10f2a43-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/148/s10">Pub. L. 93–148, § 10</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/559">87 Stat. 559</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/148/s10">“This joint resolution [enacting this chapter] shall take effect on the date of its enactment [<date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idd10f2a44-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/148/s1">Pub. L. 93–148, § 1</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/555">87 Stat. 555</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/148/s1">“This joint resolution [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘War Powers Resolution’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a45-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction on the Permanent Stationing of United States Armed Forces in Somalia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXII/s1271">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1271</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1698">133 Stat. 1698</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXII/s1271">“Nothing in this Act [see Tables for classification] may be construed to authorize the permanent stationing of members of the Armed Forces in Somalia.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a46-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Responsible Redeployment of United States Armed Forces From Iraq</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXII/s1227">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XII, § 1227</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2525">123 Stat. 2525</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tXII/s1233/a">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title XII, § 1233(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4396">124 Stat. 4396</ref>, 4397, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tXII/s1233/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>], or <date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>, whichever occurs later, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report concerning the responsible redeployment of United States Armed Forces from Iraq in accordance with the policy announced by the President on <date date="2009-02-27">February 27, 2009</date>, and the Agreement Between the United States of America and the Republic of Iraq On the Withdrawal of United States Forces From Iraq and the Organization of Their Activities During Their Temporary Presence in Iraq.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The number of United States military personnel in Iraq by service and component for each month of the preceding 90-day period and an estimate of the personnel levels in Iraq for the 90-day period following submission of the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The number and type of military installations in Iraq occupied by 100 or more United States military personnel and the number of such military installations closed, consolidated, or transferred to the Government of Iraq in the preceding 90-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> An estimate of the number of military vehicles, containers of equipment, tons of ammunition, or other significant items belonging to the Department of Defense removed from Iraq during the preceding 90-day period, an estimate of the remaining amount of such items belonging to the Department of Defense, and an assessment of the likelihood of successfully removing, demilitarizing, or otherwise transferring all items belonging to the Department of Defense from Iraq on or before <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> An assessment of United States detainee operations and releases. Such assessment should include the total number of detainees held by the United States in Iraq, the number of detainees in each threat level category, the number of detainees who are not nationals of Iraq, the number of detainees transferred to Iraqi authorities, the number of detainees who were released from United States custody and the reasons for their release, and the number of detainees who having been released in the past were recaptured or had their remains identified planning or after carrying out attacks on United States or Coalition forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> A listing of the objective and subjective factors utilized by the commander of United States Forces–Iraq, including any changes to that list in the case of an update to the report, to determine risk levels associated with the drawdown of United States Armed Forces, and the process and timing that will be utilized by the commander of United States Forces–Iraq and the Secretary of Defense to assess risk and make recommendations to the President about either continuing the redeployment of United States Armed Forces from Iraq in accordance with the schedule announced by the President or modifying the pace or timing of that redeployment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> An assessment of progress to transfer responsibility of programs, projects, and activities carried out in Iraq by the Department of Defense to other United States Government departments and agencies, international or nongovernmental entities, or the Government of Iraq. The assessment should include a description of the numbers and categories of programs, projects, and activities for which such other entities have taken responsibility or which have been discontinued by the Department of Defense. The assessment should also include a discussion of any difficulties or barriers in transitioning such programs, projects, and activities and what, if any, solutions have been developed to address such difficulties or barriers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><chapeau> An assessment of progress toward the goal of building the minimum essential capabilities of the Ministry of Defense and the Ministry of the Interior of Iraq, including a description of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> such capabilities both extant and remaining to be developed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> major equipment necessary to achieve such capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the level and type of support provided by the United States to address shortfalls in such capabilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the level of commitment, both financial and political, made by the Government of Iraq to develop such capabilities, including a discussion of resources used by the Government of Iraq to develop capabilities that the Secretary determines are not minimum essential capabilities for purposes of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> A listing and assessment of the anticipated level and type of support to be provided by United States special operations forces to the Government of Iraq and Iraqi special operations forces during the redeployment of United States conventional forces from Iraq. The assessment should include a listing of anticipated critical support from general purpose forces required by United States special operations forces and Iraqi special operations forces. The assessment should also include combat support, including rotary aircraft and intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance assets, combat service support, and contractor support needed through <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary of State Comments</inline>.—</heading><content>Prior to submitting the report required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall provide a copy of the report to the Secretary of State for review. At the request of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense shall include an appendix to the report which contains any comments or additional information that the Secretary of State requests.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>The report required under subsection (a) may include a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Congressional Committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirement to submit the report required under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2012-09-30">September 30, 2012</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a47-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States Policy on Iraq</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tXII/s1227">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XII, § 1227</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3465">119 Stat. 3465</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tXII/s1223/a/1">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XII, § 1223(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/373">122 Stat. 373</ref>, 374, known as the “United States Policy in Iraq Act”, which required the President to submit reports to Congress on United States policy and military operations in Iraq not later than 90 days after <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, and every three months thereafter, until all United States combat brigades had been redeployed from Iraq, and required congressional briefings by senior officials of the Department of Defense subsequent to the submission of each such report, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tXII/s1233/f/1">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title XII, § 1233(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4397">124 Stat. 4397</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a48-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/243">Pub. L. 107–243</ref>, <date date="2002-10-16">Oct. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1498">116 Stat. 1498</ref>, known as the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002, which authorized the President to use the Armed Forces of the United States to defend the national security of the United States against the continuing threat posed by Iraq and enforce all relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions regarding Iraq, subject to presidential determinations and with reporting requirements, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXIII/s8370/2">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXIII, § 8370(2)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1907">139 Stat. 1907</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a49-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization for Use of Military Force Against September 11 Terrorists</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/40">Pub. L. 107–40</ref>, <date date="2001-09-18">Sept. 18, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/224">115 Stat. 224</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/40">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I25" class="indent1 firstIndent-1">“Whereas, on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, acts of treacherous violence were committed against the United States and its citizens; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I25" class="indent1 firstIndent-1">“Whereas, such acts render it both necessary and appropriate that the United States exercise its rights to self-defense and to protect United States citizens both at home and abroad; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I25" class="indent1 firstIndent-1">“Whereas, in light of the threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States posed by these grave acts of violence; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I25" class="indent1 firstIndent-1">“Whereas, such acts continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I25" class="indent1 firstIndent-1">“Whereas, the President has authority under the Constitution to take action to deter and prevent acts of international terrorism against the United States: Now, therefore, be it</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><i>“Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I580467" class="indent2 firstIndent-2 bold">“SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This joint resolution may be cited as the ‘Authorization for Use of Military Force’.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I580467" class="indent2 firstIndent-2 bold">“SEC. 2. AUTHORIZATION FOR USE OF UNITED STATES ARMED FORCES.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—That the President is authorized to use all necessary and appropriate force against those nations, organizations, or persons he determines planned, authorized, committed, or aided the terrorist attacks that occurred on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, or harbored such organizations or persons, in order to prevent any future acts of international terrorism against the United States by such nations, organizations or persons.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) <inline class="small-caps">War Powers Resolution Requirements.—</inline></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) <inline class="small-caps">Specific statutory authorization</inline>.—Consistent with section 8(a)(1) of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1547/a/1">50 U.S.C. 1547(a)(1)</ref>], the Congress declares that this section is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1544/b">50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of other requirements</inline>.—Nothing in this resolution supercedes any requirement of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.].”</p>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a4a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Deployment of Armed Forces in Haiti During Fiscal Year 2000 and Congressional Notice of Deployments to Haiti</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tXII/s1232">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/788">113 Stat. 788</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tXII/s1222">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XII, § 1222</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1253">115 Stat. 1253</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tXII/s1222">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Deployment</inline>.—</heading><content>No funds available to the Department of Defense during fiscal year 2000 may be expended after <date date="2000-05-31">May 31, 2000</date>, for the continuous deployment of United States Armed Forces in Haiti pursuant to the Department of Defense operation designated as Operation Uphold Democracy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0" status="repealed"><num value="b">“[(b)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tXII/s1222">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XII, § 1222</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1253">115 Stat. 1253</ref>.]”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a4b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Involvement of Armed Forces in Haiti</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/423">Pub. L. 103–423</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4358">108 Stat. 4358</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/423">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SENSE OF CONGRESS REGARDING UNITED STATES ARMED FORCES OPERATIONS IN HAITI.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> the men and women of the United States Armed Forces in Haiti who are performing with professional excellence and dedicated patriotism are to be commended;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> the President should have sought and welcomed Congressional approval before deploying United States Armed Forces to Haiti;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> the departure from power of the de facto authorities in Haiti, and Haitian efforts to achieve national reconciliation, democracy and the rule of law are in the best interests of the Haitian people;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> the President’s lifting of the unilateral economic sanctions on Haiti, and his efforts to bring about the lifting of economic sanctions imposed by the United Nations are appropriate; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> Congress supports a prompt and orderly withdrawal of all United States Armed Forces from Haiti as soon as possible.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> PRESIDENTIAL STATEMENT OF NATIONAL SECURITY OBJECTIVES.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The President shall prepare and submit to the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives (hereafter, ‘Congress’) not later than seven days after enactment of this resolution [<date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>] a statement of the national security objectives to be achieved by Operation Uphold Democracy, and a detailed description of United States policy, the military mission and the general rules of engagement under which operations of United States Armed Forces are conducted in and around Haiti, including the role of United States Armed Forces regarding Haitian on Haitian violence, and efforts to disarm Haitian military or police forces, or civilians. Changes or modifications to such objectives, policy, military mission, or general rules of engagement shall be submitted to Congress within forty-eight hours of approval.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> REPORT ON THE SITUATION IN HAITI.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Not later than <date date="1994-11-01">November 1, 1994</date>, and monthly thereafter until the cessation of Operation Uphold Democracy, the President shall submit a report to Congress on the situation in Haiti, including—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> a listing of the units of the United States Armed Forces and of the police and military units of other nations participating in operations in and around Haiti;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> the estimated duration of Operation Uphold Democracy and progress toward the withdrawal of all United States Armed Forces from Haiti consistent with the goal of section 1(e) of this resolution;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> armed incidents or the use of force in or around Haiti involving United States Armed Forces or Coast Guard personnel in the time period covered by the report;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="d">“(d)</num><chapeau> the estimated cumulative incremental cost of all United States activities subsequent to <date date="1993-09-30">September 30, 1993</date>, in and around Haiti, including but not limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the cost of all deployments of United States Armed Forces and Coast Guard personnel, training, exercises, mobilization, and preparation activities, including the preparation of police and military units of the other nations of the multinational force involved in enforcement of sanctions, limits on migration, establishment and maintenance of migrant facilities at Guantanamo Bay and elsewhere, and all other activities relating to operations in and around Haiti; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the costs of all other activities relating to United States policy toward Haiti, including humanitarian assistance, reconstruction, aid and other financial assistance, and all other costs to the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="e">“(e)</num><chapeau> a detailed accounting of the source of funds obligated or expended to meet the costs described in subparagraph (d), including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in the case of funds expended from the Department of Defense budget, a breakdown by military service or defense agency, line item and program, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the case of funds expended from the budgets of departments and agencies other than the Department of Defense, by department or agency and program;</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> the Administration plan for financing the costs of the operations and the impact on readiness without supplemental funding;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="g">“(g)</num><chapeau> a description of the situation in Haiti, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the security situation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the progress made in transferring the functions of government to the democratically elected government of Haiti; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> progress toward holding free and fair parliamentary elections;</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="h">“(h)</num><chapeau> a description of issues relating to the United Nations Mission in Haiti (UNMIH), including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the preparedness of the United Nations Mission in Haiti (UNMIH) to deploy to Haiti to assume its functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> troop commitments by other nations to UNMIH;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the anticipated cost to the United States of participation in UNMIH, including payments to the United Nations and financial, material and other assistance to UNMIH;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> proposed or actual participation of United States Armed Forces in UNMIH;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> proposed command arrangements for UNMIH, including proposed or actual placement of United States Armed Forces under foreign command; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the anticipated duration of UNMIH.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> REPORT ON HUMAN RIGHTS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Not later than <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, the Secretary of State shall report to Congress on the participation or involvement of any member of the de jure or de facto Haitian government in violations of internationally-recognized human rights from <date date="1990-12-15">December 15, 1990</date>, to <date date="1994-12-15">December 15, 1994</date>.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> REPORT ON UNITED STATES AGREEMENTS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Not later than <date date="1994-11-15">November 15, 1994</date>, the Secretary of State shall provide a comprehensive report to Congress on all agreements the United States has entered into with other nations, including any assistance pledged or provided, in connection with United States efforts in Haiti. Such report shall also include information on any agreements or commitments relating to United Nations Security Council actions concerning Haiti since 1992.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6">“SEC. 6.</num><heading> TRANSITION TO UNITED NATIONS MISSION IN HAITI.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Nothing in this resolution should be construed or interpreted to constitute Congressional approval or disapproval of the participation of United States Armed Forces in the United Nations Mission in Haiti.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a4c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Involvement of Armed Forces in Somalia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXV/s1512">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XV, § 1512</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1840">107 Stat. 1840</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXV/s1512">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress Regarding United States Policy Toward Somalia.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Since United States Armed Forces made significant contributions under Operation Restore Hope towards the establishment of a secure environment for humanitarian relief operations and restoration of peace in the region to end the humanitarian disaster that had claimed more than 300,000 lives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Since the mission of United States forces in support of the United Nations appears to be evolving from the establishment of ‘a secure environment for humanitarian relief operations,’ as set out in United Nations Security Council Resolution 794 of <date date="1992-12-03">December 3, 1992</date>, to one of internal security and nation building.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement of Congressional Policy.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation with the congress</inline>.—</heading><content>The President should consult closely with the Congress regarding United States policy with respect to Somalia, including in particular the deployment of United States Armed Forces in that country, whether under United Nations or United States command.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Planning</inline>.—</heading><content>The United States shall facilitate the assumption of the functions of United States forces by the United Nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting requirement.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The President shall ensure that the goals and objectives supporting deployment of United States forces to Somalia and a description of the mission, command arrangements, size, functions, location, and anticipated duration in Somalia of those forces are clearly articulated and provided in a detailed report to the Congress by <date date="1993-10-15">October 15, 1993</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Such report shall include the status of planning to transfer the function contained in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional approval</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon reporting under the requirements of paragraph (3) Congress believes the President should by <date date="1993-11-15">November 15, 1993</date>, seek and receive congressional authorization in order for the deployment of United States forces to Somalia to continue.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd10f2a4d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Duration of Authorization for United States Participation in Multinational Force in Somalia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/139/tVIII/s8151">Pub. L. 103–139, title VIII, § 8151</ref>, <date date="1993-11-11">Nov. 11, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1475">107 Stat. 1475</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/139/tVIII/s8151">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the United States entered into Operation Restore Hope in December of 1992 for the purpose of relieving mass starvation in Somalia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the original mission in Somalia, to secure the environment for humanitarian relief, had the unanimous support of the Senate, expressed in Senate Joint Resolution 45, passed on <date date="1993-02-04">February 4, 1993</date>, and was endorsed by the House when it amended S.J. Res. 45 on <date date="1993-05-25">May 25, 1993</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Operation Restore Hope was being successfully accomplished by United States forces, working with forces of other nations, when it was replaced by the UNOSOM II mission, assumed by the United Nations on <date date="1993-05-04">May 4, 1993</date>, pursuant to United Nations Resolution 814 of <date date="1993-03-26">March 26, 1993</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> neither the expanded United Nations mission of national reconciliation, nor the broad mission of disarming the clans, nor any other mission not essential to the performance of the humanitarian mission has been endorsed or approved by the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the expanded mission of the United Nations was, subsequent to an attack upon United Nations forces, diverted into a mission aimed primarily at capturing certain persons, pursuant to United Nations Security Council Resolution 837, of <date date="1993-06-06">June 6, 1993</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the actions of hostile elements in Mogadishu, and the United Nations mission to subdue those elements, have resulted in open conflict in the city of Mogadishu and the deaths of 29 Americans, at least 159 wounded, and the capture of American personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> during fiscal years 1992 and 1993, the United States incurred expenses in excess of $1,100,000,000 to support operations in Somalia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The Congress approves the use of United States Armed Forces in Somalia for the following purposes:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The protection of United States personnel and bases; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The provision of assistance in securing open lines of communication for the free flow of supplies and relief operations through the provision of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> United States military logistical support services to United Nations forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> United States combat forces in a security role and as an interim force protection supplement to United Nations units: <i>Provided</i>, That funds appropriated, or otherwise made available, in this or any other Act to the Department of Defense may be obligated for expenses incurred only through <date date="1994-03-31">March 31, 1994</date>, for the operations of United States Armed Forces in Somalia: <i>Provided further</i>, That such date may be extended if so requested by the President and authorized by the Congress: <i>Provided further</i>, That funds may be obligated beyond <date date="1994-03-31">March 31, 1994</date> to support a limited number of United States military personnel sufficient only to protect American diplomatic facilities and American citizens, and noncombat personnel to advise the United Nations commander in Somalia: <i>Provided further</i>, That United States combat forces in Somalia shall be under the command and control of United States commanders under the ultimate direction of the President of the United States: <i>Provided further</i>, That the President should intensify efforts to have United Nations member countries immediately deploy additional troops to Somalia to fulfill previous force commitments made to the United Nations and to deploy additional forces to assume the security missions of United States Armed Forces: <i>Provided further</i>, That—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> captured United States personnel in Somalia should be treated humanely and fairly; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the United States and the United Nations should make all appropriate efforts to ensure the immediate and safe return of any future captured United States personnel: <i>Provided further</i>, That the President should ensure that, at all times, United States military personnel in Somalia have the capacity to defend themselves, and American citizens: <i>Provided further</i>, That the United States Armed Forces should remain deployed in or around Somalia until such time as all American service personnel missing in action in Somalia are accounted for, and all American service personnel held prisoner in Somalia are released: <i>Provided further</i>, That nothing herein shall be deemed to restrict in any way the authority of the President under the Constitution to protect the lives of Americans.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1119b4e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/1">Pub. L. 102–1</ref>, <date date="1991-01-14">Jan. 14, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/3">105 Stat. 3</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dA/tII/s207">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title II, § 207]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–422, known as the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution, which authorized the President to use United States Armed Forces pursuant to United Nations Security Council Resolution 678 in order to achieve implementation of Security Council Resolutions 660, 661, 662, 664, 665, 666, 667, 669, 670, 674, and 677, subject to determination of necessity and with reporting requirements, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXIII/s8370/1">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXIII, § 8370(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1907">139 Stat. 1907</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1119b4f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Introduction of United States Armed Forces Into Central America for Combat</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tIII/s310">Pub. L. 98–525, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2516">98 Stat. 2516</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/525/tIII/s310">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The President has stated that there is no need to introduce United States Armed Forces into Central America for combat and that he has no intention of doing so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The President of El Salvador has stated that there is no need for United States Armed Forces to conduct combat operations in El Salvador and that he has no intention of asking that they do so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The possibility of the introduction of United States Armed Forces into Central America for combat raises very grave concern in the Congress and the American people.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> United States Armed Forces should not be introduced into or over the countries of Central America for combat; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> if circumstances change from those present on the date of the enactment of this Act and the President believes that those changed circumstances require the introduction of United States Armed Forces into or over a country of Central America for combat, the President should consult with Congress before any decision to so introduce United States Armed Forces and any such introduction of United States Armed Forces must comply with the War Powers Resolution [this chapter].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tI/s101/h/tVIII/s8101">Pub. L. 98–473, title I, § 101(h) [title VIII, § 8101]</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1904">98 Stat. 1904</ref>, 1942, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/473/tI/s101/h/tVIII/s8101">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The President has stated that there is no need to introduce United States Armed Forces into Central America for combat and that he has no intention of doing so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The President of El Salvador has stated that there is no need for United States Armed Forces to conduct combat operations in El Salvador and that he has no intention of asking that they do so.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The possibility of the introduction of United States Armed Forces into Central America for combat raises very grave concern in the Congress and the American people.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> United States Armed Forces should not be introduced into or over the countries of Central America for combat; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> if circumstances change from those present on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>] and the President believes that those changed circumstances require the introduction of United States Armed Forces into or over a country of Central America for combat, the President should consult with Congress before any decision to so introduce United States Armed Forces and any such introduction of United States Armed Forces must comply with the War Powers Resolution [this chapter].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1119b50-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Multinational Force in Lebanon Resolution</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/119">Pub. L. 98–119</ref>, <date date="1983-10-12">Oct. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/805">97 Stat. 805</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/119">
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“short title</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="1">“Section 1.</num><content> This joint resolution may be cited as the ‘Multinational Force in Lebanon Resolution’.</content>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“findings and purpose</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="2">“Sec. 2.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the removal of all foreign forces from Lebanon is an essential United States foreign policy objective in the Middle East;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in order to restore full control by the Government of Lebanon over its own territory, the United States is currently participating in the multinational peacekeeping force (hereafter in this resolution referred to as the ‘Multinational Force in Lebanon’) which was established in accordance with the exchange of letters between the Governments of the United States and Lebanon dated <date date="1982-09-25">September 25, 1982</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Multinational Force in Lebanon better enables the Government of Lebanon to establish its unity, independence, and territorial integrity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> progress toward national political reconciliation in Lebanon is necessary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> United States Armed Forces participating in the Multinational Force in Lebanon are now in hostilities requiring authorization of their continued presence under the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Congress determines that the requirements of section 4(a)(1) of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1543/a/1">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)(1)</ref>] became operative on <date date="1983-08-29">August 29, 1983</date>. Consistent with section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1544/b">50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</ref>], the purpose of this joint resolution is to authorize the continued participation of United States Armed Forces in the Multinational Force in Lebanon.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The Congress intends this joint resolution to constitute the necessary specific statutory authorization under the War Powers Resolution for continued participation by United States Armed Forces in the Multinational Force in Lebanon.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“authorization for continued participation of united states armed forces in the multinational force in lebanon</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="3">“Sec. 3.</num><content> The President is authorized, for purposes of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1544/b">50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</ref>], to continue participation by United States Armed Forces in the Multinational Force in Lebanon, subject to the provisions of section 6 of this joint resolution. Such participation shall be limited to performance of the functions, and shall be subject to the limitations, specified in the agreement establishing the Multinational Force in Lebanon as set forth in the exchange of letters between the Governments of the United States and Lebanon dated <date date="1982-09-25">September 25, 1982</date>, except that this shall not preclude such protective measures as may be necessary to ensure the safety of the Multinational Force in Lebanon.</content>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“reports to the congress</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="4">“Sec. 4.</num><chapeau> As required by section 4(c) of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1543/c">50 U.S.C. 1543(c)</ref>], the President shall report periodically to the Congress with respect to the situation in Lebanon, but in no event shall he report less often than once every three months. In addition to providing the information required by that section on the status, scope, and duration of hostilities involving United States Armed Forces, such reports shall describe in detail—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the activities being performed by the Multinational Force in Lebanon;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the present composition of the Multinational Force in Lebanon, including a description of the responsibilities and deployment of the armed forces of each participating country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the results of efforts to reduce and eventually eliminate the Multinational Force in Lebanon;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> how continued United States participation in the Multinational Force in Lebanon is advancing United States foreign policy interests in the Middle East; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> what progress has occurred toward national political reconciliation among all Lebanese groups.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“statements of policy</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="5">“Sec. 5.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> The Congress declares that the participation of the armed forces of other countries in the Multinational Force in Lebanon is essential to maintain the international character of the peacekeeping function in Lebanon.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Congress believes that it should continue to be the policy of the United States to promote continuing discussions with Israel, Syria, and Lebanon with the objective of bringing about the withdrawal of all foreign troops from Lebanon and establishing an environment which will permit the Lebanese Armed Forces to carry out their responsibilities in the Beirut area.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> It is the sense of the Congress that, not later than one year after the date of enactment of this joint resolution [<date date="1983-10-12">Oct. 12, 1983</date>] and at least once a year thereafter, the United States should discuss with the other members of the Security Council of the United Nations the establishment of a United Nations peacekeeping force to assume the responsibilities of the Multinational Force in Lebanon. An analysis of the implications of the response to such discussions for the continuation of the Multinational Force in Lebanon shall be included in the reports required under paragraph (3) of section 4 of this resolution.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“duration of authorization for united states participation in the multinational force in lebanon</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="6">“Sec. 6.</num><chapeau> The participation of United States Armed Forces in the Multinational Force in Lebanon shall be authorized for purposes of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.] until the end of the eighteen-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this resolution [<date date="1983-10-12">Oct. 12, 1983</date>] unless the Congress extends such authorization, except that such authorization shall terminate sooner upon the occurrence of any one of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the withdrawal of all foreign forces from Lebanon, unless the President determines and certifies to the Congress that continued United States Armed Forces participation in the Multinational Force in Lebanon is required after such withdrawal in order to accomplish the purposes specified in the <date date="1982-09-25">September 25, 1982</date>, exchange of letters providing for the establishment of the Multinational Force in Lebanon; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the assumption by the United Nations or the Government of Lebanon of the responsibilities of the Multinational Force in Lebanon; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the implementation of other effective security arrangements in the area; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the withdrawal of all other countries from participation in the Multinational Force in Lebanon.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“interpretation of this resolution</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="7">“Sec. 7.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> Nothing in this joint resolution shall preclude the President from withdrawing United States Armed Forces participation in the Multinational Force in Lebanon if circumstances warrant, and nothing in this joint resolution shall preclude the Congress by joint resolution from directing such a withdrawal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Nothing in this joint resolution modifies, limits, or supersedes any provision of the War Powers Resolution [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.] or the requirement of section 4(a) of the Lebanon Emergency Assistance Act of 1983, relating to congressional authorization for any substantial expansion in the number or role of United States Armed Forces in Lebanon.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“congressional priority procedures for amendments</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="8">“Sec. 8.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> Any joint resolution or bill introduced to amend or repeal this Act shall be referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, as the case may be. Such joint resolution or bill shall be considered by such committee within fifteen calendar days and may be reported out, together with its recommendations, unless such House shall otherwise determine pursuant to its rules.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Any joint resolution or bill so reported shall become the pending business of the House in question (in the case of the Senate the time for debate shall be equally divided between the proponents and the opponents) and shall be voted on within three calendar days thereafter, unless such House shall otherwise determine by the yeas and nays.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Such a joint resolution or bill passed by one House shall be referred to the committee of the other House named in subsection (a) and shall be reported out by such committee together with its recommendations within fifteen calendar days and shall thereupon become the pending business of such House and shall be voted upon within three calendar days, unless such House shall otherwise determine by the yeas and nays.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> In the case of any disagreement between the two Houses of Congress with respect to a joint resolution or bill passed by both Houses, conferees shall be promptly appointed and the committee of conference shall make and file a report with respect to such joint resolution within six calendar days after the legislation is referred to the committee of conference. Notwithstanding any rule in either House concerning the printing of conference reports in the Record or concerning any delay in the consideration of such reports, such report shall be acted on by both Houses not later than six calendar days after the conference report is filed. In the event the conferees are unable to agree within forty-eight hours, they shall report back to their respective Houses in disagreement.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1119b51-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Adherence to War Powers Resolution</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/342/tX/s1008">Pub. L. 96–342, title X, § 1008</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1122">94 Stat. 1122</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/342/tX/s1008">“Whereas, the National Command Authority must have the capacity to carry out any military mission which is essential to the national security of the United States having in its hands in the Rapid Deployment Force an increased capability to extend the reach of our military power in an expedited manner; and whereas, without the significant safeguard of the War Powers Resolution (<ref href="/us/pl/93/148">Public Law 93–148</ref>) [this chapter], United States foreign and defense policies could be subject to misinterpretation; it is therefore the sense of the Congress that the provisions of the War Powers Resolution be strictly adhered to and that the congressional consultation process specified by such Resolution be utilized strictly according to the terms of the War Powers Resolution.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd1119b52-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1119b53-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Certain Reporting Authority</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2004-07-02">July 2, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 43723, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and laws of the United States, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, I hereby delegate to you the functions and authority conferred upon the President by section 4 of the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002, <ref href="/us/pl/107/243">Public Law 107–243</ref> [set out in a note above], and by section 3 of the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution, <ref href="/us/pl/102/1">Public Law 102–1</ref> [set out in a note above], to make the specified reports to the Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
