<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1119b73-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1544"><num value="1544">§ 1544.</num><heading> Congressional action</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1119b74-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1544/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal of report and referral to Congressional committees; joint request for convening Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report submitted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1543/a/1">section 1543(a)(1) of this title</ref> shall be transmitted to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and to the President pro tempore of the Senate on the same calendar day. Each report so transmitted shall be referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate for appropriate action. If, when the report is transmitted, the Congress has adjourned sine die or has adjourned for any period in excess of three calendar days, the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate, if they deem it advisable (or if petitioned by at least 30 percent of the membership of their respective Houses) shall jointly request the President to convene Congress in order that it may consider the report and take appropriate action pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1119b75-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1544/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of use of United States Armed Forces; exceptions; extension period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within sixty calendar days after a report is submitted or is required to be submitted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1543/a/1">section 1543(a)(1) of this title</ref>, whichever is earlier, the President shall terminate any use of United States Armed Forces with respect to which such report was submitted (or required to be submitted), unless the Congress (1) has declared war or has enacted a specific authorization for such use of United States Armed Forces, (2) has extended by law such sixty-day period, or (3) is physically unable to meet as a result of an armed attack upon the United States. Such sixty-day period shall be extended for not more than an additional thirty days if the President determines and certifies to the Congress in writing that unavoidable military necessity respecting the safety of United States Armed Forces requires the continued use of such armed forces in the course of bringing about a prompt removal of such forces.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1119b76-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1544/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Concurrent resolution for removal by President of United States Armed Forces</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (b), at any time that United States Armed Forces are engaged in hostilities outside the territory of the United States, its possessions and territories without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization, such forces shall be removed by the President if the Congress so directs by concurrent resolution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1119b77-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/148/s5">Pub. L. 93–148, § 5</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/556">87 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
