<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1119b8a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547"><num value="1547">§ 1547.</num><heading> Interpretation of joint resolution</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1119b8b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Inferences from any law or treaty</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Authority to introduce United States Armed Forces into hostilities or into situations wherein involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances shall not be inferred—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1119b8c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> from any provision of law (whether or not in effect before <date date="1973-11-07">November 7, 1973</date>), including any provision contained in any appropriation Act, unless such provision specifically authorizes the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities or into such situations and states that it is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1119b8d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> from any treaty heretofore or hereafter ratified unless such treaty is implemented by legislation specifically authorizing the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities or into such situations and stating that it is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1119b8e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Joint headquarters operations of high-level military commands</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require any further specific statutory authorization to permit members of United States Armed Forces to participate jointly with members of the armed forces of one or more foreign countries in the headquarters operations of high-level military commands which were established prior to <date date="1973-11-07">November 7, 1973</date>, and pursuant to the United Nations Charter or any treaty ratified by the United States prior to such date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1119b8f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Introduction of United States Armed Forces</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “introduction of United States Armed Forces” includes the assignment of members of such armed forces to command, coordinate, participate in the movement of, or accompany the regular or irregular military forces of any foreign country or government when such military forces are engaged, or there exists an imminent threat that such forces will become engaged, in hostilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1119b90-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Constitutional authorities or existing treaties unaffected; construction against grant of Presidential authority respecting use of United States Armed Forces</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1119b91-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is intended to alter the constitutional authority of the Congress or of the President, or the provisions of existing treaties; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1119b92-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1547/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall be construed as granting any authority to the President with respect to the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities or into situations wherein involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances which authority he would not have had in the absence of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1119b93-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/148/s8">Pub. L. 93–148, § 8</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/558">87 Stat. 558</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
