<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd0f75ce0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s167j"><num value="167j">§ 167j.</num><heading> Land conveyance in Potter County, Texas</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd0f75ce1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s167j/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall transfer all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the parcel of land described in subsection (b) to the Texas Plains Girl Scout Council for consideration of $1, reserving to the United States such easements as may be necessary for pipeline rights-of-way.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd0f75ce2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s167j/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Land description</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The parcel of land referred to in subsection (a) is all those certain lots, tracts or parcels of land lying and being situated in the County of Potter and State of Texas, and being the East Three Hundred Thirty-One (E331) acres out of Section Seventy-eight (78) in Block Nine (9), B.S. &amp; F. Survey, (some times known as the G.D. Landis pasture) Potter County, Texas, located by certificate No. 1/39 and evidenced by letters patents Nos. 411 and 412 issued by the State of Texas under date of <date date="1937-11-23">November 23, 1937</date>, and of record in Vol. 66A of the Patent Records of the State of Texas. The metes and bounds description of such lands is as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd0f75ce3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s167j/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> First tract</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">One Hundred Seventy-one (171) acres of land known as the North part of the East part of said survey Seventy-eight (78) aforesaid, described by metes and bounds as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" role="listItem" class="indent2">Beginning at a stone 20 x 12 x 3 inches marked X, set by W.D. Twichell in 1905, for the Northeast corner of this survey and the Northwest corner of Section 59;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" role="listItem" class="indent2">Thence, South 0 degrees 12 minutes East with the West line of said Section 59, 999.4 varas to the Northeast corner of the South 160 acres of East half of Section 78;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Thence, North 89 degrees 47 minutes West with the North line of the South 150 acres of the East half, 956.8 varas to a point in the East line of the West half Section 78;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Thence, North 0 degrees 10 minutes West with the East line of the West half 999.4 varas to a stone 18 x 14 x 3 inches in the middle of the South line of Section 79;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Thence, South 89 degrees 47 minutes East 965 varas to the place of beginning.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd0f75ce4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s167j/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Second tract</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">One Hundred Sixty (160) acres of land known as the South part of the East part of said survey No. Seventy-eight (78) described by metes and bounds as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" role="listItem" class="indent2">Beginning at the Southwest corner of Section 59, a stone marked X and a pile of stones; Thence, North 89 degrees 47 minutes West with the North line of Section 77, 966.5 varas to the Southeast corner of the West half of Section 78; Thence, North 0 degrees 10 minutes West with the East line of the West half of Section 78;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" role="listItem" class="indent2">Thence, South 89 degrees 47 minutes East 965.8 varas to a point in the East line of Section 78;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Thence, South 0 degrees 12 minutes East 934.6 varas to the place of beginning.</p>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Containing an area of 331 acres, more or less.</continuation>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd0f75ce5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1925-03-03/ch426/s12">Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 426, § 12</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/86/777/s2">Pub. L. 86–777, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/923">74 Stat. 923</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/273/s6">Pub. L. 104–273, § 6</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3318">110 Stat. 3318</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd0f75ce6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd0f75ce7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd0f75ce8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/273">Pub. L. 104–273</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section related to Secretary’s authority under Federal helium refining program to obtain loans and issue obligations to carry out program.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
