<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd143a7d5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842"><num value="1842">§ 1842.</num><heading> Pen registers and trap and trace devices for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a7d6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application for authorization or approval</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a7d7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Attorney General or a designated attorney for the Government may make an application for an order or an extension of an order authorizing or approving the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device for any investigation to obtain foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution which is being conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation under such guidelines as the Attorney General approves pursuant to Executive Order No. 12333, or a successor order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a7d8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The authority under paragraph (1) is in addition to the authority under subchapter I of this chapter to conduct the electronic surveillance referred to in that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a7d9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Form of application; recipient</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each application under this section shall be in writing under oath or affirmation to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7da-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a judge of the court established by <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1803/a">section 1803(a) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7db-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a United States Magistrate Judge under chapter 43 of title 28 who is publicly designated by the Chief Justice of the United States to have the power to hear applications for and grant orders approving the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device on behalf of a judge of that court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a7dc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Executive approval; contents of application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each application under this section shall require the approval of the Attorney General, or a designated attorney for the Government, and shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7dd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the identity of the Federal officer seeking to use the pen register or trap and trace device covered by the application;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7de-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a certification by the applicant that the information likely to be obtained is foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or is relevant to an ongoing investigation to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7df-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a specific selection term to be used as the basis for the use of the pen register or trap and trace device;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7e0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> a certification by the Federal Officer seeking to use the pen register or trap and trace device covered by the application that, to the best knowledge of the Federal Officer, the Attorney General or a designated attorney for the Government has been apprised of all information that might reasonably—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7e1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> call into question the accuracy of the application or the reasonableness of any assessment in the application conducted by the department or agency on whose behalf the application is made; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7e2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> otherwise raise doubts with respect to the findings required under subsection (d); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7e3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> non-cumulative information known to the Federal officer seeking to use the pen register or trap and trace device covered by the application, that is potentially exculpatory regarding the requested legal findings or any assessment in the application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a7e4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Ex parte judicial order of approval</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a7e5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon an application made pursuant to this section, the judge shall enter an ex parte order as requested, or as modified, approving the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device if the judge finds that the application satisfies the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a7e6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> An order issued under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7e7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> shall specify—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7e8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the identity, if known, of the person who is the subject of the investigation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7e9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the identity, if known, of the person to whom is leased or in whose name is listed the telephone line or other facility to which the pen register or trap and trace device is to be attached or applied; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7ea-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the attributes of the communications to which the order applies, such as the number or other identifier, and, if known, the location of the telephone line or other facility to which the pen register or trap and trace device is to be attached or applied and, in the case of a trap and trace device, the geographic limits of the trap and trace order;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7eb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> shall direct that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7ec-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> upon request of the applicant, the provider of a wire or electronic communication service, landlord, custodian, or other person shall furnish any information, facilities, or technical assistance necessary to accomplish the installation and operation of the pen register or trap and trace device in such a manner as will protect its secrecy and produce a minimum amount of interference with the services that such provider, landlord, custodian, or other person is providing the person concerned;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7ed-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> such provider, landlord, custodian, or other person—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7ee-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> shall not disclose the existence of the investigation or of the pen register or trap and trace device to any person unless or until ordered by the court; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7ef-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> shall maintain, under security procedures approved by the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence pursuant to section 1805(b)(2)(C) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002033">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002033"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title, any records concerning the pen register or trap and trace device or the aid furnished; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7f0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the applicant shall compensate such provider, landlord, custodian, or other person for reasonable expenses incurred by such provider, landlord, custodian, or other person in providing such information, facilities, or technical assistance; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a7f1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> shall direct that, upon the request of the applicant, the provider of a wire or electronic communication service shall disclose to the Federal officer using the pen register or trap and trace device covered by the order—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7f2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> in the case of the customer or subscriber using the service covered by the order (for the period specified by the order)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7f3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the name of the customer or subscriber;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7f4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the address of the customer or subscriber;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7f5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the telephone or instrument number, or other subscriber number or identifier, of the customer or subscriber, including any temporarily assigned network address or associated routing or transmission information;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7f6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> the length of the provision of service by such provider to the customer or subscriber and the types of services utilized by the customer or subscriber;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7f7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> in the case of a provider of local or long distance telephone service, any local or long distance telephone records of the customer or subscriber;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7f8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> if applicable, any records reflecting period of usage (or sessions) by the customer or subscriber; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7f9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/i/VII"><num value="VII">(VII)</num><content> any mechanisms and sources of payment for such service, including the number of any credit card or bank account utilized for payment for such service; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd143a7fa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> if available, with respect to any customer or subscriber of incoming or outgoing communications to or from the service covered by the order—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7fb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the name of such customer or subscriber;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7fc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the address of such customer or subscriber;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7fd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the telephone or instrument number, or other subscriber number or identifier, of such customer or subscriber, including any temporarily assigned network address or associated routing or transmission information; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd143a7fe-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/2/C/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> the length of the provision of service by such provider to such customer or subscriber and the types of services utilized by such customer or subscriber.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a7ff-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A denial of the application made under this subsection may be reviewed as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1803">section 1803 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a800-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Time limitation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a801-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), an order issued under this section shall authorize the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device for a period not to exceed 90 days. Extensions of such an order may be granted, but only upon an application for an order under this section and upon the judicial finding required by subsection (d). The period of extension shall be for a period not to exceed 90 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a802-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of an application under subsection (c) where the applicant has certified that the information likely to be obtained is foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person, an order, or an extension of an order, under this section may be for a period not to exceed one year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a803-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cause of action barred</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No cause of action shall lie in any court against any provider of a wire or electronic communication service, landlord, custodian, or other person (including any officer, employee, agent, or other specified person thereof) that furnishes any information, facilities, or technical assistance under subsection (d) in accordance with the terms of an order issued under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a804-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Furnishing of results</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Unless otherwise ordered by the judge, the results of a pen register or trap and trace device shall be furnished at reasonable intervals during regular business hours for the duration of the order to the authorized Government official or officials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a805-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Privacy procedures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a806-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Attorney General shall ensure that appropriate policies and procedures are in place to safeguard nonpublicly available information concerning United States persons that is collected through the use of a pen register or trap and trace device installed under this section. Such policies and procedures shall, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with the need to protect national security, include privacy protections that apply to the collection, retention, and use of information concerning United States persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a807-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1842/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection limits the authority of the court established under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1803/a">section 1803(a) of this title</ref> or of the Attorney General to impose additional privacy or minimization procedures with regard to the installation or use of a pen register or trap and trace device.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd143a808-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/511/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 95–511, title IV, § 402</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/272/tVI/s601/2">Pub. L. 105–272, title VI, § 601(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-20">Oct. 20, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2405">112 Stat. 2405</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tII/s214/a">Pub. L. 107–56, title II, § 214(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/286">115 Stat. 286</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/108/tIII/s314/a/5">Pub. L. 107–108, title III, § 314(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1402">115 Stat. 1402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1071/e">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1071(e)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3691">118 Stat. 3691</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/tI">Pub. L. 109–177, title I</ref>, §§ 105(c), 128(a), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/195">120 Stat. 195</ref>, 228; <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tVIII/s806/a/2">Pub. L. 111–259, title VIII, § 806(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2748">124 Stat. 2748</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/tII">Pub. L. 114–23, title II</ref>, §§ 201(a), 202(a), <date date="2015-06-02">June 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/277">129 Stat. 277</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/118/tII/s205/b/4">Pub. L. 115–118, title II, § 205(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-01-19">Jan. 19, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/22">132 Stat. 22</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/49/s10/a/3">Pub. L. 118–49, § 10(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="2024-04-20">Apr. 20, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/876">138 Stat. 876</ref>, 877.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd143a809-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd143a80a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd143a80b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 12333, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1805/b/2/C">Section 1805(b)(2)(C) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(B)(ii)(II), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1805/c/2/C">section 1805(c)(2)(C) of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/106/567/tVI/s602/b/1">Pub. L. 106–567, title VI, § 602(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2851">114 Stat. 2851</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd143a80c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/49/s10/a/3">Pub. L. 118–49, § 10(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/118/49/s10/b/3">Pub. L. 118–49, § 10(b)(3)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/118">Pub. L. 115–118</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/s201/a">Pub. L. 114–23, § 201(a)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/s202/a">Pub. L. 114–23, § 202(a)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Pub. L. 111–259</ref> made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>. See 2004 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/s128/a/1">Pub. L. 109–177, § 128(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and” at end of cl. (ii) and substituted semicolon for period at end of cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/s128/a/2">Pub. L. 109–177, § 128(a)(2)</ref>, (3), added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/s105/c">Pub. L. 109–177, § 105(c)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (2), an order issued” for “An order issued”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Pub. L. 111–259</ref>, substituted “Director of National Intelligence” for “Director of Central Intelligence”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s214/a/1">Pub. L. 107–56, § 214(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “for any investigation to obtain foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution” for “for any investigation to gather foreign intelligence information or information concerning international terrorism”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/108/s314/a/5/A">Pub. L. 107–108, § 314(a)(5)(A)</ref>, inserted “and” after semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s214/a/2">Pub. L. 107–56, § 214(a)(2)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “a certification by the applicant that the information likely to be obtained is relevant to an ongoing foreign intelligence or international terrorism investigation being conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation under guidelines approved by the Attorney General; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s214/a/3">Pub. L. 107–56, § 214(a)(3)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “information which demonstrates that there is reason to believe that the telephone line to which the pen register or trap and trace device is to be attached, or the communication instrument or device to be covered by the pen register or trap and trace device, has been or is about to be used in communication with—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) an individual who is engaging or has engaged in international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities that involve or may involve a violation of the criminal laws of the United States; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) a foreign power or agent of a foreign power under circumstances giving reason to believe that the communication concerns or concerned international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities that involve or may involve a violation of the criminal laws of the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s214/a/4">Pub. L. 107–56, § 214(a)(4)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “shall specify—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the identity, if known, of the person who is the subject of the foreign intelligence or international terrorism investigation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) in the case of an application for the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device with respect to a telephone line—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(I) the identity, if known, of the person to whom is leased or in whose name the telephone line is listed; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(II) the number and, if known, physical location of the telephone line; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) in the case of an application for the use of a pen register or trap and trace device with respect to a communication instrument or device not covered by clause (ii)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(I) the identity, if known, of the person who owns or leases the instrument or device or in whose name the instrument or device is listed; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(II) the number of the instrument or device; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/108/s314/a/5/B">Pub. L. 107–108, § 314(a)(5)(B)</ref>, substituted “terms of an order issued” for “terms of a court”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd143a80d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd143a80e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2024 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/118/49/s10/a/3">section 10(a)(3) of Pub. L. 118–49</ref> applicable with respect to applications made on or after the date that is 120 days after <date date="2024-04-20">Apr. 20, 2024</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/118/49/s10/a/6">section 10(a)(6) of Pub. L. 118–49</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1804">section 1804 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/118/49/s10/b/3">section 10(b)(3) of Pub. L. 118–49</ref> applicable with respect to applications made on or after the date that is 120 days after <date date="2024-04-20">Apr. 20, 2024</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/118/49/s10/b/6">section 10(b)(6) of Pub. L. 118–49</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1804">section 1804 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd143a80f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For Determination by President that amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref> take effect on <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, see Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 23925, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref> effective not later than six months after <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s1097/a">section 1097(a) of Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out in an Effective Date of 2004 Amendment; Transition Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
