<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd143a810-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843"><num value="1843">§ 1843.</num><heading> Authorization during emergencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a811-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for authorization</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, when the Attorney General makes a determination described in subsection (b), the Attorney General may authorize the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device on an emergency basis to gather foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or information to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a812-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a judge referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1842/b">section 1842(b) of this title</ref> is informed by the Attorney General or his designee at the time of such authorization that the decision has been made to install and use the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, on an emergency basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a813-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an application in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1842">section 1842 of this title</ref> is made to such judge as soon as practicable, but not more than 7 days, after the Attorney General authorizes the installation and use of the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a814-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of emergency and factual basis</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A determination under this subsection is a reasonable determination by the Attorney General that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a815-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an emergency requires the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device to obtain foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or information to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution before an order authorizing the installation and use of the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, can with due diligence be obtained under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1842">section 1842 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a816-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the factual basis for issuance of an order under such <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1842">section 1842 of this title</ref> to approve the installation and use of the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, exists.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a817-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of absence of order</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a818-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the absence of an order applied for under subsection (a)(2) approving the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device authorized under this section, the installation and use of the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, shall terminate at the earlier of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a819-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> when the information sought is obtained;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a81a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> when the application for the order is denied under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1842">section 1842 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd143a81b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> 7 days after the time of the authorization by the Attorney General.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a81c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the event that an application for an order applied for under subsection (a)(2) is denied, or in any other case where the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device under this section is terminated and no order under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1842">section 1842 of this title</ref> is issued approving the installation and use of the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, no information obtained or evidence derived from the use of the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, shall be received in evidence or otherwise disclosed in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, office, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or political subdivision thereof, and no information concerning any United States person acquired from the use of the pen register or trap and trace device, as the case may be, shall subsequently be used or disclosed in any other manner by Federal officers or employees without the consent of such person, except with the approval of the Attorney General if the information indicates a threat of death or serious bodily harm to any person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd143a81d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A denial of the application made under subsection (a)(2) may be reviewed as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1803">section 1803 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd143a81e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s1843/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Privacy procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Information collected through the use of a pen register or trap and trace device installed under this section shall be subject to the policies and procedures required under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1842/h">section 1842(h) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd143a81f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/511/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 95–511, title IV, § 403</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/272/tVI/s601/2">Pub. L. 105–272, title VI, § 601(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-20">Oct. 20, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2407">112 Stat. 2407</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tII/s214/b">Pub. L. 107–56, title II, § 214(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/287">115 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/261/tI/s108">Pub. L. 110–261, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="2008-07-10">July 10, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2464">122 Stat. 2464</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/23/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 114–23, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-06-02">June 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/278">129 Stat. 278</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/118/tII/s205/b/5">Pub. L. 115–118, title II, § 205(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2018-01-19">Jan. 19, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/22">132 Stat. 22</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd143a820-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd143a821-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd143a822-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/118">Pub. L. 115–118</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/23">Pub. L. 114–23</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsecs. (a)(2), (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/110/261">Pub. L. 110–261</ref> substituted “7 days” for “48 hours”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s214/b/1">Pub. L. 107–56, § 214(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or information to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution” for “foreign intelligence information or information concerning international terrorism” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s214/b/2">Pub. L. 107–56, § 214(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or information to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution” for “foreign intelligence information or information concerning international terrorism”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd143a823-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd143a824-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/261">Pub. L. 110–261</ref> effective <date date="2008-07-10">July 10, 2008</date>, except as provided in <ref href="/us/pl/110/261/s404">section 404 of Pub. L. 110–261</ref>, set out as a Transition Procedures note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/261/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 110–261</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2008 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
