<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd15b75c9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082"><num value="2082">§ 2082.</num><heading> Prior service credit</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75ca-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participant may, subject to the provisions of this section, include in the participant’s period of service—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd15b75cb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> civilian service in the Government before becoming a participant that would be creditable toward retirement under subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5 (as determined under section 8332(b) of such title); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd15b75cc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> honorable active service in the Armed Forces before the date of the separation upon which eligibility for an annuity is based, or honorable active service in the Regular or Reserve Corps <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002044">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002044"><num>1</num> See Change of Name note below.</note> of the Public Health Service after <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, or as a commissioned officer of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration after <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75cd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75ce-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the total service of any participant shall exclude—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75cf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any period of civilian service on or after <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, for which retirement deductions or deposits have not been made,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75d0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any period of service for which a refund of contributions has been made, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75d1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any period of service for which contributions were not transferred pursuant to subsection (c)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">unless the participant makes a deposit to the fund in an amount equal to the percentages of basic pay received for such service as specified in the table contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/c">section 8334(c) of title 5</ref>, together with interest computed in accordance with section 8334(e) of such title. The deposit may be made in one or more installments (including by allotment from pay), as determined by the Director.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75d2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of retirement deductions not made</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a participant has not paid a deposit for civilian service performed before <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, for which retirement deductions were not made, such participant’s annuity shall be reduced by 10 percent of the deposit described in paragraph (1) remaining unpaid, unless the participant elects to eliminate the service involved for the purpose of the annuity computation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75d3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of refund of retirement contributions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A participant who received a refund of retirement contributions under this or any other retirement system for Government employees covering service for which the participant may be allowed credit under this subchapter may deposit the amount received, with interest computed under paragraph (1). Credit may not be allowed for the service covered by the refund until the deposit is made, except that a participant who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75d4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> separated from Government service before <date date="1991-03-31">March 31, 1991</date>, and received a refund of the participant’s retirement contributions covering a period of service ending before <date date="1991-03-31">March 31, 1991</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75d5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is entitled to an annuity under this subchapter (other than a disability annuity) which commences after <date date="1992-12-01">December 1, 1992</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75d6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> does not make the deposit required to receive credit for the service covered by the refund;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be entitled to an annuity actuarially reduced in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/d/2/B">section 8334(d)(2)(B) of title 5</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75d7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Entitlement under another system</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Credit toward retirement under the system shall not be allowed for any period of civilian service on the basis of which the participant is receiving (or will in the future be entitled to receive) an annuity under another retirement system for Government employees, unless the right to such annuity is waived and a deposit is made under paragraph (1) covering that period of service, or a transfer is made pursuant to subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75d8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer from other Government retirement systems</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75d9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If an employee who is under another retirement system for Government employees becomes a participant in the system by direct transfer, the Government’s contributions (including interest accrued thereon computed in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/e">section 8334(e) of title 5</ref>) under such retirement system on behalf of the employee as well as such employee’s total contributions and deposits (including interest accrued thereon), except voluntary contributions, shall be transferred to the employee’s credit in the fund effective as of the date such employee becomes a participant in the system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75da-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent of employee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each such employee shall be deemed to consent to the transfer of such funds, and such transfer shall be a complete discharge and acquittance of all claims and demands against the other Government retirement fund on account of service rendered before becoming a participant in the system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75db-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional contributions; refunds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A participant whose contributions are transferred pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not be required to make additional contributions for periods of service for which full contributions were made to the other Government retirement fund, nor shall any refund be made to any such participant on account of contributions made during any period to the other Government retirement fund at a higher rate than that fixed for employees by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/c">section 8334(c) of title 5</ref> for contributions to the fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75dc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer to other Government retirement systems</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75dd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a participant in the system becomes an employee under another Government retirement system by direct transfer to employment covered by such system, the Government’s contributions (including interest accrued thereon computed in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/e">section 8334(e) of title 5</ref>) to the fund on the participant’s behalf as well as the participant’s total contributions and deposits (including interest accrued thereon), except voluntary contributions, shall be transferred to the participant’s credit in the fund of such other retirement system effective as of the date on which the participant becomes eligible to participate in such other retirement system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75de-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent of employee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each such employee shall be deemed to consent to the transfer of such funds, and such transfer shall be a complete discharge and acquittance of all claims and demands against the fund on account of service rendered before the participant’s becoming eligible for participation in that other system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75df-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Prior military service credit</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75e0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Application to obtain credit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a deposit required to obtain credit for prior military service described in subsection (a)(2) was not made to another Government retirement fund and transferred under subsection (c)(1), the participant may obtain credit for such military service, subject to the provisions of this subsection and subsections (f) through (h), by applying for it to the Director before retirement or separation from the Agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15b75e1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment starting before, on, or after <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date></heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75e2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the service of a participant who first became a Federal employee before <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, shall include credit for each period of military service performed before the date of separation on which entitlement to an annuity under this subchapter is based, subject to subsection (f); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15b75e3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the service of a participant who first becomes a Federal employee on or after <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, shall include credit for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd15de6e4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> each period of military service performed before <date date="1957-01-01">January 1, 1957</date>, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd15de6e5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> each period of military service performed after <date date="1956-12-31">December 31, 1956</date>, and before the separation on which entitlement to an annuity under this subchapter is based, only if a deposit (with interest, if any) is made with respect to that period, as provided in subsection (h).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6e6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of receipt of military retired pay</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a participant who is entitled to retired pay based on a period of military service, the participant’s service may not include credit for such period of military service unless the retired pay is paid—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6e7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> on account of a service-connected disability—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd15de6e8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> incurred in combat with an enemy of the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd15de6e9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> caused by an instrumentality of war and incurred in the line of duty during a period of war (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1101">section 1101 of title 38</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6ea-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> under chapter 67 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002045">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002045"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 10.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6eb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Survivor annuity</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (3), the survivor annuity of a survivor of a participant—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6ec-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who was awarded retired pay based on any period of military service, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6ed-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whose death occurs before separation from the Agency,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be computed in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332/c/3">section 8332(c)(3) of title 5</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6ee-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of entitlement to social security benefits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6ef-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section (except paragraph (3) of this subsection) or <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2083">section 2083 of this title</ref>, any military service (other than military service covered by military leave with pay from a civilian position) performed by a participant after December 1956 shall be excluded in determining the aggregate period of service on which an annuity payable under this subchapter to such participant or to the participant’s spouse, former spouse, previous spouse, or child is based, if such participant, spouse, former spouse, previous spouse, or child is entitled (or would upon proper application be entitled), at the time of such determination, to monthly old-age or survivors’ insurance benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">section 402 of title 42</ref>, based on such participant’s wages and self-employment income. If the military service is not excluded under the preceding sentence, but upon attaining age 62, the participant or spouse, former spouse, or previous spouse becomes entitled (or would upon proper application be entitled) to such benefits, the aggregate period of service on which the annuity is based shall be redetermined, effective as of the first day of the month in which the participant or spouse, former spouse, or previous spouse attains age 62, so as to exclude such service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6f0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of paragraph (1) relating to credit for military service do not apply to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6f1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any period of military service of a participant with respect to which the participant has made a deposit with interest, if any, under subsection (h); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6f2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the military service of any participant described in subsection (e)(2)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6f3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of entitlement before <date date="1982-09-08">September 8, 1982</date></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd15de6f4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The annuity recomputation required by paragraph (1) shall not apply to any participant who was entitled to an annuity under this subchapter on or before <date date="1982-09-08">September 8, 1982</date>, or who is entitled to a deferred annuity based on separation from the Agency occurring on or before such date. Instead of an annuity recomputation, the annuity of such participant shall be reduced at age 62 by an amount equal to a fraction of the participant’s old-age or survivors’ insurance benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">section 402 of title 42</ref>. The reduction shall be determined by multiplying the participant’s monthly Social Security benefit by a fraction, the numerator of which is the participant’s total military wages and deemed additional wages (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s429">section 429 of title 42</ref>) that were subject to Social Security deductions and the denominator of which is the total of all the participant’s wages, including military wages, and all self-employment income that were subject to Social Security deductions before the calendar year in which the determination month occurs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd15de6f5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The reduction determined in accordance with subparagraph (A) shall not be greater than the reduction that would be required under paragraph (1) if such paragraph applied to the participant. The new formula shall be applicable to any annuity payment payable after <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, including annuity payments to participants who had previously reached age 62 and whose annuities had already been recomputed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd15de6f6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “determination month” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6f7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the first month for which the participant is entitled to old-age or survivors’ insurance benefits (or would be entitled to such benefits upon application therefor); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd15de6f8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/f/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> October 1982, in the case of any participant entitled to such benefits for that month.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6f9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposits paid by survivors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of survivor annuities, deposits authorized by subsections (b) and (h) may also be made by the survivor of a participant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd15de6fa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposits for periods of military service</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd15de6fb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd15de6fc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Each participant who has performed military service before the date of separation on which entitlement to an annuity under this subchapter is based may pay to the Agency an amount equal to 7 percent of the amount of basic pay paid under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s204">section 204 of title 37</ref> to the participant for each period of military service after December 1956; except, the amount to be paid for military service performed beginning on <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, through <date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>, shall be as follows:<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c3,L0,ns,tp0,p1,7/8,s10,xs54,xs102,ns,tp0,p1,7/8,s10,xs54,xs102; " id="idd15de6fd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 42pt;" />
<html:col style="width:58pt ; max-width:58pt;" />
<html:col style="width:106pt ; max-width:106pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:1pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:td />
</html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style="min-width: 42.0pt; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style="width:58.0pt ; max-width:58.0pt; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">7.25 percent of basic pay</html:p></html:td><html:td style="width:106.0pt ; max-width:106.0pt; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">January 1, 1999</html:span>, to <html:span class="date">December 31, 1999</html:span>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">7.4 percent of basic pay</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:span class="date">January 1, 2000</html:span>, to <html:span class="date">December 31, 2000</html:span>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd15de6fe-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amount of such payments shall be based on such evidence of basic pay for military service as the participant may provide or, if the Director determines sufficient evidence has not been provided to adequately determine basic pay for military service, such payment shall be based upon estimates of such basic pay provided to the Director under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd15de6ff-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Any deposit made under paragraph (1) more than two years after the later of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd15de700-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd15de701-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the date on which the participant making the deposit first becomes an employee of the Federal Government,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall include interest on such amount computed and compounded annually beginning on the date of expiration of the two-year period. The interest rate that is applicable in computing interest in any year under this paragraph shall be equal to the interest rate that is applicable for such year under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334/e">section 8334(e) of title 5</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd15de702-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any payment received by the Director under this subsection shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd15de703-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2082/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The provisions of section 2031(<i>l</i>) of this title shall apply with respect to such information as the Director determines to be necessary for the administration of this subsection in the same manner that such section applies concerning information described in that section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd15de704-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/643/tII/s252">Pub. L. 88–643, title II, § 252</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/tVIII/s802">Pub. L. 102–496, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3229">106 Stat. 3229</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tVII/s7001/c/3">Pub. L. 105–33, title VII, § 7001(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/659">111 Stat. 659</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/346/s101/a/tV/s505/c/2">Pub. L. 106–346, § 101(a) [title V, § 505(c)(2)]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-23">Oct. 23, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1356">114 Stat. 1356</ref>, 1356A–53; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXII/s6202/a/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXII, § 6202(a)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, (c), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2185">133 Stat. 2185</ref>, 2186.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd15de705-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd15de706-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd15de707-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 67 of title 10, referred to in subsec. (e)(3)(B), was transferred to part II of subtitle E of Title 10, Armed Forces, renumbered as chapter 1223, and amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1662/j/1">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2998">108 Stat. 2998</ref>. A new chapter 67 (§ 1331) of Title 10 was added by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1662/j/7">section 1662(j)(7) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idd15de708-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/88/643/s252">section 252 of Pub. L. 88–643</ref>, title II, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1050">78 Stat. 1050</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/626">Pub. L. 91–626</ref>, §§ 5, 6, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1872">84 Stat. 1872</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/522/tII/s211">Pub. L. 94–522, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2471">90 Stat. 2471</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 12443, §§ 9–11, 15, <date date="1983-09-27">Sept. 27, 1983</date>, 48 F.R. 44753, 44755; Ex. Ord. No. 12485, <date date="1984-07-13">July 13, 1984</date>, 49 F.R. 28827; <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tV/s501/2">Pub. L. 99–335, title V, § 501(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/622">100 Stat. 622</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/2">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/406">105 Stat. 406</ref>, related to prior service credit and was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403">section 403 of this title</ref> prior to the general amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/88/643">Pub. L. 88–643</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s802">section 802 of Pub. L. 102–496</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd15de709-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s6202/c">Pub. L. 116–92, § 6202(c)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1991-03-31">March 31, 1991</date>” for “<date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s6202/a/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–92, § 6202(a)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “2031(<i>l</i>)” for “2031(k)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (h)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/346">Pub. L. 106–346</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “<date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>” for “<date date="2002-12-31">December 31, 2002</date>” and in table struck out item at end relating to payment of 7.5 percent of basic pay for service period <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>, to <date date="2002-12-31">December 31, 2002</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “Each participant who has performed military service before the date of separation on which entitlement to an annuity under this subchapter is based may pay to the Agency an amount equal to 7 percent of the amount of basic pay paid under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s204">section 204 of title 37</ref> to the participant for each period of military service after December 1956. The amount of such payments shall be based on such evidence of basic pay for military service as the participant may provide or, if the Director determines sufficient evidence has not been provided to adequately determine basic pay for military service, such payment shall be based upon estimates of such basic pay provided to the Director under paragraph (4).”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd15de70a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idd15de70b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service deemed to be a reference to the Ready Reserve Corps, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s204/c/3">section 204(c)(3) of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd15de70c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2019 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> effective as if enacted on <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, and applicable to computations or participants, respectively, as of such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s6202/e">section 6202(e) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2031">section 2031 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd15de70d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/346">Pub. L. 106–346</ref> effective upon the close of calendar year 2000 and applicable thereafter, see section 101(a) [title V, § 505(i)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/346">Pub. L. 106–346</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334">section 8334 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd15de70e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> effective <date date="1997-10-01">Oct. 1, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s7001/f">section 7001(f) of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8334">section 8334 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd15de70f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on first day of fourth month beginning after <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s805">section 805 of Pub. L. 102–496</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
