<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd0f9a6f5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s225"><num value="225">§ 225.</num><heading> Bond to deliver cargo at destination named in clearance</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a permit or clearance is granted for either a foreign or domestic port, it shall be lawful for the collector of the customs granting the same, if he deems it necessary, under the circumstances of the case, to require a bond to be executed by the master or the owner of the vessel, in a penalty equal to the value of the cargo, and with sureties to the satisfaction of such collector, that the cargo shall be delivered at the destination for which it is cleared or permitted, and that no part thereof shall be used in affording aid or comfort to any person or parties in insurrection against the authority of the United States.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idd0f9a6f6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(R.S. § 5321.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd0f9a6f7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd0f9a6f8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd0f9a6f9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 5321 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1862-05-20/ch81/s2">act May 20, 1862, ch. 81, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/12/404">12 Stat. 404</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd0f9a6fa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idd0f9a6fb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All offices of collector of customs, comptroller of customs, surveyor of customs, and appraiser of merchandise of Bureau of Customs of Department of the Treasury to which appointments were required to be made by President with advice and consent of Senate ordered abolished, with such offices to be terminated not later than <date date="1966-12-31">December 31, 1966</date>, by Reorg. Plan No. 1, of 1965, eff. <date date="1965-05-25">May 25, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 7035, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1317">79 Stat. 1317</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. All functions of offices eliminated were already vested in Secretary of the Treasury by Reorg. Plan No. 26 of 1950, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
