<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd162a20f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2314"><num value="2314">§ 2314.</num><heading> Chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and high-yield explosives response team</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd162a210-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2314/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Department of Defense rapid response team</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall develop and maintain at least one domestic terrorism rapid response team composed of members of the Armed Forces and employees of the Department of Defense who are capable of aiding Federal, State, and local officials in the detection, neutralization, containment, dismantlement, and disposal of weapons of mass destruction containing chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and high-yield explosives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd162a211-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2314/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Addition to Federal response plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall incorporate into the National Response Plan prepared pursuant to section 502(6) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002048">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002048"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s312/6">6 U.S.C. 312(6)</ref>), other existing Federal emergency response plans, and programs prepared under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5196/b">section 5196(b) of title 42</ref> guidance on the use and deployment of the rapid response teams established under this section to respond to emergencies involving weapons of mass destruction. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall carry out this subsection in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of other Federal agencies involved with the emergency response plans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd162a212-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tXIV/s1414">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1414</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2720">110 Stat. 2720</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tX/s1033">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1033</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3429">119 Stat. 3429</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd162a213-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd162a214-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd162a215-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 502(6) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (b), probably should be a reference to section 504(a)(6) of that Act, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s314/a/6">section 314(a)(6) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security. Section 502 of the Act was renumbered section 504 and par. (6) of that section was redesignated subsec. (a)(6) by <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/tVI/s611/8">Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 611(8)</ref>, (12)(B), <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1395">120 Stat. 1395</ref>, 1398.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd162a216-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s1033/1">Pub. L. 109–163, § 1033(1)</ref>, substituted “Chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and high-yield explosives response team” for “Chemical-biological emergency response team” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s1033/2">Pub. L. 109–163, § 1033(2)</ref>, substituted “radiological, nuclear, and high-yield explosives” for “or related materials”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s1033/3">Pub. L. 109–163, § 1033(3)</ref>, in heading, substituted “plans” for “plan” and, in text, substituted “The Secretary of Homeland Security shall incorporate into the National Response Plan prepared pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s312/6">section 312(6) of title 6</ref>, other existing Federal emergency response plans, and” for “Not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall develop and incorporate into existing Federal emergency response plans and” in first sentence and “Secretary of Homeland Security” for “Director” and “coordination” for “consultation” in second sentence.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
