<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd162a232-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317"><num value="2317">§ 2317.</num><heading> Rapid response information system</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd162a233-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Inventory of rapid response assets</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd162a234-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The head of each Federal Response Plan agency shall develop and maintain an inventory of physical equipment and assets under the jurisdiction of that agency that could be made available to aid State and local officials in search and rescue and other disaster management and mitigation efforts associated with an emergency involving weapons of mass destruction. The agency head shall submit a copy of the inventory, and any updates of the inventory, to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for inclusion in the master inventory required under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd162a235-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each inventory shall include a separate listing of any equipment that is excess to the needs of that agency and could be considered for disposal as excess or surplus property for use for response and training with regard to emergencies involving weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd162a236-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Master inventory</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall compile and maintain a comprehensive listing of all inventories prepared under subsection (a). The first such master list shall be completed not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, and shall be updated annually thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd162a237-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Addition to Federal response plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall develop and incorporate into existing Federal emergency response plans and programs prepared under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5196/b">section 5196(b) of title 42</ref> guidance on accessing and using the physical equipment and assets included in the master list developed under subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002049">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002049"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection (b)”.</note> to respond to emergencies involving weapons of mass destruction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1651238-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Database on chemical and biological materials</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall prepare a database on chemical and biological agents and munitions characteristics and safety precautions for civilian use. The initial design and compilation of the database shall be completed not later than <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1651239-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2317/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to inventory and database</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall design and maintain a system to give Federal, State, and local officials access to the inventory listing and database maintained under this section in the event of an emergency involving weapons of mass destruction or to prepare and train to respond to such an emergency. The system shall include a secure but accessible emergency response hotline to access information and request assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd165123a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tXIV/s1417">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1417</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2724">110 Stat. 2724</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/tVI/s612/c">Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 612(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-04">Oct. 4, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1410">120 Stat. 1410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd165123b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd165123c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idd165123d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency” substituted for “Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency” wherever appearing in text on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s612/c">section 612(c) of Pub. L. 109–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s313">section 313 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security. Any reference to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/109/295">Pub. L. 109–295</ref> or an amendment by title VI to be considered to refer and apply to the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency until <date date="2007-03-31">Mar. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/295/s612/f/2">section 612(f)(2) of Pub. L. 109–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s313">section 313 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
