<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1651301-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2357"><num value="2357">§ 2357.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1651302-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2357/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> United States nonproliferation efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union have achieved important results in ensuring that weapons of mass destruction, weapons-usable material and technology, and weapons-related knowledge remain beyond the reach of terrorists and weapons-proliferating states;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1651303-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2357/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> although these efforts are in the United States national security interest, the effectiveness of these efforts has suffered from a lack of coordination within and among United States Government agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1651304-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2357/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> increased spending and investment by the United States private sector on nonproliferation efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union, specifically, spending and investment by the United States private sector in job creation initiatives and proposals for unemployed Russian Federation weapons scientists and technicians, are making an important contribution in ensuring that knowledge related to weapons of mass destruction remains beyond the reach of terrorists and weapons-proliferating states; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1651305-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2357/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> increased spending and investment by the United States private sector on nonproliferation efforts in the independent states of the former Soviet Union make advisable the establishment of a coordinating body to ensure that United States public and private efforts are not in conflict, and to ensure that public spending on efforts by the independent states of the former Soviet Union is maximized to ensure efficiency and further United States national security interests.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idd1651306-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dB/tXIII/s1332">Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1332</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1448">116 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1651307-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1651308-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idd1651309-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of subtitle C (§§ 1331–1339) of title XIII of div. B of <ref href="/us/pl/107/228">Pub. L. 107–228</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, as the “Nonproliferation Assistance Coordination Act of 2002”, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s1331">section 1331 of Pub. L. 107–228</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2301">section 2301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
