<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1675c74-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368"><num value="2368">§ 2368.</num><heading> Annual reports on the proliferation of missiles and essential components of nuclear, biological, chemical, and radiological weapons</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c75-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2003-03-01">March 1, 2003</date>, and annually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the designated congressional committees an annual report on the transfer by any country of weapons, technology, components, or materials that can be used to deliver, manufacture (including research and experimentation), or weaponize nuclear, biological, chemical or radiological weapons (in this section referred to as “NBC weapons”) to any country other than a country referred to in subsection (d) that is seeking to possess or otherwise acquire such weapons, technology, or materials, or other system that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to develop, acquire, or deliver NBC weapons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c76-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Matters to be included</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each such report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c77-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the transfer of all aircraft, cruise missiles, artillery weapons, unguided rockets and multiple rocket systems, and related bombs, shells, warheads and other weaponization technology and materials that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be intended for the delivery of NBC weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c78-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> international transfers of MTCR equipment or technology to any country that is seeking to acquire such equipment or any other system that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be used to deliver NBC weapons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c79-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the transfer of technology, test equipment, radioactive materials, feedstocks and cultures, and all other specialized materials that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to manufacture NBC weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c7a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Content of report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each such report shall include the following with respect to preceding <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002058">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002058"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “the”.</note> calendar year:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c7b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The status of missile, aircraft, and other NBC weapons delivery and weaponization programs in any such country, including efforts by such country or by any subnational group to acquire MTCR-controlled equipment, NBC-capable aircraft, or any other weapon or major weapon component which may be utilized in the delivery of NBC weapons, whose primary use is the delivery of NBC weapons, or that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to deliver NBC weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c7c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The status of NBC weapons development, acquisition, manufacture, stockpiling, and deployment programs in any such country, including efforts by such country or by any subnational group to acquire essential test equipment, manufacturing equipment and technology, weaponization equipment and technology, and radioactive material, feedstocks or components of feedstocks, and biological cultures and toxins.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c7d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A description of assistance provided by any person or government, after <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, to any such country or subnational group in the acquisition or development of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1675c7e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> NBC weapons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1675c7f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> missile systems, as defined in the MTCR or that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be used to deliver NBC weapons; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1675c80-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> aircraft and other delivery systems and weapons that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to deliver NBC weapons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c81-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A listing of those persons and countries that continue to provide such equipment or technology described in paragraph (3) to any country or subnational group as of the date of submission of the report, including the extent to which foreign persons and countries were found to have knowingly and materially assisted such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c82-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A description of the use of, or substantial preparations to use, the equipment of technology described in paragraph (3) by any foreign country or subnational group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c83-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> A description of the diplomatic measures that the United States, and that other adherents to the MTCR and other arrangements affecting the acquisition and delivery of NBC weapons, have made with respect to activities and private persons and governments suspected of violating the MTCR and such other arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c84-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> An analysis of the effectiveness of the regulatory and enforcement regimes of the United States and other countries that adhere to the MTCR and other arrangements affecting the acquisition and delivery of NBC weapons in controlling the export of MTCR and other NBC weapons and delivery system equipment or technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c85-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> A summary of advisory opinions issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4612/b/4">section 4612(b)(4) of this title</ref> and under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2797b/d">section 2797b(d) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c86-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> An explanation of United States policy regarding the transfer of MTCR equipment or technology to foreign missile programs, including programs involving launches of space vehicles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1675c87-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> A description of each transfer by any person or government during the preceding 12-month period which is subject to sanctions under the Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 (title XVI of <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Public Law 102–484</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c88-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The countries excluded under subsection (a) are Australia, Belgium, Canada, the Czech Republic, Denmark, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Italy, Japan, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Spain, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c89-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Classification of report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall make every effort to submit all of the information required by this section in unclassified form. Whenever the Secretary submits any such information in classified form, the Secretary shall submit such classified information in an addendum and shall also submit concurrently a detailed summary, in unclassified form, of that classified information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c8a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c8b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Designated congressional committees</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “designated congressional committees” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1675c8c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1675c8d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c8e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Missile; MTCR; MTCR equipment or technology</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The terms “missile”, “MTCR”, and “MTCR equipment or technology” have the meanings given those terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2797c">section 2797c of title 22</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c8f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Person</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “person” means any United States or foreign individual, partnership, corporation, or other form of association, or any of its successor entities, parents, or subsidiaries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1675c90-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s2368/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Weaponize; weaponization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “weaponize” or “weaponization” means to incorporate into, or the incorporation into, usable ordnance or other militarily useful means of delivery.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1675c91-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dB/tXIII/s1308">Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1308</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1439">116 Stat. 1439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1675c92-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1675c93-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd1675c94-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992, referred to in subsec. (c)(10), is title XVI of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2571">106 Stat. 2571</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1675c95-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s1308">section 1308 of Pub. L. 107–228</ref>. Subsec. (g) of <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s1308">section 1308 of Pub. L. 107–228</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5606">section 5606 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, amended provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2656">section 2656 of Title 22</ref>, and repealed provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of Title 22</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Security Assistance Act of 2002, and also as part of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003, and not as part of the Defense Against Weapons of Mass Destruction Act of 1996 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1675c96-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idd1675c97-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on International Relations of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Foreign Affairs of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idd1675c98-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of “Secretary” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 107–228</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651">section 2651 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd1675c99-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="idd1675c9a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of congressional reporting functions of President under subsec. (a) of this section, see section 1 of Ex. Ord. No. 13313, <date date="2003-07-31">July 31, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 46073, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref>, The President.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
