<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1865608-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024"><num value="3024">§ 3024.</num><heading> Responsibilities and authorities of the Director of National Intelligence</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1865609-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of intelligence</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186560a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence shall be responsible for ensuring that national intelligence is provided—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186560b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186560c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to the heads of departments and agencies of the executive branch;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186560d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and senior military commanders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186560e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to the Senate and House of Representatives and the committees thereof; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186560f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> to such other persons as the Director of National Intelligence determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865610-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such national intelligence should be timely, objective, independent of political considerations, and based upon all sources available to the intelligence community and other appropriate entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1865611-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to intelligence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Unless otherwise directed by the President, the Director of National Intelligence shall have access to all national intelligence and intelligence related to the national security which is collected by any Federal department, agency, or other entity, except as otherwise provided by law or, as appropriate, under guidelines agreed upon by the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1865612-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget authorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865613-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> With respect to budget requests and appropriations for the National Intelligence Program, the Director of National Intelligence shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1865614-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> based on intelligence priorities set by the President, provide to the heads of departments containing agencies or organizations within the intelligence community, and to the heads of such agencies and organizations, guidance for developing the National Intelligence Program budget pertaining to such agencies and organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1865615-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> based on budget proposals provided to the Director of National Intelligence by the heads of agencies and organizations within the intelligence community and the heads of their respective departments and, as appropriate, after obtaining the advice of the Joint Intelligence Community Council, develop and determine an annual consolidated National Intelligence Program budget; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1865616-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> present such consolidated National Intelligence Program budget, together with any comments from the heads of departments containing agencies or organizations within the intelligence community, to the President for approval.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865617-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In addition to the information provided under paragraph (1)(B), the heads of agencies and organizations within the intelligence community shall provide the Director of National Intelligence such other information as the Director shall request for the purpose of determining the annual consolidated National Intelligence Program budget under that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865618-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865619-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall participate in the development by the Secretary of Defense of the annual budget for the Military Intelligence Program or any successor program or programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186561a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall provide guidance for the development of the annual budget for each element of the intelligence community that is not within the National Intelligence Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186561b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall ensure the effective execution of the annual budget for intelligence and intelligence-related activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186561c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186561d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall be responsible for managing appropriations for the National Intelligence Program by directing the allotment or allocation of such appropriations through the heads of the departments containing agencies or organizations within the intelligence community and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, with prior notice (including the provision of appropriate supporting information) to the head of the department containing an agency or organization receiving any such allocation or allotment or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186561e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, pursuant to relevant appropriations Acts for the National Intelligence Program, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall exercise the authority of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to apportion funds, at the exclusive direction of the Director of National Intelligence, for allocation to the elements of the intelligence community through the relevant host executive departments and the Central Intelligence Agency. Department comptrollers or appropriate budget execution officers shall allot, allocate, reprogram, or transfer funds appropriated for the National Intelligence Program in an expeditious manner.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186561f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall monitor the implementation and execution of the National Intelligence Program by the heads of the elements of the intelligence community that manage programs and activities that are part of the National Intelligence Program, which shall include audits and evaluations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865620-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Consistent with subparagraph (C), the Director of National Intelligence shall ensure that the programs and activities that are part of the National Intelligence Program, including those of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, are structured and executed in a manner than enables budget traceability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865621-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Apportionment and allotment of funds under this subsection shall be subject to chapter 13 and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1517">section 1517 of title 31</ref> and the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621">2 U.S.C. 621</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865622-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall report to the President and the Congress not later than 15 days after learning of any instance in which a departmental comptroller acts in a manner inconsistent with the law (including permanent statutes, authorization Acts, and appropriations Acts), or the direction of the Director of National Intelligence, in carrying out the National Intelligence Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1865623-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Role of Director of National Intelligence in transfer and reprogramming of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865624-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865625-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> No funds made available under the National Intelligence Program may be transferred or reprogrammed without the prior approval of the Director of National Intelligence, except in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865626-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Director of National Intelligence before transferring or reprogramming funds made available under the Military Intelligence Program or any successor program or programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1865627-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Subject to the succeeding provisions of this subsection, the Director of National Intelligence may transfer or reprogram funds appropriated for a program within the National Intelligence Program—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1865628-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to another such program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1865629-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to other departments or agencies of the United States Government for the development and fielding of systems of common concern related to the collection, processing, analysis, exploitation, and dissemination of intelligence information; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186562a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to a program funded by appropriations not within the National Intelligence Program to address critical gaps in intelligence information sharing or access capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186562b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence may only transfer or reprogram funds referred to in paragraph (1)(A)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186562c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd186562d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> after consultation with the heads of departments containing agencies or organizations within the intelligence community to the extent such agencies or organizations are affected, and, in the case of the Central Intelligence Agency, after consultation with the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd186562e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The amounts available for transfer or reprogramming in the National Intelligence Program in any given fiscal year, and the terms and conditions governing such transfers and reprogrammings, are subject to the provisions of annual appropriations Acts and this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c72f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c730-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A transfer or reprogramming of funds may be made under this subsection only if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c731-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the funds are being transferred to an activity that is a higher priority intelligence activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c732-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the transfer or reprogramming supports an emergent need, improves program effectiveness, or increases efficiency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c733-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the transfer or reprogramming does not involve a transfer or reprogramming of funds to a Reserve for Contingencies of the Director of National Intelligence or the Reserve for Contingencies of the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c734-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> the transfer or reprogramming results in a cumulative transfer or reprogramming of funds out of any department or agency, as appropriate, funded in the National Intelligence Program in a single fiscal year—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c735-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> that is less than $150,000,000, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c736-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> that is less than 5 percent of amounts available to a department or agency under the National Intelligence Program; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c737-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the transfer or reprogramming does not terminate an acquisition program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c738-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A transfer or reprogramming may be made without regard to a limitation set forth in clause (iv) or (v) of subparagraph (A) if the transfer has the concurrence of the head of the department involved or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (in the case of the Central Intelligence Agency). The authority to provide such concurrence may only be delegated by the head of the department involved or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (in the case of the Central Intelligence Agency) to the deputy of such officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c739-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Funds transferred or reprogrammed under this subsection shall remain available for the same period as the appropriations account to which transferred or reprogrammed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c73a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Any transfer or reprogramming of funds under this subsection shall be carried out in accordance with existing procedures applicable to reprogramming notifications for the appropriate congressional committees. Any proposed transfer or reprogramming for which notice is given to the appropriate congressional committees shall be accompanied by a report explaining the nature of the proposed transfer or reprogramming and how it satisfies the requirements of this subsection. In addition, the congressional intelligence committees shall be promptly notified of any transfer or reprogramming of funds made pursuant to this subsection in any case in which the transfer or reprogramming would not have otherwise required reprogramming notification under procedures in effect as of <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c73b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Tasking and other authorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c73c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c73d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c73e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> establish objectives, priorities, and guidance for the intelligence community to ensure timely and effective collection, processing, analysis, and dissemination (including access by users to collected data consistent with applicable law and, as appropriate, the guidelines referred to in subsection (b) and analytic products generated by or within the intelligence community) of national intelligence;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c73f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> determine requirements and priorities for, and manage and direct the tasking of, collection, analysis, production, and dissemination of national intelligence by elements of the intelligence community, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c740-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> approving requirements (including those requirements responding to needs provided by consumers) for collection and analysis; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c741-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> resolving conflicts in collection requirements and in the tasking of national collection assets of the elements of the intelligence community; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c742-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> provide advisory tasking to intelligence elements of those agencies and departments not within the National Intelligence Program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c743-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The authority of the Director of National Intelligence under subparagraph (A) shall not apply—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c744-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> insofar as the President so directs;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c745-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to clause (ii) of subparagraph (A), insofar as the Secretary of Defense exercises tasking authority under plans or arrangements agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c746-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to the direct dissemination of information to State government and local government officials and private sector entities pursuant to sections 121 and 482 of title 6.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c747-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall oversee the National Counterterrorism Center, the National Counterproliferation Center, and the National Counterintelligence and Security Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c748-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c749-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence shall prescribe, in consultation with the heads of other agencies or elements of the intelligence community, and the heads of their respective departments, binding personnel policies and programs applicable to the intelligence community that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c74a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> require and facilitate assignments and details of personnel to national intelligence centers, and between elements of the intelligence community over the course of the careers of such personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c74b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> set standards for education, training, and career development of personnel of the intelligence community;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c74c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> encourage and facilitate the recruitment and retention by the intelligence community of highly qualified individuals for the effective conduct of intelligence activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c74d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> ensure that the personnel of the intelligence community are sufficiently diverse for purposes of the collection and analysis of intelligence through the recruitment and training of women, minorities, and individuals with diverse ethnic, cultural, and linguistic backgrounds;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c74e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> require service in more than one element of the intelligence community as a condition of promotion to such positions within the intelligence community as the Director shall specify, and take requisite steps to ensure compliance among elements of the intelligence community; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c74f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> ensure the effective management of intelligence community personnel who are responsible for intelligence community-wide matters.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c750-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Policies prescribed under subparagraph (A) shall not be inconsistent with the personnel policies otherwise applicable to members of the uniformed services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c751-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall ensure compliance with the Constitution and laws of the United States by the Central Intelligence Agency and shall ensure such compliance by other elements of the intelligence community through the host executive departments that manage the programs and activities that are part of the National Intelligence Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c752-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall ensure the elimination of waste and unnecessary duplication within the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c753-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall establish requirements and priorities for foreign intelligence information to be collected under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.), and provide assistance to the Attorney General to ensure that information derived from electronic surveillance or physical searches under that Act is disseminated so it may be used efficiently and effectively for national intelligence purposes, except that the Director shall have no authority to direct or undertake electronic surveillance or physical search operations pursuant to that Act unless authorized by statute or Executive order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c754-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c755-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall, if the Director determines it is necessary, or may, if requested by a congressional intelligence committee, conduct an accountability review of an element of the intelligence community or the personnel of such element in relation to a failure or deficiency within the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c756-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall establish guidelines and procedures for conducting an accountability review under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c757-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c758-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/7/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall provide the findings of an accountability review conducted under subparagraph (A) and the Director’s recommendations for corrective or punitive action, if any, to the head of the applicable element of the intelligence community. Such recommendations may include a recommendation for dismissal of personnel.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c759-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/7/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If the head of such element does not implement a recommendation made by the Director under clause (i), the head of such element shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a notice of the determination not to implement the recommendation, including the reasons for the determination.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c75a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The requirements of this paragraph shall not be construed to limit any authority of the Director of National Intelligence under subsection (<i>l</i>) or with respect to supervision of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c75b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c75c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conduct assessments and audits of the compliance of each element of the intelligence community with minimum insider threat policy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c75d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> receive information from each element of the intelligence community regarding the collection, sharing, and use by such element of audit and monitoring data for insider threat detection across all classified and unclassified information technology systems within such element;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c75e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide guidance and oversight to Federal departments and agencies to fully implement automated records checks, consistent with personnel vetting reforms and the Trusted Workforce 2.0 initiative, or successor initiative, and ensure that information collected pursuant to such records checks is appropriately shared in support of intelligence community-wide insider threat initiatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c75f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> carry out evaluations of the effectiveness of counterintelligence, security, and insider threat program activities of each element of the intelligence community, including with respect to the lowest organizational unit of each such element, that include an identification of any gaps, shortfalls, or resource needs of each such element;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c760-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> identify gaps, shortfalls, resources needs, and recommendations for adjustments in allocations and additional resources and other remedies to strengthen counterintelligence, security, and insider threat detection programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c761-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> pursuant to final damage assessments facilitated by the National Counterintelligence and Security Center that have been undertaken as a result of an unauthorized disclosure, determine whether the heads of the elements of the intelligence community implement recommended mitigation, and notify the congressional intelligence committees of such determinations and notify the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives in cases involving elements of the intelligence community within the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c762-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/8/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> study the data collected during the course of background investigations and adjudications for security clearances granted to individuals who subsequently commit unauthorized disclosures, and issue findings regarding the quality of such data as a predictor for insider threat activity, delineated by the severity of the unauthorized disclosure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c763-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall ensure there is established a policy for minimum insider threat standards for the intelligence community and ensure compliance by the elements of the intelligence community with that policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c764-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall perform such other intelligence-related functions as the President may direct, and upon receiving any such direction, the Director shall notify the congressional intelligence committees immediately in writing with a description of such other intelligence-related functions directed by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c765-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/e/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as affecting the role of the Department of Justice or the Attorney General under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c766-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Intelligence information sharing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c767-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence shall have principal authority to ensure maximum availability of and access to intelligence information within the intelligence community consistent with national security requirements. The Director of National Intelligence shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c768-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> establish uniform security standards and procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c769-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> establish common information technology standards, protocols, and interfaces;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c76a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> ensure development of information technology systems that include multi-level security and intelligence integration capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c76b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> establish policies and procedures to resolve conflicts between the need to share intelligence information and the need to protect intelligence sources and methods;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c76c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> develop an enterprise architecture for the intelligence community and ensure that elements of the intelligence community comply with such architecture;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c76d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> have procurement approval authority over all enterprise architecture-related information technology items funded in the National Intelligence Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c76e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> in accordance with Executive Order No. 13526 (75 Fed. Reg. 707; relating to classified national security information) (or any subsequent corresponding executive order), and part 2001 of title 32, Code of Federal Regulations (or any subsequent corresponding regulation), establish—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c76f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> guidance to standardize, in appropriate cases, the formats for classified and unclassified intelligence products created by elements of the intelligence community for purposes of promoting the sharing of intelligence products; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c770-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/1/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> policies and procedures requiring the increased use, in appropriate cases, and including portion markings, of the classification of portions of information within one intelligence product.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c771-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The President shall ensure that the Director of National Intelligence has all necessary support and authorities to fully and effectively implement paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c772-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Except as otherwise directed by the President or with the specific written agreement of the head of the department or agency in question, a Federal agency or official shall not be considered to have met any obligation to provide any information, report, assessment, or other material (including unevaluated intelligence information) to that department or agency solely by virtue of having provided that information, report, assessment, or other material to the Director of National Intelligence or the National Counterterrorism Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c773-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall, in a timely manner, report to Congress any statute, regulation, policy, or practice that the Director believes impedes the ability of the Director to fully and effectively ensure maximum availability of access to intelligence information within the intelligence community consistent with the protection of the national security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c774-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Analysis</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To ensure the most accurate analysis of intelligence is derived from all sources to support national security needs, the Director of National Intelligence shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c775-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> implement policies and procedures—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c776-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to require sound analytic methods and tradecraft, independent of political considerations, throughout the elements of the intelligence community;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c777-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to ensure that analysis is based upon all sources available; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c778-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to ensure that the elements of the intelligence community regularly conduct competitive analysis of analytic products, whether such products are produced by or disseminated to such elements;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c779-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensure that resource allocation for intelligence analysis is appropriately proportional to resource allocation for intelligence collection systems and operations in order to maximize analysis of all collected data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c77a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> ensure that substantial differences in analytic judgment are fully considered, brought to the attention of policymakers, and documented in analytic products; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c77b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> ensure that sufficient relationships are established between intelligence collectors and analysts to facilitate greater understanding of the needs of analysts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c77c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of intelligence sources and methods</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c77d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall protect, and shall establish and enforce policies to protect, intelligence sources and methods from unauthorized disclosure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c77e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Consistent with paragraph (1), in order to maximize the dissemination of intelligence, the Director of National Intelligence shall establish and implement requirements for the intelligence community for the following purposes:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c77f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Classification of information under applicable law, Executive orders, or other Presidential directives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c780-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Access to and dissemination of intelligence, both in final form and in the form when initially gathered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c781-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Preparation of intelligence products in such a way that source information is removed to allow for dissemination at the lowest level of classification possible or in unclassified form to the extent practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c782-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Director may only delegate a duty or authority given the Director under this subsection to the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c783-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c784-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Each head of an element of the intelligence community shall ensure that any congressionally mandated report submitted to Congress by the head, other than such a report submitted solely to the congressional intelligence committees, shall be consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods in accordance with the policies established by the Director under paragraph (1), regardless of whether the provision of law mandating the report explicitly requires such protection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c785-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/h/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to alter any congressional leadership’s or congressional committee’s jurisdiction or access to information from any element of the intelligence community under the rules of either chamber of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c786-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Uniform procedures for classified information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence, subject to the direction of the President, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c787-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish uniform standards and procedures for the grant of access to sensitive compartmented information to any officer or employee of any agency or department of the United States and to employees of contractors of those agencies or departments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c788-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensure the consistent implementation of those standards and procedures throughout such agencies and departments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c789-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> ensure that security clearances granted by individual elements of the intelligence community are recognized by all elements of the intelligence community, and under contracts entered into by those agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c78a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> ensure that the process for investigation and adjudication of an application for access to sensitive compartmented information is performed in the most expeditious manner possible consistent with applicable standards for national security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c78b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> ensure that the background of each employee or officer of an element of the intelligence community, each contractor to an element of the intelligence community, and each individual employee of such a contractor who has been determined to be eligible for access to classified information is monitored on a continual basis under standards developed by the Director, including with respect to the frequency of evaluation, during the period of eligibility of such employee or officer of an element of the intelligence community, such contractor, or such individual employee to such a contractor to determine whether such employee or officer of an element of the intelligence community, such contractor, and such individual employee of such a contractor continues to meet the requirements for eligibility for access to classified information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c78c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/i/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> develop procedures to require information sharing between elements of the intelligence community concerning potentially derogatory security information regarding an employee or officer of an element of the intelligence community, a contractor to an element of the intelligence community, or an individual employee of such a contractor that may impact the eligibility of such employee or officer of an element of the intelligence community, such contractor, or such individual employee of such a contractor for a security clearance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c78d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with foreign governments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under the direction of the President and in a manner consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3927">section 3927 of title 22</ref>, the Director of National Intelligence shall oversee the coordination of the relationships between elements of the intelligence community and the intelligence or security services of foreign governments or international organizations on all matters involving intelligence related to the national security or involving intelligence acquired through clandestine means.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c78e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Enhanced personnel management</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c78f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c790-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence shall, under regulations prescribed by the Director, provide incentives for personnel of elements of the intelligence community to serve—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c791-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> on the staff of the Director of National Intelligence;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c792-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> on the staff of the national intelligence centers;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c793-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> on the staff of the National Counterterrorism Center; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c794-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> in other positions in support of the intelligence community management functions of the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c795-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Incentives under subparagraph (A) may include financial incentives, bonuses, and such other awards and incentives as the Director considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c796-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c797-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the personnel of an element of the intelligence community who are assigned or detailed under paragraph (1)(A) to service under the Director of National Intelligence shall be promoted at rates equivalent to or better than personnel of such element who are not so assigned or detailed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c798-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Director may prescribe regulations to carry out this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c799-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c79a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall prescribe mechanisms to facilitate the rotation of personnel of the intelligence community through various elements of the intelligence community in the course of their careers in order to facilitate the widest possible understanding by such personnel of the variety of intelligence requirements, methods, users, and capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c79b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The mechanisms prescribed under subparagraph (A) may include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c79c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The establishment of special occupational categories involving service, over the course of a career, in more than one element of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c79d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The provision of rewards for service in positions undertaking analysis and planning of operations involving two or more elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c79e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The establishment of requirements for education, training, service, and evaluation for service involving more than one element of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c79f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> It is the sense of Congress that the mechanisms prescribed under this subsection should, to the extent practical, seek to duplicate for civilian personnel within the intelligence community the joint officer management policies established by chapter 38 of title 10 and the other amendments made by title IV of the Goldwater-Nichols Department of Defense Reorganization Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/pl/99/433">Public Law 99–433</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7a0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> The mechanisms prescribed under subparagraph (A) and any other policies of the Director—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7a1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> may not require an employee of an office of inspector general for an element of the intelligence community, including the Office of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, to rotate to a position in an office or organization of such an element over which such office of inspector general exercises jurisdiction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7a2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall be implemented in a manner that exempts employees of an office of inspector general from a rotation that may impact the independence of such office.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7a3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7a4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and subparagraph (D), this subsection shall not apply with respect to personnel of the elements of the intelligence community who are members of the uniformed services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7a5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Mechanisms that establish requirements for education and training pursuant to paragraph (3)(B)(iii) may apply with respect to members of the uniformed services who are assigned to an element of the intelligence community funded through the National Intelligence Program, but such mechanisms shall not be inconsistent with personnel policies and education and training requirements otherwise applicable to members of the uniformed services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7a6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The personnel policies and programs developed and implemented under this subsection with respect to law enforcement officers (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5541/3">section 5541(3) of title 5</ref>) shall not affect the ability of law enforcement entities to conduct operations or, through the applicable chain of command, to control the activities of such law enforcement officers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7a7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/k/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Assignment to the Office of the Director of National Intelligence of commissioned officers of the Armed Forces shall be considered a joint-duty assignment for purposes of the joint officer management policies prescribed by chapter 38 of title 10 and other provisions of that title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c7a8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional authority with respect to personnel</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7a9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In addition to the authorities under subsection (f)(3),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002067">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002067"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the Director of National Intelligence may exercise with respect to the personnel of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence any authority of the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency with respect to the personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency under the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3501">50 U.S.C. 3501</ref> et seq.], and other applicable provisions of law, as of <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, to the same extent, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, that the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may exercise such authority with respect to personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency, including with respect to the notification requirement under section 8(c) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c">50 U.S.C. 3510(c)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7aa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Employees and applicants for employment of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence shall have the same rights and protections under the Office of the Director of National Intelligence as employees of the Central Intelligence Agency have under the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3501">50 U.S.C. 3501</ref> et seq.], and other applicable provisions of law, as of <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c7ab-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition and other authorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7ac-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In carrying out the responsibilities and authorities under this section, the Director of National Intelligence may exercise the acquisition and appropriations authorities referred to in the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3501">50 U.S.C. 3501</ref> et seq.] other than the authorities referred to in section 8(b) of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3510/b">50 U.S.C. 3510(b)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7ad-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the purpose of the exercise of any authority referred to in paragraph (1), a reference to the head of an agency shall be deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence or the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7ae-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7af-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any determination or decision to be made under an authority referred to in paragraph (1) by the head of an agency may be made with respect to individual purchases and contracts or with respect to classes of purchases or contracts, and shall be final.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7b0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Director of National Intelligence or the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence may, in such official’s discretion, delegate to any officer or other official of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence any authority to make a determination or decision as the head of the agency under an authority referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7b1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The limitations and conditions set forth in section 3(d) of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3503/d">50 U.S.C. 3503(d)</ref>] shall apply to the exercise by the Director of National Intelligence of an authority referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7b2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Each determination or decision required by an authority referred to in the second sentence of section 3(d) of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3503/d">50 U.S.C. 3503(d)</ref>] shall be based upon written findings made by the official making such determination or decision, which findings shall be final and shall be available within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence for a period of at least six years following the date of such determination or decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7b3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7b4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In addition to the authority referred to in paragraph (1), the Director of National Intelligence may authorize the head of an element of the intelligence community to exercise an acquisition authority referred to in section 3 or 8(a) of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3503">50 U.S.C. 3503</ref>, 3510(a)] for an acquisition by such element that is more than 50 percent funded under the National Intelligence Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7b5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The head of an element of the intelligence community may not exercise an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) until—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7b6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the head of such element (without delegation) submits to the Director of National Intelligence a written request that includes—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7b7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a description of such authority requested to be exercised;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7b8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an explanation of the need for such authority, including an explanation of the reasons that other authorities are insufficient; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7b9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><chapeau> a certification that the mission of such element would be—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd188c7ba-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/i/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> impaired if such authority is not exercised; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd188c7bb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/i/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> significantly and measurably enhanced if such authority is exercised; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7bc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the Director of National Intelligence issues a written authorization that includes—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7bd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a description of the authority referred to in subparagraph (A) that is authorized to be exercised; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7be-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a justification to support the exercise of such authority.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7bf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A request and authorization to exercise an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) may be made with respect to an individual acquisition or with respect to a specific class of acquisitions described in the request and authorization referred to in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> A request from a head of an element of the intelligence community located within one of the departments described in clause (ii) to exercise an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be submitted to the Director of National Intelligence in accordance with any procedures established by the head of such department.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The departments described in this clause are the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the Department of the Treasury.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The head of an element of the intelligence community may not be authorized to utilize an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) for a class of acquisitions for a period of more than 3 years, except that the Director of National Intelligence (without delegation) may authorize the use of such an authority for not more than 6 years.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Each authorization to utilize an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) may be extended in accordance with the requirements of subparagraph (B) for successive periods of not more than 3 years, except that the Director of National Intelligence (without delegation) may authorize an extension period of not more than 6 years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Subject to clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (E), the Director of National Intelligence may only delegate the authority of the Director under subparagraphs (A) through (E) to the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence or a Deputy Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7c7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence shall submit—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7c8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to the congressional intelligence committees a notification of an authorization to exercise an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) or an extension of such authorization that includes the written authorization referred to in subparagraph (B)(ii); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7c9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget a notification of an authorization to exercise an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) for an acquisition or class of acquisitions that will exceed $50,000,000 annually.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7ca-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Requests and authorizations to exercise an authority referred to in subparagraph (A) shall remain available within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence for a period of at least 6 years following the date of such request or authorization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7cb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/4/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to alter or otherwise limit the authority of the Central Intelligence Agency to independently exercise an authority under section 3 or 8(a) of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3503">50 U.S.C. 3503</ref>, 3510(a)].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7cc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Any authority provided to the Director of National Intelligence or the head of an element of the intelligence community pursuant to this subsection to make an expenditure referred to in subsection (a) of section 8 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3510">50 U.S.C. 3510</ref>) is subject to the notification requirement under subsection (c) of such section, including the guidance issued under paragraph (2) of such subsection (c). If the Director of National Intelligence is required to make a notification for a specific expenditure pursuant to both this paragraph and paragraph (4)(G), the Director may make a single notification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7cd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other transaction authority.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7ce-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition to other acquisition authorities, the Director of National Intelligence may exercise the acquisition authorities referred to in sections 4021 and 4022 of title 10, subject to the provisions of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7cf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delegation</inline>.—</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Director shall delegate the authorities provided by subparagraph (A) to the heads of elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The heads of elements of the intelligence community shall, to the maximum extent practicable, delegate the authority delegated under clause (i) to the official of the respective element of the intelligence community responsible for decisions with respect to basic, applied, or advanced research activities or the adoption of such activities within such element.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Intelligence community authority</inline>.—</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the limitation in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4022/a/1">section 4022(a)(1) of title 10</ref> shall not apply to elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Subject to section 4022(a)(2) of such title, the Director may enter into transactions and agreements (other than contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants) of amounts not to exceed $75,000,000 under this paragraph to carry out basic, applied, and advanced research projects and prototype projects in support of intelligence activities.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph, the limitations specified in section 4022(a)(2) of such title shall apply to the intelligence community in lieu of the Department of Defense, and the Director shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7d6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> identify appropriate officials who can make the determinations required in subparagraph (B)(i) of such section for the intelligence community; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7d7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> brief the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives in lieu of the congressional defense committees, as specified in subparagraph (B)(ii) of such section.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the limitation in section 4022(a)(3) of such title shall not apply to elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7d9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> In carrying out this paragraph, section 4022(d)(1) of such title shall be applied by substituting “Director of National Intelligence” for “Secretary of Defense”.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7da-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the limitations in section 4022(d)(2) of such title shall not apply to elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7db-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><chapeau> In addition to the follow-on production contract criteria in section 4022(f)(2) of such title, the following additional criteria shall apply:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7dc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The authorizing official of the relevant element of the intelligence community determines that Government users of the proposed production product or production service have been consulted.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7dd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> In the case of a proposed production product that is software, there are mechanisms in place for Government users to provide ongoing feedback to participants to the follow-on production contract.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7de-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> In the case of a proposed production product that is software, there are mechanisms in place to promote the interoperability and accessibility with and between Government and commercial software providers, including by the promotion of open application programming interfaces and requirement of appropriate software documentation.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7df-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> The award follows a documented market analysis as mandated by the Federal Acquisition Regulations surveying available and comparable products.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7e0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><chapeau> In the case of a proposed production product that is software, the follow-on production contract includes a requirement that, for the duration of such contract (or such other period of time as may be agreed to as a term of such contract)—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd188c7e1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/V/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the participants provide the most up-to-date version of the product that is available in the commercial marketplace and is consistent with security requirements;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd188c7e2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/V/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> there are mechanisms in place for the participants to provide timely updates to the production product; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd188c7e3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/C/vii/V/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> the authority specified in section 4022(f)(5) of such title shall be exercised by the Director in lieu of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7e4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director, in consultation with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community, shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7e5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, establish and implement an intelligence community-wide policy prescribing the use and limitations of the authority under this paragraph, particularly with respect to the application of subparagraphs (B) and (C);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7e6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> periodically review and update the policy established under clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7e7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives the policy when established under clause (i) or updated under clause (ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7e8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual report.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7e9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not less frequently than annually, the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report detailing the use by the intelligence community of the authority provided by this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd188c7ea-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements.—</inline></heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd188c7eb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report required by clause (i) shall detail the following:</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idd188c7ec-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The number of transactions.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idd188c7ed-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> The participants to such transactions.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idd188c7ee-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/I/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> The purpose of the transaction.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idd188c7ef-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/I/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><content> The amount of each transaction.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idd188c7f0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/I/ee"><num value="ee">(ee)</num><content> Concerns with the efficiency of the policy.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idd188c7f1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/I/ff"><num value="ff">(ff)</num><content> Any recommendations for how to improve the process.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd188c7f2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m/6/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other elements</inline>.—</heading><content>Each report required by clause (i) may describe such transactions which have been awarded follow-on production contracts either pursuant to the authority provided by this paragraph or another acquisition authority available to the intelligence community.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c7f3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of views of elements of intelligence community</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the duties and responsibilities under this section, the Director of National Intelligence shall take into account the views of a head of a department containing an element of the intelligence community and of the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c7f4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain Responsibilities of Director of National Intelligence Relating to National Intelligence Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7f5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/o/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to the direction of the President, the Director of National Intelligence shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Defense, ensure that the National Intelligence Program budgets for the elements of the intelligence community that are within the Department of Defense are adequate to satisfy the national intelligence needs of the Department of Defense, including the needs of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the commanders of the unified and specified commands, and wherever such elements are performing Government-wide functions, the needs of other Federal departments and agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7f6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/o/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Consistent with subsection (c)(5)(C), the Director of National Intelligence shall, after consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, ensure that the programs and activities of the Federal Bureau of Investigation that are part of the National Intelligence Program are executed in a manner that conforms with the requirements of the national intelligence strategy under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3043a">section 3043a of this title</ref> and the National Intelligence Priorities Framework of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (or any successor mechanism established for the prioritization of such programs and activities).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7f7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/o/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not later than March 1 of each year, the President, acting through the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a copy of the most recently updated National Intelligence Priorities Framework of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (or any such successor mechanism).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd188c7f8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p"><num value="p" class="bold">(p)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisitions of major systems</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd188c7f9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> For each intelligence program within the National Intelligence Program for the acquisition of a major system, the Director of National Intelligence shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd188c7fa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> require the development and implementation of a program management plan that includes cost, schedule, security risks, and performance goals and program milestone criteria, except that with respect to Department of Defense programs the Director shall consult with the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b37fb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> serve as exclusive milestone decision authority, except that with respect to Department of Defense programs the Director shall serve as milestone decision authority jointly with the Secretary of Defense or the designee of the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b37fc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> periodically—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd18b37fd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> review and assess the progress made toward the achievement of the goals and milestones established in such plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd18b37fe-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> submit to Congress a report on the results of such review and assessment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b37ff-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Director of National Intelligence and the Secretary of Defense are unable to reach an agreement on a milestone decision under paragraph (1)(B), the President shall resolve the conflict.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3800-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the authority of the Director of National Intelligence to delegate to any other official any authority to perform the responsibilities of the Director under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3801-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3802-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The term “intelligence program”, with respect to the acquisition of a major system, means a program that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd18b3803-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is carried out to acquire such major system for an element of the intelligence community; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd18b3804-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is funded in whole out of amounts available for the National Intelligence Program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3805-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/p/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “major system” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s109">section 109 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b3806-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/q"><num value="q" class="bold">(q)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance of common services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence shall, in consultation with the heads of departments and agencies of the United States Government containing elements within the intelligence community and with the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, coordinate the performance by the elements of the intelligence community within the National Intelligence Program of such services as are of common concern to the intelligence community, which services the Director of National Intelligence determines can be more efficiently accomplished in a consolidated manner.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b3807-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r"><num value="r" class="bold">(r)</num><heading class="bold"> Pay authority for critical positions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3808-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any pay limitation established under any other provision of law applicable to employees in elements of the intelligence community, the Director of National Intelligence may, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, grant authority to the head of a department or agency to fix the rate of basic pay for one or more positions within the intelligence community at a rate in excess of any applicable limitation, subject to the provisions of this subsection. The exercise of authority so granted is at the discretion of the head of the department or agency employing the individual in a position covered by such authority, subject to the provisions of this subsection and any conditions established by the Director of National Intelligence when granting such authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3809-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Authority under this subsection may be granted or exercised only—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b380a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with respect to a position that requires an extremely high level of expertise and is critical to successful accomplishment of an important mission; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b380b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to the extent necessary to recruit or retain an individual exceptionally well qualified for the position.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b380c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The head of a department or agency may not fix a rate of basic pay under this subsection at a rate greater than the rate payable for level II of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of title 5</ref>, except upon written approval of the Director of National Intelligence or as otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b380d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The head of a department or agency may not fix a rate of basic pay under this subsection at a rate greater than the rate payable for level I of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5312">section 5312 of title 5</ref>, except upon written approval of the President in response to a request by the Director of National Intelligence or as otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b380e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Any grant of authority under this subsection for a position shall terminate at the discretion of the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b380f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3810-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall notify the congressional intelligence committees not later than 30 days after the date on which the Director grants authority to the head of a department or agency under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3811-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/r/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The head of a department or agency to which the Director of National Intelligence grants authority under this subsection shall notify the congressional intelligence committees and the Director of the exercise of such authority not later than 30 days after the date on which such head exercises such authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b3812-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/s"><num value="s" class="bold">(s)</num><heading class="bold"> Award of rank to members of the Senior National Intelligence Service</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3813-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/s/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President, based on the recommendation of the Director of National Intelligence, may award a rank to a member of the Senior National Intelligence Service or other intelligence community senior civilian officer not already covered by such a rank award program in the same manner in which a career appointee of an agency may be awarded a rank under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s4507">section 4507 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3814-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/s/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The President may establish procedures to award a rank under paragraph (1) to a member of the Senior National Intelligence Service or a senior civilian officer of the intelligence community whose identity as such a member or officer is classified information (as defined in section 3126(1) <sup>1</sup> of this title).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b3815-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/t"><num value="t" class="bold">(t)</num><heading class="bold"> Conflict of interest regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, shall issue regulations prohibiting an officer or employee of an element of the intelligence community from engaging in outside employment if such employment creates a conflict of interest or appearance thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b3816-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u"><num value="u" class="bold">(u)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to establish positions in excepted service</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3817-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence, with the concurrence of the head of the covered department concerned and in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3818-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> convert competitive service positions, and the incumbents of such positions, within an element of the intelligence community in such department, to excepted service positions as the Director of National Intelligence determines necessary to carry out the intelligence functions of such element; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3819-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> establish new positions in the excepted service within an element of the intelligence community in such department, if the Director of National Intelligence determines such positions are necessary to carry out the intelligence functions of such element.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b381a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An incumbent occupying a position on <date date="2012-01-03">January 3, 2012</date>, selected to be converted to the excepted service under this section shall have the right to refuse such conversion. Once such individual no longer occupies the position, the position may be converted to the excepted service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b381b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A covered department may appoint an individual to a position converted or established pursuant to this subsection without regard to the civil-service laws, including parts II and III of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b381c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “covered department” means the Department of Energy, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of State, or the Department of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b381d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Nuclear Proliferation Assessment Statements intelligence community addendum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the heads of the appropriate elements of the intelligence community and the Secretary of State, shall provide to the President, the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate an addendum to each Nuclear Proliferation Assessment Statement accompanying a civilian nuclear cooperation agreement, containing a comprehensive analysis of the country’s export control system with respect to nuclear-related matters, including interactions with other countries of proliferation concern and the actual or suspected nuclear, dual-use, or missile-related transfers to such countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b381e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/w"><num value="w" class="bold">(w)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for intelligence community contractors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b381f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/w/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> ensure that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd18b3820-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/w/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any contractor to an element of the intelligence community with access to a classified network or classified information develops and operates a security plan that is consistent with standards established by the Director of National Intelligence for intelligence community networks; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd18b3821-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/w/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> each contract awarded by an element of the intelligence community includes provisions requiring the contractor comply with such plan and such standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3822-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/w/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> conduct periodic assessments of each security plan required under paragraph (1)(A) to ensure such security plan complies with the requirements of such paragraph; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3823-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/w/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> ensure that the insider threat detection capabilities and insider threat policies of the intelligence community, including the policy under subsection (e)(8), apply to facilities of contractors with access to a classified network.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b3824-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/x"><num value="x" class="bold">(x)</num><heading class="bold"> Fundraising</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3825-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/x/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Director of National Intelligence may engage in fundraising in an official capacity for the benefit of nonprofit organizations that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3826-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/x/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide support to surviving family members of a deceased employee of an element of the intelligence community; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3827-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/x/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> otherwise provide support for the welfare, education, or recreation of employees of an element of the intelligence community, former employees of an element of the intelligence community, or family members of such employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3828-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/x/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “fundraising” means the raising of funds through the active participation in the promotion, production, or presentation of an event designed to raise funds and does not include the direct solicitation of money by any other means.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3829-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/x/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not later than 7 days after the date the Director engages in fundraising authorized by this subsection or at the time the decision is made to participate in such fundraising, the Director shall notify the congressional intelligence committees of such fundraising.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b382a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/x/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, shall issue regulations to carry out the authority provided in this subsection. Such regulations shall ensure that such authority is exercised in a manner that is consistent with all relevant ethical constraints and principles, including the avoidance of any prohibited conflict of interest or appearance of impropriety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd18b382b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y"><num value="y" class="bold">(y)</num><heading class="bold"> Analyses and impact statements regarding proposed investment into the United States</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b382c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 20 days after the completion of a review or an investigation of any proposed investment into the United States for which the Director has prepared analytic materials, the Director shall submit to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representative copies of such analytic materials, including any supplements or amendments to such analysis made by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b382d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Not later than 60 days after the completion of consideration by the United States Government of any investment described in paragraph (1), the Director shall determine whether such investment will have an operational impact on the intelligence community, and, if so, shall submit a report on such impact to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives. Each such report shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b382e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> describe the operational impact of the investment on the intelligence community, including with respect to counterintelligence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b382f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> describe any actions that have been or will be taken to mitigate such impact.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd18b3830-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3831-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “a review or an investigation of any proposed investment into the United States for which the Director has prepared analytic materials” includes a review, investigation, assessment, or analysis conducted by the Director pursuant to section 7 or 10(g) of Executive Order 13913 (85 Fed. Reg. 19643; relating to Establishing the Committee for the Assessment of Foreign Participation in the United States Telecommunications Services Sector), or successor order.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd18b3832-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3024/y/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “investment” includes any activity reviewed, investigated, assessed, or analyzed by the Director pursuant to section 7 or 10(g) of Executive Order 13913, or successor order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd18b3833-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title I, § 102A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1011/a">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1011(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3644">118 Stat. 3644</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/258/s5/a">Pub. L. 111–258, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2650">124 Stat. 2650</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tIII">Pub. L. 111–259, title III</ref>, §§ 303, 304, 306, 307, 326, title IV, §§ 401, 402(a), title VIII, § 804(2), <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2658">124 Stat. 2658</ref>, 2659, 2661, 2662, 2683, 2708, 2747; <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/tIII">Pub. L. 112–87, title III</ref>, §§ 304, 305, 311(d), <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1880">125 Stat. 1880</ref>, 1881, 1886; <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tIII/s329/b/2">Pub. L. 113–126, title III, § 329(b)(2)</ref>, title V, §§ 501, 502(a), <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1406">128 Stat. 1406</ref>, 1411, 1412; <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tI/s105/a">Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title I, § 105(a)</ref>, title VII, § 701(c)(1), <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2912">129 Stat. 2912</ref>, 2929; <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dN/tIII">Pub. L. 115–31, div. N, title III</ref>, §§ 303(a), 309(b), title IV, §§ 401(c), 402, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/810">131 Stat. 810</ref>, 815, 818, 820; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLIII/s5305">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LIII, § 5305</ref>, title LXVII, § 6742(b)(1), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2122">133 Stat. 2122</ref>, 2239; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIV">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title IV</ref>, §§ 402, 403, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/975">136 Stat. 975</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXIII/s6314/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXIII, § 6314(a)</ref>, (c), title LXIV, §§ 6401, 6402, 6415(b), title LXVII, § 6711(b), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3511">136 Stat. 3511</ref>, 3524, 3525, 3528, 3563; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tIII">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title III</ref>, §§ 7307(a), 7308, 7309, title IX, § 7901(a)(1), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1026-1028">137 Stat. 1026–1028</ref>, 1106; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dF/tLXIII/s6308">Pub. L. 118–159, div. F, title LXIII, § 6308</ref>, title LXIV, § 6437, title LXIX, § 6902(a)(1), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2477">138 Stat. 2477</ref>, 2492, 2517; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6402/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXIV, § 6402(a)</ref>–(c)(1), title LXV, § 6501(b), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1615">139 Stat. 1615</ref>, 1619.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd18b3834-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd18b3835-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd18b3836-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (c)(6), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/344">Pub. L. 93–344</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/297">88 Stat. 297</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621">section 621 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (e)(6), (11), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/511">Pub. L. 95–511</ref>, <date date="1978-10-25">Oct. 25, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1783">92 Stat. 1783</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 36 (§ 1801 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13526, referred to in subsec. (f)(1)(G), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Goldwater-Nichols Department of Defense Reorganization Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (k)(3)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/99/433">Pub. L. 99–433</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/992">100 Stat. 992</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1986 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">section 111 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (f)(3), referred to in subsec. (<i>l</i>), was redesignated as subsec. (e)(3) of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6402/c/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXIV, § 6402(c)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1615">139 Stat. 1615</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, referred to in subsecs. (<i>l</i>) and (m)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-06-20/ch227">act June 20, 1949, ch. 227</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/208">63 Stat. 208</ref>, which was formerly classified generally to section 403a et seq. of this title prior to editorial reclassification in this title and is now classified generally to chapter 46 (§ 3501 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3126/1">Section 3126(1) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (s)(2), was in the original “section 606(1)”, meaning section 606(1) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, which was translated as reading “section 605(1)”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the renumbering of section 606 as 605 by <ref href="/us/pl/112/277/s310/a/4/B">section 310(a)(4)(B) of Pub. L. 112–277</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 13913, referred to in subsec. (y)(3), is Ex. Ord. No. 13913, <date date="2020-04-04">Apr. 4, 2020</date>, 85 F.R. 19643, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s154">section 154 of Title 47</ref>, Telecommunications.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd18b3837-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403–1">section 403–1 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (p)(4)(B), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s109">section 109 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 4(9) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s403/9">41 U.S.C. 403(9)</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idd18b3838-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 102A of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tI">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title I</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/293/tVIII/s805/b">Pub. L. 104–293, title VIII, § 805(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3479">110 Stat. 3479</ref>, provided there is a Central Intelligence Agency and described its function prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI">Pub. L. 108–458, title I</ref>, §§ 1011(a), 1097(a), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3643">118 Stat. 3643</ref>, 3698, effective not later than six months after <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided. See <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3035">section 3035 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 102a of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tI">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title I</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/215/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 98–215, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1983-12-09">Dec. 9, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1477">97 Stat. 1477</ref>, related to appointment of Director of the Intelligence Community Staff prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/tVII/s705/a/1">Pub. L. 102–496, title VII, § 705(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3190">106 Stat. 3190</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd18b3839-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/a">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(a)</ref>, struck out subpar. (B) designation and subpar. (A) which read as follows: “The Director of National Intelligence shall provide a semi-annual report, beginning <date date="2005-04-01">April 1, 2005</date>, and ending <date date="2007-04-01">April 1, 2007</date>, to the President and the Congress regarding implementation of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/b/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(1)(A), redesignated subsec. (f) as (e) and struck out former subsec. (e) which related to transfer of personnel.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(7)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/c/1/B">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(c)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “under subsection (<i>l</i>)” for “under subsection (m)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/c/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(c)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/b/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “and may establish such other national intelligence centers as the Director determines necessary” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (m). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/c/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(c)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (h) to (n) as (g) to (m), respectively. Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6501/b">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6501(b)</ref>, substituted “of such section, including the guidance issued under paragraph (2) of such subsection (c)” for “of such section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (n) to (w). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/c/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(c)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (<i>o</i>) to (x) as (n) to (w), respectively. Former subsec. (n) redesignated (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (w)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/c/1/C">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(c)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “under subsection (e)(8)” for “under subsection (f)(8)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (x) to (z). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6402/c/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6402(c)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (y) and (z) as (x) and (y), respectively. Former subsec. (x) redesignated (w).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (f)(8)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6902/a/1">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6902(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “within” for “withing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6308">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6308</ref>, inserted “, and upon receiving any such direction, the Director shall notify the congressional intelligence committees immediately in writing with a description of such other intelligence-related functions directed by the President” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (z)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6437/1">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6437(1)</ref>, inserted “, including with respect to counterintelligence” after “the intelligence community”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (z)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6437/2">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6437(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (f)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7307/a/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7307(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “binding personnel policies” for “personnel policies” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7307/a/2">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7307(a)(2)</ref>, amended cl. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (i) read as follows: “encourage and facilitate assignments and details of personnel to national intelligence centers, and between elements of the intelligence community;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3)(A)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7307/a/3">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7307(a)(3)</ref>, amended cl. (v) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (v) read as follows: “make service in more than one element of the intelligence community a condition of promotion to such positions within the intelligence community as the Director shall specify; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(8) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7308">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7308</ref>, added par. (8) and redesignated former pars. (8) to (10) as (9) to (11), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7901/a/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7901(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated second par. (5), relating to other transaction authority, as (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7309">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7309</ref>, substituted “March 1” for “October 1”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6401/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6401(1)</ref>, substituted “shall include” for “may include”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s403/1">Pub. L. 117–103, § 403(1)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6314/a/2">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6314(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (8). Former par. (8) redesignated (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s402">Pub. L. 117–103, § 402</ref>, substituted “such other intelligence-related functions” for “such other functions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(9), (10). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6314/a/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6314(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated pars. (8) and (9) as (9) and (10), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6401/2/A">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6401(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “require” for “encourage” and inserted “, independent of political considerations,” after “tradecraft”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6401/2/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6401(2)(B)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “ensure that differences in analytic judgment are fully considered and brought to the attention of policymakers; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6401/3/A">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6401(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “, and shall establish and enforce policies to protect,” after “protect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6401/3/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6401(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “requirements” for “guidelines” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6401/3/C">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6401(3)(C)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6415/b/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6415(b)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “, including with respect to the notification requirement under section 8(c) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c">50 U.S.C. 3510(c)</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6711/b">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6711(b)</ref>, added par. (5) relating to other transaction authority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6415/b/2">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6415(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (5) relating to notification requirement for expenditure made by Director of National Intelligence or head of element of intelligence community.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s403/2">Pub. L. 117–103, § 403(2)</ref>, substituted “Certain Responsibilities of Director of National Intelligence Relating to National Intelligence Program” for “Responsibility of Director of National Intelligence regarding National Intelligence Program budget concerning the Department of Defense” in heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6402">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6402</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (x). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6401/4">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6401(4)</ref>, substituted “the heads of the elements of the intelligence community” for “the head of each department of the Federal Government that contains an element of the intelligence community and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (x)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6314/c">Pub. L. 117–263, § 6314(c)</ref>, inserted “, including the policy under subsection (f)(8),” after “policies of the intelligence community”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (g)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s6742/b/1/A">Pub. L. 116–92, § 6742(b)(1)(A)</ref>, realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s5305">Pub. L. 116–92, § 5305</ref>, inserted “security risks,” after “schedule,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (v)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s6742/b/1/B">Pub. L. 116–92, § 6742(b)(1)(B)</ref>, realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/s401/c">Pub. L. 115–31, § 401(c)</ref>, inserted “, the National Counterproliferation Center, and the National Counterintelligence and Security Center” after “National Counterterrorism Center”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/s309/b">Pub. L. 115–31, § 309(b)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (y). <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/s303/a">Pub. L. 115–31, § 303(a)</ref>, added subsec. (y).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (z). <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/s402">Pub. L. 115–31, § 402</ref>, added subsec. (z).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (u). <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/s701/c/1">Pub. L. 114–113, § 701(c)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (1) designation before “The Director of National Intelligence” and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “The Director of National Intelligence shall annually submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report describing all outside employment for officers and employees of elements of the intelligence community that was authorized by the head of an element of the intelligence community during the preceding calendar year. Such report shall be submitted each year on the date provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3106">section 3106 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (v)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/s105/a">Pub. L. 114–113, § 105(a)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (g)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s329/b/2">Pub. L. 113–126, § 329(b)(2)</ref>, amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows: “Not later than February 1 of each year, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the President and to the Congress an annual report that identifies any statute, regulation, policy, or practice that the Director believes impedes the ability of the Director to fully and effectively implement paragraph (1).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s501/1">Pub. L. 113–126, § 501(1)</ref>, substituted “classified information” for “sensitive compartmented information” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s501/2">Pub. L. 113–126, § 501(2)</ref>–(4), added pars. (5) and (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (x). <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s502/a">Pub. L. 113–126, § 502(a)</ref>, added subsec. (x).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (e)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/s311/d">Pub. L. 112–87, § 311(d)</ref>, substituted “For each of the fiscal years 2010, 2011, and 2012, the” for “The” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (v). <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/s304">Pub. L. 112–87, § 304</ref>, added subsec. (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (w). <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/s305">Pub. L. 112–87, § 305</ref>, added subsec. (w).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s804/2/A">Pub. L. 111–259, § 804(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “annual budget for the Military Intelligence Program or any successor program or programs” for “annual budgets for the Joint Military Intelligence Program and for Tactical Intelligence and Related Activities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s804/2/B/i">Pub. L. 111–259, § 804(2)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “Military Intelligence Program or any successor program or programs” for “Joint Military Intelligence Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s402/a">Pub. L. 111–259, § 402(a)</ref>, substituted “Program—” for “Program to another such program.” and added subpars. (A) to (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s804/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–259, § 804(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(A)” for “subparagraph (A)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s804/2/B/iii/I">Pub. L. 111–259, § 804(2)(B)(iii)(I)</ref>, struck out “or personnel” after “funds” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s804/2/B/iii/II">Pub. L. 111–259, § 804(2)(B)(iii)(II)</ref>, substituted “delegated by the head of the department involved or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (in the case of the Central Intelligence Agency)” for “delegated by the head of the department or agency involved”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s306">Pub. L. 111–259, § 306</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(7) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s401">Pub. L. 111–259, § 401</ref>, added par. (7) and redesignated former pars. (7) and (8) as (8) and (9), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/111/258">Pub. L. 111–258</ref> added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s804/2/C">Pub. L. 111–259, § 804(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “paragraph” for “section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s804/2/D">Pub. L. 111–259, § 804(2)(D)</ref>, inserted “and other” after “Acquisition” in the heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/s326">Pub. L. 111–259, § 326</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (s) to (u). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Pub. L. 111–259</ref>, §§ 303, 304, 307, added subsecs. (s) to (u).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd18b383a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd18b383b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2912">129 Stat. 2912</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tI/s105/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to an appointment under section 102A(v) [now 102A(u)] of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3024/v">50 U.S.C. 3024(v)</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3024/u">50 U.S.C. 3024(u)</ref>]) made on or after the date of the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/87">Public Law 112–87</ref>) [<date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>] and to any proceeding pending on or filed after the date of the enactment of this section [<date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>] that relates to such an appointment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd18b383c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 113–126, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1412">128 Stat. 1412</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/126/tV/s502/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to contracts entered into or renewed after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd18b383d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For Determination by President that section take effect on <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, see Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 23925, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective not later than six months after <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s1097/a">section 1097(a) of Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out in an Effective Date of 2004 Amendment; Transition Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18b383e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancing Intelligence Community Technology Adoption Metrics</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVI/s6621">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXVI, § 6621</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1641">139 Stat. 1641</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVI/s6621">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Metric Development and Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office, and the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency shall each develop and implement a process (which may be different from the processes of the other elements) that makes use of a single set of metrics to assess, on an agency-wide, aggregate basis, the success of the agency’s efforts regarding the adoption, integration, and operational impact of the most relevant emerging technologies within the respective agencies of those Directors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each agency described in subsection (a) shall provide to the congressional intelligence committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on the implementation of this section, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the metrics established under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the success of the element toward meeting such metrics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any recommendations of the head of such agency for legislative or regulatory reforms to improve technology adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘emerging technology’ has the meaning given such term in section 6701 of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (division F of <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3024">50 U.S.C. 3024</ref> note) [set out below].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6621">section 6621 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18b383f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Policy and Performance Framework for Mobility of Intelligence Community Workforce</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tIII/s7302">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title III, § 7302</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1025">137 Stat. 1025</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tIII/s7302">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management as the Director of National Intelligence considers appropriate, develop and implement a policy and performance framework to ensure the timely and effective mobility of employees and contractors of the Federal Government who are transferring employment between elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy and performance framework required by subsection (a) shall include processes with respect to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Human resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Medical reviews.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Determinations of suitability or eligibility for access to classified information in accordance with Executive Order 13467 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">50 U.S.C. 3161</ref> note; relating to reforming processes related to suitability for Government employment, fitness for contractor employees, and eligibility for access to classified national security information).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “intelligence community” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7302">section 7302 of Pub. L. 118–31</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7002">section 7002 of Pub. L. 118–31</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18b3840-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Intelligence Community Commercial Remote Sensing Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tV/s7509">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title V, § 7509</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1091">137 Stat. 1091</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tV/s7509">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the United States benefits from a robust commercial remote sensing industry that supports a science, technology, engineering, and mathematics academic pipeline, enables skilled manufacturing jobs, and fosters technological innovation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> commercial remote sensing capabilities complement and augment dedicated Government remote sensing capabilities, both when integrated into Government architectures and leveraged as stand-alone services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Director of National Intelligence and Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security should serve as the United States Government leads for commercial remote sensing procurement and seek to accommodate commercial remote sensing needs of the intelligence community, the Department of Defense, and Federal civil organizations under the preview of the cognizant functional managers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> a transparent, sustained investment by the United States Government in commercial remote sensing capabilities—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is required to strengthen the United States commercial remote sensing commercial industry; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> should include electro-optical, synthetic aperture radar, hyperspectral, and radio frequency detection and other innovative phenemonology that may have national security applications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Director of National Intelligence and the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security shall jointly develop guidance requiring the Commercial Strategy Board or, if that is not feasible, such other entities within the intelligence community and the Department of Defense that the Director and the Under Secretary determine appropriate, to perform, on a recurring basis, the following functions related to commercial remote sensing:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Validation of the current and long-term commercial remote sensing capability needs, as determined by the relevant functional managers, of the Department of Defense, the intelligence community, and Federal civil users under the preview of the cognizant functional managers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Development of commercial remote sensing requirements documents that are unclassified and releasable to United States commercial industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Development of a cost estimate that is unclassified and releasable to United States commercial industry, covering at least 5 years, associated with fulfilling the requirements contained in the commercial remote sensing requirements documents referred developed [sic] under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding Levels</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of any fiscal year for which a cost estimate is developed under subsection (b)(3) and for which the budget of the President (as submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, United States Code) requests a level of funding for the procurement of commercial remote sensing requirements that is less than the amount identified in the cost estimate, the President shall include with the budget an explanation for the difference.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence and the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the congressional intelligence committees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7509">section 7509 of Pub. L. 118–31</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7002">section 7002 of Pub. L. 118–31</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18b3841-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improving Onboarding of Personnel in Intelligence Community</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVI/s6601">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVI, § 6601</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3556">136 Stat. 3556</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVI/s6601">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Onboard Period</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘onboard period’ means the period beginning on the date on which an individual submits an application for employment and ending on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the date on which the individual is offered one or more entrance on duty dates; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the date on which the individual enters on duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy Guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall establish policy guidance appropriate for all elements of the intelligence community that can be used to measure, consistently and reliably, the onboard period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on the time it takes to onboard personnel in the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><content>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall cover the mean and median time it takes to onboard personnel in the intelligence community, disaggregated by mode of onboarding and element of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director, in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a plan to reduce the onboard period for personnel in the intelligence community, for elements of the intelligence community that currently have median onboarding times that exceed 180 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><content>The plan submitted under paragraph (1) shall include milestones to achieve certain specific goals with respect to the mean, median, and mode time it takes to onboard personnel in the elements of the intelligence community described in such paragraph, disaggregated by element of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The heads of the elements of the intelligence community, including the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, shall implement the plan submitted under subsection (d) and take all such actions each head considers appropriate and necessary to ensure that by <date date="2023-12-31">December 31, 2023</date>, the median duration of the onboard period for new employees at each element of the intelligence community is equal to less than 180 days.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6601">section 6601 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18b3842-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation Plan and Advisability Study for Offices of Commercial Integration</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6712">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6712</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3565">136 Stat. 3565</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tV/s7513/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title V, § 7513(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1096">137 Stat. 1096</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tV/s7513/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan and Study.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> a plan for the establishment of a centralized office or offices within each appropriate element of the intelligence community, to be known as the ‘Office of Commercial Integration’, for the purpose of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> assisting persons desiring to submit an offer for a contract with the intelligence community; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> assisting with the procurement of commercial products and commercial services; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> the findings of a study conducted by the Director into the advisability of implementing such plan, including an assessment of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> whether there should be a single Office of Commercial Integration for the intelligence community or whether each element of the intelligence community shall establish such an Office;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the costs and benefits of the implementation of such plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> whether there is within any element of the intelligence community an existing office or program similar to the proposed Office of Commercial Integration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The materials submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> A recommendation by the Director, based on the findings of the study under paragraph (1)(B), on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> how the plan under paragraph (1)(A) compares to specific alternative actions of the intelligence community that could be taken to assist persons desiring to submit an offer for a contract with the intelligence community and assist with the procurement of commercial products and commercial services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> whether to implement such plan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A proposal for the designation of a senior official of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence who would be responsible for the coordination across the intelligence community or across the Offices of Commercial Integration, depending on the findings of the study under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Draft guidelines that would require the coordination and sharing of best practices and other information across the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A timeline of the steps that would be necessary to establish each Office of Commercial Integration by the date that is not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><chapeau> An assessment of the personnel requirements, and any other resource requirements, that would be necessary to establish the Office or Offices of Commercial Integration by such date, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the amount of personnel necessary for the establishment of the Office or Offices of Commercial Integration; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the necessary qualifications of any such personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Policies regarding the types of assistance that, if an Office or Offices of Commercial Integration were to be established, could be provided to contractors by the Director of such Office, taking into account the role of such assistance as an incentive for emerging technology companies to enter into contracts with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Eligibility criteria for determining the types of offerors or contractors that would be eligible to receive assistance provided by each Office of Commercial Integration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> Policies regarding outreach efforts that would be required to be conducted by the Office or Offices of Commercial Integration with respect to eligible contractors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> Policies regarding how the intelligence community would coordinate with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to provide proactive counterintelligence risk analysis and assistance to entities in the private sector.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><chapeau> Draft guidelines that would require the Office or Offices of Commercial Integration to appoint and assign personnel with expertise in a range of disciplines necessary for the accelerated integration of commercial technologies into the intelligence community (as determined by the Office or Offices of Commercial Integration), including expertise in the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> Authorizations to operate.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Contracting.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Facility clearances.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> Security clearances.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="K">“(K)</num><content> Such other intelligence community-wide policies as the Director of National Intelligence may prescribe relating to the improvement of commercial integration (and the coordination of such improvements) by and among the elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Website on Commercial Integration.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the head of the relevant elements of the intelligence community (as determined by the Director) and the designated element leads under section 6702(c) [now 6702(e)] [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3334m/e">50 U.S.C. 3334m(e)</ref>], shall establish a publicly accessible website that includes relevant information necessary for offerors or contractors to conduct business with each element of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of certain information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If there is established an Office or Offices of Commercial Integration in accordance with subsection (a), the website under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> information, as appropriate, on the elements under subsection (a)(2) relating to that Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> contact information for the relevant senior officers of the Office or Offices.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6712">section 6712 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “commercial product”, “commercial service”, “emerging technology”, and “authorization to operate” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6712">section 6712 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6701">section 6701 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8233-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Designated Emerging Technology Transition Projects</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6713">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6713</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3568">136 Stat. 3568</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6713">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall carry out a pilot program to more effectively transition promising prototypes or products in a developmental stage to a production stage, through designating eligible projects as ‘Emerging Technology Transition Projects’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall issue guidelines to implement the pilot program under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The guidelines issued pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include the following requirements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Each head of an element of the intelligence community shall submit to the Director of National Intelligence a prioritized list of not more than 10 eligible projects per year to be considered for designation by the Director of National Intelligence as Emerging Technology Transition Projects during the budget formulation process.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Director of National Intelligence shall designate not more than 10 eligible projects per year as Emerging Technology Transition Projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> No eligible project may be designated by the Director of National Intelligence as an Emerging Technology Transition Project unless the head of an element of the intelligence community includes the project in the prioritized list under subparagraph (A) and submits to the Director of National Intelligence, with respect to the project, each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> A justification of why the product was nominated for transition, including a description of the importance of the proposed product to the mission of the intelligence community and the nominating agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> A certification that the project provides new technologies or processes, or new applications of existing technologies, that shall enable more effective alternatives to existing programs, systems, or initiatives of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> A certification that the project provides future cost savings, significantly reduces the time to deliver capabilities to the intelligence community, or significantly improves a capability of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> A certification that funding is not proposed for the project in the budget request of the respective covered element for the fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the project is submitted for consideration.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> A certification in writing by the nominating head that the project meets all applicable criteria and requirements of the respective covered element for transition to production and that the nominating head would fund the project if additional funds were made available for such purpose.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> A description of the means by which the proposed production product shall be incorporated into the activities and long-term budget of the respective covered element following such transition.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vii">“(vii)</num><content> A description of steps taken to ensure that the use of the product shall reflect commercial best practices, as applicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A clear description of the selection of eligible projects, including specific criteria, that shall include, at a minimum, the requirements specified in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> The designation of an official responsible for implementing this section and coordinating with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community with respect to the guidelines issued pursuant to paragraph (1) and overseeing the awards of funds to Emerging Technology Transition Projects with respect to that element.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revocation of designation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The designation of an Emerging Technology Transition Project under subsection (b) may be revoked at any time by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Director of National Intelligence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the relevant head of a covered element of the intelligence community that previously submitted a project under subsection (b), in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Benefits of Designation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusion in multiyear national intelligence program plan</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall include in the relevant multiyear national intelligence program plan submitted to Congress under section 1403 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3301">50 U.S.C. 3301</ref>) the planned expenditures, if any, of each designated project during the period of its designation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusion under separate exhibit</inline>.—</heading><content>The heads of elements of the intelligence community shall ensure that each designated project is included in a separate budget exhibit in the relevant multiyear national intelligence program plan submitted to Congress under such section 1403 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3301">50 U.S.C. 3301</ref>) for the period of the designation of such project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration in programming and budgeting</inline>.—</heading><content>Each designated project shall be taken into consideration by the nominating head in the programming and budgeting phases of the intelligence planning, programming, budgeting, and evaluation process during the period of its designation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports to Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>On an annual basis for each fiscal year during which the pilot program under subsection (a) is carried out, concurrently with the submission of the budget of the President for that fiscal year under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A description of each designated project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A summary of the potential of each designated project, as specified in subsection (b)(2)(C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> For each designated project, a description of the progress made toward delivering on such potential.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A description of any funding proposed for the designated project in the future-years intelligence program, including by program, appropriation account, expenditure center, and project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Such other information on the status of such pilot program as the Director considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final report</inline>.—</heading><content>In the final report submitted under paragraph (1) prior to the date of termination under subsection (e), the Director of National Intelligence shall include a recommendation on whether to extend the pilot program under subsection (a) and the appropriate duration of such extension, if any.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination Date</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority to carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2027-12-31">December 31, 2027</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Covered Element of the Intelligence Community</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘covered element of the intelligence community’ means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The National Security Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The National Reconnaissance Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The Defense Intelligence Agency.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6713">section 6713 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8234-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Harmonization of Authorizations To Operate</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6714">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6714</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3570">136 Stat. 3570</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6714">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Appropriate Committees of Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the congressional intelligence committees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protocol</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of the elements of the intelligence community, shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a single protocol setting forth policies and procedures relating to authorizations to operate for Department of Defense or intelligence community systems held by industry providers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>The protocol under subsection (b) shall be limited to authorizations to operate for Department of Defense and intelligence community systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The protocol under subsection (b) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A policy for reciprocal recognition, as appropriate, among the elements of the intelligence community and the Department of Defense of authorizations to operate held by commercial providers. Such reciprocal recognition shall be limited to authorizations to operate for systems that collect, process, maintain, use, share, disseminate, or dispose of data classified at an equal or lower classification level than the original authorization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Procedures under which, subject to such criteria as may be prescribed by the Director of National Intelligence jointly with the Secretary of Defense, a provider that holds an authorization to operate for a Department of Defense or intelligence community system may provide to the head of an element of the intelligence community or the Department of Defense the most recently updated version of any software, data, or application for use on such system without being required to submit an application for new or renewed authorization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Procedures for the review, renewal, and revocation of authorizations to operate held by commercial providers, including procedures for maintaining continuous authorizations to operate, subject to such conditions as may be prescribed by the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense. Such procedures may encourage greater use of modern security practices already being adopted by the Department of Defense and other Federal agencies, such as continuous authorization with system security focused on continuous monitoring of risk and security controls, active system defense, and the use of an approved mechanism for secure and continuous delivery of software (commonly referred to as ‘DevSecOps’).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> A policy for the harmonization of documentation requirements for commercial providers submitting applications for authorizations to operate, with the goal of a uniform requirement across the Department of Defense and the elements of the intelligence community (subject to exceptions established by the Director and the Secretary). Such policy shall include the following requirements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A requirement for the full disclosure of evidence in the reciprocity process across the Department of Defense and the elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> With respect to a system with an existing authorization to operate, a requirement for approval by the Chief Information Officer or a designated official (as the head of the respective element of the intelligence community determines appropriate) for such system to operate at an equal or higher level classification level, to be granted prior to the performance of an additional security assessment with respect to such system, and regardless of which element of the intelligence community or Department of Defense granted the original authorization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> A requirement to establish a joint secure portal of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence and the Department of Defense for the maintenance of records, applications, and system requirements for authorizations to operate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><chapeau> A plan to examine, and if necessary, address, the shortage of intelligence community and Department of Defense personnel authorized to support and grant an authorization to operate. Such plan shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a report on the current average wait times for authorizations to operate and backlogs, disaggregated by each element of the intelligence community and the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> appropriate recommendations to increase pay or implement other incentives to recruit and retain such personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a plan to leverage independent third-party assessment organizations to support assessments of applications for authorizations to operate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Procedures to ensure data security and safety with respect to the implementation of the protocol.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> A proposed timeline for the implementation of the protocol by the deadline specified in subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordinating Officials</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Director of National Intelligence shall designate an official of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence responsible for implementing this section on behalf of the Director and leading coordination across the intelligence community for such implementation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Secretary of Defense shall designate an official of the Department of Defense responsible for implementing this section on behalf of the Secretary and leading coordination across the Department of Defense for such implementation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> each head of an element of the intelligence community shall designate an official of that element responsible for implementing this section and overseeing implementation of the protocol under subsection (b) with respect to the element.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Documentation Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Under the protocol under subsection (b), no head of a Federal agency may commence the operation of a system using an authorization to operate granted by another Federal agency without possessing documentation of the original authorization to operate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Required</inline>.—</heading><content>The protocol under subsection (b) shall be implemented not later than <date date="2025-01-01">January 1, 2025</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “congressional intelligence committees” and “intelligence community” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6714">section 6714 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “authorization to operate” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6714">section 6714 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6701">section 6701 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8235-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Compliance by Intelligence Community With Requirements of Federal Acquisition Regulation Relating to Commercially Available Off-the-Shelf Items and Commercial Services</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6716">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6716</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3575">136 Stat. 3575</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6716">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance Policy.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall implement a policy to ensure that each element of the intelligence community complies with parts 10 and 12 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation with respect to any Federal Acquisition Regulation-based procurements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> Written criteria for an element of the intelligence community to evaluate when a procurement of a covered item or service is permissible, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> requiring the element to conduct an independent market analysis to determine whether a commercially available off-the-shelf item, nondevelopmental item, or commercial service is viable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a description of the offeror for such covered item or service and how the covered item or service to be acquired will be integrated into existing systems of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> A detailed set of performance measures for the acquisition personnel of the intelligence community that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> prioritizes adherence to parts 10 and 12 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> encourages acquisition of commercially available off-the-shelf items, nondevelopmental items, or commercial services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> incentivizes such personnel of the intelligence community that enter into contracts for covered items or services only when necessary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the policy developed pursuant to paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the plan to implement such policy by not later than 1 year after the date of such enactment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Market analysis</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the independent market analysis pursuant to paragraph (2)(A)(i), the Director may enter into a contract with an independent market research group with qualifications and expertise to find available commercial products or commercial services to meet the needs of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Director, in consultation with the head of each element of the intelligence community, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on the policy developed under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the period covered by the report, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An evaluation of the success of the policy, including with respect to the progress the elements have made in complying with parts 10 and 12 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A description of how any market analyses are conducted pursuant to subsection (a)(2)(A)(i).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Any recommendations to improve compliance with such parts 10 and 12.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6716">section 6716 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “covered item or service”, “commercial product”, and “commercial service” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6716">section 6716 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6701">section 6701 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8236-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Policy on Required User Adoption Metrics in Certain Contracts for Artificial Intelligence and Emerging Technology Software Products</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6717">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6717</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3576">136 Stat. 3576</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6717">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall establish a policy regarding user adoption metrics for contracts and other agreements for the procurement of covered products as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> With respect to a contract or other agreement entered into between the head of an element of the intelligence community and a commercial provider for the procurement of a covered product for users within the intelligence community, a requirement that each such contract or other agreement include, as a term of the contract or agreement, an understanding of the anticipated use of the covered product with a clear metric for success and for collecting user adoption metrics, as appropriate, for assessing the adoption of the covered product by such users.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Such exceptions to the requirements under paragraph (1) as may be determined appropriate pursuant to guidance established by the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A requirement that prior to the procurement of, or the continuation of the use of, any covered product procured by the head of an element of the intelligence community, the head has determined a method for assessing the success of the covered product from user adoption metrics.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the policy under subsection (a) is established, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives such policy.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6717">section 6717 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “artificial intelligence”, “emerging technology”, and “covered product” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6717">section 6717 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6701">section 6701 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8237-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Emerging Technology Education and Training</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6732">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6732</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3583">136 Stat. 3583</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tIX/s7901/b/2">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title IX, § 7901(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1106">137 Stat. 1106</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tIX/s7901/b/2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Training Curriculum.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>No later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence and the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the President of the Defense Acquisition University and the heads of the elements of the intelligence community that the Director and Secretary determine appropriate, shall jointly establish a training curriculum for members of the acquisition workforce in the Department of Defense (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) and the acquisition officials within the intelligence community focused on improving the understanding and awareness of contracting authorities and procedures for the acquisition of emerging technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provision of training</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director shall ensure that the training curriculum under paragraph (1) is made available to each element of the intelligence community not later than 60 days after the completion of the curriculum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2024-01-01">January 1, 2024</date>, the Director and Secretary shall jointly submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Armed Services and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Armed Services and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report containing an update on the status of the curriculum under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreements Officers</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2024-10-01">October 1, 2024</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall ensure that at least 75 percent of the contracting staff within the intelligence community whose primary responsibilities include the acquisition of emerging technologies shall have received the appropriate training to become warranted as agreements officers who are given authority to execute and administer the transactions authorized by paragraph (6) of section 102A(n) [now 102A(m)] of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3024/n">50 U.S.C. 3024(n)</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3024/m">50 U.S.C. 3024(m)</ref>]), as added by section 6711. The training shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the appropriate courses offered by the Defense Acquisition University;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the training curriculum established under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> best practices for monitoring, identifying, and procuring emerging technologies with potential benefit to the intelligence community, including commercial services and products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Emerging Technology Training Activities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2024-01-01">January 1, 2024</date>, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community that the Director determines relevant, shall establish and implement training activities designed for appropriate mid-career and senior managers across the intelligence community to train the managers on how to identify, acquire, implement, and manage emerging technologies as such technologies may be applied to the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Director establishes the training activities under paragraph (1), each head of an element of the intelligence community shall certify to the Director whether the managers of the element described in paragraph (1) have successfully completed the education activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2024-01-01">January 1, 2024</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall provide to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a briefing regarding the training activities established under paragraph (1), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> an overview of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the managers described in paragraph (1) who participated in the training activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> what technologies were included in the training activities; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an identification of other incentives, activities, resources, or programs the Director determines may be necessary to ensure the managers are generally trained in the most emerging technologies and able to retain and incorporate such technologies across the intelligence community.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6732">section 6732 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “emerging technology”, “commercial service”, and “commercial product” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6732">section 6732 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6701">section 6701 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8238-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvements to Use of Commercial Software Products</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6741">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6741</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3584">136 Stat. 3584</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6741">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy Regarding Procurement of Commercial Software Products</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community and appropriate nongovernmental experts that the Director determines relevant, shall issue an intelligence community-wide policy to ensure the procurement of commercial software products by the intelligence community is carried out—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> using, to the extent practicable, standardized terminology; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in accordance with acquisition and operation best practices reflecting modern software as a service capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy issued under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Guidelines for the heads of the elements of the intelligence community to determine which contracts for commercial software products are covered by the policy, including with respect to agreements, authorizations to operate, and other acquisition activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Guidelines for using standardized terms in such contracts, modeled after commercial best practices, including common procedures and language regarding—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> terms for the responsible party and timelines for system integration under the contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a mechanism included in each contract to ensure the ability of the vendor to provide, and the United States Government to receive, continuous updates and version control for the software, subject to appropriate security considerations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> automatic technological mechanisms for security and data validation, including security protocols that are predicated on commercial best practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> procedures to provide incentives, and a technical framework, for system integration for new commercial software solutions to fit within existing workflows and information technology infrastructure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Guidelines and a timeline for enforcing the policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2025-01-01">January 1, 2025</date>, and annually thereafter through 2028, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on the policy issued under subsection (a), including the following with respect to the period covered by the report:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> An evaluation of compliance with such policy by each of the elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Additional recommendations to better coordinate system integration throughout the intelligence community using best practices.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6741">section 6741 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “commercial product” and “authorization to operate” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6741">section 6741 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6701">section 6701 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8239-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Fifth-Generation Technology Prize Competition</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLVII/s5723">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LVII, § 5723</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2177">133 Stat. 2177</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLVII/s5723">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prize Competition</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to section 24 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3719">15 U.S.C. 3719</ref>), the Director of National Intelligence, acting through the Director of the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Agency [probably should be “Activity”], shall carry out a program to award prizes competitively to stimulate research and development relevant to fifth-generation technology.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prize Amount</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Director may award not more than a total of $5,000,000 to one or more winners of the prize competition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Director may consult with the heads of relevant departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fifth-generation Technology Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘fifth-generation technology’ means hardware, software, or other technologies relating to fifth-generation wireless networks (known as ‘5G’).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d823a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Deepfakes Prize Competition</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLVII/s5724">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LVII, § 5724</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2177">133 Stat. 2177</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLVII/s5724">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prize Competition</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to section 24 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3719">15 U.S.C. 3719</ref>), the Director of National Intelligence, acting through the Director of the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Agency [probably should be “Activity”], shall carry out a program to award prizes competitively to stimulate the research, development, or commercialization of technologies to automatically detect machine-manipulated media.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prize Amount</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Director may award not more than a total of $5,000,000 to one or more winners of the prize competition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Director may consult with the heads of relevant departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Machine-Manipulated Media Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘machine-manipulated media’ means video, image, or audio recordings generated or substantially modified using machine-learning techniques in order to falsely depict events, to falsely depict the speech or conduct of an individual, or to depict individuals who do not exist.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d823b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Identification of and Countermeasures Against Certain International Mobile Subscriber Identity-Catchers</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLVII/s5725">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LVII, § 5725</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2178">133 Stat. 2178</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVIII/s6809">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVIII, § 6809</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3599">136 Stat. 3599</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVIII/s6809">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, in collaboration with the Director of National Intelligence, the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Intelligence and Analysis, and the heads of such other Federal, State, or local agencies as the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation determines appropriate, and in accordance with applicable law and policy, may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> undertake an effort to identify International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers operated within the United States by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> hostile foreign governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> individuals who have violated a criminal law of the United States or of any State, or who have committed acts that would be a criminal violation if committed within the jurisdiction of the United States or any State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> when appropriate, develop countermeasures against such International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers, with prioritization given to such International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers identified in the National Capital Region.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, in collaboration with the Director of National Intelligence, the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Intelligence and Analysis, and the heads of such other Federal, State, or local agencies as the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation determines appropriate, and in accordance with applicable law and policy, shall conduct a pilot program designed to implement subsection (a)(1)(A) with respect to the National Capital Region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commencement; completion</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> commence carrying out the pilot program required by paragraph (1) not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> complete the pilot program not later than 2 years after the date on which the Director commences carrying out the pilot program under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notifications Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall notify the majority leader of the Senate, the minority leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the Capitol Police Board of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the placement of sensors designed to identify International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers capable of conducting surveillance against the United States Capitol or associated buildings and facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the discovery of any International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers capable of conducting surveillance against the United States Capitol or associated buildings and facilities and any countermeasures against such International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation determines that the pilot program required by subsection (b)(1) is operational, the Director shall provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the use of International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers operated by the individuals and governments described in subsection (a)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> potential countermeasures deployed by the Federal Bureau of Investigation against such International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catchers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any legal or policy limitations with respect to the development or carrying out of such countermeasures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the congressional intelligence committees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International mobile subscriber identity-catcher</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘International Mobile Subscriber Identity-catcher’ means a device used for intercepting mobile phone identifying information and location data.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s5725">section 5725 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s5003">section 5003 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d823c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Intelligence Community Information Technology Environment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXIII/s6312">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXIII, § 6312</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2191">133 Stat. 2191</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXIII/s6312">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Core service</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘core service’ means a capability that is available to multiple elements of the intelligence community and required for consistent operation of the intelligence community information technology environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Intelligence community information technology environment</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘intelligence community information technology environment’ means all of the information technology services across the intelligence community, including the data sharing and protection environment across multiple classification domains.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Roles and Responsibilities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director of national intelligence</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of National Intelligence shall be responsible for coordinating the performance by elements of the intelligence community of the intelligence community information technology environment, including each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Ensuring compliance with all applicable environment rules and regulations of such environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Ensuring measurable performance goals exist for such environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Documenting standards and practices of such environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Acting as an arbiter among elements of the intelligence community related to any disagreements arising out of the implementation of such environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Delegating responsibilities to the elements of the intelligence community and carrying out such other responsibilities as are necessary for the effective implementation of such environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Core service providers</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Providers of core services shall be responsible for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> providing core services, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> providing the Director with information requested and required to fulfill the responsibilities of the Director under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of core services.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each element of the intelligence community shall use core services when such services are available.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence may provide for a written exception to the requirement under subparagraph (A) if the Director determines there is a compelling financial or mission need for such exception.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Management Accountability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall designate and maintain one or more accountable executives of the intelligence community information technology environment to be responsible for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> management, financial control, and integration of such environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> overseeing the performance of each core service, including establishing measurable service requirements and schedules;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to the degree feasible, ensuring testing of each core service of such environment, including testing by the intended users, to evaluate performance against measurable service requirements and to ensure the capability meets user requirements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> coordinate transition or restructuring efforts of such environment, including phaseout of legacy systems.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Security Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall develop and maintain a security plan for the intelligence community information technology environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Long-Term Roadmap</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and during each of the second and fourth fiscal quarters thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a long-term roadmap that shall include each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> A description of the minimum required and desired core service requirements, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> key performance parameters; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an assessment of current, measured performance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Implementation milestones for the intelligence community information technology environment, including each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> A schedule for expected deliveries of core service capabilities during each of the following phases:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> Concept refinement and technology maturity demonstration.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Development, integration, and demonstration.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Production, deployment, and sustainment.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> System retirement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Dependencies of such core service capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Plans for the transition or restructuring necessary to incorporate core service capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A description of any legacy systems and discontinued capabilities to be phased out.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Such other matters as the Director determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Business Plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], and during each of the second and fourth fiscal quarters thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a business plan that includes each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A systematic approach to identify core service funding requests for the intelligence community information technology environment within the proposed budget, including multiyear plans to implement the long-term roadmap required by subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A uniform approach by which each element of the intelligence community shall identify the cost of legacy information technology or alternative capabilities where services of the intelligence community information technology environment will also be available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A uniform effort by which each element of the intelligence community shall identify transition and restructuring costs for new, existing, and retiring services of the intelligence community information technology environment, as well as services of such environment that have changed designations as a core service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Presentations</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall provide to the congressional intelligence committees quarterly updates regarding ongoing implementation of the intelligence community information technology environment as compared to the requirements in the most recently submitted security plan required by subsection (d), long-term roadmap required by subsection (e), and business plan required by subsection (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Notifications</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall provide timely notification to the congressional intelligence committees regarding any policy changes related to or affecting the intelligence community information technology environment, new initiatives or strategies related to or impacting such environment, and changes or deficiencies in the execution of the security plan required by subsection (d), long-term roadmap required by subsection (e), and business plan required by subsection (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The section shall have no effect on or after <date date="2024-09-30">September 30, 2024</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s6312">section 6312 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s5003">section 5003 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d823d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Policy on Minimum Insider Threat Standards</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXIII/s6314">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXIII, § 6314</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2194">133 Stat. 2194</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXIII/s6314">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall establish a policy for minimum insider threat standards that is consistent with the National Insider Threat Policy and Minimum Standards for Executive Branch Insider Threat Programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each element of the intelligence community shall implement the policy established under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “intelligence community” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s6314">section 6314 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s5003">section 5003 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d823e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports and Briefings on National Security Effects of Global Water Insecurity and Emerging Infectious Disease and Pandemics</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXVII/s6722">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXVII, § 6722</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2232">133 Stat. 2232</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dW/tVI/s622">Pub. L. 116–260, div. W, title VI, § 622</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2404">134 Stat. 2404</ref>, which required the Director of National Intelligence to submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the implications of water insecurity on the national security interests of the United States and a briefing with updates every 5 years and to submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the anticipated geopolitical effects of emerging infectious disease and pandemics and their implications on the national security of the United States and annual briefings with updates, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVIII/s6801/b/5">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXVIII, § 6801(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1653">139 Stat. 1653</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d823f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Activities of Employees of an Office of Inspector General</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dN/tIII/s309/a">Pub. L. 115–31, div. N, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/814">131 Stat. 814</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/31/dN/tIII/s309/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall develop and implement a uniform policy for each covered office of an inspector general to better ensure the independence of each such office. Such policy shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> provisions to prevent any conflict of interest related to a matter any employee of a covered office of an inspector general personally and substantially participated in during previous employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> standards to ensure personnel of a covered office of an inspector general are free both in fact and in appearance from personal, external, and organizational impairments to independence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> provisions to permit the head of each covered office of an inspector general to waive the application of the policy with respect to an individual if such head—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> prepares a written and signed justification for such waiver that sets out, in detail, the need for such waiver, provided that waivers shall not be issued for in fact impairments to independence; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> submits to the congressional intelligence committees [Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives] each such justification; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> any other protections the Director determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered office of an inspector general defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘covered office of an inspector general’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Office of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> the office of an inspector general for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the Office of the Director of National Intelligence;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the Central Intelligence Agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the National Security Agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> the Defense Intelligence Agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> the National Reconnaissance Office.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing to the congressional intelligence committees</inline>.—</heading><content>Prior to the date that the policy required by paragraph (1) takes effect, the Director of National Intelligence shall provide the congressional intelligence committees a briefing on such policy.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8240-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Personnel Information Notification Policy by the Director of National Intelligence</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tIII/s308">Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2917">129 Stat. 2917</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tIII/s308">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Directive Required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall issue a directive containing a written policy for the timely notification to the congressional intelligence committees of the identities of individuals occupying senior level positions within the intelligence community.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Senior Level Position</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In identifying positions that are senior level positions in the intelligence community for purposes of the directive required under subsection (a), the Director of National Intelligence shall consider whether a position—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> constitutes the head of an entity or a significant component within an agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> is involved in the management or oversight of matters of significant import to the leadership of an entity of the intelligence community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> provides significant responsibility on behalf of the intelligence community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> requires the management of a significant number of personnel or funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> requires responsibility management or oversight of sensitive intelligence activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> is held by an individual designated as a senior intelligence management official as such term is defined in section 368(a)(6) of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Public Law 111–259</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s404i–1">50 U.S.C. 404i–1</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3051">50 U.S.C. 3051</ref>] note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director shall ensure that each notification under the directive issued under subsection (a) includes each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The name of the individual occupying the position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any previous senior level position held by the individual, if applicable, or the position held by the individual immediately prior to the appointment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The position to be occupied by the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Any other information the Director determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Laws</inline>.—</heading><content>The directive issued under subsection (a) and any amendment to such directive shall be consistent with the provisions of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s401">50 U.S.C. 401</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">50 U.S.C. 3001</ref>] et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>], the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees the directive issued under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “congressional intelligence committees” and “intelligence community” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/s308">section 308 of div. M of Pub. L. 114–113</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/s2">section 2 of div. M of Pub. L. 114–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18d8241-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Designation of Lead Intelligence Officer for Tunnels</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tIII/s309">Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2918">129 Stat. 2918</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tIII/s309">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall designate an official to manage the collection and analysis of intelligence regarding the tactical use of tunnels by state and nonstate actors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than the date that is 10 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>], and biennially thereafter until the date that is 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees [Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives] and the congressional defense committees (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a/16">section 101(a)(16) of title 10</ref>, United States Code) a report describing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> trends in the use of tunnels by foreign state and nonstate actors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> collaboration efforts between the United States and partner countries to address the use of tunnels by adversaries.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff342-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reporting Process Required for Tracking Certain Requests for Country Clearance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tIII/s310">Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2918">129 Stat. 2918</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tIII/s310">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>By not later than <date date="2016-09-30">September 30, 2016</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall establish a formal internal reporting process for tracking requests for country clearance submitted to overseas Director of National Intelligence representatives by departments and agencies of the United States. Such reporting process shall include a mechanism for tracking the department or agency that submits each such request and the date on which each such request is submitted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>By not later than <date date="2016-12-31">December 31, 2016</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall brief the congressional intelligence committees [Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives] on the progress of the Director in establishing the process required under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff343-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Insider Threat Detection Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/18/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 112–18, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2011-06-08">June 8, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/227">125 Stat. 227</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/277/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 112–277, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2471">126 Stat. 2471</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/277/tIII/s304">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial Operating Capability</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2013-10-01">October 1, 2013</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall establish an initial operating capability for an effective automated insider threat detection program for the information resources in each element of the intelligence community in order to detect unauthorized access to, or use or transmission of, classified intelligence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Full Operating Capability</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2014-10-01">October 1, 2014</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall ensure the program described in subsection (a) has reached full operating capability.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2011-12-01">December 1, 2011</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on the resources required to implement the insider threat detection program referred to in subsection (a) and any other issues related to such implementation the Director considers appropriate to include in the report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information Resources Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘information resources’ means networks, systems, workstations, servers, routers, applications, databases, websites, online collaboration environments, and any other information resources in an element of the intelligence community designated by the Director of National Intelligence.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/112/18/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 112–18</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/18/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 112–18</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff344-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Joint Procedures for Operational Coordination Between Department of Defense and Central Intelligence Agency</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1013">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1013</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3662">118 Stat. 3662</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1013">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development of Procedures</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, shall develop joint procedures to be used by the Department of Defense and the Central Intelligence Agency to improve the coordination and deconfliction of operations that involve elements of both the Armed Forces and the Central Intelligence Agency consistent with national security and the protection of human intelligence sources and methods. Those procedures shall, at a minimum, provide the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Methods by which the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency and the Secretary of Defense can improve communication and coordination in the planning, execution, and sustainment of operations, including, as a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> information exchange between senior officials of the Central Intelligence Agency and senior officers and officials of the Department of Defense when planning for such an operation commences by either organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> exchange of information between the Secretary and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency to ensure that senior operational officials in both the Department of Defense and the Central Intelligence Agency have knowledge of the existence of the ongoing operations of the other.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> When appropriate, in cases where the Department of Defense and the Central Intelligence Agency are conducting separate missions in the same geographical area, a mutual agreement on the tactical and strategic objectives for the region and a clear delineation of operational responsibilities to prevent conflict and duplication of effort.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Act [<date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) and the congressional intelligence committees (as defined in section 3(7) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s401a/7">50 U.S.C. 401a(7)</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003/7">50 U.S.C. 3003(7)</ref>]) a report describing the procedures established pursuant to subsection (a) and the status of the implementation of those procedures.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff345-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Alternative Analysis of Intelligence by the Intelligence Community</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1017">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1017</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3670">118 Stat. 3670</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1017">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the effective date of this Act [probably means the effective date of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, see Effective Date of 2004 Amendment; Transition Provisions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>], the Director of National Intelligence shall establish a process and assign an individual or entity the responsibility for ensuring that, as appropriate, elements of the intelligence community conduct alternative analysis (commonly referred to as ‘red-team analysis’) of the information and conclusions in intelligence products.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 270 days after the effective date of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall provide a report to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee of the House of Representatives on the implementation of subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff346-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancing Classified Counterterrorist Travel Efforts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7201/e">Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7201(e)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3813">118 Stat. 3813</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7201/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall significantly increase resources and personnel to the small classified program that collects and analyzes intelligence on terrorist travel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2009 such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff347-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Intelligence Community Use of National Infrastructure Simulation and Analysis Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVIII/s8101">Pub. L. 108–458, title VIII, § 8101</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3864">118 Stat. 3864</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tVIII/s8101">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of National Intelligence shall establish a formal relationship, including information sharing, between the elements of the intelligence community and the National Infrastructure Simulation and Analysis Center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>The purpose of the relationship under subsection (a) shall be to permit the intelligence community to take full advantage of the capabilities of the National Infrastructure Simulation and Analysis Center, particularly vulnerability and consequence analysis, for real time response to reported threats and long term planning for projected threats.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff348-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Analysis of Signals and Other Intelligence by Intelligence Analysts of Various Elements of the Intelligence Community</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/177/tIII/s317">Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 317</ref>, <date date="2003-12-13">Dec. 13, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2611">117 Stat. 2611</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI">Pub. L. 108–458, title I</ref>, §§ 1071(g)(3)(A)(i), (ii), 1072(d)(2)(A), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3692">118 Stat. 3692</ref>, 3693, required Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with Secretary of Defense, to carry out pilot program to assess feasibility and advisability of permitting intelligence analysts of various elements of intelligence community to access and analyze signals intelligence of the National Security Agency and other selected intelligence from databases of other elements of intelligence community in order to achieve certain objectives; pilot program was to commence not later than <date date="2003-12-31">Dec. 31, 2003</date>, be assessed not later than <date date="2004-02-01">Feb. 1, 2004</date>, and a report on the assessment submitted to Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff349-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Standardized Transliteration of Names Into the Roman Alphabet</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/306/tIII/s352">Pub. L. 107–306, title III, § 352</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2401">116 Stat. 2401</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1071/g/2/D">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1071(g)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3691">118 Stat. 3691</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1071/g/2/D">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Method of Transliteration Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>], the Director of Central Intelligence shall provide for a standardized method for transliterating into the Roman alphabet personal and place names originally rendered in any language that uses an alphabet other than the Roman alphabet.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use by Intelligence Community</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of National Intelligence shall ensure the use of the method established under subsection (a) in—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> all communications among the elements of the intelligence community; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> all intelligence products of the intelligence community.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff34a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Standards for Spelling of Foreign Names and Places and for Use of Geographic Coordinates</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/107/tIII/s309">Pub. L. 105–107, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2253">111 Stat. 2253</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/107/tIII/s309">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Survey of Current Standards.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Survey</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of Central Intelligence shall carry out a survey of current standards for the spelling of foreign names and places, and the use of geographic coordinates for such places, among the elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>], the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on the survey carried out under paragraph (1). The report shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidelines.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuance</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall issue guidelines to ensure the use of uniform spelling of foreign names and places and the uniform use of geographic coordinates for such places. The guidelines shall apply to all intelligence reports, intelligence products, and intelligence databases prepared and utilized by the elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Basis</inline>.—</heading><content>The guidelines under paragraph (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be based on current United States Government standards for the transliteration of foreign names, standards for foreign place names developed by the Board on Geographic Names, and a standard set of geographic coordinates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submittal to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director shall submit a copy of the guidelines to the congressional intelligence committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Intelligence Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘congressional intelligence committees’ means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff34b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Periodic Reports on Expenditures</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/293/s807/c">Pub. L. 104–293, § 807(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3480">110 Stat. 3480</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/293/s807/c">“Not later than <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, the Director of Central Intelligence and the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe guidelines to ensure prompt reporting to the Director and the Secretary on a periodic basis of budget execution data for all national, defense-wide, and tactical intelligence activities.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff34c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Database Program Tracking</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/293/tVIII/s807/d">Pub. L. 104–293, title VIII, § 807(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3481">110 Stat. 3481</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/293/tVIII/s807/d">“Not later than <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, the Director of Central Intelligence and the Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a database to provide timely and accurate information on the amounts, purposes, and status of the resources, including periodic budget execution updates, for all national, defense-wide, and tactical intelligence activities.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idd18ff34d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6701">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6701</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3560">136 Stat. 3560</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tV/s7502/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title V, § 7502(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1081">137 Stat. 1081</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tV/s7502/b">
<inline>“In this title [enacting sections 3034b, 3334m, 3334n, and 3334<i>o</i> of this title, amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3030">section 3030 of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3030">section 3030 of this title</ref>]:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Artificial intelligence</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘artificial intelligence’ has the meaning given that term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization to operate</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘authorization to operate’ has the meaning given that term in Circular Number A-130 of the Office of Management and Budget, ‘Managing Information as a Strategic Resource’, or any successor document.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Code-free artificial intelligence enablement tools</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘code-free artificial intelligence enablement tools’ means software that provides an environment in which visual drag-and-drop applications, or similar tools, allow one or more individuals to program applications without linear coding.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commercial product</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘commercial product’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s103">section 103 of title 41</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commercial service</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘commercial service’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s103a">section 103a of title 41</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered item or service</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘covered item or service’ means a product, system, or service that is not a commercially available off-the-shelf item, a commercial service, or a nondevelopmental item, as those terms are defined in title 41, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered product</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘covered product’ means a commercial software product that involves emerging technologies or artificial intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emerging technology</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘emerging technology’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> technology that is in a developmental stage or that may be developed during the subsequent 10-year period; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any technology included in the Critical and Emerging Technologies List published by the White House in February 2022, or any successor document.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd18ff34e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd18ff34f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of the Cyber Threat Intelligence Integration Center</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2015-02-25">Feb. 25, 2015</date>, 80 F.R. 11317, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State[,] the Secretary of Defense[,] the Secretary of the Treasury[,] the Secretary of Commerce[,] the Attorney General[,] the Secretary of Homeland Security[,] the Director of National Intelligence[,] the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff[,] the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency[,] the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation[, and] the Director of the National Security Agency</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, I hereby direct as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Establishment of the Cyber Threat Intelligence Integration Center</i>. The Director of National Intelligence (DNI) shall establish a Cyber Threat Intelligence Integration Center (CTIIC). Executive departments and agencies (agencies) shall support the DNI’s efforts to establish the CTIIC, including by providing, as appropriate, personnel and resources needed for the CTIIC to reach full operating capability by the end of fiscal year 2016.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Responsibilities of the Cyber Threat Intelligence Integration Center</i>. The CTIIC shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) provide integrated all-source analysis of intelligence related to foreign cyber threats or related to cyber incidents affecting U.S. national interests;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) support the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center, the National Cyber Investigative Joint Task Force, U.S. Cyber Command, and other relevant United States Government entities by providing access to intelligence necessary to carry out their respective missions;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) oversee the development and implementation of intelligence sharing capabilities (including systems, programs, policies, and standards) to enhance shared situational awareness of intelligence related to foreign cyber threats or related to cyber incidents affecting U.S. national interests among the organizations referenced in subsection (b) of this section;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) ensure that indicators of malicious cyber activity and, as appropriate, related threat reporting contained in intelligence channels are downgraded to the lowest classification possible for distribution to both United States Government and U.S. private sector entities through the mechanism described in section 4 of Executive Order 13636 of <date date="2013-02-12">February 12, 2013</date> (Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) facilitate and support interagency efforts to develop and implement coordinated plans to counter foreign cyber threats to U.S. national interests using all instruments of national power, including diplomatic, economic, military, intelligence, homeland security, and law enforcement activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Implementation</i>. (a) Agencies shall provide the CTIIC with all intelligence related to foreign cyber threats or related to cyber incidents affecting U.S. national interests, subject to applicable law and policy. The CTIIC shall access, assess, use, retain, and disseminate such information, in a manner that protects privacy and civil liberties and is consistent with applicable law, Executive Orders, Presidential directives, and guidelines, such as guidelines established under section 102A(b) of the National Security Act of 1947, as amended, Executive Order 12333 of <date date="1981-12-04">December 4, 1981</date> (United States Intelligence Activities), as amended, and Presidential Policy Directive–28; and that is consistent with the need to protect sources and methods.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Within 90 days of the date of this memorandum, the DNI, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of the National Security Agency shall provide a status report to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism on the establishment of the CTIIC. This report shall further refine the CTIIC’s mission, roles, and responsibilities, consistent with this memorandum, ensuring that those roles and responsibilities are appropriately aligned with other Presidential policies as well as existing policy coordination mechanisms.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Privacy and Civil Liberties Protections</i>. Agencies providing information to the CTIIC shall ensure that privacy and civil liberties protections are provided in the course of implementing this memorandum. Such protections shall be based upon the Fair Information Practice Principles or other privacy and civil liberties policies, principles, and frameworks as they apply to each agency’s activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department, agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The DNI is hereby authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
