<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1971f49-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036"><num value="3036">§ 3036.</num><heading> Director of the Central Intelligence Agency</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1971f4a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Director of Central Intelligence Agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is a Director of the Central Intelligence Agency who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1971f4b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Supervision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall report to the Director of National Intelligence regarding the activities of the Central Intelligence Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1971f4c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1971f4d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> serve as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1971f4e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1971f4f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1971f50-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> collect intelligence through human sources and by other appropriate means, except that the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall have no police, subpoena, or law enforcement powers or internal security functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1971f51-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> correlate and evaluate intelligence related to the national security and provide appropriate dissemination of such intelligence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1971f52-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide overall direction for and coordination of the collection of national intelligence outside the United States through human sources by elements of the intelligence community authorized to undertake such collection and, in coordination with other departments, agencies, or elements of the United States Government which are authorized to undertake such collection, ensure that the most effective use is made of resources and that appropriate account is taken of the risks to the United States and those involved in such collection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1971f53-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> perform such other functions and duties related to intelligence affecting the national security as the President or the Director of National Intelligence may direct.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1971f54-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of employment of CIA employees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1971f55-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may, in the discretion of the Director, terminate the employment of any officer or employee of the Central Intelligence Agency whenever the Director deems the termination of employment of such officer or employee necessary or advisable in the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1971f56-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any termination of employment of an officer or employee under paragraph (1) shall not affect the right of the officer or employee to seek or accept employment in any other department, agency, or element of the United States Government if declared eligible for such employment by the Office of Personnel Management.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1971f57-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3036/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with foreign governments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under the direction of the Director of National Intelligence and in a manner consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3927">section 3927 of title 22</ref>, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall coordinate the relationships between elements of the intelligence community and the intelligence or security services of foreign governments or international organizations on all matters involving intelligence related to the national security or involving intelligence acquired through clandestine means.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1971f58-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title I, § 104A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1011/a">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1011(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3660">118 Stat. 3660</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/487/tVI/s611/a">Pub. L. 108–487, title VI, § 611(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3954">118 Stat. 3954</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tVIII/s804/4">Pub. L. 111–259, title VIII, § 804(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2747">124 Stat. 2747</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/tIV/s412/a">Pub. L. 112–87, title IV, § 412(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1890">125 Stat. 1890</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXIV/s6414/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXIV, § 6414(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2199">133 Stat. 2199</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1971f59-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1971f5a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1971f5b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403–4a">section 403–4a of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1971f5c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> struck out subsec. (g) which related to foreign language proficiency requirement for certain senior level positions in the Central Intelligence Agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/s412/a/1">Pub. L. 112–87, § 412(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “in the Directorate of Intelligence career service or the National Clandestine Service career service” after “an individual” and “or promoted” after “appointed”, substituted “individual has been certified as having a professional speaking and reading proficiency in a foreign language, such proficiency being at least level 3 on the Interagency Language Roundtable Language Skills Level or commensurate proficiency level using such other indicator of proficiency as the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency considers appropriate.” for “individual—”, and struck out subpars. (A) and (B) which related to required level of proficiency in a foreign language and ability to effectively communicate and exercise influence in that language, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/s412/a/2">Pub. L. 112–87, § 412(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “position, category of positions, or occupation” for “position or category of positions” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Pub. L. 111–259</ref> substituted “National Clandestine Service” for “Directorate of Operations” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/108/487">Pub. L. 108–487</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1971f5d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd1971f5e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/487/tVI/s611/b">Pub. L. 108–487, title VI, § 611(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3955">118 Stat. 3955</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/tIV/s412/b">Pub. L. 112–87, title IV, § 412(b)</ref>, <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1890">125 Stat. 1890</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/87/tIV/s412/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to appointments or promotions made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd1971f5f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For Determination by President that section take effect on <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, see Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 23925, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective not later than six months after <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s1097/a">section 1097(a) of Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out in an Effective Date of 2004 Amendment; Transition Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1971f60-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Creating an Official Record of the Osama Bin Laden Operation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/87/tIV/s414">Pub. L. 112–87, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1891">125 Stat. 1891</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/87/tIV/s414">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> On <date date="2011-05-01">May 1, 2011</date>, United States personnel killed terrorist leader Osama bin Laden during the course of a targeted strike against his secret compound in Abbottabad, Pakistan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Osama bin Laden was the leader of the al Qaeda terrorist organization, the most significant terrorism threat to the United States and the international community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Osama bin Laden was the architect of terrorist attacks which killed nearly 3,000 civilians on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, the most deadly terrorist attack against our Nation, in which al Qaeda terrorists hijacked four airplanes and crashed them into the World Trade Center in New York City, the Pentagon in Washington, D.C., and, due to heroic efforts by civilian passengers to disrupt the terrorists, near Shanksville, Pennsylvania.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Osama bin Laden planned or supported numerous other deadly terrorist attacks against the United States and its allies, including the 1998 bombings of United States embassies in Kenya and Tanzania and the 2000 attack on the U.S.S. Cole in Yemen, and against innocent civilians in countries around the world, including the 2004 attack on commuter trains in Madrid, Spain and the 2005 bombings of the mass transit system in London, England.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Following the <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, terrorist attacks, the United States, under President George W. Bush, led an international coalition into Afghanistan to dismantle al Qaeda, deny them a safe haven in Afghanistan and ungoverned areas along the Pakistani border, and bring Osama bin Laden to justice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> President Barack Obama in 2009 committed additional forces and resources to efforts in Afghanistan and Pakistan as ‘the central front in our enduring struggle against terrorism and extremism’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> The valiant members of the United States Armed Forces have courageously and vigorously pursued al Qaeda and its affiliates in Afghanistan and around the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> The anonymous, unsung heroes of the intelligence community have pursued al Qaeda and affiliates in Afghanistan, Pakistan, and around the world with tremendous dedication, sacrifice, and professionalism.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> The close collaboration between the Armed Forces and the intelligence community prompted the Director of National Intelligence, General James Clapper, to state, ‘Never have I seen a more remarkable example of focused integration, seamless collaboration, and sheer professional magnificence as was demonstrated by the Intelligence Community in the ultimate demise of Osama bin Laden.’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> While the death of Osama bin Laden represents a significant blow to the al Qaeda organization and its affiliates and to terrorist organizations around the world, terrorism remains a critical threat to United States national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> President Obama said, ‘For over two decades, bin Laden has been al Qaeda’s leader and symbol, and has continued to plot attacks against our country and our friends and allies. The death of bin Laden marks the most significant achievement to date in our Nation’s effort to defeat al Qaeda.’.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the raid that killed Osama bin Laden demonstrated the best of the intelligence community’s capabilities and teamwork;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> for years to come, Americans will look back at this event as a defining point in the history of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> it is vitally important that the United States memorialize all the events that led to the raid so that future generations will have an official record of the events that transpired before, during, and as a result of the operation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> preserving this history now will allow the United States to have an accurate account of the events while those that participated in the events are still serving in the Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on the Operation That Killed Osama Bin Laden</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the completion of the report being prepared by the Center for the Study of Intelligence that documents the history of and lessons learned from the raid that resulted in the death of Osama bin Laden, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall submit such report to the congressional intelligence committees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preservation of Records</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall preserve any records, including intelligence information and assessments, used to generate the report described in subsection (c).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/s414">section 414 of Pub. L. 112–87</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/87/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 112–87</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1971f61-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Report on Foreign Companies Involved in the Proliferation of Weapons of Mass Destruction That Raise Funds in the United States Capital Markets</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/306/tVIII/s827">Pub. L. 107–306, title VIII, § 827</ref>, <date date="2002-11-27">Nov. 27, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2430">116 Stat. 2430</ref>, required Director of Central Intelligence to submit annual report on foreign companies involved in the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction that raised or attempted to raise funds in the United States capital markets, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/177/tIII/s361/e">Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 361(e)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-13">Dec. 13, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2625">117 Stat. 2625</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd1971f62-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idd1971f63-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13355</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13355, <date date="2004-08-27">Aug. 27, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 53593, which related to strengthened management of the Intelligence Community, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12333, § 3.6, <date date="1981-12-04">Dec. 4, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 59954, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 13470, § 4(j), <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, 73 F.R. 45341, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
