<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd19968f7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043"><num value="3043">§ 3043.</num><heading> Annual national security strategy report</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd19968f8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19968f9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President shall transmit to Congress each year a comprehensive report on the national security strategy of the United States (hereinafter in this section referred to as a “national security strategy report”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19968fa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The national security strategy report for any year shall be transmitted on the date on which the President submits to Congress the budget for the next fiscal year under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19968fb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not later than 150 days after the date on which a new President takes office, the President shall transmit to Congress a national security strategy report under this section. That report shall be in addition to the report for that year transmitted at the time specified in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd19968fc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each national security strategy report shall set forth the national security strategy of the United States and shall include a comprehensive description and discussion of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd19968fd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The worldwide interests, goals, and objectives of the United States that are vital to the national security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd19968fe-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The foreign policy, worldwide commitments, and national defense capabilities of the United States necessary to deter aggression and to implement the national security strategy of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd19968ff-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The proposed short-term and long-term uses of the political, economic, military, and other elements of the national power of the United States to protect or promote the interests and achieve the goals and objectives referred to in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1996900-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The adequacy of the capabilities of the United States to carry out the national security strategy of the United States, including an evaluation of the balance among the capabilities of all elements of the national power of the United States to support the implementation of the national security strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1996901-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Such other information as may be necessary to help inform Congress on matters relating to the national security strategy of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1996902-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3043/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Classified and unclassified form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each national security strategy report shall be transmitted to Congress in classified form, but may include an unclassified summary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1996903-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title I, § 108, formerly § 104, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tVI/s603/a/1">Pub. L. 99–433, title VI, § 603(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1074">100 Stat. 1074</ref>; renumbered § 108, <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/tVII/s705/a/2">Pub. L. 102–496, title VII, § 705(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3190">106 Stat. 3190</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIX/s901/b">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IX, § 901(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/717">113 Stat. 717</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tIX/s944">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 944</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2371">130 Stat. 2371</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLXVII/s6742/b/4">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXVII, § 6742(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2240">133 Stat. 2240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1996904-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1996905-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1996906-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s404a">section 404a of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1996907-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> substituted “to Congress in classified form, but may include an unclassified summary” for “in both a classified and an unclassified form”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, which directed substitution of “to Congress in classified form, but may include an unclassified summary” for “in both a classified form and an unclassified form”, could not be executed because the words “in both a classified form and an unclassified form” did not appear in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> added par. (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1996908-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1996909-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Security Planning Guidance To Deny Safe Havens to Al-Qaeda and Its Violent Extremist Affiliates</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tX/s1032">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1032</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1571">125 Stat. 1571</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXII/s1262">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XII, § 1262</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3580">128 Stat. 3580</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXII/s1262">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>The purpose of this section is to improve interagency strategic planning and execution to more effectively integrate efforts to deny safe havens and strengthen at-risk states to further the goals of the National Security Strategy related to the disruption, dismantlement, and defeat of al-Qaeda and its violent extremist affiliates.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Security Planning Guidance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance required</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall issue classified or unclassified national security planning guidance in support of objectives stated in the national security strategy report submitted to Congress by the President pursuant to section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s404a">50 U.S.C. 404a</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3043">50 U.S.C. 3043</ref>] to deny safe havens to al-Qaeda and its violent extremist affiliates and to strengthen at-risk states. Such guidance shall serve as the strategic plan that governs United States and coordinated international efforts to enhance the capacity of governmental and nongovernmental entities to work toward the goal of eliminating the ability of al-Qaeda and its violent extremist affiliates to establish or maintain safe havens.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents of guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The guidance required under paragraph (1) shall include each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A prioritized list of specified geographic areas that the President determines are necessary to address and an explicit discussion and list of the criteria or rationale used to prioritize the areas on the list, including a discussion of the conditions that would hamper the ability of the United States to strengthen at-risk states or other entities in such areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> For each specified geographic area, a description, analysis, and discussion of the core problems and contributing issues that allow or could allow al-Qaeda and its violent extremist affiliates to use the area as a safe haven from which to plan and launch attacks, engage in propaganda, or raise funds and other support, including any ongoing or potential radicalization of the population, or to use the area as a key transit route for personnel, weapons, funding, or other support.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> For each specified geographic area, a description of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> The feasibility of conducting multilateral programs to train and equip the military forces of relevant countries in the area.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The authority and funding that would be required to support such programs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> How such programs would be implemented.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> How such programs would support the national security priorities and interests of the United States and complement other efforts of the United States Government in the area and in other specified geographic areas.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A list of short-term, mid-term, and long-term goals for each specified geographic area, prioritized by importance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> A description of the role and mission of each Federal department and agency involved in executing the guidance, including the Departments of Defense, Justice, Treasury, and State and the Agency for International Development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> A description of gaps in United States capabilities to meet the goals listed pursuant to subparagraph (D), and the extent to which those gaps can be met through coordination with nongovernmental, international, or private sector organizations, entities, or companies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review and update of guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President shall review and update the guidance required under paragraph (1) as necessary. Any such review shall address each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The overall progress made toward achieving the goals listed pursuant to paragraph (2)(D), including an overall assessment of the progress in denying a safe haven to al-Qaeda and its violent extremist affiliates.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The performance of each Federal department and agency involved in executing the guidance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The performance of the unified country team and appropriate combatant command, or in the case of a cross-border effort, country teams in the area and the appropriate combatant command.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Any addition to, deletion from, or change in the order of the prioritized list maintained pursuant to paragraph (2)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Carl Levin and Howard P. ‘Buck’ McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 [<date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>], the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a detailed summary of the national security planning guidance required under paragraph (1), including any updates thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>The report may include a classified annex as determined to be necessary by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this paragraph, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives]; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specified geographic area defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term ‘specified geographic area’ means any country, subnational territory, or region—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> that serves or may potentially serve as a safe haven for al-Qaeda or a violent extremist affiliate of al-Qaeda—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> from which to plan and launch attacks, engage in propaganda, or raise funds and other support; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> for use as a key transit route for personnel, weapons, funding, or other support; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> over which one or more governments or entities exert insufficient governmental or security control to deny al-Qaeda and its violent extremist affiliates the ability to establish a large scale presence.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd199690a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation Plan for Whole-of-Government Vision Prescribed in the National Security Strategy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tX/s1072">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1072</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1592">125 Stat. 1592</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tX/s1076/d">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1076(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/998">129 Stat. 998</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tX/s1076/d">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>], the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an implementation plan for achieving the whole-of-government integration vision prescribed in the President’s National Security Strategy of May 2010. The implementation plan shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a description of ongoing and future actions planned to be taken by the President and the Executive agencies to implement organizational changes, programs, and any other efforts to achieve each component of the whole-of-government vision prescribed in the National Security Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a timeline for specific actions taken and planned to be taken by the President and the Executive agencies to implement each component of the whole-of-government vision prescribed in the National Security Strategy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an outline of specific actions desired or required to be taken by Congress to achieve each component of the whole-of-government vision prescribed in the National Security Strategy, including suggested timing and sequencing of actions proposed for Congress and the Executive agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> any progress made and challenges or obstacles encountered since May 2010 in implementing each component of the whole-of-government vision prescribed in the National Security Strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> such other information as the President determines is necessary to understand progress in implementing each component of the whole-of-government vision prescribed in the National Security Strategy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations, Select Committee on Intelligence, Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs, Committee on the Budget, Committee on the Judiciary, and Committee on Appropriations in the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs, Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, Committee on Homeland Security, Committee on the Budget, Committee on the Judiciary, Committee on Oversight and Government Reform [now Committee on Oversight and Accountability], and Committee on Appropriations in the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Executive agency’ has the meaning given that term by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s105">section 105 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd199690b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Commission on the Future Role of United States Nuclear Weapons, Problems of Command, Control, and Safety of Soviet Nuclear Weapons, and Reduction of Nuclear Weapons</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/172/tVIII/s8132">Pub. L. 102–172, title VIII, § 8132</ref>, <date date="1991-11-26">Nov. 26, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1208">105 Stat. 1208</ref>, provided for establishment of a National Commission which was to submit to Congress, not later than <date date="1993-05-01">May 1, 1993</date>, a final report containing an assessment and recommendations regarding role of, and requirements for, nuclear weapons in security strategy of United States as result of significant changes in former Warsaw Pact, former Soviet Union, and Third World, including possibilities for international cooperation with former Soviet Union regarding such problems, and safeguards to protect against accidental or unauthorized use of nuclear weapons, further directed Commission to obtain study from National Academy of Sciences on these matters, further authorized establishment of joint working group comprised of experts from governments of United States and former Soviet Union which was to meet on regular basis and provide recommendations regarding these matters, and further provided for composition of Commission as well as powers, procedures, personnel matters, appropriations, and termination of Commission upon submission of its final report.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
