<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd19e4b38-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057"><num value="3057">§ 3057.</num><heading> National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd19e4b39-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19e4b3a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The President shall establish a National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, taking into account all appropriate government tools to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd19e4b3b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd19e4b3c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> lead integration and mission management of all intelligence activities pertaining to biosecurity and foreign biological threats.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19e4b3d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The head of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall be the Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, who shall be appointed by the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19e4b3e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall be located within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19e4b3f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall serve as the principal coordinator for the intelligence community, and as the principal advisor to the Director of National Intelligence, with respect to counterproliferation, biosecurity, and foreign biological threats.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd19e4b40-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Missions and objectives</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd19e4b41-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Counterproliferation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In establishing the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, the President shall address the following missions and objectives to prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b42-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Establishing a primary organization within the United States Government for integrating all intelligence possessed or acquired by the United States pertaining to proliferation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b43-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Ensuring that appropriate agencies have full access to and receive all-source intelligence support needed to execute their counterproliferation plans or activities, and perform independent, alternative analyses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b44-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Coordinating the establishment of a central repository on known and suspected proliferation activities, including the goals, strategies, capabilities, networks, and any individuals, groups, or entities engaged in proliferation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b45-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Overseeing the dissemination of proliferation information, including proliferation threats and analyses, to the President, to the appropriate departments and agencies, and to the appropriate committees of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b46-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Conducting and coordinating net assessments and warnings about the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b47-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Coordinating counterproliferation plans and activities of the various departments and agencies of the United States Government to prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b48-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Coordinating and advancing strategic operational counterproliferation planning for the United States Government to prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd19e4b49-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Biosecurity</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In establishing the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, the President shall address the following missions and objectives to ensure that the Center serves as the lead for the intelligence community for the integration, mission management, and coordination of intelligence activities pertaining to biosecurity and foreign biological threats, regardless of origin:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b4a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Ensuring that the elements of the intelligence community provide timely and effective warnings to the President and the Director of National Intelligence regarding emerging foreign biological threats, including diseases with pandemic potential.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b4b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Overseeing and coordinating the collection of intelligence on biosecurity and foreign biological threats in support of the intelligence needs of the Federal departments and agencies responsible for public health, including by conveying collection priorities to elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b4c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Overseeing and coordinating the analysis of intelligence on biosecurity and foreign biological threats in support of the intelligence needs of Federal departments and agencies responsible for public health, including by providing analytic priorities to elements of the intelligence community and by coordinating net assessments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b4d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Coordinating intelligence support to the Federal departments and agencies responsible for public health on matters relating to biosecurity and foreign biological threats, including by ensuring that intelligence pertaining to biosecurity and foreign biological threats is disseminated among appropriately cleared personnel of such departments and agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b4e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Coordinating with the Federal departments and agencies responsible for public health to encourage information sharing with the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b4f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Identifying gaps in the capabilities of the intelligence community regarding biosecurity and countering foreign biological threats and providing to the Director of National Intelligence recommended solutions for such gaps, including by encouraging research and development of new capabilities and authorities to counter foreign biological threats.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd19e4b50-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Enhancing coordination between elements of the intelligence community and private sector entities on information relevant to biosecurity, biotechnology, and foreign biological threats, and coordinating such information with relevant Federal departments and agencies, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd19e4b51-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> National security waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may waive the requirements of this section, and any parts thereof, if the President determines that such requirements do not materially improve the ability of the United States Government to prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies. Such waiver shall be made in writing to Congress and shall include a description of how the missions and objectives in subsection (b) are being met.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd19e4b52-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19e4b53-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than nine months after the implementation of this chapter, the President shall submit to Congress, in classified form if necessary, the findings and recommendations of the President’s Commission on Weapons of Mass Destruction established by Executive Order in February 2004, together with the views of the President regarding the establishment of a National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd19e4b54-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the President decides not to exercise the waiver authority granted by subsection (c), the President shall submit to Congress from time to time updates and plans regarding the establishment of a National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd19e4b55-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3057/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that a central feature of counterproliferation activities, consistent with the President’s Proliferation Security Initiative, should include the physical interdiction, by air, sea, or land, of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies, and enhanced law enforcement activities to identify and disrupt proliferation networks, activities, organizations, and persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd19e4b56-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title I, § 119A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1022">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1022</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3675">118 Stat. 3675</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tIV/s407/a">Pub. L. 111–259, title IV, § 407(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2721">124 Stat. 2721</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIV/s401/a">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/973">136 Stat. 973</ref>, 974; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dF/tLXV/s6502">Pub. L. 118–159, div. F, title LXV, § 6502</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2494">138 Stat. 2494</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6404/c/2">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXIV, § 6404(c)(2)</ref>, (d), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1618">139 Stat. 1618</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd19e4b57-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="idd19e4b58-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Section</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6404/c/2">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXIV, § 6404(c)(2)</ref>, (d), (g), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1618">139 Stat. 1618</ref>, provided that, effective 180 days after <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, section is amended as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(1) in the heading, by striking “National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center” and inserting “Counterproliferation and Biosecurity”;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(2) in subsection (a)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(A) in the heading, by striking “Establishment” and inserting “Organization”;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(B) in paragraph (1)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(i) by striking “The President shall establish a National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, taking into account all appropriate government tools to” and inserting “The Director of National Intelligence shall”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(ii) in subparagraph (A), by inserting “support efforts to” before “prevent and halt”;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(C) by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0 fontsize8"><i>“(2) The Director of National Intelligence shall appoint an appropriate official within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to oversee the efforts and activities undertaken pursuant to this section.”; and</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(D) by striking paragraphs (3) and (4); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(3) in subsection (b)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(A) in paragraph (1)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(i) by striking “establishing the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, the President” and inserting “carrying out this section, the Director”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(ii) in subparagraph (A), by striking “Establishing a primary organization within the United States Government for integrating” and inserting “Integrating”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(B) in paragraph (2), by striking “In establishing the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, the President shall address the following missions and objectives to ensure that the Center serves as the lead for the intelligence community for” and inserting “In carrying out this section, the Director shall address the following missions and objectives to ensure”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(4) by striking subsections (c), (d), and (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">See 2025 Amendment notes below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd19e4b59-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd19e4b5a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/495">61 Stat. 495</ref>, known as the National Security Act of 1947, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Executive Order in February 2004 establishing the President’s Commission on Weapons of Mass Destruction, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), is Ex. Ord. No. 13328, <date date="2004-02-06">Feb. 6, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 6901, which was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13385, § 3(a), <date date="2005-09-29">Sept. 29, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 57990, and was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2301">section 2301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd19e4b5b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 404<i>o</i>–1 of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd19e4b5c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—<ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Counterproliferation and Biosecurity” for “National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/B/i">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “Organization” for “Establishment” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/B/ii/I">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(B)(ii)(I)</ref>, substituted “The Director of National Intelligence shall” for “The President shall establish a National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, taking into account all appropriate government tools to” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/B/ii/II">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(B)(ii)(II)</ref>, inserted “support efforts to” before “prevent and halt”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/B/iii">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(B)(iii)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “The head of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall be the Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, who shall be appointed by the Director of National Intelligence.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/B/iv">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(B)(iv)</ref>, struck out pars. (3) and (4) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) The National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall be located within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) The Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall serve as the principal coordinator for the intelligence community, and as the principal advisor to the Director of National Intelligence, with respect to counterproliferation, biosecurity, and foreign biological threats.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/C/i/I">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(C)(i)(I)</ref>, substituted “carrying out this section, the Director” for “establishing the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, the President” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/C/i/II">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(C)(i)(II)</ref>, substituted “Integrating” for “Establishing a primary organization within the United States Government for integrating”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/c/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(c)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, substituted “In carrying out this section, the Director shall address the following missions and objectives to ensure” for “In establishing the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, the President shall address the following missions and objectives to ensure that the Center serves as the lead for the intelligence community for” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/d">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6404(d)</ref>, struck out subsecs. (c) to (e) which related to national security waiver, report to Congress, and sense of Congress, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/1">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(1)</ref>, substituted “counterproliferation, biosecurity, and” for “biosecurity and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/A/i">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(A)(i)</ref>, struck out “analyzing and” before “integrating all intelligence”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “Coordinating the establishment of” for “Establishing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/A/iii">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, substituted “Overseeing the dissemination of” for “Disseminating”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/A/iv">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(A)(iv)</ref>, inserted “and coordinating” after “Conducting”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/A/v">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(A)(v)</ref>, substituted “Coordinating and advancing” for “Conducting”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/B/i">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(B)(i)</ref>, struck out “and analysis” after “coordinating the collection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/B/iii">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(B)(iii)</ref>, added subpar. (C). Former subpar. (C) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, (iv), redesignated subpar. (C) as (D) and inserted “on matters relating to biosecurity and foreign biological threats” after “public health”. Former subpar. (D) redesignated (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (E). Former subpar. (E) redesignated (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/B/v">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(B)(v)</ref>, which directed insertion of “and authorities” after “capabilities”, was executed by making the insertion after “capabilities” the second place appearing, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (E) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s6502/2/B/vi">Pub. L. 118–159, § 6502(2)(B)(vi)</ref>, added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—<ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s401/a">Pub. L. 117–103, § 401(a)</ref>, (d), substituted “Counterproliferation and Biosecurity” for “Counter Proliferation” in section catchline and “National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center” for “National Counter Proliferation Center” and “counterproliferation” for “counter proliferation” wherever appearing in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s401/b/1">Pub. L. 117–103, § 401(b)(1)</ref>, inserted dash after “government tools to” and subpar. (A) designation before “prevent” and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s401/b/2">Pub. L. 117–103, § 401(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s401/c">Pub. L. 117–103, § 401(c)</ref>, designated introductory provisions as par. (1) and inserted heading, redesignated former pars. (1) to (7) as subpars. (A) to (G), respectively, of par. (1) and realigned margins, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Pub. L. 111–259</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “The” for “Not later than 18 months after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, the”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd19e4b5d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd19e4b5e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2025 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6404/g">section 6404(g) of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3025">section 3025 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd19e4b5f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For Determination by President that section take effect on <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, see Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 23925, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective not later than six months after <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s1097/a">section 1097(a) of Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out in an Effective Date of 2004 Amendment; Transition Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd19e4b60-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center; Director</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6404/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXIV, § 6404(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1617">139 Stat. 1617</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6404/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of center</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall terminate the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, including such missions, objectives, staff, and resources of the Center, as is consistent with the provisions of this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3025">section 3025 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3025">section 3025 of this title</ref>] and the amendments made by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of director of the center</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall terminate the position of the Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, as is consistent with the provisions of this section.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd19e4b61-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Law</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6404/h">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXIV, § 6404(h)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1618">139 Stat. 1618</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXIV/s6404/h">“On and after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], any reference to the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center in law shall be treated as a reference to the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and any reference to the Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center in law shall be treated as a reference to the Director of National Intelligence.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd19e4b62-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Reference to National Counter Proliferation Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIV/s401/e">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title IV, § 401(e)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/975">136 Stat. 975</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIV/s401/e">“Any reference in any law, regulation, guidance, instruction, or other document of the United States Government to the National Counter Proliferation Center shall be deemed to refer to the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd19e4b63-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="idd19e4b64-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reporting functions of President under this section assigned to the Director of National Intelligence by section 3 of Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 48633, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref>, The President.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
