<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1ac7b92-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3114"><num value="3114">§ 3114.</num><heading> Submission of covered documents and classified annexes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1ac7b93-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3114/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered document defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “covered document” means any executive order, memorandum, or policy directive issued by the President, including national security Presidential memoranda and Presidential policy directives, or such successor memoranda and directives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1ac7b94-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3114/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 7 days after the date on which the President issues or amends a covered document, the President, acting through the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives the covered document and any classified annex accompanying that document if such covered document or annex contains a direction to, establishes a requirement for, or includes a restriction on any element of the intelligence community.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1ac7b95-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title V, § 515, as added <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXIII/s6316/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXIII, § 6316(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3513">136 Stat. 3513</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1ac7b96-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1ac7b97-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1ac7b98-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Initial Submission</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXIII/s6316/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXIII, § 6316(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3513">136 Stat. 3513</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXIII/s6316/b">“Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives each covered document and classified annex required under section 515 of the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3114">50 U.S.C. 3114</ref>], as added by subsection (a), in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6316/b">section 6316(b) of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
