<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1c470ee-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3233"><num value="3233">§ 3233.</num><heading> Misuse of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence name, initials, or seal</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1c470ef-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3233/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibited acts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person may, except with the written permission of the Director of National Intelligence, or a designee of the Director, knowingly use the words “Office of the Director of National Intelligence”, the initials “ODNI”, the seal of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, or any colorable imitation of such words, initials, or seal in connection with any merchandise, impersonation, solicitation, or commercial activity in a manner reasonably calculated to convey the impression that such use is approved, endorsed, or authorized by the Director of National Intelligence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1c470f0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3233/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Injunction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever it appears to the Attorney General that any person is engaged or is about to engage in an act or practice which constitutes or will constitute conduct prohibited by subsection (a), the Attorney General may initiate a civil proceeding in a district court of the United States to enjoin such act or practice. Such court shall proceed as soon as practicable to the hearing and determination of such action and may, at any time before final determination, enter such restraining orders or prohibitions, or take such other action as is warranted, to prevent injury to the United States or to any person or class of persons for whose protection the action is brought.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1c470f1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title XI, § 1103, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tIV/s413/a">Pub. L. 111–259, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2726">124 Stat. 2726</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1c470f2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1c470f3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1c470f4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s442b">section 442b of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
