<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1c6ba83-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237"><num value="3237">§ 3237.</num><heading> Annual reports on influence operations and campaigns in the United States by the Chinese Communist Party</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1c6ba84-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On an annual basis, consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods, the Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center, in coordination with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, and any other relevant head of an element of the intelligence community, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the influence operations and campaigns in the United States conducted by the Chinese Communist Party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1c6ba85-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba86-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A description of the organization of the United Front Work Department of the People’s Republic of China, or the successors of the United Front Work Department, and the links between the United Front Work Department and the Central Committee of the Chinese Communist Party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba87-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An assessment of the degree to which organizations that are associated with or receive funding from the United Front Work Department, particularly such entities operating in the United States, are formally tasked by the Chinese Communist Party or the Government of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba88-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A description of the efforts by the United Front Work Department and subsidiary organizations of the United Front Work Department to target, coerce, and influence foreign populations, particularly those of ethnic Chinese descent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba89-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An assessment of attempts by the Chinese Embassy, consulates, and organizations affiliated with the Chinese Communist Party (including, at a minimum, the United Front Work Department) to influence the United States-based Chinese Student Scholar Associations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba8a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A description of the evolution of the role of the United Front Work Department under the leadership of the President of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba8b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> An assessment of the activities of the United Front Work Department designed to influence the opinions of elected leaders of the United States, or candidates for elections in the United States, with respect to issues of importance to the Chinese Communist Party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba8c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> A listing of all known organizations affiliated with the United Front Work Department that are operating in the United States as of the date of the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba8d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> An identification of influence activities and operations employed by the Chinese Communist Party against the United States science and technology sectors, specifically employees of the United States Government, researchers, scientists, and students in the science and technology sector in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba8e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> A listing of all known Chinese talent recruitment programs operating in the United States as of the date of the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba8f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> A listing of provincial, municipal, or other law enforcement institutions, including police departments, in the People’s Republic of China associated with establishing or maintaining a Chinese police presence in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba90-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> A listing of colleges and universities in the People’s Republic of China that conduct military research or host dedicated military initiatives or laboratories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1c6ba91-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> With respect to reports submitted after the first report, an assessment of the change in goals, tactics, techniques, and procedures of the influence operations and campaigns conducted by the Chinese Communist Party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1c6ba92-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3237/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1c6ba93-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title XI, § 1107, as added <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLV/s5511/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LV, § 5511(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2146">133 Stat. 2146</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dW/tVI/s605/a">Pub. L. 116–260, div. W, title VI, § 605(a)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2386">134 Stat. 2386</ref>, 2387; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/999">136 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVII/s6701">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXVII, § 6701</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1643">139 Stat. 1643</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1c6ba94-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1c6ba95-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1c6ba96-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6701/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6701(1)</ref>, inserted “, in coordination with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, and any other relevant head of an element of the intelligence community,” after “Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center” and “the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives,” after “congressional intelligence committees,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10) to (12). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6701/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6701(2)</ref>, added pars. (10) and (11) and redesignated former par. (10) as (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6701/3">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6701(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c). Prior to amendment, text of subsec. (c) read as follows: “In carrying out subsection (a), the Director shall coordinate with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, and any other relevant head of an element of the intelligence community.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b)(9), (10). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103">Pub. L. 117–103</ref> added par. (9) and redesignated former par. (9) as (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—<ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s605/d/1/A">Pub. L. 116–260, § 605(d)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Chinese Communist Party” for “Communist Party of China” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a), (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s605/d/1/B">Pub. L. 116–260, § 605(d)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Chinese Communist Party” for “Communist Party of China”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s605/a">Pub. L. 116–260, § 605(a)</ref>, added par. (8) and redesignated former par. (8) as (9).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1c6ba97-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1c6ba98-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Initial Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLV/s5511/c">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LV, § 5511(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2147">133 Stat. 2147</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLV/s5511/c">“The Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees [Select Committee on Intelligence and Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives], the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate the first report under section 1107 of the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3237">50 U.S.C. 3237</ref>], as added by subsection (a), by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
