<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1c92b29-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3302"><num value="3302">§ 3302.</num><heading> Identification of constituent components of base intelligence budget</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of Central Intelligence shall include the same level of budgetary detail for the Base Budget that is provided for Ongoing Initiatives and New Initiatives to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate in the congressional justification materials for the annual submission of the National Foreign Intelligence Program of each fiscal year.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idd1c92b2a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/359/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 103–359, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1994-10-14">Oct. 14, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3433">108 Stat. 3433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1c92b2b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1c92b2c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1c92b2d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403–1">section 403–1 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1c92b2e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idd1c92b2f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
