<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1cb9ca3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3329"><num value="3329">§ 3329.</num><heading> Intelligence community contracting</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9ca4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3329/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence shall direct that elements of the intelligence community, whenever compatible with the national security interests of the United States and consistent with the operational and security concerns related to the conduct of intelligence activities, and where fiscally sound, shall award contracts in a manner that would maximize the procurement of products in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9ca5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3329/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Intelligence community defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003/4">section 3003(4) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1cb9ca6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/183/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 102–183, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1267">105 Stat. 1267</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tVIII/s810">Pub. L. 111–259, title VIII, § 810</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2750">124 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1cb9ca7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1cb9ca8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1cb9ca9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403–2">section 403–2 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idd1cb9caa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in the following prior authorization act: <ref href="/us/pl/102/88/tIV/s404">Pub. L. 102–88, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/434">105 Stat. 434</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1cb9cab-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Pub. L. 111–259</ref> added subsec. (b), designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, substituted “Director of National Intelligence” for “Director of Central Intelligence” and “intelligence community” for “Intelligence Community”, and struck out at end “For purposes of this provision, the term ‘Intelligence Community’ has the same meaning as set forth in paragraph 3.4(f) of Executive Order 12333, dated <date date="1981-12-04">December 4, 1981</date>, or successor orders.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1cb9cac-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1cb9cad-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Intelligence Community Contracting With Chinese Military Companies Engaged in Biotechnology Research, Development, or Manufacturing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVII/s6703">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXVII, § 6703</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1644">139 Stat. 1644</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVII/s6703">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> 1260H <inline class="small-caps">list</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘1260H list’ means the list of Chinese military companies operating in the United States most recently submitted under section 1260H(b)(1) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 [<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113">10 U.S.C. 113</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Affiliate</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘affiliate’ means an entity that directly or indirectly controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Biotechnology</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘biotechnology’ means the use of biological processes, organisms, or systems for manufacturing, research, or medical purposes, including genetic engineering, synthetic biology, and bioinformatics.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to subsections (d) and (e), a head of an element of the intelligence community may not enter into, renew, or extend any contract for a product or service with—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any entity listed on the 1260H list that is engaged in biotechnology research, development, or manufacturing activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any entity that is a known or assessed affiliate of any entity described in paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any entity that has a known or assessed joint venture, partnership, or contractual relationship with any entity described in paragraph (1), if the Director of National Intelligence determines that the relationship presents a risk to the national security of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> any other entity that is engaged in biotechnology research, development, or manufacturing activities, if the Director of National Intelligence determines that the activities present a risk to the national security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation and Compliance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of National Intelligence shall, in consultation with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> establish guidelines for the implementation of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> maintain both a publicly available and classified list of entities covered by the prohibition in subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> require that each head of an element of the intelligence community ensure that any contractor engaged by the element certify that neither it nor any of its subcontractors are engaged in a contract for a product or service with an entity covered by the prohibition in subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> otherwise ensure compliance with subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver Process.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of National Intelligence may establish a waiver process for the heads of the elements of the intelligence community under which the head of the relevant element may waive the prohibition under subsection (b) for a procurement on a case-by-case basis. A waiver may be made under the process only if the head of the relevant element—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> complies with any conditions the Director may establish for the process; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> determines, in writing, that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the procurement is essential for national security and no reasonable alternative source exists; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> appropriate measures are in place to mitigate risks associated with the procurement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional notification</inline>.—</heading><content>For each waiver for a procurement issued under subsection (b) [probably should be “paragraph (1)”], the Director and the relevant head of the element of the intelligence community shall, not later than 30 days after issuing the waiver, submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a notice of the waiver, which shall include a justification for the waiver and a description of the risk mitigation measures implemented for the procurement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The prohibition in subsection (b) shall not apply to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> the acquisition or provision of health care services overseas for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> employees of the United States, including members of the uniformed services (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code), whose official duty stations are located overseas or who are on permissive temporary duty travel overseas; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> employees of contractors or subcontractors of the United States—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> who are performing under a contract that directly supports the missions or activities of individuals described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> whose primary duty stations are located overseas or who are on permissive temporary duty travel overseas; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the acquisition, use, or distribution of human multiomic data, lawfully compiled, that is commercially or publicly available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>This section shall take effect on the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>] and apply to any contract entered into, renewed, or extended on or after such effective date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of this section shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>This section shall only be construed to apply to activities of an element of the intelligence community.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6703">section 6703 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1cb9cae-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhanced Procurement Authority To Manage Supply Chain Risk</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/87/tIII/s309">Pub. L. 112–87, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="2012-01-03">Jan. 3, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1883">125 Stat. 1883</ref>, formerly set out as a note under this section, was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3334e">section 3334e of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
