<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1cb9caf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330"><num value="3330">§ 3330.</num><heading> Reports to the intelligence community on penetrations of networks and information systems of certain contractors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cb0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for reporting penetrations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence shall establish procedures that require each cleared intelligence contractor to report to an element of the intelligence community designated by the Director for purposes of such procedures when a network or information system of such contractor that meets the criteria established pursuant to subsection (b) is successfully penetrated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cb1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Networks and information systems subject to reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence shall, in consultation with appropriate officials, establish criteria for covered networks to be subject to the procedures for reporting system penetrations under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cb2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cb3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Rapid reporting</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The procedures established pursuant to subsection (a) shall require each cleared intelligence contractor to rapidly report to an element of the intelligence community designated pursuant to subsection (a) of each successful penetration of the network or information systems of such contractor that meet the criteria established pursuant to subsection (b). Each such report shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cb4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the technique or method used in such penetration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cb5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A sample of the malicious software, if discovered and isolated by the contractor, involved in such penetration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cb6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A summary of information created by or for such element in connection with any program of such element that has been potentially compromised due to such penetration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cb7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to equipment and information by intelligence community personnel</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The procedures established pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cb8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> include mechanisms for intelligence community personnel to, upon request, obtain access to equipment or information of a cleared intelligence contractor necessary to conduct forensic analysis in addition to any analysis conducted by such contractor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cb9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide that a cleared intelligence contractor is only required to provide access to equipment or information as described in subparagraph (A) to determine whether information created by or for an element of the intelligence community in connection with any intelligence community program was successfully exfiltrated from a network or information system of such contractor and, if so, what information was exfiltrated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cba-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide for the reasonable protection of trade secrets, commercial or financial information, and information that can be used to identify a specific person (other than the name of the suspected perpetrator of the penetration).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cbb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on dissemination of certain information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The procedures established pursuant to subsection (a) shall prohibit the dissemination outside the intelligence community of information obtained or derived through such procedures that is not created by or for the intelligence community except—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cbc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with the approval of the contractor providing such information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cbd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to the congressional intelligence committees or the Subcommittees on Defense of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate for such committees and such Subcommittees to perform oversight; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1cb9cbe-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to law enforcement agencies to investigate a penetration reported under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cbf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of procedures and establishment of criteria</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cc0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, the Director of National Intelligence shall establish the procedures required under subsection (a) and the criteria required under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cc1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The requirements of this section shall apply on the date on which the Director of National Intelligence establishes the procedures required under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cc2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with the Secretary of Defense to prevent duplicate reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, the Director of National Intelligence and the Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures to permit a contractor that is a cleared intelligence contractor and a cleared defense contractor under section 941 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2224">10 U.S.C. 2224</ref> note) to submit a single report that satisfies the requirements of this section and such section 941 for an incident of penetration of network or information system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cc3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cc4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Cleared intelligence contractor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “cleared intelligence contractor” means a private entity granted clearance by the Director of National Intelligence or the head of an element of the intelligence community to access, receive, or store classified information for the purpose of bidding for a contract or conducting activities in support of any program of an element of the intelligence community.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cc5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered network</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “covered network” means a network or information system of a cleared intelligence contractor that contains or processes information created by or for an element of the intelligence community with respect to which such contractor is required to apply enhanced protection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1cb9cc6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3330/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings clauses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or limit any otherwise authorized access by government personnel to networks or information systems owned or operated by a contractor that processes or stores government data.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1cb9cc7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tIII/s325">Pub. L. 113–126, title III, § 325</ref>, <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1402">128 Stat. 1402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1cb9cc8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1cb9cc9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idd1cb9cca-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 113–126</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
