<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1d057c8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p"><num value="3334p">§ 3334p.</num><heading> Increased intelligence-related engineering, research, and development capabilities of minority institutions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057c9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057ca-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director of National Intelligence shall develop a plan to promote intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities at covered institutions for the purpose of contributing toward the research necessary to achieve the intelligence advantage of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057cb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The plan under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d057cc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An assessment of opportunities to support engineering, research, and development at covered institutions in computer sciences, including artificial intelligence, quantum computing, and machine learning, and synthetic biology and an assessment of opportunities to support the associated workforce and physical research infrastructure of such institutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d057cd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> An assessment of opportunities to enhance the ability of covered institutions—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d057ce-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to participate in intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d057cf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to effectively compete for intelligence-related engineering, research and development contracts in support of the most urgent research requirements of the intelligence community.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d057d0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> An assessment of the activities and investments the Director determines necessary—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d057d1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to expand opportunities for covered institutions to partner with other research organizations and educational institutions that the intelligence community frequently partners with to conduct research; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d057d2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to increase participation of covered institutions in intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d057d3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Recommendations identifying actions that may be taken by the Director, Congress, covered institutions, and other organizations to increase participation of such institutions in intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities and contracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d057d4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Specific goals, incentives, and metrics to increase and measure the capacity of covered institutions to address the engineering, research, and development needs of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057d5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In developing the plan under paragraph (1), the Director shall consult with covered institutions and other departments or agencies of the United States Government or private sector organizations that the Director determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057d6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available on the internet website of the Director, a report containing the plan under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057d7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities to support research and engineering capacity</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Director may establish a program to award contracts, grants, or other agreements, on a competitive basis, and to perform other appropriate activities, for any of the following purposes:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057d8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Developing the capability, including the workforce and the research infrastructure, for covered institutions to more effectively compete for intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities and contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057d9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any other purposes the Director determines appropriate to enhance the capabilities of covered institutions to carry out intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities and contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057da-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Increased partnerships between IARPA and covered institutions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall establish goals and incentives to encourage the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057db-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> partner with covered institutions to advance the research and development needs of the intelligence community through partnerships and collaborations with the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057dc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the Director determines appropriate, foster the establishment of similar relationships between such institutions and other organizations that have partnerships with the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057dd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered institution defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “covered institution” means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057de-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A part B institution (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1061">section 1061 of title 20</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057df-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334p/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An institution of higher education (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of title 20</ref>) not covered by paragraph (1) at which not less than 50 percent of the total student enrollment consists of students from ethnic groups that are underrepresented in the fields of science and engineering, as determined by the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1d2a0d0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVIII/s6812">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVIII, § 6812</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3602">136 Stat. 3602</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1d2a0d1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1d2a0d2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idd1d2a0d3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
