<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1d057a3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n"><num value="3334n">§ 3334n.</num><heading> Certification relating to information technology and software systems</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057a4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Certifications required</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Prior to the date on which the head of an element of the intelligence community enters into, renews, or extends a contract for the acquisition of an information technology or software system, the head shall certify to the Director of National Intelligence the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057a5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> That the information technology or software system is the most up-to-date version of the system available or, if it is not, why a more out of date version was chosen.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057a6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> That the information technology or software system is compatible with integrating new and emerging technologies, such as artificial intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057a7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> That the information technology or software system was thoroughly reviewed and alternative products are not superior to meet the requirements of the element.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057a8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of National Intelligence may exempt elements of the intelligence community, as appropriate, from the requirements under (a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002090">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002090"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection (a)”.</note> if meeting such requirements may pose security or operational risks.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d057a9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall issue to the heads of the elements of the intelligence community, and submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, guidance to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057aa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish guidelines that the heads of the relevant elements of the intelligence community shall use to evaluate the criteria required for the certifications under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057ab-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> incentivize each such head to adopt and integrate new and emerging technology within information technology and software systems of the element and to decommission and replace outdated systems, including through potential funding enhancements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d057ac-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3334n/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> incentivize, and hold accountable, personnel of the intelligence community with respect to the integration of new and emerging technology within such systems, including through the provision of appropriate training programs and evaluations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1d057ad-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVII/s6718">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6718</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3577">136 Stat. 3577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1d057ae-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1d057af-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idd1d057b0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of “intelligence community” and “congressional intelligence committees” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of “emerging technology” and “artificial intelligence” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s6701">section 6701 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3024">section 3024 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
