<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1d2a11b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341"><num value="3341">§ 3341.</num><heading> Security clearances</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a11c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a11d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “agency” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a11e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an executive agency (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s105">section 105 of title 5</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a11f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a military department (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s102">section 102 of title 5</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a120-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an element of the intelligence community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a121-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “authorized investigative agency” means an agency designated by the head of the agency selected pursuant to subsection (b) to conduct a counterintelligence investigation or investigation of persons who are proposed for access to classified information to ascertain whether such persons satisfy the criteria for obtaining and retaining access to such information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a122-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “authorized adjudicative agency” means an agency authorized by law, regulation, or direction of the Director of National Intelligence to determine eligibility for access to classified information in accordance with Executive Order 12968.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a123-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The term “highly sensitive program” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a124-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a government program designated as a Special Access Program (as that term is defined in section 4.1(h) of Executive Order 12958 or any successor Executive order); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a125-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> a government program that applies restrictions required for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a126-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> restricted data (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2014/y">section 2014(y) of title 42</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a127-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> other information commonly referred to as “sensitive compartmented information”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a128-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The term “current investigation file” means, with respect to a security clearance, a file on an investigation or adjudication that has been conducted during—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a129-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the 5-year period beginning on the date the security clearance was granted, in the case of a Top Secret Clearance, or the date access was granted to a highly sensitive program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a12a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the 10-year period beginning on the date the security clearance was granted in the case of a Secret Clearance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a12b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the 15-year period beginning on the date the security clearance was granted in the case of a Confidential Clearance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a12c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “personnel security investigation” means any investigation required for the purpose of determining the eligibility of any military, civilian, or government contractor personnel to access classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a12d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> The term “periodic reinvestigations” means investigations conducted for the purpose of updating a previously completed background investigation—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a12e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> every 5 years in the case of a top secret clearance or access to a highly sensitive program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a12f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> every 10 years in the case of a secret clearance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a130-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> every 15 years in the case of a Confidential Clearance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a131-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a132-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committees on Armed Services, Homeland Security, Government Reform, and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a133-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committees on Armed Services, Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Judiciary of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a134-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Access determination</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “access determination” means the determination regarding whether an employee—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a135-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is eligible for access to classified information in accordance with Executive Order 12968 (60 Fed. Reg. 40245; relating to access to classified information), or any successor thereto, and Executive Order 10865 (25 Fed. Reg. 1583; relating to safeguarding classified information within industry), or any successor thereto; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a136-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/a/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> possesses a need to know under such an Order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a137-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of entity</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, not later than 90 days after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, the President shall select a single department, agency, or element of the executive branch to be responsible for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a138-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> directing day-to-day oversight of investigations and adjudications for personnel security clearances, including for highly sensitive programs, throughout the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a139-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> developing and implementing uniform and consistent policies and procedures to ensure the effective, efficient, and timely completion of security clearances and determinations for access to highly sensitive programs, including the standardization of security questionnaires, financial disclosure requirements for security clearance applicants, and polygraph policies and procedures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a13a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> serving as the final authority to designate an authorized investigative agency or authorized adjudicative agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a13b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> ensuring reciprocal recognition of access to classified information among the agencies of the United States Government, including acting as the final authority to arbitrate and resolve disputes involving the reciprocity of security clearances and access to highly sensitive programs pursuant to subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a13c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> ensuring, to the maximum extent practicable, that sufficient resources are available in each agency to achieve clearance and investigative program goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a13d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> reviewing and coordinating the development of tools and techniques for enhancing the conduct of investigations and granting of clearances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a13e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> not later than 180 days after <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, and consistent with subsection (j)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a13f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> developing policies and procedures that permit, to the extent practicable, individuals alleging reprisal for having made a protected disclosure (provided the individual does not disclose classified information or other information contrary to law) to appeal any action affecting an employee’s access to classified information and to retain their government employment status while such challenge is pending; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a140-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> developing and implementing uniform and consistent policies and procedures to ensure proper protections during the process for denying, suspending, or revoking a security clearance or access to classified information following a protected disclosure, including the ability to appeal such a denial, suspension, or revocation, except that there shall be no appeal of an agency’s suspension of a security clearance or access determination for purposes of conducting an investigation, if that suspension lasts no longer than 1 year or the head of the agency or a designee of the head of the agency certifies that a longer suspension is needed before a final decision on denial or revocation to prevent imminent harm to the national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a141-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance of security clearance investigations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a142-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 180 days after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, the President shall, in consultation with the head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b), select a single agency of the executive branch to conduct, to the maximum extent practicable, security clearance investigations of employees and contractor personnel of the United States Government who require access to classified information and to provide and maintain all security clearances of such employees and contractor personnel. The head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) may designate other agencies to conduct such investigations if the head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) considers it appropriate for national security and efficiency purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a143-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The agency selected under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a144-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> take all necessary actions to carry out the requirements of this section, including entering into a memorandum of understanding with any agency carrying out responsibilities relating to security clearances or security clearance investigations before <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a145-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> as soon as practicable, integrate reporting of security clearance applications, security clearance investigations, and determinations of eligibility for security clearances, with the database required by subsection (e); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a146-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> ensure that security clearance investigations are conducted in accordance with uniform standards and requirements established under subsection (b), including uniform security questionnaires and financial disclosure requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a147-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reciprocity of security clearance and access determinations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a148-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> All security clearance background investigations and determinations completed by an authorized investigative agency or authorized adjudicative agency shall be accepted by all agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a149-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> All security clearance background investigations initiated by an authorized investigative agency shall be transferable to any other authorized investigative agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a14a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a14b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An authorized investigative agency or authorized adjudicative agency may not establish additional investigative or adjudicative requirements (other than requirements for the conduct of a polygraph examination) that exceed requirements specified in Executive Orders establishing security requirements for access to classified information without the approval of the head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a14c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) may establish such additional requirements as the head of such entity considers necessary for national security purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a14d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An authorized investigative agency or authorized adjudicative agency may not conduct an investigation for purposes of determining whether to grant a security clearance to an individual where a current investigation or clearance of equal level already exists or has been granted by another authorized adjudicative agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a14e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) may disallow the reciprocal recognition of an individual security clearance by an agency under this section on a case-by-case basis if the head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) determines that such action is necessary for national security purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a14f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) shall establish a review procedure by which agencies can seek review of actions required under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a150-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Database on security clearances</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a151-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 12 months after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, in cooperation with the heads of the entities selected pursuant to subsections (b) and (c), establish and commence operating and maintaining an integrated, secure, database into which appropriate data relevant to the granting, denial, or revocation of a security clearance or access pertaining to military, civilian, or government contractor personnel shall be entered from all authorized investigative and adjudicative agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a152-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The database under this subsection shall function to integrate information from existing Federal clearance tracking systems from other authorized investigative and adjudicative agencies into a single consolidated database.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a153-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Each authorized investigative or adjudicative agency shall check the database under this subsection to determine whether an individual the agency has identified as requiring a security clearance has already been granted or denied a security clearance, or has had a security clearance revoked, by any other authorized investigative or adjudicative agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a154-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) shall evaluate the extent to which an agency is submitting information to, and requesting information from, the database under this subsection as part of a determination of whether to certify the agency as an authorized investigative agency or authorized adjudicative agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a155-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) may authorize an agency to withhold information about certain individuals from the database under this subsection if the head of the entity considers it necessary for national security purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a156-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation of use of available technology in clearance investigations and adjudications</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a157-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) shall evaluate the use of available information technology and databases to expedite investigative and adjudicative processes for all and to verify standard information submitted as part of an application for a security clearance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a158-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The evaluation shall assess the application of the technologies described in paragraph (1) for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a159-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> granting interim clearances to applicants at the secret, top secret, and special access program levels before the completion of the appropriate full investigation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a15a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> expediting investigations and adjudications of security clearances, including verification of information submitted by the applicant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a15b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> ongoing verification of suitability of personnel with security clearances in effect for continued access to classified information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a15c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> use of such technologies to augment periodic reinvestigations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a15d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> assessing the impact of the use of such technologies on the rights of applicants to verify, correct, or challenge information obtained through such technologies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d2a15e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> such other purposes as the head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a15f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An individual subject to verification utilizing the technology described in paragraph (1) shall be notified of such verification, shall provide consent to such use, and shall have access to data being verified in order to correct errors or challenge information the individual believes is incorrect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d2a160-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Not later than one year after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, the head of the entity selected pursuant to subsection (b) shall submit to the President and the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the results of the evaluation, including recommendations on the use of technologies described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a161-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold">, (h). Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tVII">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title VII</ref>, §§ 7702(a)(3), 7703(c), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1101">137 Stat. 1101</ref>, 1102</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a162-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2005 and each fiscal year thereafter for the implementation, maintenance, and operation of the database required by subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a163-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Retaliatory revocation of security clearances and access determinations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a164-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Agency personnel with authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve personnel security clearance or access determinations shall not take or fail to take, or threaten to take or fail to take, any action with respect to any employee’s security clearance or access determination in retaliation for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a165-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> any lawful disclosure of information to the Director of National Intelligence (or an employee designated by the Director of National Intelligence for such purpose) or a supervisor in the employee’s direct chain of command, or a supervisor of the employing agency with responsibility for the subject matter of the disclosure, up to and including the head of the employing agency (or employee designated by the head of that agency for such purpose) by an employee that the employee reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a166-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a violation of any Federal law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a167-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a168-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> any lawful disclosure to the Inspector General of an agency or another employee designated by the head of the agency to receive such disclosures, of information which the employee reasonably believes evidences—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a169-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a violation of any Federal law, rule, or regulation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a16a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a16b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> any lawful disclosure that complies with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a16c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subsections (a)(1), (d), and (h) of section 8H of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002094">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002094"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a16d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subparagraphs (A), (D), and (H) of <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3517/d/5">section 3517(d)(5) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a16e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> subparagraphs (A), (D), and (I) of <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3033/k/5">section 3033(k)(5) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a16f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> if the actions do not result in the employee or applicant unlawfully disclosing information specifically required by Executive order to be kept classified in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs, any lawful disclosure in conjunction with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a170-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the exercise of any appeal, complaint, or grievance right granted by any law, rule, or regulation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a171-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> testimony for or otherwise lawfully assisting any individual in the exercise of any right referred to in clause (i); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a172-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/1/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> cooperation with or disclosing information to the Inspector General of an agency, in accordance with applicable provisions of law in connection with an audit, inspection, or investigation conducted by the Inspector General.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a173-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Consistent with the protection of sources and methods, nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to authorize the withholding of information from Congress or the taking of any personnel action or clearance action against an employee who lawfully discloses information to Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a174-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A disclosure shall not be excluded from paragraph (1) because—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a175-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the disclosure was made to a person, including a supervisor, who participated in an activity that the employee reasonably believed to be covered by paragraph (1)(A)(ii);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a176-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the disclosure revealed information that had been previously disclosed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a177-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the disclosure was not made in writing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a178-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the disclosure was made while the employee was off duty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a179-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> of the amount of time which has passed since the occurrence of the events described in the disclosure; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a17a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the disclosure was made during the normal course of duties of an employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a17b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency adjudication</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a17c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Remedial procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An employee or former employee who believes that he or she has been subjected to a reprisal prohibited by paragraph (1) may, within 90 days (except as provided by subparagraph (D)) after the issuance of notice of such decision, appeal that decision within the agency of that employee or former employee through proceedings authorized by subsection (b)(7), except that there shall be no appeal of an agency’s suspension of a security clearance or access determination for purposes of conducting an investigation, if that suspension lasts not longer than 1 year (or a longer period in accordance with a certification made under subsection (b)(7)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a17d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Corrective action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If, in the course of proceedings authorized under subparagraph (A), it is determined that the adverse security clearance or access determination violated paragraph (1), the agency shall take specific corrective action to return the employee or former employee, as nearly as practicable and reasonable, to the position such employee or former employee would have held had the violation not occurred. Such corrective action may include back pay and related benefits, travel expenses, and compensatory damages not to exceed $300,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a17e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributing factor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In determining whether the adverse security clearance or access determination violated paragraph (1), the agency shall find that paragraph (1) was violated if a disclosure described in paragraph (1) was a contributing factor in the adverse security clearance or access determination taken against the individual, unless the agency demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that it would have taken the same action in the absence of such disclosure, giving the utmost deference to the agency’s assessment of the particular threat to the national security interests of the United States in the instant matter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a17f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Tolling</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The time requirement established by subparagraph (A) for an employee or former employee to appeal the decision of an agency may be tolled if the employee or former employee presents substantial credible evidence showing why the employee or former employee did not timely initiate the appeal and why the enforcement of the time requirement would be unfair, such as evidence showing that the employee or former employee—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a180-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> did not receive notice of the decision; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd1d2a181-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> could not timely initiate the appeal because of factors beyond the control of the employee or former employee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a182-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Appellate review of security clearance access determinations by Director of National Intelligence</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a183-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Appeal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Within 60 days after receiving notice of an adverse final agency determination under a proceeding under paragraph (4), an employee or former employee may appeal that determination in accordance with the procedures established under subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a184-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Policies and procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Defense, shall develop and implement policies and procedures for adjudicating the appeals authorized by subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a185-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Consistent with the protection of sources and methods, at the time the Director of National Intelligence issues an order regarding an appeal pursuant to the policies and procedures established by this paragraph, the Director of National Intelligence shall notify the congressional intelligence committees.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a186-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit or require judicial review of any—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a187-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> agency action under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1d2a188-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> action of the appellate review procedures established under paragraph (5).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a189-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Private cause of action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit, authorize, or require a private cause of action to challenge the merits of a security clearance determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a18a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the President shall provide for the enforcement of this section consistent, to the fullest extent possible, with the policies and procedures used to adjudicate alleged violations of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2302/b/8">section 2302(b)(8) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d2a18b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3341/j/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion of contractor employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “employee” includes an employee of a contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor, of an agency. With respect to such employees, the term “employing agency” shall be deemed to be the contracting agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1d2a18c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tIII/s3001">Pub. L. 108–458, title III, § 3001</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3705">118 Stat. 3705</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tVI/s602/a/1">Pub. L. 113–126, title VI, § 602(a)(1)</ref>, (b), (c), <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1416">128 Stat. 1416</ref>, 1417, 1419; <ref href="/us/pl/113/293/tIII/s310">Pub. L. 113–293, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3999">128 Stat. 3999</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/118/tI/s110/c">Pub. L. 115–118, title I, § 110(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-01-19">Jan. 19, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/17">132 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title V, § 501(b)</ref>–(d)(1), (e)(2), (h)–(k), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/981-985">136 Stat. 981–985</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/b/101">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(101)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4353">136 Stat. 4353</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tVII">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title VII</ref>, §§ 7702(a)(3), 7703(c), title IX, § 7901(e), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1101">137 Stat. 1101</ref>, 1102, 1107.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1d2a18d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1d2a18e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd1d2a18f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12968, referred to in subsec. (a)(3), (9)(A), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12958, referred to in subsec. (a)(4)(A), which was formerly set out as a note under section 435 (now section 3161) of this title, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13526, § 6.2(g), <date date="2009-12-29">Dec. 29, 2009</date>, 75 F.R. 731.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 10865, referred to in subsec. (a)(9)(A), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8H of the Inspector General Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (j)(1)(C)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/452/s8H">section 8H of Pub. L. 95–452</ref>, which was formerly set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s416">section 416 of Title 5</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s3/b">Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4242">136 Stat. 4242</ref>. Subsecs. (a)(1) and (d) of section 8H were enacted as subsecs. (b)(1) and (e), respectively, of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s416">section 416 of Title 5</ref>. Subsec. (h) of section 8H, which defined terms for the section, was enacted as subsec. (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s416">section 416 of Title 5</ref>, while subsec. (g) of section 8H, which related to notifying the congressional intelligence committees regarding the submission of a complaint or information, was enacted as subsec. (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s416">section 416 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1d2a190-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s435b">section 435b of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1d2a191-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(4)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7901/e/1/A">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7901(e)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “);” for semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7901/e/1/B">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7901(e)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “within industry” for “with industry”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7702/a/3">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7702(a)(3)</ref>, struck out subsec. (g) which related to reduction in length of personnel security clearance process.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7703/c">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7703(c)</ref>, struck out subsec. (h) which related to annual reports.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s7901/e/2">Pub. L. 118–31, § 7901(e)(2)</ref>, substituted “(d), and (h) of section 8H” for “(d), and (g) of section 8H”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/c">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(c)</ref>, substituted “or” for “and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/j">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(j)</ref>, substituted “to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve” for “over” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/e/2">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(e)(2)</ref>, inserted “a supervisor in the employee’s direct chain of command, or a supervisor of the employing agency with responsibility for the subject matter of the disclosure, up to and including” before “the head of the employing agency” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(A)(ii), (B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/d/1">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “mismanagement” for “gross mismanagement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref>, which directed substitution of “subsections (b)(1), (e), and (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s416">section 416 of title 5</ref>;” for “subsections (a)(1), (d), and (h) of section 8H of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.);”, could not be executed because “(h)” did not appear in text after the intervening amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/k">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(k)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/k">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(k)</ref>, substituted “(g)” for “(h)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/i">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(i)</ref>, inserted “or clearance action” after “personnel action”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/h">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(h)</ref>, reenacted heading of par. (3), designated introductory provisions of subpar. (A) as introductory provisions of par. (3), redesignated cls. (i) to (v) of former subpar. (A) as subpars. (A) to (E), respectively, of par. (3), realigned margins, added subpar. (F), and struck out former subpar. (A) heading and former subpar. (B). Text of former subpar. (B) read as follows: “If a disclosure is made during the normal course of duties of an employee, the disclosure shall not be excluded from paragraph (1) if any employee who has authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action with respect to the employee making the disclosure, took, failed to take, or threatened to take or fail to take a personnel action with respect to that employee in reprisal for the disclosure.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/b/2/A">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “(except as provided by subparagraph (D))” after “within 90 days”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/b/2/B">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(b)(2)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s501/b/1">Pub. L. 117–103, § 501(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (8) and redesignated former par. (8) as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (j)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/115/118">Pub. L. 115–118</ref> added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s602/c">Pub. L. 113–126, § 602(c)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s602/a/1/A">Pub. L. 113–126, § 602(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Except as otherwise provided, not” for “Not” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/113/293/s310/1">Pub. L. 113–293, § 310(1)</ref>, inserted “, and consistent with subsection (j)” after “2014” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s602/a/1/B">Pub. L. 113–126, § 602(a)(1)(B)</ref>–(D), added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/293/s310/2">Pub. L. 113–293, § 310(2)</ref>, substituted “alleging reprisal for having made a protected disclosure (provided the individual does not disclose classified information or other information contrary to law) to appeal any action affecting an employee’s access to classified information” for “to appeal a determination to suspend or revoke a security clearance or access to classified information”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/293/s310/3">Pub. L. 113–293, § 310(3)</ref>, substituted “information following a protected disclosure,” for “information,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/113/126/s602/b">Pub. L. 113–126, § 602(b)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1d2a192-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idd1d2a193-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1d2a194-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tVI/s602/e">Pub. L. 113–126, title VI, § 602(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1419">128 Stat. 1419</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/126/tVI/s602/e">“Nothing in section 3001 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3341">50 U.S.C. 3341</ref>), as amended by this title, shall be construed to require the repeal or replacement of agency appeal procedures implementing Executive Order 12968 (60 Fed. Reg. 40245; relating to access to classified information) [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">50 U.S.C. 3161</ref> note], or any successor thereto, and Executive Order 10865 (25 Fed. Reg. 1583; relating to safeguarding classified information with[in] industry) [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">50 U.S.C. 3161</ref> note], or any successor thereto, that meet the requirements of paragraph (7) of section 3001(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/7">50 U.S.C. 3341(b)(7)</ref>], as added by this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1d2a195-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Performance Measures Regarding Timeliness for Personnel Mobility</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/972">136 Stat. 972</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIII/s311">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>], the Director of National Intelligence shall issue a policy for measuring the total time it takes to transfer personnel with security clearances and eligibility for access to information commonly referred to as ‘sensitive compartmented information’ from one element of the intelligence community to another, or from one contract to another in the case of a contractor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy issued under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to the degree practicable, cover all personnel who are moving to positions that require a security clearance and access to sensitive compartmented information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> cover the period from the first time an element of the intelligence community or company submits a request to an element of the intelligence community for the transfer of the employment of an individual with a clearance access or eligibility determination to another element of the intelligence community, to the time the individual is authorized by that receiving element to start to work in the new position; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> include analysis of all appropriate phases of the process, including polygraph, suitability determination, fitness determination, human resources review, transfer of the sensitive compartmented information access, and contract actions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updated Policies.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Modifications</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Director issues the policy under subsection (a), the Director shall issue modifications to such policies as the Director determines were issued before the issuance of the policy under such subsection and are relevant to such updated policy, as the Director considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Director issues the policy under subsection (a), the Director shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees recommendations for legislative action to update metrics specified elsewhere in statute to measure parts of the process that support transfers described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after issuing the policy required by subsection (a) and not less frequently than once each year thereafter until the date that is 3 years after the date of such issuance, the Director shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of such policy. Such report shall address performance by department or agency and by clearance type in meeting such policy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Congressional Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the congressional intelligence committees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Subcommittees on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “congressional intelligence committees” and “intelligence community” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/s311">section 311 of div. X of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/s2">section 2 of div. X of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1d2a196-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Required Elements of Policies and Procedures</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tVI/s602/a/2">Pub. L. 113–126, title VI, § 602(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1416">128 Stat. 1416</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/126/tVI/s602/a/2">“The policies and procedures for appeal developed under paragraph (7) of section 3001(b) of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3341/b/7">50 U.S.C. 3341(b)(7)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall provide for the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, or the inspector general of the employing agency, to conduct fact-finding and report to the agency head or the designee of the agency head within 180 days unless the employee and the agency agree to an extension or the investigating inspector general determines in writing that a greater period of time is required. To the fullest extent possible, such fact-finding shall include an opportunity for the employee to present relevant evidence such as witness testimony.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1d2a197-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Existing Rights Preserved</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/126/tVI/s602/d">Pub. L. 113–126, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-07">July 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1419">128 Stat. 1419</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/126/tVI/s602/d">“Nothing in this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to preempt, preclude, or otherwise prevent an individual from exercising rights, remedies, or avenues of redress currently provided under any other law, regulation, or rule.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd1d2a198-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Strategy for Security Clearance Reciprocity</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/277/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 112–277, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2472">126 Stat. 2472</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/277/tIII/s306">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President shall develop a strategy and a schedule for carrying out the requirements of section 3001(d) of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s435b/d">50 U.S.C. 435b(d)</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3341/d">50 U.S.C. 3341(d)</ref>]. Such strategy and schedule shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a process for accomplishing the reciprocity required under such section for a security clearance issued by a department or agency of the Federal Government, including reciprocity for security clearances that are issued to both persons who are and who are not employees of the Federal Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a description of the specific circumstances under which a department or agency of the Federal Government may not recognize a security clearance issued by another department or agency of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>], the President shall inform Congress of the strategy and schedule developed under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
