<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1d9cd13-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d"><num value="3355d">§ 3355d.</num><heading> Standards and procedures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d9cd14-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Liaison</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd15-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The head of each agency with the authority under an Executive order to classify information and the head of each Federal Presidential library shall designate an employee of such agency or library to act as liaison to the Board for purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd16-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Board may establish liaison and otherwise consult with such other historical and advisory committees as the Board considers appropriate for purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d9cd17-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on access</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd18-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd19-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), if the head of an agency or the head of a Federal Presidential library determines it necessary to deny or restrict access of the Board, or of the agency or library liaison to the Board, to information contained in a record or material, in whole or in part, the head of the agency or the head of the library shall promptly notify the Board in writing of such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd1a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Each notice to the Board under subparagraph (A) shall include a description of the nature of the records or materials, and a justification for the determination, covered by such notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd1b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of a determination referred to in paragraph (1) with respect to a special access program created by the Secretary of Defense, the Director of National Intelligence, or the head of any other agency, the notification of denial of access under paragraph (1), including a description of the nature of the Board’s request for access, shall be submitted to the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs rather than to the Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d9cd1c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Discretion to disclose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the conclusion of a declassification review, the head of an agency may, in the discretion of the head of the agency, determine that the public’s interest in the disclosure of records or materials of the agency covered by such review, and still properly classified, outweighs the Government’s need to protect such records or materials, and may release such records or materials in accordance with the provisions of Executive Order 13526 or any successor order to such Executive order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d9cd1d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Discretion to protect</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the conclusion of a declassification review, the head of an agency may, in the discretion of the head of the agency, determine that the interest of the agency in the protection of records or materials of the agency covered by such review, and still properly classified, outweighs the public’s need for access to such records or materials, and may deny release of such records or materials in accordance with the provisions of Executive Order 13526 or any successor order to such Executive order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d9cd1e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd1f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd20-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Board shall annually submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the activities of the Board under this subchapter, including summary information regarding any denials to the Board by the head of an agency or the head of a Federal Presidential library of access to records or materials under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd21-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In this paragraph, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1d9cd22-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), notice that the Board has been denied access to records and materials, and a justification for the determination in support of the denial, shall be submitted by the agency denying the access as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d9cd23-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of the denial of access to a special access program created by the Secretary of Defense, to the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and to the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d9cd24-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of the denial of access to a special access program created by the Director of National Intelligence, or by the head of any other agency (including the Department of Defense) if the special access program pertains to intelligence activities, or of access to any information and materials relating to intelligence sources and methods, to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1d9cd25-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of the denial of access to a special access program created by the Secretary of Energy or the Administrator for Nuclear Security, to the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and to the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1d9cd26-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3355d/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In response to a specific congressional request for declassification review described in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3355a/b/5">section 3355a(b)(5) of this title</ref>, the Board shall advise the originators of the request in a timely manner whether the Board intends to conduct such review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1d9cd27-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/567/tVII/s706">Pub. L. 106–567, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2861">114 Stat. 2861</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tI/s1102/e">Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1102(e)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3700">118 Stat. 3700</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tVI/s602/1">Pub. L. 110–53, title VI, § 602(1)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/335">121 Stat. 335</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXVIII/s6824/d/4">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVIII, § 6824(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3615">136 Stat. 3615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1d9cd28-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1d9cd29-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd1d9cd2a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 13526, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (d), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1d9cd2b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1d9cd2c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> substituted “Executive Order 13526” for “Executive Order No. 12958”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsecs. (b)(2), (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/53">Pub. L. 110–53</ref> substituted “Director of National Intelligence” for “Director of Central Intelligence”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1d9cd2d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idd1d9cd2e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, <date date="2004-10-09">Oct. 9, 2004</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
