<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1e0f901-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374"><num value="3374">§ 3374.</num><heading> Requirements with respect to duty to warn former senior officials and other United States persons</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1e0f902-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that Congress is gravely concerned about the ongoing threat of lethal plotting against United States persons from adversary nations, including those against numerous former senior United States officials, principally from the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran. Information collected regarding plots against United States persons requires expeditious fulfilment of the duty to warn process of the intelligence community, including close consultation with the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1e0f903-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of warning</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1e0f904-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If an element of the intelligence community determines pursuant to procedures established in accordance with Intelligence Community Directive 191 (or any successor directive) that such element has a duty to warn a United States person inside the United States of an impending threat and, after consultation with the Federal Bureau of Investigation when required, notifies such person or facilitates notification of such person by another party, the head of such element shall also immediately provide notice of the warning to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and, if such person is under the protection of an element of the Federal Government, a person responsible for the protection of such United States person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd1e0f905-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Process for notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If notice is required under paragraph (1) to a person responsible for the protection of a United States person, such notice may be made in any appropriate and expeditious manner, including through the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1e0f906-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal Bureau of Investigation records of warnings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall establish a process for documenting and maintaining records of each notice of a warning provided to the Director in accordance with subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1e0f907-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit any duty to warn already in effect, including under Intelligence Community Directive 191 (relating to duty to warn) and any policies or procedures issued in accordance with such directive.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1e0f908-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3374/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> United States person defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “United States person” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3039">section 3039 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1e0f909-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVII/s6718">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXVII, § 6718</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1651">139 Stat. 1651</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1e0f90a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1e0f90b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idd1e0f90c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of “intelligence community” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
