<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1e5b46f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510"><num value="3510">§ 3510.</num><heading> Appropriations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b470-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, sums made available to the Agency by appropriation or otherwise may be expended for purposes necessary to carry out its functions, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1e5b471-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> personal services, including personal services without regard to limitations on types of persons to be employed, and rent at the seat of government and elsewhere; health-service program as authorized by law (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7901">5 U.S.C. 7901</ref>); payment of death benefits in cases in which the circumstances of the death of an employee of the Agency, a detailee of the Agency or other employee of another department or agency of the Federal Government assigned to the Agency, or an individual affiliated with the Agency (as determined by the Director), is not covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3511">section 3511 of this title</ref>, other similar provisions of Federal law, or any regulation issued by the Director providing death benefits, but that the Director determines such payment appropriate; rental of news-reporting services; purchase or rental and operation of photographic, reproduction, cryptographic, duplication, and printing machines, equipment, and devices, and radio-receiving and radio-sending equipment and devices, including telegraph and teletype equipment; purchase, maintenance, operation, repair, and hire of passenger motor vehicles, and aircraft, and vessels of all kinds; subject to policies established by the Director, transportation of officers and employees of the Agency in Government-owned automotive equipment between their domiciles and places of employment, where such personnel are engaged in work which makes such transportation necessary, and transportation in such equipment, to and from school, of children of Agency personnel who have quarters for themselves and their families at isolated stations outside the continental United States where adequate public or private transportation is not available; printing and binding; purchase, maintenance, and cleaning of firearms, including purchase, storage, and maintenance of ammunition; subject to policies established by the Director, expenses of travel in connection with, and expenses incident to attendance at meetings of professional, technical, scientific, and other similar organizations when such attendance would be a benefit in the conduct of the work of the Agency; association and library dues; payment of premiums or costs of surety bonds for officers or employees without regard to the provisions of section 14 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002103">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002103"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 6; payment of claims pursuant to title 28; acquisition of necessary land and the clearing of such land; construction of buildings and facilities without regard to <ref href="/us/stat/36/699">36 Stat. 699</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s259">40 U.S.C. 259</ref>, 267; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002103">1</ref> repair, rental, operation, and maintenance of buildings, utilities, facilities, and appurtenances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1e5b472-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> supplies, equipment, and personnel and contractual services otherwise authorized by law and regulations, when approved by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b473-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The sums made available to the Agency may be expended without regard to the provisions of law and regulations relating to the expenditure of Government funds; and for objects of a confidential, extraordinary, or emergency nature, such expenditures to be accounted for solely on the certificate of the Director and every such certificate shall be deemed a sufficient voucher for the amount therein certified.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b474-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b475-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Director makes a novel and significant expenditure pursuant to subsection (a), the Director shall notify the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives of such expenditure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b476-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b477-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Not later than 180 days after <date date="2025-12-18">December 18, 2025</date>, the Director shall issue written guidance to ensure the timely identification and reporting of novel and significant expenditures in accordance with this subsection. Such guidance shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1e5b478-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> establish a definition of a novel and significant expenditure for purposes of this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1e5b479-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> define internal procedures to evaluate expenditures to determine if such expenditures are novel and significant using the definition established pursuant to clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1e5b47a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> require timely congressional notification in accordance with this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b47b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Director shall regularly review and update the guidance issued under this paragraph as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd1e5b47c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3510/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Not later than 60 days after the date on which the initial guidance is issued under this paragraph, and not later than 60 days after the date on which any material revisions to such guidance take effect, the Director shall provide to the committees specified in paragraph (1) a briefing with respect to such guidance or such material revisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1e5b47d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-06-20/ch227/s8">June 20, 1949, ch. 227, § 8</ref>, formerly § 10, <ref href="/us/stat/63/212">63 Stat. 212</ref>; renumbered § 8, <ref href="/us/pl/85/507/s21/b/2">Pub. L. 85–507, § 21(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/337">72 Stat. 337</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLIII/s5341">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LIII, § 5341</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2142">133 Stat. 2142</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dF/tLXIV/s6415/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXIV, § 6415(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3528">136 Stat. 3528</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXV/s6501/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXV, § 6501(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1619">139 Stat. 1619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1e5b47e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1e5b47f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd1e5b480-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t6/s14">Section 14 of title 6</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/93/310/tII/s203/1">Pub. L. 93–310, title II, § 203(1)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/202">86 Stat. 202</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The reference to <ref href="/us/stat/36/699">36 Stat. 699</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s259">40 U.S.C. 259</ref>, 267, in subsec. (a)(1), was probably meant to be a reference to section 3734 of the Revised Statutes. Section 33 of <ref href="/us/act/1910-06-25/ch383">act June 25, 1910, ch. 383</ref>, which appears at <ref href="/us/stat/36/699">36 Stat. 699</ref>, amended generally section 3734 of the Revised Statutes which was classified to sections 259 and 267 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works. Section 3734 of the Revised Statutes was subsequently repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/86/249/s17/12">Pub. L. 86–249, § 17(12)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-09">Sept. 9, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/485">73 Stat. 485</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1e5b481-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403j">section 403j of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(1), “(<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7901">5 U.S.C. 7901</ref>)” substituted for “(<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s150">5 U.S.C. 150</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idd1e5b482-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 8 of act <date date="1949-06-20">June 20, 1949</date>, was renumbered section 7 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3508">section 3508 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1e5b483-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> inserted “payment of death benefits in cases in which the circumstances of the death of an employee of the Agency, a detailee of the Agency or other employee of another department or agency of the Federal Government assigned to the Agency, or an individual affiliated with the Agency (as determined by the Director), is not covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3511">section 3511 of this title</ref>, other similar provisions of Federal law, or any regulation issued by the Director providing death benefits, but that the Director determines such payment appropriate;” before “rental of”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
