<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1ece053-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519"><num value="3519">§ 3519.</num><heading> Special rules for disability retirement and death-in-service benefits with respect to certain employees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1ece054-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Officers and employees to whom section 2051 rules apply</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an officer or employee of the Central Intelligence Agency subject to retirement system coverage under subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5 who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece055-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has five years of civilian service credit toward retirement under such subchapter III of chapter 83, title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece056-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has not been designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref> as a participant in the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece057-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> has become disabled during a period of assignment to the performance of duties that are qualifying toward such designation under such <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece058-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> satisfies the requirements for disability retirement under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8337">section 8337 of title 5</ref>—</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall, upon his own application or upon order of the Director, be retired on an annuity computed in accordance with the rules prescribed in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>, in lieu of an annuity computed as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8337">section 8337 of title 5</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1ece059-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Survivors of officers and employees to whom section 2052 rules apply</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of an officer or employee of the Central Intelligence Agency subject to retirement system coverage under subchapter III of chapter 83, title 5, who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece05a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has at least eighteen months of civilian service credit toward retirement under such subchapter III of chapter 83, title 5;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece05b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has not been designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002107">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002107"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> as a participant in the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece05c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> prior to separation or retirement from the Agency, dies during a period of assignment to the performance of duties that are qualifying toward such designation under such <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1ece05d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> is survived by a surviving spouse, former spouse, or child as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2002">section 2002 of this title</ref>, who would otherwise be entitled to an annuity under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of title 5</ref>—</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">such surviving spouse, former spouse, or child of such officer or employee shall be entitled to an annuity computed in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2052">section 2052 of this title</ref>, in lieu of an annuity computed in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8341">section 8341 of title 5</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1ece05e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3519/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Annuities under this section deemed annuities under chapter 83 of title 5</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The annuities provided under subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be deemed to be annuities under chapter 83 of title 5 for purposes of the other provisions of such chapter and other laws (including title 26) relating to such annuities, and shall be payable from the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund maintained pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1ece05f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-06-20/ch227/s19">June 20, 1949, ch. 227, § 19</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/193/tIII/s307/a">Pub. L. 101–193, title III, § 307(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1705">103 Stat. 1705</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/tVIII/s803/a/3">Pub. L. 102–496, title VIII, § 803(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3252">106 Stat. 3252</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/178/tV/s501/3">Pub. L. 103–178, title V, § 501(3)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-03">Dec. 3, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2038">107 Stat. 2038</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tIX/s7901/g/5">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title IX, § 7901(g)(5)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1107">137 Stat. 1107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1ece060-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1ece061-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd1ece062-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403s">section 403s of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Some section numbers of this title referenced in amendment notes below reflect the classification of such sections prior to their editorial reclassification.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1ece063-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> substituted “as a participant” for “, as a participant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/178/s501/3/A">Pub. L. 103–178, § 501(3)(A)</ref>, (C), substituted “section 2052” for “section 2051” in heading and concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/178/s501/3/B">Pub. L. 103–178, § 501(3)(B)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref> to update reference to corresponding section of original act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s803/a/3/A">Pub. L. 102–496, § 803(a)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted heading, redesignated cl. (i) as par. (1), in cl. (ii), substituted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref> for reference in original to section 203 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees, as amended, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403">section 403 of this title</ref>, and redesignated such cl. as par. (2), in cl. (iii), inserted “such” before reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref> and redesignated such cl. as par. (3), redesignated cl. (iv) as par. (4), and substituted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref> for “such section 231” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s803/a/3/B/i">Pub. L. 102–496, § 803(a)(3)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), (iv)–(vi), inserted heading, redesignated cl. (i) as par. (1), in cl. (ii), substituted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2013">section 2013 of this title</ref> for reference in original to section 203 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees, as amended, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403">section 403 of this title</ref>, and redesignated cl. (ii) as par. (2), redesignated cls. (iii) and (iv) as pars. (3) and (4), respectively, and in concluding provisions, substituted “surviving spouse, former spouse, or child” for “widow or widower, former spouse, and/or child or children” and substituted reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref> for “such section 232”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s803/a/3/B/iii">Pub. L. 102–496, § 803(a)(3)(B)(iii)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “surviving spouse, former spouse, or child as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2002">section 2002 of this title</ref>” in cl. (iv) for “widow or widower, former spouse, and/or child or children as defined in section 204 and section 232 of such the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees”, was executed by making the substitution for “widow or widower, former spouse, and/or a child or children as defined in section 204 and section 232 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s803/a/3/D/i">Pub. L. 102–496, § 803(a)(3)(D)(i)</ref>–(iii), inserted heading, struck out par. (1) designation before “The annuities provided”, substituted “maintained pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>” for “established by section 202 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees”, and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “The annuities and/or other benefits provided under subsections (c) and (d) of this section shall be deemed to be annuities and/or benefits under chapter 84 of title 5 for purposes of the other provisions of such chapter and other laws (including title 26) relating to such annuities and/or benefits, but shall be payable from the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund established by section 202 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s803/a/3/C">Pub. L. 102–496, § 803(a)(3)(C)</ref>, (D), redesignated subsec. (e) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which provided for retirement of officers and employees of the Central Intelligence Agency as though designated pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/88/643/s302/a">section 302(a) of Pub. L. 88–643</ref> which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403">section 403 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s803/a/3/C">Pub. L. 102–496, § 803(a)(3)(C)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which provided that survivors of officers and employees of the Central Intelligence Agency were to receive benefits as though deceased had been designated pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/88/643/s302/a">section 302(a) of Pub. L. 88–643</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403">section 403 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s803/a/3/D">Pub. L. 102–496, § 803(a)(3)(D)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd1ece064-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd1ece065-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/496">Pub. L. 102–496</ref> effective on first day of fourth month beginning after <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/496/s805">section 805 of Pub. L. 102–496</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
