<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd1f67d83-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743"><num value="3743">§ 3743.</num><heading> Reports on activities and assistance under Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1f67d84-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any year in which the President submits to Congress, under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the budget for a fiscal year that requests funds for the Department of Defense for activities or assistance under the Program, the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the activities and assistance carried out under the Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1f67d85-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report under subsection (a) shall be submitted not later than the first Monday in February of a year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1f67d86-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Matters included</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1f67d87-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An estimate of the total amount that will be required to be expended by the United States during the fiscal year covered by the budget described in subsection (a) in order to achieve the objectives of the Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1f67d88-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A five-year plan setting forth the amount of funds and other resources proposed to be provided by the United States for the Program during the period covered by the plan, including the purpose for which such funds and resources will be used.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1f67d89-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A description of the activities and assistance carried out under the Program during the fiscal year preceding the submission of the report, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d8a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the funds notified, obligated, and expended for such activities and assistance and the purposes for which such funds were notified, obligated, and expended for such fiscal year and cumulatively for the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d8b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of the participation, if any, of each department and agency of the Federal Government in such activities and assistance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d8c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a description of such activities and assistance, including the forms of assistance provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d8d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a description of the United States private sector participation in the portion of such activities and assistance that were supported by the obligation and expenditure of funds for the Program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d8e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate to fully inform Congress of the operation of activities and assistance carried out under the Program, including, with respect to proposed demilitarization or conversion projects, information on the progress toward demilitarization of facilities and the conversion of the demilitarized facilities to civilian activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1f67d8f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> A description of the means (including program management, audits, examinations, and other means) used by the United States during the fiscal year preceding the submission of the report to ensure that assistance provided under the Program is fully accounted for, that such assistance is being used for its intended purpose, and that such assistance is being used efficiently and effectively, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d90-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if such assistance consisted of equipment, a description of the current location of such equipment and the current condition of such equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d91-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if such assistance consisted of contracts or other services, a description of the status of such contracts or services and the methods used to ensure that such contracts and services are being used for their intended purpose;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d92-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a determination whether the assistance described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) has been used for its intended purpose and an assessment of whether the assistance being provided is being used effectively and efficiently; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d93-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a description of the efforts planned to be carried out during the fiscal year beginning in the year of the report to ensure that Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction assistance provided during such fiscal year is fully accounted for and is used for its intended purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd1f67d94-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> A description of the defense and military activities carried out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3711/a/6">section 3711(a)(6) of this title</ref> during the fiscal year preceding the submission of the report, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d95-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount of funds obligated or expended for such activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d96-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the strategy, goals, and objectives for which such funds were obligated and expended;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d97-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a description of the activities carried out, including the forms of assistance provided, and the justification for each form of assistance provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d98-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the success of each activity, including the goals and objectives achieved for each activity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d99-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a description of participation by private sector entities in the United States in carrying out such activities, and the participation of any other department or agency of the Federal Government in such activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd1f67d9a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/c/5/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any other information that the Secretary considers relevant to provide a complete description of the operation and success of activities carried out under the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd1f67d9b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s3743/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The requirement to submit the report under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2030-01-01">January 1, 2030</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd1f67d9c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXIII/s1343">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1343</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3605">128 Stat. 3605</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXVI/s1652/b">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1652(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2201">138 Stat. 2201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd1f67d9d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd1f67d9e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd1f67d9f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
