<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd210bb96-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104"><num value="4104">§ 4104.</num><heading> Internees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bb97-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> “Civilian American citizen” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in subsections (b) and (f) of this section, the term “civilian American citizen” means any person who, being then a citizen of the United States, was captured by the Imperial Japanese Government on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, at Midway, Guam, Wake Island, the Philippine Islands, or any Territory or possession of the United States attacked or invaded by such government, or while in transit to or from any such place, or who went into hiding at any such place in order to avoid capture or internment by such government; except (1) a person who at any time voluntarily gave aid to, collaborated with, or in any manner served such government, or (2) a person who at the time of his capture or entrance into hiding was a regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of any military or naval force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bb98-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of detention benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to receive, adjudicate according to law, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by, or on behalf of, any civilian American citizen for detention benefits for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1941-12-06">December 6, 1941</date>, during which he was held by the Imperial Japanese Government as a prisoner, internee, hostage, or in any other capacity, or remained in hiding to avoid being captured or interned by such Imperial Japanese Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bb99-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of detention benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The detention benefit allowed to any person under the provisions of subsection (b) shall be at the rate of $60 for each calendar month during which such person was at least eighteen years of age and at the rate of $25 per month for each calendar month during which such person was less than eighteen years of age.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bb9a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons entitled to detention benefits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The detention benefits allowed under subsection (b) shall be allowed to the person entitled thereto, or, in the event of his death, only to the following persons:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bb9b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bb9c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Widow or husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or husband and the other half to the child or children in equal shares;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bb9d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Child or children of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow or husband; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bb9e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Parents (in equal shares) if there is no husband, or child.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bb9f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification of claims</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any claim allowed by the Commission under this section (except under subsections (g) and (i)) shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of the war claims funds established by <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4110">section 4110 of this title</ref>, and shall be payable by the Secretary of the Treasury to the person entitled thereto; except that where the person entitled to payment is under any legal disability, any part of the amount payable may, in the discretion of the Commission, be paid, for the use of the claimant, to the natural or legal guardian, committee, conservator, or curator of the claimant, or, if there is no such guardian, committee, conservator, or curator, then the Commission may, in its discretion, make payment to any other person, including the spouse of such claimant, whom the Commission may determine is vested with the care of the claimant or his estate for the use and benefit of such claimant or estate; and if such person is a minor, any part of the amount payable may, in the discretion of the Commission, be paid to such minor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bba0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of War Hazards Compensation Act; factors for determining benefits; effective date</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bba1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the provisions of titles I and II of the Act entitled “An Act to provide benefits for the injury, disability, death, or enemy detention of employees of contractors with the United States, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1701">42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq., 1711 et seq.], are extended and shall apply with respect to the injury, disability, or death resulting from injury of a civilian American citizen occurring while he was held by or in hiding from the Imperial Japanese Government, to the same extent as if such civilian American citizen were an employee within the purview of such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bba2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For the purpose of determining the benefits extended and made applicable by paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bba3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the average weekly wage of any such civilian American citizen, whether employed, self-employed, or not employed, shall be deemed to have been $37.50;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bba4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the provisions of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1701">42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.],<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002120">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002120"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> shall be applicable whether or not any such civilian American citizen was employed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bba5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> notice of injury or death shall not be required; and limitation provisions with respect to the filing of claims for injury, disability, or death shall not begin to run until <date date="1948-07-03">July 3, 1948</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bba6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the monthly compensation in cases involving partial disability shall be determined by the percentage the degree of partial disability bears to total disability and shall not be determined with respect to the extent of loss of wage earning capacity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bba7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The following provisions of such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1701">42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.], shall not apply in the case of such civilian American citizens: The last sentence of section 101(a), section 101(b), section 101(d) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1701/a">42 U.S.C. 1701(a)</ref>, (b), (d)], section 104 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1704">42 U.S.C. 1704</ref>], and section 105 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1705">42 U.S.C. 1705</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bba8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Rights or benefits which, under this subsection, are to be determined with reference to other provisions of law shall be determined with reference to such provisions of law as in force on <date date="1948-01-03">January 3, 1948</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bba9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The money benefit for disability or death shall be paid only to the person entitled thereto, or to his legal or natural guardian if he has one, and shall not upon death of the person so entitled survive for the benefit of his estate or any other person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbaa-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The benefit of a minor or of an incompetent person who has no natural or legal guardian may, in the discretion of the Secretary of Labor, be paid, in whole or in such part as he may determine for and on behalf of such minor or incompetent directly to the person or institution caring for, supporting, or having custody of such minor or incompetent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbab-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> No person, except a widow or a child, shall be entitled to benefits for disability with respect to himself, and to death benefits on account of the death of another.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbac-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> If a civilian American citizen or his dependent receives or has received from the United States any payments on account of the same injury or death, or from his employer, in the form of wages, or payments in lieu of wages, or in any form of support or compensation (including workmen’s compensation) in respect to the same objects, the benefits under this section shall be diminished by the amount of such payments in the following manner: (A) Benefits on account of injury or disability shall be reduced by the amount of payments to the injured person on account of the same injury or disability; and (B) benefits on account of death shall be reduced by the amount of payments to the dependents of the deceased civilian American citizen on account of the same death.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbad-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> This subsection shall take effect as of <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, and the right of individuals to benefits shall be held to have begun to accrue as though this subsection had been in effect as of such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbae-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> No benefits provided by this subsection for injury, disability, or death shall accrue to any person who, without regard to this subsection, is entitled to or has received benefits for the same injury, disability, or death under such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1701">42 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbaf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/f/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> No benefits provided by this subsection shall accrue to any person to whom benefits have been paid, or are payable, under the Federal Employees’ Compensation Act, or any extension thereof, by reason of disability or death of an employee of the United States suffered after capture, detention, or other restraint by an enemy of the United States, when such disability or death is deemed, in the administration of the Federal Employees’ Compensation Act to have resulted from injury occurring while in the performance of duty, under subsection (b) of section 5 of the Act entitled “An Act to amend the Act entitled ‘An Act to provide compensation for employees of the United States suffering injuries while in the performance of their duties, and for other purposes’, as amended”, approved <date date="1945-07-28">July 28, 1945</date>, as amended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bbb0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Benefits for civilian internees in Korea, and dependents; time</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbb1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> As used in this subsection, the term “civilian American citizens” means any person who, being then a citizen of the United States, was captured in Korea on or after <date date="1950-06-25">June 25, 1950</date>, by any hostile force with which the Armed Forces of the United States were actually engaged in armed conflict subsequent to such date and prior to <date date="1954-08-21">August 21, 1954</date>, or who went into hiding in Korea in order to avoid capture or internment by any such hostile force; except (A) a person who at any time voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with or in any manner served any such hostile force, or (B) a regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbb2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by, or on behalf of, any civilian American citizen for detention benefits for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1950-06-25">June 25, 1950</date>, during which he was held by any such hostile force as a prisoner, internee, hostage, or in any other capacity, or remained in hiding to avoid being captured or interned by any such hostile force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbb3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The detention benefit allowed to any person under the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be at the rate of $60 for each calendar month during which such person was at least eighteen years of age and at the rate of $25 per month for each calendar month during which such person was less than eighteen years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbb4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The detention benefits allowed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be allowed to the person entitled thereto, or, in the event of his death, only to the following persons:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbb5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbb6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> widow or dependent husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or dependent husband and the other half to the child or children in equal shares;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbb7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> child or children of the deceased (in equal shares) if there is no widow or dependent husband.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbb8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Any claim allowed by the Commission under this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection, and shall be paid by the Secretary of the Treasury to the person entitled thereto, except that where any person entitled to payment under this subsection is under any legal disability, payment may be made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbb9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> Each claim filed under this subsection must be filed not later than one year from whichever of the following dates last occurs:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbba-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <date date="1954-08-21">August 21, 1954</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbbb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The date the civilian American citizen by whom the claim is filed returned to the jurisdiction of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbbc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The date upon which the Commission, at the request of a potentially eligible survivor, makes a determination that the civilian American citizen has actually died or may be presumed to be dead, in the case of any civilian American citizen who has not returned to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Commission shall complete its determinations with respect to each claim filed under this subsection at the earliest practicable date, but in no event later than one year after the date on which such claim was filed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbbd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbbe-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including necessary administrative expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbbf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/g/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Commission shall determine, from time to time, the share of its administrative expenses attributable to the performance of its functions under this subsection and make the appropriate adjustments in its accounts, and determinations and adjustments made pursuant to this subparagraph shall be final and conclusive.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bbc0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Benefits for Guamanians killed or captured at Wake Island on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any Guamanian killed or captured by the Imperial Japanese Government on or after <date date="1941-12-07">December 7, 1941</date>, at Wake Island, benefits shall be granted under subsections (a) through (f) of this section in the same manner and to the same extent as apply in the case of civilian American citizens so killed or captured. Claims for benefits under subsections (a) through (e) of this section must be filed within six months after <date date="1962-08-31">August 31, 1962</date>, and the time limitation applicable to any individual by subsection (f) shall not begin to run until <date date="1962-08-31">August 31, 1962</date>, with respect to any individual who is entitled to such benefits solely by reason of this subsection. The preceding sentence shall not be construed to affect the right of any individual to receive such benefits with respect to any period prior to <date date="1962-08-31">August 31, 1962</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd210bbc1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Detention benefits for civilian internees in Southeast Asia; definitions; authority of Commission; claim for benefits; rate of compensation; persons entitled to payments; certification for payment; filing date; determination of claims; appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbc2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbc3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “Vietnam conflict” relates to the period beginning on <date date="1961-02-28">February 28, 1961</date>, and ending on such date as shall thereafter be determined by Presidential proclamation or concurrent resolution of the Congress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbc4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “civilian American citizen” means any person who, being then a citizen of the United States, was captured in Southeast Asia during the Vietnam conflict by any force hostile to the United States, or who went into hiding in Southeast Asia, in order to avoid capture or internment by any such hostile force, except (i) a person who voluntarily, knowingly, and without duress, gave aid to or collaborated with or in any manner served any such hostile force, or (ii) a regularly appointed, enrolled, enlisted, or inducted member of the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbc5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commission is authorized to receive and to determine, according to law, the amount and validity, and provide for the payment of any claim filed by, or on behalf of, any civilian American citizen for detention benefits for any period of time subsequent to <date date="1961-02-27">February 27, 1961</date>, during which he was held by any such hostile force as a prisoner, internee, hostage, or in any other capacity, or remained in hiding to avoid capture or internment by any such hostile force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbc6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The detention benefits allowed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be at the rate of $150 for each calendar month.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbc7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The detention benefits allowed under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be allowed to the civilian American citizen entitled thereto, or, in the event of his death, only to the following persons:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbc8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the widow or husband if there is no child or children of the deceased;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbc9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the widow or dependent husband and child or children of the deceased, one-half to the widow or dependent husband and the other half to the child or children in equal shares;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbca-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the child or children of the deceased in equal shares if there is no widow or dependent husband.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbcb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Any claim allowed by the Commission under this subsection shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment out of funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection, and shall be paid to the person entitled thereto, except that if a person entitled to payment under this section is under any legal disability, payment shall be made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbcc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> Each claim filed under this section must be filed not later than three years from whichever of the following dates last occurs:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbcd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <date date="1970-06-24">June 24, 1970</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbce-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the date the civilian American citizen by whom the claim is filed returned to the jurisdiction of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd210bbcf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the date upon which the Commission, at the request of a potentially eligible survivor, makes a determination that the civilian American citizen has actually died or may be presumed to be dead, in the case of any civilian American citizen who has not returned to the jurisdiction of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Commission shall complete its determinations for each claim filed under this subsection at the earliest practicable date, but not later than one year after the date on which such claim was filed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd210bbd0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4104/i/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including necessary administrative expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd210bbd1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-07-03/ch826">July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, title I, § 5, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1242">62 Stat. 1242</ref>; 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 19, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1271">64 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-04-09/ch168/s1">Apr. 9, 1952, ch. 168, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/49">66 Stat. 49</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-21/ch784/s1">Aug. 21, 1954, ch. 784, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/759">68 Stat. 759</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1162">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1162</ref>, title I, §§ 101 (a)–(c), 102(a), <ref href="/us/stat/68/1033">68 Stat. 1033</ref>, 1034; <ref href="/us/pl/87/617">Pub. L. 87–617</ref>, <date date="1962-08-31">Aug. 31, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/413">76 Stat. 413</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/846/tI/s102">Pub. L. 87–846, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1107">76 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/289/s3">Pub. L. 91–289, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-06-24">June 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/324">84 Stat. 324</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/383">Pub. L. 94–383</ref>, <date date="1976-08-12">Aug. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1122">90 Stat. 1122</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd210bbd2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd210bbd3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd210bbd4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act entitled “An Act to provide benefits for the injury, disability, death, or enemy detention of employees of contractors with the United States, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, referred to in subsec. (f)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1942-12-02/ch668">act Dec. 2, 1942, ch. 668</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/56/1028">56 Stat. 1028</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 12 (§ 1701 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Titles I and II of the act, popularly known as the War Hazards Compensation Act, are classified generally to subchapters I (§ 1701 et seq.) and II (§ 1711 et seq.) of chapter 12 of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Employee Compensation Act, referred to in subsec. (f)(11), is <ref href="/us/act/1916-09-07/ch458">act Sept. 7, 1916, ch. 458</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/742">39 Stat. 742</ref>. The act was repealed, and the provisions thereof were reenacted as subchapter I (§ 8101 et seq.) of chapter 81 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) of section 5 of the Act entitled “An Act to amend the Act entitled ‘An Act to provide compensation for employees of the United States suffering injuries while in the performance of their duties, and for other purposes’, as amended”, approved <date date="1945-07-28">July 28, 1945</date>, referred to in subsec. (f)(11), is section 5(b) of <ref href="/us/act/1945-07-28/ch328">act July 28, 1945, ch. 328</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/504">59 Stat. 504</ref>, which enacted section 801 of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/85/608/s303">Pub. L. 85–608, § 303</ref>, <date date="1958-08-08">Aug. 8, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/539">72 Stat. 539</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8102/b">section 8102(b) of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd210bbd5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 2004 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd210bbd6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (i)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/383">Pub. L. 94–383</ref> substituted “$150” for “$60”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/289/s3/1">Pub. L. 91–289, § 3(1)</ref>, included reference to subsec. (i) in parenthetical phrase.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/91/289/s3/2">Pub. L. 91–289, § 3(2)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/87/846">Pub. L. 87–846</ref> made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4110">section 4110 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/87/617">Pub. L. 87–617</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, § 101(a), included as eligible for detention benefits, civilian American citizens who were captured at certain Pacific islands by the Japanese, but who were formerly expressly excluded from these benefits by reason of being Federal employees or employees of contractors with the United States, and to make them eligible for disability compensation. Act <date date="1954-08-21">Aug. 21, 1954</date>, § 1(b), limited the application of such section’s definition of “civilian American citizen” to subsecs. (b) and (f) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, § 102(a), (b), struck out “dependent” wherever appearing, and added cl. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1954-08-21">Aug. 21, 1954</date>, § 1(c), inserted “(except under subsection (g) )” after “under this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). Act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, § 101(b), amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “The following provisions of such Act of <date date="1942-12-02">December 2, 1942</date>, as amended, shall not apply in the case of such civilian American citizens: Section 101(b), section 104, and section 105.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(10), (11). Act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, § 101(c), added pars. (10) and (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1954-08-21">Aug. 21, 1954</date>, § 1(a), added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1952—Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1952-04-09">Apr. 9, 1952</date>, allowed the award for the benefit of claimant to be paid to the claimant’s natural or legal guardian, committee, conservator, or curator, or to such other person as is charged with the care of the claimant, and permitted the payment of an award payable to a minor, directly to such minor.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd210bbd7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idd210bbd8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions transferring Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States to Department of Justice, as a separate agency, see section 1622a et seq. of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd210bbd9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idd210bbda-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Labor” substituted for “Federal Security Administrator” in subsec. (f)(6) pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 19 of 1950, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1271">64 Stat. 1271</ref>, which transferred functions of Federal Security Administrator and Federal Security Agency under this section to Secretary of Labor, with power to delegate, and was set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, §8(a), <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/662">80 Stat. 662</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8145">section 8145 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">War Claims Commission, including offices of its members, abolished and functions transferred to Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1954, §§ 2, 4, eff. <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>, 19 F.R. 3985, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1279">68 Stat. 1279</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. See, also, <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4101">section 4101 of this title</ref> and notes thereunder.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
