<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd226191a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4338"><num value="4338">§ 4338.</num><heading> Divestment of estates, trusts, insurance policies, annuities, remainders, pensions, workmen’s compensation and veterans’ benefits; exceptions; notice of divestment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd226191b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4338/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) hereof, all rights and interests of individuals in estates, trusts, insurance policies, annuities, remainders, pensions, workmen’s compensation and veterans’ benefits vested under this chapter after <date date="1941-12-17">December 17, 1941</date>, which have not become payable or deliverable to or have not vested in possession in the Attorney General prior to <date date="1961-12-31">December 31, 1961</date>, are divested: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of this section shall not affect the right of the Attorney General to retain all such property rights and interests and to collect all income which is payable to or vested in possession in him prior to <date date="1961-12-31">December 31, 1961</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd226191c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4338/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception to requirement where beneficial owner convicted of certain crimes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing contained in this section shall divest or require the divestment of any portion of any such interest the beneficial owner of which is a natural person who has been convicted personally and by name by a court of competent jurisdiction of murder, ill treatment, or deportation for slave labor of prisoners of war, political opponents, hostages, or civilian population in occupied territories, or of murder or ill treatment of military or naval persons, or of plunder or wanton destruction without justified military necessity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd226191d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4338/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of divestment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the earliest practicable time after the effective date of this Act, the Attorney General shall transmit to the lawful owner or custodian of any interest divested by this section written notice of such divestment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd226191e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1917-10-06/ch106/s40">Oct. 6, 1917, ch. 106, § 40</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/87/846/tII/s205">Pub. L. 87–846, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1115">76 Stat. 1115</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd226191f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd2261920-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd2261921-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1917-10-06/ch106">act Oct. 6, 1917, ch. 106</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/411">40 Stat. 411</ref>, known as the Trading with the enemy Act, also known as the Trading with the Enemy Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of this Act, referred to in subsec. (c), probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/87/846">Pub. L. 87–846</ref>, which added this section and was approved <date date="1962-10-22">Oct. 22, 1962</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd2261922-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 41 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
