<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd2288949-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4341"><num value="4341">§ 4341.</num><heading> Motion picture prints, transfer of title</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd228894a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4341/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prints in custody of Library of Congress; exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General is authorized and directed to transfer to the Library of Congress the title to all prints of motion pictures now in the custody of the Library, which prints were vested in or transferred to the Alien Property Custodian or the Attorney General pursuant to this chapter after <date date="1941-12-17">December 17, 1941</date>, except prints of motion pictures which are the subject of suits or claims under section 4309(a) or <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4329">section 4329 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd228894b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4341/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prints in custody of Attorney General; exception; right of selection by Library of Congress; disposal of unselected prints by Attorney General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the right of selection by the Library of Congress, the authorization, direction, and exception contained in subsection (a) hereof shall apply with respect to such prints now in the custody of the Attorney General. Prints not selected by the Library of Congress may be disposed of by the Attorney General in any manner he deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd228894c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4341/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention, reproduction, and disposal of prints by Library of Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to all prints concerning which title is transferred to the Library of Congress pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) hereof, the Library shall have complete discretion to retain such prints and to reproduce copies thereof, or to dispose of them in any manner it deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd228894d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1917-10-06/ch106/s43">Oct. 6, 1917, ch. 106, § 43</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/87/861/s2">Pub. L. 87–861, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1140">76 Stat. 1140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd228894e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd228894f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd2288950-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1917-10-06/ch106">act Oct. 6, 1917, ch. 106</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/411">40 Stat. 411</ref>, known as the Trading with the enemy Act, also known as the Trading with the Enemy Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd2288951-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 44 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd2288952-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idd2288953-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested by law in Alien Property Custodian and Office of Alien Property Custodian transferred to Attorney General by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1947, § 101, eff. <date date="1947-07-01">July 1, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4534, <ref href="/us/stat/61/951">61 Stat. 951</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
