<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd23e0d79-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581"><num value="4581">§ 4581.</num><heading> Prohibition on investments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd23e0d7a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may prohibit, in accordance with regulations issued under subsection (e), a United States person, including its controlled foreign entities, from knowingly engaging in a covered national security transaction in any prohibited technology.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd23e0d7b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Evasion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any action that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate the prohibition set forth in subsection (a) is prohibited.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd23e0d7c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd23e0d7d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> National interest exemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary is authorized to exempt from the prohibition set forth in subsection (a) any activity determined by the President, in consultation with the Secretary, or delegated to the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of State, and, as appropriate, the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, to be in the national interest of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd23e0d7e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Intelligence exemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Regulations issued under subsection (e) shall not apply to any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd240576f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd2405770-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> notify the appropriate congressional committees not later than five business days after issuing an exemption under subsection (c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd2405771-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> include in such notification an identification of the national interest justifying the use of the exemption, subject to appropriate confidentiality and classification requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405772-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405773-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of State and, as appropriate, the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, may issue or update existing regulations to carry out this section subject to public notice and comment in accordance with subchapter II of chapter 5 and chapter 7 of title 5, and not subject to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4559">section 4559 of this title</ref>. The regulations issued pursuant to this paragraph shall, as necessary, amend, terminate, supersede, revoke, or streamline existing requirements in part 850 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (the Outbound Investment Rule) and shall provide a reasonable timeframe for compliance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405774-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-binding feedback</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405775-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall include a process under which a person can request to receive non-binding feedback on a confidential basis, or as anonymized guidance to the public, as to whether a transaction would constitute a covered national security transaction in a prohibited technology.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405776-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to limit frivolous feedback requests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In establishing the process required by subparagraph (A), the Secretary may prescribe limitations on requests for feedback identified as frivolous for purposes of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405777-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice; opportunity to cure</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405778-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall account for whether a United States person has self-identified and self-disclosed a violation of the prohibition set forth in subsection (a) in determining the legal consequences of that violation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idd2405779-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Self-disclosure letters</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall dictate the form and content of a letter of self-disclosure, which shall include relevant facts about the violation, why the United States person believes its activity to have violated the prohibition set forth in subsection (a), and a proposal for mitigation of the harm of such action.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd240577a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Low-burden regulations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In issuing regulations under paragraph (1), the Secretary should balance the priority of protecting the national security interest of the United States while, to the extent practicable—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd240577b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> minimizing the cost and complexity of compliance for affected parties, including the duplication of reporting requirements under current regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd240577c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> adopting the least burdensome alternative that achieves regulatory objectives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd240577d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> prioritizing transparency and stakeholder involvement in the process of issuing the rules.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd240577e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4581/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Burden of proof</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s556/d">section 556(d) of title 5</ref>, in an enforcement action for a violation of the prohibition set forth in subsection (a), the burden of proof shall be upon the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd240577f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-09-08/ch932">Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932</ref>, title VIII, § 801, as added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXV/s8521">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXV, § 8521</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1924">139 Stat. 1924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd2405780-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd2405781-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2405782-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comprehensive Outbound Investment National Security</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXV">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXV</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1920">139 Stat. 1920</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXV">
<subtitle style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="A">“Subtitle A—</num><heading>General Matters</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8501">“SEC. 8501.</num><heading> SECRETARY DEFINED.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Except as otherwise provided, in this title [enacting this subchapter and this note], the term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8502">“SEC. 8502.</num><heading> SEVERABILITY.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“If any provision of this title or any amendment made by this title, or the application thereof, is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this title or any amendment made by this title and the application of such provision to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8503">“SEC. 8503.</num><heading> AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated $150,000,000 to the Department of the Treasury, out of which amounts may be transferred to the Department of Commerce to jointly conduct outreach to industry and persons affected by this title or any amendment made by this title, and to administer the provisions of this title or any amendment made by this title, for each of the first two fiscal years beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this title [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], to carry out this title or any amendment made by this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hiring Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">By the president</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may appoint, without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3318 of title 5, United States Code, not more than 15 individuals directly to positions in the competitive service (as defined in section 2102 of that title) to carry out this title or any amendment made by this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">By agencies</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary and the Secretary of Commerce may appoint, without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3318 of title 5, United States Code, individuals directly to positions in the competitive service (as defined in section 2102 of that title) of the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Commerce, respectively, to carry out this title or any amendment made by this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8504">“SEC. 8504.</num><heading> SENSE OF CONGRESS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> due to the fact that there are countless known and unknown entities in countries of concern, to include the People’s Republic of China (PRC), developing dual-use strategic technologies that benefit a foreign adversary’s military modernization efforts, surveillance states, and human rights abuses, restricting certain United States outbound investments into these technologies in countries of concern is necessary to prevent harm to United States national security and foreign policy interests; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the President should therefore exercise the authorities granted in this title or any amendment made by this title to prevent countries of concern from exploiting United States capital to undermine United States national security and foreign policy interests.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8505">“SEC. 8505.</num><heading> TERMINATION.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This title and any amendment made by this title shall cease to have any force or effect on the date that is seven years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>].</p>
</content>
</section>
</subtitle><subtitle style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="B">“Subtitle B—</num><heading>Imposition of Sanctions</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8511">“SEC. 8511.</num><heading> IMPOSITION OF SANCTIONS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person determined to be a covered foreign person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sanctions Described</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.) to the extent necessary to prohibit any United States person from investing in or purchasing significant amounts of equity or debt instruments of a foreign person that is determined to be a covered foreign person pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading><content>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</ref>) shall apply to any person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of any prohibition of this section, or an order or regulation prescribed under this section, to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1705/a">50 U.S.C. 1705(a)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for Intelligence and Law Enforcement Activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for United States Government Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the Federal Government by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], and annually thereafter for seven years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that states whether any foreign person on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List is a covered foreign person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative Provisions</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</ref> and 1704) to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the President to designate foreign persons for the imposition of sanctions pursuant to any other provision of Federal law, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8512">“SEC. 8512.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this subtitle:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Country of concern</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘country of concern’ means the People’s Republic of China, including the Hong Kong and Macau Special Administrative Regions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered foreign person</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘covered foreign person’ means a foreign person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> that is incorporated in, has a principal place of business in, or is organized under the laws of a country of concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> that is a member of the Central Committee of the Chinese Communist Party or member of the political leadership of a country of concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> that is the state or the government of a country of concern, as well as any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> that is subject to the direction or control of any entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (C); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> that is owned in the aggregate, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more by an entity or a group of entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> that knowingly engaged in significant operations in the defense and related materiel sector or the surveillance technology sector of the economy of a country of concern.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign person</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘foreign person’ means a person that is not a United States person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Knowingly</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘knowingly’, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-SDN chinese military-industrial complex companies list</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List’ means the list maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury under Executive Order 13959, as amended by Executive Order 14032 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People’s Republic of China), or any successor order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Person</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘person’ means an individual or entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United states person</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘United States person’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> any United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States (including any foreign branch of such an entity); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> any person in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8513">“SEC. 8513.</num><heading> EXCEPTION RELATING TO IMPORTATION OF GOODS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this title shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Good Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘good’ means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</subtitle><subtitle style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="C">“Subtitle C—</num><heading>Prohibition and Notification on Investments Relating to Covered National Security Transactions</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8521">“SEC. 8521.</num><heading> PROHIBITION AND NOTIFICATION ON INVESTMENTS RELATING TO COVERED NATIONAL SECURITY TRANSACTIONS.</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" style="-uslm-lc:I21" id="idd2405783-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<p class="indent0">“[Enacted this subchapter.]</p></note>
</section>
</subtitle><subtitle style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="D">“Subtitle D—</num><heading>Securities and Related Matters</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8531">“SEC. 8531.</num><heading> REQUIREMENTS RELATING TO THE NON-SDN CHINESE MILITARY-INDUSTRIAL COMPLEX COMPANIES LIST.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], and biennially thereafter for six years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that states whether any of the following foreign persons qualifies for inclusion on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Any PRC person listed on the Military End-User List (Supplement No. 7 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Any PRC person listed pursuant to section 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 [<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113">10 U.S.C. 113</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Any PRC person listed on the Department of Commerce’s Entity List (Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Any PRC person listed on the Federal Communications Commission’s Covered List pursuant to the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1601">47 U.S.C. 1601</ref> [et seq.]).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Any PRC person listed on the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act Entity List pursuant to the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act (<ref href="/us/pl/117/78">P.L. 117–78</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6901">22 U.S.C. 6901</ref> note].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Process required</inline>.—</heading><content>To prepare the reports required by paragraph (1), the President shall establish a process under which the Federal agencies responsible for administering the lists described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1) shall share with each other all relevant information that led to the identification of the entities described in such lists.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Risk-based prioritization framework</inline>.—</heading><content>In making the initial determinations under paragraph (1), the Secretary may establish a risk-based prioritization framework factoring in prioritization of entity review submitted to the Secretary by the Federal agencies administering the lists described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual reports to the appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><content>The report under paragraph (1) may summarize findings concerning entities previously reviewed pursuant to this section that do not necessitate additional review by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters to be included</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall include in the report required by paragraph (1) an overview of the criteria required for listing on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List. The heads of the Federal agencies administering the lists described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1) shall provide to the Secretary for use in the report an overview of the criteria for entity identification or listing on each respective list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Country of concern</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘country of concern’—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> means the People’s Republic of China; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> includes the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region and the Macau Special Administrative Region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-SDN chinese military-industrial complex companies list</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List’ means the list maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury under Executive Order 13959, as amended by Executive Order 14032 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People’s Republic of China), and any successor order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">PRC person</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘PRC person’ means a foreign person that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is incorporated in a principal place of business in, or is organized under the laws of, a country of concern;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is a member of the Central Committee of the Chinese Communist Party;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is the state or the government of a country of concern, as well as any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> is owned in the aggregate, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more by an entity or a group of entities described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</subtitle></quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
