<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd24057b9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584"><num value="4584">§ 4584.</num><heading> Multilateral engagement and coordination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd24057ba-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, should—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057bb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> conduct bilateral and multilateral engagement with the governments of countries that are allies and partners of the United States to promote and increase coordination of protocols and procedures to facilitate the effective implementation of and appropriate compliance with the prohibitions and notification requirement pursuant to this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057bc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> upon adoption of protocols and procedures described in paragraph (1), work with those governments to establish mechanisms for sharing information, including trends, with respect to such activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057bd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> work with and encourage the governments of countries that are allies and partners of the United States to develop similar mechanisms of their own, for the exclusive purpose of preventing the development of prohibited technologies by a country of concern.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd24057be-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategy for multilateral engagement and coordination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the date of the regulations implementing enactment of this subchapter, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, should—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057bf-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> develop a strategy to work with the governments of countries that are allies and partners of the United States to develop mechanisms that are comparable to the prohibitions and notification requirements pursuant to this subchapter, for the exclusive purpose of preventing the development of prohibited technologies by a country of concern; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057c0-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assess opportunities to provide technical assistance to those countries with respect to the development of those mechanisms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd24057c1-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after the date of the regulations implementing enactment of this subchapter, and annually thereafter for four years, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report, subject to the appropriate confidentiality and classification requirements, that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057c2-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a discussion of any strategy developed pursuant to subsection (b)(1), including key tools and objectives for the development of comparable mechanisms by the governments of allies and partners of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057c3-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a list of partner and allied countries to target for cooperation in developing their own prohibitions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057c4-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the status of the strategy’s implementation and outcomes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057c5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a description of impediments to the establishment of comparable mechanisms by governments of allies and partners of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd24057c6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057c7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd24057c8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s4584/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd24057c9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-09-08/ch932">Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932</ref>, title VIII, § 804, as added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXV/s8521">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXV, § 8521</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1929">139 Stat. 1929</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
