<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd0fe88fd-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s491"><num value="491">§ 491.</num><heading> Establishment and development of land-based air warning and control installations and facilities; extent of appropriation; procurement of communication services</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force is authorized to establish and develop within and without the continental limits of the United States in fulfilling the air defense responsibilities of the Department of the Air Force such land-based air warning and control installations and facilities, by the construction, installation, or equipment of temporary or permanent public works, including buildings, facilities, appurtenances, utilities, and access roads, and to provide for necessary administration and planning therefor, without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31, as he may deem necessary in the interest of national security: <i>Provided</i>, That not to exceed $85,500,000 shall be appropriated for the construction of public works authorized by this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Air Force is authorized to procure communication services required for the semiautomatic ground environment system. No contract for such services may be for a period of more than ten years from the date communication services are first furnished under such contract. The aggregate contingent liability of the Government under the termination provisions of all contracts authorized hereunder may not exceed a total of $222,000,000 and the Government Accountability Office shall have access to such carrier records and accounts as it may deem necessary for the purpose of audit. In procuring such services, the Secretary of the Air Force shall utilize to the fullest extent practicable the facilities and capabilities of communication common carriers, including rural telephone cooperatives, within their respective service areas and for power supply, shall utilize to the fullest extent practicable, the facilities and capabilities of public utilities and rural electric cooperatives within their respective service areas. Negotiations with communication common carriers, including cooperatives, and representation in proceedings involving such carriers before Federal and State regulatory bodies where such negotiations or proceedings involve contracts authorized by this paragraph shall be in accordance with the provisions of sections 501–505 of title 40.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idd0fe88fe-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-03-30/ch41/s1">Mar. 30, 1949, ch. 41, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/17">63 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-03/ch939">Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 939</ref>, title III, § 303, <ref href="/us/stat/70/1012">70 Stat. 1012</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/214/s10/b/4">Pub. L. 97–214, § 10(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/175">96 Stat. 175</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/tI/s128/a">Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 128(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3841">110 Stat. 3841</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd0fe88ff-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd0fe8900-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd0fe8901-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31” substituted in text for “section 3648 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s529">31 U.S.C. 529</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In text, “sections 501–505 of title 40” substituted for “<ref href="/us/act/1949-06-30/s201">section 201 of the Act of June 30, 1949</ref>, as amended (40 U.S.C.A. sec. 481)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd0fe8902-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—<ref href="/us/pl/108/271">Pub. L. 108–271</ref> substituted “Government Accountability Office” for “General Accounting Office” in second par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/316">Pub. L. 104–316</ref>, in third sentence of second par., struck out “no termination payment shall be final until audited and approved by” after “$222,000,000 and”, struck out “which” after “Office”, and inserted “of audit” after “for the purpose”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/214">Pub. L. 97–214</ref> struck out reference to sections 1136 [<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4774">10 U.S.C. 4774</ref>, 9774] and 3734 [<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s259">40 U.S.C. 259</ref>, 267] of the Revised Statutes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Act <date date="1956-08-03">Aug. 3, 1956</date>, authorized procurement of communication services required for the semiautomatic ground environment system.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd0fe8903-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd0fe8904-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/214">Pub. L. 97–214</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, and applicable to military construction projects, and to construction and acquisition of military family housing, authorized before, on, or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/214/s12/a">section 12(a) of Pub. L. 97–214</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2801">section 2801 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
