<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd0fe8920-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s511"><num value="511">§ 511.</num><heading> Joint development of unitary plan for construction of facilities; construction at educational institutions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (hereinafter referred to as the “Administrator”) and the Secretary of Defense are authorized and directed jointly to develop a unitary plan for the construction of transsonic, supersonic, and hypersonic wind-tunnel facilities for the solution of research, development, and evaluation problems in aeronautics, including the construction of facilities at educational institutions within the continental limits of the United States for training and research in aeronautics, and to revise the uncompleted portions of the unitary plan from time to time to accord with changes in national defense requirements and scientific and technical advances. The Administrator and the Secretaries of the Army, the Navy, and the Air Force are authorized to proceed with the construction and equipment of facilities in implementation of the unitary plan to the extent permitted by appropriations pursuant to existing authority and the authority contained in this chapter. Any further implementation of the unitary plan shall be subject to such additional authorizations as may be approved by Congress.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idd0fe8921-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-10-27/ch766">Oct. 27, 1949, ch. 766</ref>, title I, § 101, <ref href="/us/stat/63/936">63 Stat. 936</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/568/tIII/s301/d/1">Pub. L. 85–568, title III, § 301(d)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1958-07-29">July 29, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/433">72 Stat. 433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/391/tIII/s312/1">Pub. L. 106–391, title III, § 312(1)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1594">114 Stat. 1594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd0fe8922-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd0fe8923-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd0fe8924-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/391">Pub. L. 106–391</ref> substituted “transsonic, supersonic, and hypersonic” for “transsonic and supersonic”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/568">Pub. L. 85–568</ref> substituted “The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (hereinafter referred to as the ‘Administrator’)” for “The National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics (hereinafter referred to as the ‘Committee’)”, and “Administrator” for “Committee” in second sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd0fe8925-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd0fe8926-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/568/tIII/s301/e">Pub. L. 85–568, title III, § 301(e)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-29">July 29, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/433">72 Stat. 433</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/568/tIII/s301/e">“This section [amending this section and sections 512, 513, and 515 of this title, section 22–1 of former Title 5, and sections 2302 and 2303 of Title 10, Armed Forces, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2472">section 2472 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare] shall take effect ninety days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1958-07-29">July 29, 1958</date>], or on any earlier date on which the Administrator [of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration] shall determine, and announce by proclamation published in the Federal Register, that the Administration has been organized and is prepared to discharge the duties and exercise the powers conferred upon it by this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idd0fe8927-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-27/ch766/tI/s106">Act Oct. 27, 1949, ch. 766, title I, § 106</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/937">63 Stat. 937</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1949-10-27/ch766/tI/s106">“This title [enacting this subchapter] may be cited as the ‘Unitary Wind Tunnel Plan Act of 1949’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-27/ch766/tII/s205">Act Oct. 27, 1949, ch. 766, title II, § 205</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/938">63 Stat. 938</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1949-10-27/ch766/tII/s205">“This title [enacting subchapter II of this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Air Engineering Development Center Act of 1949’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
