<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd0e69424-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s82"><num value="82">§ 82.</num><heading> Procurement of ships and material during war</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd0e69425-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s82/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The word “person” as used in subsections (b) and (c) shall include any individual, trustee, firm, association, company, or corporation. The word “ship” shall include any boat, vessel, submarine, or any form of aircraft, and the parts thereof. The words “war material” shall include arms, armament, ammunition, stores, supplies, and equipment for ships and airplanes, and everything required for or in connection with the production thereof. The word “factory” shall include any factory, workshop, engine works, building used for manufacture, assembling, construction, or any process, and any shipyard or dockyard. The words “United States” shall include the Canal Zone and all territory and waters, continental and insular, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd0e69426-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s82/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential powers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In time of war the President is authorized and empowered, in addition to all other existing provisions of law:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">First. Within the limits of the amounts appropriated therefor, to place an order with any person for such ships or war material as the necessities of the Government, to be determined by the President, may require and which are of the nature, kind, and quantity usually produced or capable of being produced by such person. Compliance with all such orders shall be obligatory on any person to whom such order is given, and such order shall take precedence over all other orders and contracts theretofore placed with such person. If any person owning, leasing, or operating any factory equipped for the building or production of ships or war material for the Navy shall refuse or fail to give to the United States such preference in the execution of such an order, or shall refuse to build, supply, furnish, or manufacture the kind, quantity, or quality of ships or war material so ordered at such reasonable price as shall be determined by the President, the President may take immediate possession of any factory of such person, or of any part thereof without taking possession of the entire factory, and may use the same at such times and in such manner as he may consider necessary or expedient.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Second. Within the limit of the amounts appropriated therefor, to modify or cancel any existing contract for the building, production, or purchase of ships or war material; and if any contractor shall refuse or fail to comply with the contract as so modified the President may take immediate possession of any factory of such contractor, or any part thereof without taking possession of the entire factory, and may use the same at such times and in such manner as he may consider necessary or expedient.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Third. To require the owner or occupier of any factory in which ships or war material are built or produced to place at the disposal of the United States the whole or any part of the output of such factory, and, within the limit of the amounts appropriated therefor, to deliver such output or parts thereof in such quantities and at such times as may be specified in the order at such reasonable price as shall be determined by the President.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Fourth. To requisition and take over for use or operation by the Government any factory, or any part thereof without taking possession of the entire factory, whether the United States has or has not any contract or agreement with the owner or occupier of such factory.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd0e69427-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s82/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002000"><num>1</num> So in original. No subsec. (c) has been enacted.</note> Compensation for commandeered material</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the United States shall cancel or modify any contract, make use of, assume, occupy, requisition, or take over any factory or part thereof, or any ships or war material, in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b), it shall make just compensation therefor, to be determined by the President, and if the amount thereof so determined by the President is unsatisfactory to the person entitled to receive the same, such person shall be paid fifty per centum of the amount so determined by the President and shall be entitled to sue the United States to recover such further sum as added to said fifty per centum shall make up such amount as will be just compensation therefor, in the manner provided for by section 1346 or <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1491">section 1491 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd0e69428-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1917-03-04/ch180">Mar. 4, 1917, ch. 180</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/1192">39 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd0e69429-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd0e6942a-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd0e6942b-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in subsec. (a), see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd0e6942c-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (d), “section 1346 or <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1491">section 1491 of title 28</ref>” substituted for “section twenty-four, paragraph twenty, and section one hundred and forty-five of the Judicial Code” (those sections classified to sections 41(20) and 250 of former Title 28, Judicial Code and Judiciary) on authority of <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">act June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/869">62 Stat. 869</ref>, section 1 of which enacted Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure. <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1346">Section 1346 of Title 28</ref> sets forth the basic jurisdiction of the district courts in cases in which the United States is defendant. <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1491">Section 1491 of Title 28</ref> sets forth the basic jurisdiction of the United States Court of Claims. Sections 24(20) and 145 of the Judicial Code were also classified to sections 1496, 1501, 1503, 2401, 2402, and 2501 of Title 28.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd0e6942d-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="similarProvisions" id="idd0e6942e-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Similar Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in the Naval Appropriation Act, 1918, <ref href="/us/act/1918-07-01/ch114">act July 1, 1918, ch. 114</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/40/719">40 Stat. 719</ref>, which terminated six months after the treaty of peace between the United States and Germany (<date date="1921-10-18">Oct. 18, 1921</date>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd0e6942f-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of War and Emergencies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1947-07-25/ch327/s3">Act July 25, 1947, ch. 327, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/451">61 Stat. 451</ref>, provided that in the interpretation of the provisions of this section, which authorized the President to acquire, through construction or conversion, ships, landing craft, and other vessels, the date <date date="1947-07-25">July 25, 1947</date>, shall be deemed to be the date of termination of any state of war theretofore declared by Congress and of the national emergencies proclaimed by the President on <date date="1939-09-08">Sept. 8, 1939</date>, and <date date="1941-05-27">May 27, 1941</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd0e69430-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idd0e69431-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12742. National Security Industrial Responsiveness</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12742, <date date="1991-01-08">Jan. 8, 1991</date>, 56 F.R. 1079, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 13286, § 36, <date date="2003-02-28">Feb. 28, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 10625, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including 50 U.S.C. App. 468 [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3816">50 U.S.C. 3816</ref>], <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4501">10 U.S.C. 4501</ref> and 9501 [former sections 4501 and 9501 of Title 10, Armed Forces], and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s82">50 U.S.C. 82</ref>, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 101. <i>Policy</i>. The United States must have the capability to rapidly mobilize its resources in the interest of national security. Therefore, to achieve prompt delivery of articles, products, and materials to meet national security requirements, the Government may place orders and require priority performance of these orders.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 102. <i>Delegation of Authority under 50 U.S.C. App. 468 [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3816">50 U.S.C. 3816</ref>].</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Subject to paragraph (b) of this section, the authorities vested in the President, under 50 U.S.C. App. 468 [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3816">50 U.S.C. 3816</ref>], with respect to the placing of orders for prompt delivery of articles or materials, except for the taking authority under (c), are hereby delegated to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) The Secretary of Agriculture with respect to all food resources;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) the Secretary of Energy with respect to all forms of energy;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) the Secretary of Transportation with respect to all forms of civil transportation; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) the Secretary of Commerce with respect to all other articles and materials, including construction materials.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The authorities delegated by paragraph (a) of this section shall be exercised only after:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) a determination by the Secretary of Defense that prompt delivery of the articles or materials for the exclusive use of the armed forces of the United States is in the interest of national security, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) a determination by the Secretary of Energy that the prompt delivery of the articles or materials for the Department of Energy’s atomic energy programs is in the interest of national security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) All determinations of the type described in paragraph (b) of this section and all delegations—made prior to the effective date of this order under the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4501">50 U.S.C. 4501</ref> et seq.], and under its implementing rules and regulations—shall be continued in effect, including but not limited to approved programs listed under the Defense Priorities and Allocations System (15 CFR Part 700).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 103. <i>Delegation of Authority under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4501">10 U.S.C. 4501</ref> and 9501, and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s82">50 U.S.C. 82</ref>.</i></p>
<p>(a) Subject to paragraph (b) of this section, the authorities vested in the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4501">10 U.S.C. 4501</ref> and 9501 [former sections 4501 and 9501 of Title 10] with respect to the placing of orders for necessary products or materials, and under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s82">50 U.S.C. 82</ref> with respect to the placing of orders for ships or war materials, except for the taking authority vested in the President by these acts, are hereby delegated to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to all food resources;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) the Secretary of Energy with respect to all forms of energy;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) the Secretary of Transportation with respect to all forms of civil transportation; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) the Secretary of Commerce with respect to all other products and materials, including construction materials.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The authorities delegated in paragraph (a) of this section may be exercised only after the President has made the statutorily required determination.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 104. <i>Implementation</i>. (a) The authorities delegated under sections 102 and 103 of this order shall include the power to redelegate such authorities, and the power of successive redelegation of such authorities, to departments and agencies, officers, and employees of the Government. The authorities delegated in this order may be implemented by regulations promulgated and administered by the Secretaries of Agriculture, Defense, Energy, Transportation, Homeland Security, and Commerce, and the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, as appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) All departments and agencies delegated authority under this order are hereby directed to amend their rules and regulations as necessary to reflect the new authorities delegated herein that are to be relied upon to carry out their functions. To the extent authorized by law, including 50 U.S.C. App. 486 [468] [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3816">50 U.S.C. 3816</ref>], <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4501">10 U.S.C. 4501</ref> and 9501 [former sections 4501 and 9501 of Title 10], and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s82">50 U.S.C. 82</ref>, all rules and regulations issued under the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, with respect to the placing of priority orders for articles, products, ships, and materials, including war materials, shall be deemed, where appropriate, to implement the authorities delegated by sections 102 and 103 of this order, and shall remain in effect until amended or revoked by the respective Secretary. All orders, regulations, and other forms of administrative actions purported to have been issued, taken, or continued in effect pursuant to the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, shall, until amended or revoked by the respective Secretaries or the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, as appropriate, remain in full force and effect, to the extent supported by any law or any authority delegated to the respective Secretary or the Director pursuant to this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Upon the request of the Secretary of Defense with respect to particular articles, products, or materials that are determined to be needed to meet national security requirements, any other official receiving a delegation of authority under this Executive order to place orders or to enforce precedence of such orders, shall exercise such authority within 10 calendar days of the receipt of the request; provided, that if the head of any department or agency having delegated responsibilities hereunder disagrees with a request of the Secretary of Defense, such department or agency head shall, within 10 calendar days from the receipt of the request, refer the issue to the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs, who shall ensure expeditious resolution of the issue.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Proposed department and agency regulations and procedures to implement the delegated authority under this order, and any new determinations made under sections 102(b)(1) or (2), shall be coordinated by the Secretary of Homeland Security with all appropriate departments and agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 105. <i>Judicial Review</i>. This order is intended only to improve the internal management of the executive branch and is not intended to create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law by a party against the United States, its agencies, its officers, or any person.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
