<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd10343b5-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s843"><num value="843">§ 843.</num><heading> Application of Internal Security Act of 1950 to members of Communist Party and other subversive organizations; “Communist Party” defined</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd10343b6-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s843/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Whoever knowingly and willfully becomes or remains a member of (1) the Communist Party, or (2) any other organization having for one of its purposes or objectives the establishment, control, conduct, seizure, or overthrow of the Government of the United States, or the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, by the use of force or violence, with knowledge of the purpose or objective of such organization shall be subject to all the provisions and penalties of the Internal Security Act of 1950, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s781">50 U.S.C. 781</ref> et seq.], as a member of a “Communist-action” organization.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd10343b7-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e" identifier="/us/usc/t50/s843/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> For the purposes of this section, the term “Communist Party” means the organization now known as the Communist Party of the United States of America, the Communist Party of any State or subdivision thereof, and any unit or subdivision of any such organization, whether or not any change is hereafter made in the name thereof.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd10343b8-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-24/ch886/s4">Aug. 24, 1954, ch. 886, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/776">68 Stat. 776</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd10343b9-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd10343ba-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd10343bb-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Internal Security Act of 1950, as amended, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-23/ch1024">act Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/987">64 Stat. 987</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapters I to III of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s781">section 781 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idd10343bc-47c4-11f1-8bcf-c89722bddd2e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Communist Control Act of 1954, and not as part of the Internal Security Act of 1950 which comprises subchapters I to III of this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
