<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0d880418-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10306"><num value="10306">§ 10306.</num><heading> Poll taxes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d880419-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10306/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional finding and declaration of policy against enforced payment of poll taxes as a device to impair voting rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that the requirement of the payment of a poll tax as a precondition to voting (i) precludes persons of limited means from voting or imposes unreasonable financial hardship upon such persons as a precondition to their exercise of the franchise, (ii) does not bear a reasonable relationship to any legitimate State interest in the conduct of elections, and (iii) in some areas has the purpose or effect of denying persons the right to vote because of race or color. Upon the basis of these findings, Congress declares that the constitutional right of citizens to vote is denied or abridged in some areas by the requirement of the payment of a poll tax as a precondition to voting.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d88041a-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10306/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Attorney General to institute actions for relief against enforcement of poll tax requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the exercise of the powers of Congress under section 5 of the fourteenth amendment, section 2 of the fifteenth amendment and section 2 of the twenty-fourth amendment, the Attorney General is authorized and directed to institute forthwith in the name of the United States such actions, including actions against States or political subdivisions, for declaratory judgment or injunctive relief against the enforcement of any requirement of the payment of a poll tax as a precondition to voting, or substitute therefor enacted after <date date="1964-11-01">November 1, 1964</date>, as will be necessary to implement the declaration of subsection (a) and the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d88041b-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10306/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of three-judge district courts; appeal to Supreme Court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction of such actions which shall be heard and determined by a court of three judges in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2284">section 2284 of title 28</ref> and any appeal shall lie to the Supreme Court. It shall be the duty of the judges designated to hear the case to assign the case for hearing at the earliest practicable date, to participate in the hearing and determination thereof, and to cause the case to be in every way expedited.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0d88041c-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/110/tI/s10">Pub. L. 89–110, title I, § 10</ref>, <date date="1965-08-06">Aug. 6, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/442">79 Stat. 442</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/91/285/s2">Pub. L. 91–285, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-06-22">June 22, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/314">84 Stat. 314</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/73/tIV/s408">Pub. L. 94–73, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="1975-08-06">Aug. 6, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/405">89 Stat. 405</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0d88041d-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0d88041e-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0d88041f-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973h">section 1973h of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0d880420-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/73/s408/2">Pub. L. 94–73, § 408(2)</ref>, (3), inserted reference to section 2 of twenty-fourth amendment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/73/s408/1">Pub. L. 94–73, § 408(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which related to post-payment of poll taxes in event of a judicial declaration of constitutionality.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
