<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0d8cbfab-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10507"><num value="10507">§ 10507.</num><heading> Survey to compile registration and voting statistics</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d8cbfac-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10507/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Elections to House of Representatives and elections designated by United States Commission on Civil Rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress hereby directs the Director of the Census forthwith to conduct a survey to compile registration and voting statistics: (i) in every State or political subdivision with respect to which the prohibitions of <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s10303/a">section 10303(a) of this title</ref> are in effect, for every statewide general election for Members of the United States House of Representatives after <date date="1974-01-01">January 1, 1974</date>; and (ii) in every State or political subdivision for any election designated by the United States Commission on Civil Rights. Such surveys shall only include a count of citizens of voting age, race or color, and national origin, and a determination of the extent to which such persons are registered to vote and have voted in the elections surveyed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d8cbfad-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10507/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition against compulsion to disclose personal data; advice of rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any survey under subsection (a) of this section no person shall be compelled to disclose his race, color, national origin, political party affiliation, or how he voted (or the reasons therefor), nor shall any penalty be imposed for his failure or refusal to make such disclosures. Every person interrogated orally, by written survey or questionnaire, or by any other means with respect to such information shall be fully advised of his right to fail or refuse to furnish such information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d8cbfae-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10507/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Census shall, at the earliest practicable time, report to the Congress the results of every survey conducted pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d8cbfaf-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s10507/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of information; penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of section 9 and chapter 7 of title 13 shall apply to any survey, collection, or compilation of registration and voting statistics carried out under subsection (a) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0d8cbfb0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/110/tII/s207">Pub. L. 89–110, title II, § 207</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/73/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 94–73, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1975-08-06">Aug. 6, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/404">89 Stat. 404</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0d8cbfb1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0d8cbfb2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0d8cbfb3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973aa–5">section 1973aa–5 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
