<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0d965ca9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506"><num value="20506">§ 20506.</num><heading> Voter registration agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d965caa-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cab-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each State shall designate agencies for the registration of voters in elections for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cac-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Each State shall designate as voter registration agencies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cad-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all offices in the State that provide public assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cae-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all offices in the State that provide State-funded programs primarily engaged in providing services to persons with disabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965caf-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cb0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In addition to voter registration agencies designated under paragraph (2), each State shall designate other offices within the State as voter registration agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cb1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Voter registration agencies designated under subparagraph (A) may include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cb2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> State or local government offices such as public libraries, public schools, offices of city and county clerks (including marriage license bureaus), fishing and hunting license bureaus, government revenue offices, unemployment compensation offices, and offices not described in paragraph (2)(B) that provide services to persons with disabilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cb3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Federal and nongovernmental offices, with the agreement of such offices.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cb4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cb5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> At each voter registration agency, the following services shall be made available:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cb6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Distribution of mail voter registration application forms in accordance with paragraph (6).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cb7-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Assistance to applicants in completing voter registration application forms, unless the applicant refuses such assistance.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cb8-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Acceptance of completed voter registration application forms for transmittal to the appropriate State election official.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cb9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If a voter registration agency designated under paragraph (2)(B) provides services to a person with a disability at the person’s home, the agency shall provide the services described in subparagraph (A) at the person’s home.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cba-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> A person who provides service described in paragraph (4) shall not—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cbb-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> seek to influence an applicant’s political preference or party registration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cbc-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> display any such political preference or party allegiance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cbd-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose or effect of which is to discourage the applicant from registering to vote; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cbe-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose or effect of which is to lead the applicant to believe that a decision to register or not to register has any bearing on the availability of services or benefits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cbf-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> A voter registration agency that is an office that provides service or assistance in addition to conducting voter registration shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cc0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> distribute with each application for such service or assistance, and with each recertification, renewal, or change of address form relating to such service or assistance—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d965cc1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the mail voter registration application form described in <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s20508/a/2">section 20508(a)(2) of this title</ref>, including a statement that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d965cc2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> specifies each eligibility requirement (including citizenship);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d965cc3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> contains an attestation that the applicant meets each such requirement; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d965cc4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> requires the signature of the applicant, under penalty of perjury; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d965cc5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the office’s own form if it is equivalent to the form described in <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s20508/a/2">section 20508(a)(2) of this title</ref>,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">unless the applicant, in writing, declines to register to vote;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965cc6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> provide a form that includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d965cc7-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the question, “If you are not registered to vote where you live now, would you like to apply to register to vote here today?”;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d965cc8-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the agency provides public assistance, the statement, “Applying to register or declining to register to vote will not affect the amount of assistance that you will be provided by this agency.”;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d965cc9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> boxes for the applicant to check to indicate whether the applicant would like to register or declines to register to vote (failure to check either box being deemed to constitute a declination to register for purposes of subparagraph (C)), together with the statement (in close proximity to the boxes and in prominent type), “IF YOU DO NOT CHECK EITHER BOX, YOU WILL BE CONSIDERED TO HAVE DECIDED NOT TO REGISTER TO VOTE AT THIS TIME.”;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d965cca-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the statement, “If you would like help in filling out the voter registration application form, we will help you. The decision whether to seek or accept help is yours. You may fill out the application form in private.”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d965ccb-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the statement, “If you believe that someone has interfered with your right to register or to decline to register to vote, your right to privacy in deciding whether to register or in applying to register to vote, or your right to choose your own political party or other political preference, you may file a complaint with _____.”, the blank being filled by the name, address, and telephone number of the appropriate official to whom such a complaint should be addressed; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d965ccc-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide to each applicant who does not decline to register to vote the same degree of assistance with regard to the completion of the registration application form as is provided by the office with regard to the completion of its own forms, unless the applicant refuses such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965ccd-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> No information relating to a declination to register to vote in connection with an application made at an office described in paragraph (6) may be used for any purpose other than voter registration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d965cce-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal Government and private sector cooperation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All departments, agencies, and other entities of the executive branch of the Federal Government shall, to the greatest extent practicable, cooperate with the States in carrying out subsection (a), and all nongovernmental entities are encouraged to do so.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d965ccf-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Armed Forces recruitment offices</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cd0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each State and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly develop and implement procedures for persons to apply to register to vote at recruitment offices of the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cd1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A recruitment office of the Armed Forces of the United States shall be considered to be a voter registration agency designated under subsection (a)(2) for all purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d965cd2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal deadline</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cd3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (2), a completed registration application accepted at a voter registration agency shall be transmitted to the appropriate State election official not later than 10 days after the date of acceptance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d965cd4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s20506/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a registration application is accepted within 5 days before the last day for registration to vote in an election, the application shall be transmitted to the appropriate State election official not later than 5 days after the date of acceptance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0d965cd5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/31/s7">Pub. L. 103–31, § 7</ref>, <date date="1993-05-20">May 20, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/80">107 Stat. 80</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0d965cd6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0d965cd7-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0d965cd8-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973gg–5">section 1973gg–5 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0d965cd9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id0d965cda-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12926. Implementation of National Voter Registration Act of 1993</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12926, <date date="1994-09-12">Sept. 12, 1994</date>, 59 F.R. 47227, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 14019, § 4(a), <date date="2021-03-07">Mar. 7, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 13624, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, and in order to ensure, as required by section 7(b) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973gg">42 U.S.C. 1973gg</ref> [sic]) [<ref href="/us/usc/t52/s20506/b">52 U.S.C. 20506(b)</ref>] (“the Act”), that departments, agencies, and other entities of the executive branch of the Federal Government cooperate with the States in carrying out the Act’s requirements, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Assistance to States</i>. To the greatest extent practicable, departments, agencies, and other entities of the executive branch of the Federal Government that provide, in whole or in part, funding, grants, or assistance for, or with respect to the administration of, any program of public assistance or services to persons with disabilities within the meaning of section 7(a) of the Act shall: (a) provide, to State agencies administering any such program, guidance for the implementation of the requirements of section 7 of the Act, including guidance for use and distribution of voter registration forms in connection with applications for service;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) assist each such State agency administering any such program with the costs of implementation of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t52/s20501">52 U.S.C. 20501</ref> et seq.], consistent with legal authority and the availability of funds, and promptly indicate to each State agency the extent to which such assistance will be made available; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) designate an office or staff to be available to provide technical assistance to such State agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Armed Forces Recruitment Offices</i>. The Secretary of Defense is directed to work with the appropriate State elections authorities in each State to develop procedures for persons to apply to register to vote at Armed Forces recruitment offices as required by section 7(c) of the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Acceptance of Designation</i>. [Superseded by Ex. Ord. No. 14019, <date date="2021-03-07">Mar. 7, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 13623, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s20101">section 20101 of this title</ref>, see section 4(a) of Ex. Ord. No. 14019.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
