<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0db073d1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108"><num value="30108">§ 30108.</num><heading> Advisory opinions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db073d2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requests by persons, candidates, or authorized committees; subject matter; time for response</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0db073d3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 60 days after the Commission receives from a person a complete written request concerning the application of this Act, chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26, or a rule or regulation prescribed by the Commission, with respect to a specific transaction or activity by the person, the Commission shall render a written advisory opinion relating to such transaction or activity to the person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0db073d4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an advisory opinion is requested by a candidate, or any authorized committee of such candidate, during the 60-day period before any election for Federal office involving the requesting party, the Commission shall render a written advisory opinion relating to such request no later than 20 days after the Commission receives a complete written request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db073d5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures applicable to initial proposal of rules or regulations, and advisory opinions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any rule of law which is not stated in this Act or in chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26 may be initially proposed by the Commission only as a rule or regulation pursuant to procedures established in <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30111/d">section 30111(d) of this title</ref>. No opinion of an advisory nature may be issued by the Commission or any of its employees except in accordance with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db073d6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons entitled to rely upon opinions; scope of protection for good faith reliance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0db073d7-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any advisory opinion rendered by the Commission under subsection (a) may be relied upon by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db073d8-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any person involved in the specific transaction or activity with respect to which such advisory opinion is rendered; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db073d9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any person involved in any specific transaction or activity which is indistinguishable in all its material aspects from the transaction or activity with respect to which such advisory opinion is rendered.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0db073da-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, any person who relies upon any provision or finding of an advisory opinion in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (1) and who acts in good faith in accordance with the provisions and findings of such advisory opinion shall not, as a result of any such act, be subject to any sanction provided by this Act or by chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db073db-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30108/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Requests made public; submission of written comments by interested public</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall make public any request made under subsection (a) for an advisory opinion. Before rendering an advisory opinion, the Commission shall accept written comments submitted by any interested party within the 10-day period following the date the request is made public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0db073dc-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/225/tIII/s308">Pub. L. 92–225, title III, § 308</ref>, formerly § 313, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/tII/s208/a">Pub. L. 93–443, title II, § 208(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1283">88 Stat. 1283</ref>; renumbered § 312 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/tI">Pub. L. 94–283, title I</ref>, §§ 105, 108(a), <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/481">90 Stat. 481</ref>, 482; renumbered § 308 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/tI">Pub. L. 96–187, title I</ref>, §§ 105(4), 107(a), <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1354">93 Stat. 1354</ref>, 1357; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0db073dd-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0db073de-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0db073df-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (b), and (c)(2), means the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0db073e0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s437f">section 437f of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Some section numbers referenced in amendment notes below reflect the classification of such sections prior to their editorial reclassification to this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0db073e1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s308">section 308 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s437b">section 437b of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/96/187">Pub. L. 96–187</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s308">section 308 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s437a">section 437a of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/94/283">Pub. L. 94–283</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s308">section 308 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was renumbered section 311, and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30111">section 30111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0db073e2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (a)(1), (b), (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s107">Pub. L. 96–187, § 107</ref>, redesignated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted provisions requiring the Commission to render a written advisory opinion no later than 60 days after receiving a written request concerning the application of this Act, chapters 95 or 96 of title 26, or a rule or regulation for provisions requiring a written advisory opinion within a reasonable time in response to a written request by any individual holding Federal office, candidate for Federal office, any political committee or the national committee of a political party, provisions requiring promulgation of a rule or regulation pursuant to procedures established by <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s438/c">section 438(c) of this title</ref>, and prohibiting issuance of advisory opinions except in accordance with the provisions of this section, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s107">Pub. L. 96–187, § 107</ref>, struck out the par. (1) and (2) designations and substituted provisions requiring any rule of law not stated in this Act or chapter 95 or 96 of title 26 be initially proposed as a rule or regulation pursuant to the procedures of <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s438/d">section 438(d) of this title</ref>, and provisions prohibiting issuance of an advisory opinion except in accordance with the provisions of this section for provisions holding any person relying upon an advisory opinion free from any sanction provided by this Act or chapter 95 or 96 of title 26, and provisions allowing reliance on an advisory opinion by any person involved in the specific transaction and any person involved in a transaction indistinguishable from the transaction with respect to which such opinion was rendered.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s107">Pub. L. 96–187, § 107</ref>, redesignated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted provisions allowing reliance on any advisory opinion by any person involved in the specific transaction or activity to which such opinion was rendered and any person involved in a transaction or activity indistinguishable from the transaction with respect to which such opinion was rendered for provisions mandating that any request for an advisory opinion be made public and allowing any interested party to transmit written comments to the Commission prior to the rendering of its opinion, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s107">Pub. L. 96–187, § 107</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/s108/a">Pub. L. 94–283, § 108(a)</ref>, added national committees of political parties to the enumeration of persons and political bodies authorized to request advisory opinions, substituted the application of general rules of law as stated in the Act or in chapter 95 or 96 of title 26 or as prescribed by rules or regulations of the Commission to specific factual situations for the resolution of the question of whether or not any specific transaction or activity by an individual, candidate, or political committee would constitute a violation of the Act as the subject matter of advisory opinions, and inserted requirement that rules or regulations forming the basis for rules of law be rules or regulations proposed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s438/c">section 438(c) of this title</ref> and that advisory opinions be issued only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/s108/a">Pub. L. 94–283, § 108(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted provisions that any person who relies upon any finding or provision of an advisory opinion in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (2) and who acts in good faith in accordance with the provisions and findings of the advisory opinion shall not, as a result of that act, be subject to any sanctions provided by the Act or by chapter 95 or 96 of title 26 for provisions that any person with respect to whom an advisory opinion was rendered under subsection (a) who acted in good faith in accordance with the provisions and findings of an advisory opinion would be presumed to be in compliance with the Act, and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0db073e3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0db073e4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/187">Pub. L. 96–187</ref> effective <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s301/a">section 301(a) of Pub. L. 96–187</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0db073e5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s410/a">section 410(a) of Pub. L. 93–443</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1974 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0db073e6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Conformance of Advisory Opinions Issued Prior to <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, to Requirements Imposed Under 1976 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/283/tI/s108/b">Pub. L. 94–283, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/482">90 Stat. 482</ref>, provided that the Commission would, no later than 90 days after <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, conform the advisory opinions issued before that date to the requirements established by subsec. (a) of this section, and subsec. (b) of this section would apply to all advisory opinions issued before <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, as conformed to meet the requirements of subsec. (a) of this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
