<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0db79f85-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30119"><num value="30119">§ 30119.</num><heading> Contributions by Government contractors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f86-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30119/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f87-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30119/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> who enters into any contract with the United States or any department or agency thereof either for the rendition of personal services or furnishing any material, supplies, or equipment to the United States or any department or agency thereof or for selling any land or building to the United States or any department or agency thereof, if payment for the performance of such contract or payment for such material, supplies, equipment, land, or building is to be made in whole or in part from funds appropriated by the Congress, at any time between the commencement of negotiations for and the later of (A) the completion of performance under; or (B) the termination of negotiations for, such contract or furnishing of material, supplies, equipment, land, or buildings, directly or indirectly to make any contribution of money or other things of value, or to promise expressly or impliedly to make any such contribution to any political party, committee, or candidate for public office or to any person for any political purpose or use; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f88-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30119/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> knowingly to solicit any such contribution from any such person for any such purpose during any such period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f89-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30119/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Separate segregated funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section does not prohibit or make unlawful the establishment or administration of, or the solicitation of contributions to, any separate segregated fund by any corporation, labor organization, membership organization, cooperative, or corporation without capital stock for the purpose of influencing the nomination for election, or election, of any person to Federal office, unless the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30118">section 30118 of this title</ref> prohibit or make unlawful the establishment or administration of, or the solicitation of contributions to, such fund. Each specific prohibition, allowance, and duty applicable to a corporation, labor organization, or separate segregated fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30118">section 30118 of this title</ref> applies to a corporation, labor organization, or separate segregated fund to which this subsection applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f8a-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30119/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> “Labor organization” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “labor organization” has the meaning given it by <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30118/b/1">section 30118(b)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0db79f8b-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/225/tIII/s317">Pub. L. 92–225, title III, § 317</ref>, formerly § 322, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/tI/s112/2">Pub. L. 94–283, title I, § 112(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/492">90 Stat. 492</ref>; renumbered § 317, <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/tI/s105/5">Pub. L. 96–187, title I, § 105(5)</ref>, <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1354">93 Stat. 1354</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0db79f8c-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0db79f8d-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0db79f8e-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30118">Section 30118 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (b) and (c), was in the original “section 321” meaning <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s321">section 321 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30123">section 30123 of this title</ref>. In view of the renumbering of section 321 as section 316 by <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s105/5">section 105(5) of Pub. L. 96–187</ref>, the reference has been translated as reading “section 316” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0db79f8f-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s441c">section 441c of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0db79f90-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s317">section 317 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was renumbered section 313, and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30114">section 30114 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s317">section 317 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was renumbered section 312, and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30113">section 30113 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
