<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0db79fda-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125"><num value="30125">§ 30125.</num><heading> Soft money of political parties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fdb-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> National committees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fdc-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A national committee of a political party (including a national congressional campaign committee of a political party) may not solicit, receive, or direct to another person a contribution, donation, or transfer of funds or any other thing of value, or spend any funds, that are not subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fdd-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The prohibition established by paragraph (1) applies to any such national committee, any officer or agent acting on behalf of such a national committee, and any entity that is directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained, or controlled by such a national committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fde-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> State, district, and local committees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fdf-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), an amount that is expended or disbursed for Federal election activity by a State, district, or local committee of a political party (including an entity that is directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained, or controlled by a State, district, or local committee of a political party and an officer or agent acting on behalf of such committee or entity), or by an association or similar group of candidates for State or local office or of individuals holding State or local office, shall be made from funds subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fe0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fe1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding clause (i) or (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101/20/A">section 30101(20)(A) of this title</ref>, and subject to subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall not apply to any amount expended or disbursed by a State, district, or local committee of a political party for an activity described in either such clause to the extent the amounts expended or disbursed for such activity are allocated (under regulations prescribed by the Commission) among amounts—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fe2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> which consist solely of contributions subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act (other than amounts described in subparagraph (B)(iii)); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fe3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> other amounts which are not subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act (other than any requirements of this subsection).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fe4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall only apply if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fe5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the activity does not refer to a clearly identified candidate for Federal office;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fe6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amounts expended or disbursed are not for the costs of any broadcasting, cable, or satellite communication, other than a communication which refers solely to a clearly identified candidate for State or local office;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fe7-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the amounts expended or disbursed which are described in subparagraph (A)(ii) are paid from amounts which are donated in accordance with State law and which meet the requirements of subparagraph (C), except that no person (including any person established, financed, maintained, or controlled by such person) may donate more than $10,000 to a State, district, or local committee of a political party in a calendar year for such expenditures or disbursements; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fe8-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> the amounts expended or disbursed are made solely from funds raised by the State, local, or district committee which makes such expenditure or disbursement, and do not include any funds provided to such committee from—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0db79fe9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any other State, local, or district committee of any State party,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0db79fea-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the national committee of a political party (including a national congressional campaign committee of a political party),</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0db79feb-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> any officer or agent acting on behalf of any committee described in subclause (I) or (II), or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0db79fec-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/B/iv/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> any entity directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained, or controlled by any committee described in subclause (I) or (II).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fed-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibiting involvement of national parties, Federal candidates and officeholders, and State parties acting jointly</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding subsection (e) (other than subsection (e)(3)), amounts specifically authorized to be spent under subparagraph (B)(iii) meet the requirements of this subparagraph only if the amounts—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fee-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are not solicited, received, directed, transferred, or spent by or in the name of any person described in subsection (a) or (e); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fef-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> are not solicited, received, or directed through fundraising activities conducted jointly by 2 or more State, local, or district committees of any political party or their agents, or by a State, local, or district committee of a political party on behalf of the State, local, or district committee of a political party or its agent in one or more other States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ff0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Fundraising costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An amount spent by a person described in subsection (a) or (b) to raise funds that are used, in whole or in part, for expenditures and disbursements for a Federal election activity shall be made from funds subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ff1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt organizations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A national, State, district, or local committee of a political party (including a national congressional campaign committee of a political party), an entity that is directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained, or controlled by any such national, State, district, or local committee or its agent, and an officer or agent acting on behalf of any such party committee or entity, shall not solicit any funds for, or make or direct any donations to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79ff2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an organization that is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c">section 501(c) of title 26</ref> and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such title (or has submitted an application for determination of tax exempt status under such section) and that makes expenditures or disbursements in connection with an election for Federal office (including expenditures or disbursements for Federal election activity); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79ff3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an organization described in section 527 of such title (other than a political committee, a State, district, or local committee of a political party, or the authorized campaign committee of a candidate for State or local office).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ff4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal candidates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ff5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A candidate, individual holding Federal office, agent of a candidate or an individual holding Federal office, or an entity directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained or controlled by or acting on behalf of 1 or more candidates or individuals holding Federal office, shall not—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0db79ff6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> solicit, receive, direct, transfer, or spend funds in connection with an election for Federal office, including funds for any Federal election activity, unless the funds are subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0db79ff7-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> solicit, receive, direct, transfer, or spend funds in connection with any election other than an election for Federal office or disburse funds in connection with such an election unless the funds—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79ff8-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are not in excess of the amounts permitted with respect to contributions to candidates and political committees under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30116/a">section 30116(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79ff9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> are not from sources prohibited by this Act from making contributions in connection with an election for Federal office.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ffa-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> State law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) does not apply to the solicitation, receipt, or spending of funds by an individual described in such paragraph who is or was also a candidate for a State or local office solely in connection with such election for State or local office if the solicitation, receipt, or spending of funds is permitted under State law and refers only to such State or local candidate, or to any other candidate for the State or local office sought by such candidate, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ffb-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Fundraising events</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) or subsection (b)(2)(C), a candidate or an individual holding Federal office may attend, speak, or be a featured guest at a fundraising event for a State, district, or local committee of a political party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ffc-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Permitting certain solicitations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79ffd-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> General solicitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, an individual described in paragraph (1) may make a general solicitation of funds on behalf of any organization that is described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c">section 501(c) of title 26</ref> and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such title (or has submitted an application for determination of tax exempt status under such section) (other than an entity whose principal purpose is to conduct activities described in clauses (i) and (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101/20/A">section 30101(20)(A) of this title</ref>) where such solicitation does not specify how the funds will or should be spent.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0dba10fe-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain specific solicitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In addition to the general solicitations permitted under subparagraph (A), an individual described in paragraph (1) may make a solicitation explicitly to obtain funds for carrying out the activities described in clauses (i) and (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101/20/A">section 30101(20)(A) of this title</ref>, or for an entity whose principal purpose is to conduct such activities, if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0dba10ff-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the solicitation is made only to individuals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0dba1100-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/e/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount solicited from any individual during any calendar year does not exceed $20,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dba1101-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> State candidates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0dba1102-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A candidate for State or local office, individual holding State or local office, or an agent of such a candidate or individual may not spend any funds for a communication described in <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101/20/A/iii">section 30101(20)(A)(iii) of this title</ref> unless the funds are subject to the limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements of this Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0dba1103-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30125/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for certain communications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an individual described in such paragraph if the communication involved is in connection with an election for such State or local office and refers only to such individual or to any other candidate for the State or local office held or sought by such individual, or both.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0dba1104-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/225/tIII/s323">Pub. L. 92–225, title III, § 323</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/155/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 107–155, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-03-27">Mar. 27, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/82">116 Stat. 82</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dba1105-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0dba1106-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0dba1107-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0dba1108-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s441i">section 441i of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0dba1109-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s323">section 323 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s441i">section 441i of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, and related to acceptance of excessive honorariums, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/90/tI/s6/d">Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/451">105 Stat. 451</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s323">section 323 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was renumbered section 318, and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30120">section 30120 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0dba110a-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0dba110b-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="2002-11-06">Nov. 6, 2002</date>, except that subsec. (b) of this section not applicable with respect to runoff elections, recounts, or election contests resulting from elections held prior to <date date="2002-11-06">Nov. 6, 2002</date>, with transitional rules for the spending of soft money of national political parties, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/155/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 107–155</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2002 Amendment; Regulations note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
