<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0db79f91-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120"><num value="30120">§ 30120.</num><heading> Publication and distribution of statements and solicitations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f92-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of funding and authorizing sources</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a political committee makes a disbursement for the purpose of financing any communication through any broadcasting station, newspaper, magazine, outdoor advertising facility, mailing, or any other type of general public political advertising, or whenever any person makes a disbursement for the purpose of financing communications expressly advocating the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate, or solicits any contribution through any broadcasting station, newspaper, magazine, outdoor advertising facility, mailing, or any other type of general public political advertising or makes a disbursement for an electioneering communication (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30104/f/3">section 30104(f)(3) of this title</ref>), such communication—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f93-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if paid for and authorized by a candidate, an authorized political committee of a candidate, or its agents, shall clearly state that the communication has been paid for by such authorized political committee, or <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002025">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002025"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “or” probably should appear at the end of par. (2).</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f94-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if paid for by other persons but authorized by a candidate, an authorized political committee of a candidate, or its agents, shall clearly state that the communication is paid for by such other persons and authorized by such authorized political committee; <sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f95-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> if not authorized by a candidate, an authorized political committee of a candidate, or its agents, shall clearly state the name and permanent street address, telephone number, or World Wide Web address of the person who paid for the communication and state that the communication is not authorized by any candidate or candidate’s committee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f96-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Charge for newspaper or magazine space</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person who sells space in a newspaper or magazine to a candidate or to the agent of a candidate, for use in connection with such candidate’s campaign, may charge any amount for such space which exceeds the amount charged for comparable use of such space for other purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f97-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Specification</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any printed communication described in subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f98-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be of sufficient type size to be clearly readable by the recipient of the communication;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f99-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> be contained in a printed box set apart from the other contents of the communication; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0db79f9a-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> be printed with a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f9b-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f9c-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Communications by candidates or authorized persons</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f9d-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> By radio</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any communication described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) which is transmitted through radio shall include, in addition to the requirements of that paragraph, an audio statement by the candidate that identifies the candidate and states that the candidate has approved the communication.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79f9e-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> By television</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any communication described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) which is transmitted through television shall include, in addition to the requirements of that paragraph, a statement that identifies the candidate and states that the candidate has approved the communication. Such statement—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79f9f-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> shall be conveyed by—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0db79fa0-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> an unobscured, full-screen view of the candidate making the statement, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0db79fa1-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the candidate in voice-over, accompanied by a clearly identifiable photographic or similar image of the candidate; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0db79fa2-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall also appear in writing at the end of the communication in a clearly readable manner with a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement, for a period of at least 4 seconds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0db79fa3-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0" identifier="/us/usc/t52/s30120/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Communications by others</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any communication described in paragraph (3) of subsection (a) which is transmitted through radio or television shall include, in addition to the requirements of that paragraph, in a clearly spoken manner, the following audio statement: “_____ is responsible for the content of this advertising.” (with the blank to be filled in with the name of the political committee or other person paying for the communication and the name of any connected organization of the payor). If transmitted through television, the statement shall be conveyed by an unobscured, full-screen view of a representative of the political committee or other person making the statement, or by a representative of such political committee or other person in voice-over, and shall also appear in a clearly readable manner with a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement, for a period of at least 4 seconds.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0db79fa4-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/225/tIII/s318">Pub. L. 92–225, title III, § 318</ref>, formerly § 323, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/tI/s112/2">Pub. L. 94–283, title I, § 112(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/493">90 Stat. 493</ref>; renumbered § 318 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/tI">Pub. L. 96–187, title I</ref>, §§ 105(5), 111, <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1354">93 Stat. 1354</ref>, 1365; <ref href="/us/pl/107/155/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 107–155, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2002-03-27">Mar. 27, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/105">116 Stat. 105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0db79fa5-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0db79fa6-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0db79fa7-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s441d">section 441d of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Some section numbers referenced in amendment notes below reflect the classification of such sections prior to their editorial reclassification to this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0db79fa8-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s318">section 318 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s439b">section 439b of Title 2</ref>, The Congress, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/96/187">Pub. L. 96–187</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/92/225/s318">section 318 of Pub. L. 92–225</ref> was renumbered section 313, and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30114">section 30114 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0db79fa9-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/155/s311/1/A/iv">Pub. L. 107–155, § 311(1)(A)(iv)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or makes a disbursement for an electioneering communication (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s434/f/3">section 434(f)(3) of this title</ref>)” after “public political advertising” in introductory provisions, was executed by making the insertion after those words the second time appearing, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/155/s311/1/A/i">Pub. L. 107–155, § 311(1)(A)(i)</ref>–(iii), in introductory provisions, substituted “Whenever a political committee makes a disbursement for the purpose of financing any communication through any broadcasting station, newspaper, magazine, outdoor advertising facility, mailing, or any other type of general public political advertising, or whenever any person makes a disbursement” for “Whenever any person makes an expenditure” and struck out “direct” before “mailing,” the second time appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/155/s311/1/B">Pub. L. 107–155, § 311(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “and permanent street address, telephone number, or World Wide Web address” after “name”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/155/s311/2">Pub. L. 107–155, § 311(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s111">Pub. L. 96–187, § 111</ref>, designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), and in revising text, provided for solicitation of contributions; prescribed three categories of communications: (1) paid for and authorized by the candidate, (2) paid for by others but authorized by the candidate, and (3) not authorized by the candidate for prior two categories where (1) authorized and (2) not authorized by the candidate; struck out requirement for statement in accordance with regulations of Commission and in a conspicuous manner; and struck out from the communication not authorized by the candidate statement of name of affiliated or connected organization required to be disclosed under section 433 (b)(2) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s111">Pub. L. 96–187, § 111</ref>, added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0db79faa-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0db79fab-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/155">Pub. L. 107–155</ref> effective <date date="2002-11-06">Nov. 6, 2002</date>, but not applicable with respect to runoff elections, recounts, or election contests resulting from elections held prior to <date date="2002-11-06">Nov. 6, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/155/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 107–155</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2002 Amendment; Regulations note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0db79fac-2931-11f1-afae-ea39e71ac6b0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/187">Pub. L. 96–187</ref> effective <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/187/s301/a">section 301(a) of Pub. L. 96–187</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
