<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd2c23413-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1005"><num value="1005">§ 1005.</num><heading> Cooperation of equipment manufacturers and providers of telecommunications support services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd2c23414-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1005/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A telecommunications carrier shall consult, as necessary, in a timely fashion with manufacturers of its telecommunications transmission and switching equipment and its providers of telecommunications support services for the purpose of ensuring that current and planned equipment, facilities, and services comply with the capability requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1002">section 1002 of this title</ref> and the capacity requirements identified by the Attorney General under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1003">section 1003 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd2c23415-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1005/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to sections 1003(e), 1007(a), and 1008(b) and (d) of this title, a manufacturer of telecommunications transmission or switching equipment and a provider of telecommunications support services shall, on a reasonably timely basis and at a reasonable charge, make available to the telecommunications carriers using its equipment, facilities, or services such features or modifications as are necessary to permit such carriers to comply with the capability requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1002">section 1002 of this title</ref> and the capacity requirements identified by the Attorney General under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1003">section 1003 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd2c23416-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/414/tI/s106">Pub. L. 103–414, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4284">108 Stat. 4284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
