<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idce16ec22-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007"><num value="1007">§ 1007.</num><heading> Enforcement orders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce16ec23-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grounds for issuance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A court shall issue an order enforcing this subchapter under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2522">section 2522 of title 18</ref> only if the court finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce16ec24-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> alternative technologies or capabilities or the facilities of another carrier are not reasonably available to law enforcement for implementing the interception of communications or access to call-identifying information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce16ec25-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> compliance with the requirements of this subchapter is reasonably achievable through the application of available technology to the equipment, facility, or service at issue or would have been reasonably achievable if timely action had been taken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce16ec26-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for compliance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon issuing an order enforcing this subchapter, the court shall specify a reasonable time and conditions for complying with its order, considering the good faith efforts to comply in a timely manner, any effect on the carrier’s, manufacturer’s, or service provider’s ability to continue to do business, the degree of culpability or delay in undertaking efforts to comply, and such other matters as justice may require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce16ec27-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An order enforcing this subchapter may not—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce16ec28-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> require a telecommunications carrier to meet the Government’s <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002059">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002059"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> demand for interception of communications and acquisition of call-identifying information to any extent in excess of the capacity for which the Attorney General has agreed to reimburse such carrier;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce16ec29-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> require any telecommunications carrier to comply with assistance capability requirement <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002060">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002060"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “requirements”.</note> of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1002">section 1002 of this title</ref> if the Commission has determined (pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1008/b/1">section 1008(b)(1) of this title</ref>) that compliance is not reasonably achievable, unless the Attorney General has agreed (pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1008/b/2">section 1008(b)(2) of this title</ref>) to pay the costs described in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1008/b/2/A">section 1008(b)(2)(A) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce16ec2a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> require a telecommunications carrier to modify, for the purpose of complying with the assistance capability requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1002">section 1002 of this title</ref>, any equipment, facility, or service deployed on or before <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, unless—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce16ec2b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Attorney General has agreed to pay the telecommunications carrier for all reasonable costs directly associated with modifications necessary to bring the equipment, facility, or service into compliance with those requirements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce16ec2c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1007/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the equipment, facility, or service has been replaced or significantly upgraded or otherwise undergoes major modification.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idce16ec2d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/414/tI/s108">Pub. L. 103–414, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4285">108 Stat. 4285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
