<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd2c4a62d-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1301"><num value="1301">§ 1301.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd2c4a62e-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1301/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The deployment and adoption of broadband technology has resulted in enhanced economic development and public safety for communities across the Nation, improved health care and educational opportunities, and a better quality of life for all Americans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd2c4a62f-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1301/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Continued progress in the deployment and adoption of broadband technology is vital to ensuring that our Nation remains competitive and continues to create business and job growth.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd2c4a630-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1301/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Improving Federal data on the deployment and adoption of broadband service will assist in the development of broadband technology across all regions of the Nation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd2c4a631-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1301/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Federal Government should also recognize and encourage complementary State efforts to improve the quality and usefulness of broadband data and should encourage and support the partnership of the public and private sectors in the continued growth of broadband services and information technology for the residents and businesses of the Nation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idd2c4a632-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/385/tI/s102">Pub. L. 110–385, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4096">122 Stat. 4096</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd2c4a633-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd2c4a634-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idd2c4a635-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/385/tI/s101">Pub. L. 110–385, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4096">122 Stat. 4096</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/385/tI/s101">“This title [enacting this chapter and amending <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1302">section 1302 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Broadband Data Improvement Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2c4a636-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Benefit for Broadband Service During Emergency Period Relating to COVID–19</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dN/tIX/s904">Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2129">134 Stat. 2129</ref>, which related to benefits for broadband service during the COVID–19 emergency, was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1752">section 1752 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2c4a637-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Tribal Digital Access</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dP/tV/s508">Pub. L. 115–141, div. P, title V, § 508</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1095">132 Stat. 1095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/141/dP/tV/s508">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tribal Broadband Data Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>], the Commission [Federal Communications Commission] shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report evaluating broadband coverage in Indian country (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1151">section 1151 of title 18</ref>, United States Code) and on land held by a Native Corporation pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required assessments</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An assessment of areas of Indian country (as so defined) and land held by a Native Corporation pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act that have adequate broadband coverage.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> An assessment of unserved areas of Indian country (as so defined) and land held by a Native Corporation pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tribal Broadband Proceeding</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall complete a proceeding to address the unserved areas identified in the report under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idd2c4a638-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idd2c4a639-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13616. Accelerating Broadband Infrastructure Deployment</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13616, <date date="2012-06-14">June 14, 2012</date>, 77 F.R. 36903, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, and in order to facilitate broadband deployment on Federal lands, buildings, and rights of way, federally assisted highways, and tribal and individual Indian trust lands (tribal lands), particularly in underserved communities, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Policy</i>. Broadband access is essential to the Nation’s global competitiveness in the 21st century, driving job creation, promoting innovation, and expanding markets for American businesses. Broadband access also affords public safety agencies the opportunity for greater levels of effectiveness and interoperability. While broadband infrastructure has been deployed in a vast majority of communities across the country, today too many areas still lack adequate access to this crucial resource. For these areas, decisions on access to Federal property and rights of way can be essential to the deployment of both wired and wireless broadband infrastructure. The Federal Government controls nearly 30 percent of all land in the United States, owns thousands of buildings, and provides substantial funding for State and local transportation infrastructure, creating significant opportunities for executive departments and agencies (agencies) to help expand broadband infrastructure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Broadband Deployment on Federal Property Working Group</i>. (a) In order to ensure a coordinated and consistent approach in implementing agency procedures, requirements, and policies related to access to Federal lands, buildings, and rights of way, federally assisted highways, and tribal lands to advance broadband deployment, there is established a Broadband Deployment on Federal Property Working Group (Working Group), to be co-chaired by representatives designated by the Administrator of General Services and the Secretary of Homeland Security (Co-Chairs) from their respective agencies, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (Director) and in coordination with the Chief Performance Officer (CPO).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Working Group shall be composed of:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) a representative from each of the following agencies, and the Co-Chairs, all of which have significant ownership of, or responsibility for managing, Federal lands, buildings, and rights of way, federally assisted highways, and tribal lands (Broadband Member Agencies):</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) the Department of Defense;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) the Department of the Interior;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) the Department of Agriculture;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) the Department of Commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(5) the Department of Transportation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(6) the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(7) the United States Postal Service;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) a representative from each of the following agencies or offices, to provide advice and assistance:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) the Federal Communications Commission;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) the Council on Environmental Quality;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) the National Security Staff; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) representatives from such other agencies or offices as the Co-Chairs may invite to participate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Within 1 year of the date of this order, the Working Group shall report to the Steering Committee on Federal Infrastructure Permitting and Review Process Improvement, established pursuant to Executive Order 13604 of <date date="2012-03-22">March 22, 2012</date> (Improving Performance of Federal Permitting and Review of Infrastructure Projects), on the progress that has been made in implementing the actions mandated by sections 3 through 5 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Coordinating Consistent and Efficient Federal Broadband Procedures, Requirements, and Policies</i>. (a) Each Broadband Member Agency, following coordination with other Broadband Member Agencies and interested non-member agencies, shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) develop and implement a strategy to facilitate the timely and efficient deployment of broadband facilities on Federal lands, buildings, and rights of way, federally assisted highways, and tribal lands, that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) ensures a consistent approach across the Federal Government that facilitates broadband deployment processes and decisions, including by: avoiding duplicative reviews; coordinating review processes; providing clear notice of all application and other requirements; ensuring consistent interpretation and application of all procedures, requirements, and policies; supporting decisions on deployment of broadband service to those living on tribal lands consistent with existing statutes, treaties, and trust responsibilities; and ensuring the public availability of current information on these matters;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) where beneficial and appropriate, includes procedures for coordination with State, local, and tribal governments, and other appropriate entities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) is coordinated with appropriate external stakeholders, as determined by each Broadband Member Agency, prior to implementation; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) is provided to the Co-Chairs within 180 days of the date of this order; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) provide comprehensive and current information on accessing Federal lands, buildings, and rights of way, federally assisted highways, and tribal lands for the deployment of broadband facilities, and develop strategies to increase the usefulness and accessibility of this information, including ensuring such information is available online and in a format that is compatible with appropriate Government websites, such as the Federal Infrastructure Projects Dashboard created pursuant to my memorandum of <date date="2011-08-31">August 31, 2011</date> (Speeding Infrastructure Development Through More Efficient and Effective Permitting and Environmental Review).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The activities conducted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, particularly with respect to the establishment of timelines for permitting and review processes, shall be consistent with Executive Order 13604 and with the Federal Plan and Agency Plans to be developed pursuant to that order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Co-Chairs, in consultation with the Director and in coordination with the CPO, shall coordinate, review, and monitor the development and implementation of the strategies required by paragraph (a)(i) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Broadband Member Agencies may limit the information made available pursuant to paragraph (a)(ii) of this section as appropriate to accommodate national security, public safety, and privacy concerns.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Contracts, Applications, and Permits</i>. (a) Section 6409 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/96">Public Law 112–96</ref>) contains provisions addressing access to Federal property for the deployment of wireless broadband facilities, including requirements that the General Services Administration (GSA) develop application forms, master contracts, and fees for such access. The GSA shall consult with the Working Group in developing these application forms, master contracts, and fees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) To the extent not already addressed by section 6409, each Broadband Member Agency with responsibility for managing Federal lands, buildings, or rights of way (as determined by the Co-Chairs) shall, in coordination with the Working Group and within 1 year of the date of this order, develop and use one or more templates for uniform contract, application, and permit terms to facilitate nongovernment entities’ use of Federal property for the deployment of broadband facilities. The templates shall, where appropriate, allow for access by multiple broadband service providers and public safety entities. To ensure a consistent approach across the Federal Government and different broadband technologies, the templates shall, to the extent practicable and efficient, provide equal access to Federal property for the deployment of wireline and wireless facilities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Deployment of Conduit for Broadband Facilities in Conjunction with Federal or Federally Assisted Highway Construction</i>. (a) The installation of underground fiber conduit along highway and roadway rights of way can improve traffic flow and safety through implementation of intelligent transportation systems (ITS) and reduce the cost of future broadband deployment. Accordingly, within 1 year of the date of this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the Department of Transportation, in consultation with the Working Group, shall review dig once requirements in its existing programs and implement a flexible set of best practices that can accommodate changes in broadband technology and minimize excavations consistent with competitive broadband deployment;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the Department of Transportation shall work with State and local governments to help them develop and implement best practices on such matters as establishing dig once requirements, effectively using private investment in State ITS infrastructure, determining fair market value for rights of way on federally assisted highways, and reestablishing any highway assets disturbed by installation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) the Department of the Interior and other Broadband Member Agencies with responsibility for federally owned highways and rights of way on tribal lands (as determined by the Co-Chairs) shall revise their procedures, requirements, and policies to include the use of dig once requirements and similar policies to encourage the deployment of broadband infrastructure in conjunction with Federal highway construction, as well as to provide for the reestablishment of any highway assets disturbed by installation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) the Department of Transportation, after outreach to relevant nonfederal stakeholders, shall review and, if necessary, revise its guidance to State departments of transportation on allowing for-profit or other entities to accommodate or construct, safely and securely maintain, and utilize broadband facilities on State and locally owned rights of way in order to reflect changes in broadband technologies and markets and to promote competitive broadband infrastructure deployment; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) the Department of Transportation, in consultation with the Working Group and the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials, shall create an online platform that States and counties may use to aggregate and make publicly available their rights of way laws and joint occupancy guidelines and agreements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) For the purposes of this section, the term “dig once requirements” means requirements designed to reduce the number and scale of repeated excavations for the installation and maintenance of broadband facilities in rights of way.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) This order shall be implemented consistent with all applicable laws, treaties, and trust obligations, and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department, agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Independent agencies are strongly encouraged to comply with this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Reference to the National Security Staff deemed to be a reference to the National Security Council Staff, see Ex. Ord. No. 13657, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3021">section 3021 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idd2c4a63a-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13821. Streamlining and Expediting Requests To Locate Broadband Facilities in Rural America</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13821, <date date="2018-01-08">Jan. 8, 2018</date>, 83 F.R. 1507, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to promote better access to broadband internet service in rural America, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Policy</i>. Americans need access to reliable, affordable broadband internet service to succeed in today’s information-driven, global economy. Currently, too many American citizens and businesses still lack access to this basic tool of modern economic connectivity. This problem is particularly acute in rural America, and it hinders the ability of rural American communities to increase economic prosperity; attract new businesses; enhance job growth; extend the reach of affordable, high-quality healthcare; enrich student learning with digital tools; and facilitate access to the digital marketplace.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">It shall therefore be the policy of the executive branch to use all viable tools to accelerate the deployment and adoption of affordable, reliable, modern high-speed broadband connectivity in rural America, including rural homes, farms, small businesses, manufacturing and production sites, tribal communities, transportation systems, and healthcare and education facilities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">To implement this policy and enable sustainable rural broadband infrastructure projects, executive departments and agencies (agencies) should seek to reduce barriers to capital investment, remove obstacles to broadband services, and more efficiently employ Government resources.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Among other actions, the executive branch will continue its implementation of section 6409 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/96">Public Law 112–96</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1455">47 U.S.C. 1455</ref>] (“section 6409”), which requires, among other things, that the General Services Administration (GSA) develop a common form and master contract for wireless facility sitings on buildings and other property owned by the Federal Government. These documents enable the Federal Government to process wireless facility siting requests more efficiently and will also provide additional predictability regarding the availability of locations for asset installation to installers of wireless broadband facilities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Reviewing Requests to Locate Broadband Facilities on Federal Real Property</i>. (a) Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Administrator of General Services (Administrator), in coordination with the heads of Federal property managing agencies, shall evaluate the effectiveness of the GSA Common Form Application for use in streamlining and expediting the processing and review of requests to locate broadband facilities on Federal real property.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) As part of this evaluation, the Administrator shall determine whether any revisions to the GSA Common Form Application are appropriate and, to the extent consistent with law, shall begin implementation of any such revisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) In furtherance of section 6409, all applicants and Federal property managing agencies shall use the GSA Common Form Application for wireless service antenna structure siting developed by the Administrator for requests to locate broadband facilities on Federal property. Federal property managing agencies shall expeditiously review and approve such requests unless an approval would negatively affect performance of the agency’s mission or otherwise not be in the best interests of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Within 180 days of the date of this order, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, all Federal property managing agencies shall report to the GSA regarding their required use of the Common Form Application, the number of Common Form Applications received, the percentage approved, the percentage rejected, the basis for any rejection, and the number of working days each application was pending before being approved or rejected. Each report shall include the number of applications received, approved, and rejected within the preceding quarter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Ninety days after the date of this order, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, the Administrator shall prepare and provide to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (Director) an aggregated summary report detailing results from the reports submitted under subsection (d) of this section. Not later than 1 year from the date of this order, the Administrator shall recommend to the Director improvements to the Common Form Application needed to further the purposes of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Definitions</i>. As used in this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) The term “Federal property managing agencies” means agencies that have custody and control of, or responsibility for managing, Federal lands, buildings, and rights of way, federally assisted highways, and tribal lands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The term “Federal real property” has the same meaning as that term has in Executive Order 13327 of <date date="2004-02-04">February 4, 2004</date> (Federal Real Property Asset Management) [<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s121">40 U.S.C. 121</ref> note].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2c4a63b-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Unleashing the Wireless Broadband Revolution</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2010-06-28">June 28, 2010</date>, 75 F.R. 38387, which related to making available 500 MHz of Federal and nonfederal spectrum suitable for mobile and fixed wireless broadband use, was revoked by section 6(e) of Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2018-10-25">Oct. 25, 2018</date>, 83 F.R. 54515, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2c4a63c-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Expanding America’s Leadership in Wireless Innovation</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2013-06-14">June 14, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 37431, which related to shared access to spectrum previously allocated exclusively for Federal use, was revoked by section 6(e) of Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2018-10-25">Oct. 25, 2018</date>, 83 F.R. 54515, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2c7163d-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Supporting Broadband Tower Facilities in Rural America on Federal Properties Managed by the Department of the Interior</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2018-01-08">Jan. 8, 2018</date>, 83 F.R. 1511, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of the Interior</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Policy</i>. It is the policy of the executive branch to use all viable tools to accelerate the deployment and adoption of affordable, reliable, modern high-speed broadband connectivity in rural America, including rural homes, farms, small businesses, manufacturing and production sites, tribal communities, transportation systems, and healthcare and education facilities. Lowering the costs of broadband deployment to rural areas can strengthen the business case for broadband facilities deployment and therefore amplify investments in broadband infrastructure. To that end, the executive branch will seek to make Federal assets more available for rural broadband deployment, with due consideration of national security concerns.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Supporting Broadband Deployment</i>. (a) The Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) shall develop a plan to support rural broadband development and adoption by increasing access to tower facilities and other infrastructure assets managed by the Department of the Interior (DOI), consistent with applicable law and to the extent practicable. DOI shall draft model terms and conditions for use in securing tower facilities and other infrastructure assets for broadband deployment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Within 180 days of the date of this memorandum, the Secretary shall report to the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy recording DOI’s progress in identifying the assets that can be used to support rural broadband deployment and adoption.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
