<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd23f2187-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163"><num value="163">§ 163.</num><heading> Communications marketplace report</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd23f2188-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the last quarter of every even-numbered year, the Commission shall publish on its website and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the state of the communications marketplace.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd23f2189-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report required by subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd23f218a-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assess the state of competition in the communications marketplace, including competition to deliver voice, video, audio, and data services among providers of telecommunications, providers of commercial mobile service (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s332">section 332 of this title</ref>), multichannel video programming distributors (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s522">section 522 of this title</ref>), broadcast stations, providers of satellite communications, Internet service providers, and other providers of communications services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd23f218b-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assess the state of deployment of communications capabilities, including advanced telecommunications capability (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1302">section 1302 of this title</ref>), regardless of the technology used for such deployment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd23f218c-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assess whether laws, regulations, regulatory practices (whether those of the Federal Government, States, political subdivisions of States, Indian tribes or tribal organizations (as such terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>), or foreign governments), or demonstrated marketplace practices pose a barrier to competitive entry into the communications marketplace or to the competitive expansion of existing providers of communications services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd23f218d-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> describe the agenda of the Commission for the next 2-year period for addressing the challenges and opportunities in the communications marketplace that were identified through the assessments under paragraphs (1) through (3); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd23f218e-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> describe the actions that the Commission has taken in pursuit of the agenda described pursuant to paragraph (4) in the previous report submitted under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd23f218f-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the President designates a Commissioner as Chairman of the Commission during the last quarter of an even-numbered year, the portion of the report required by subsection (b)(4) may be published on the website of the Commission and submitted to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate as an addendum during the first quarter of the following odd-numbered year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd23f2190-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Special requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd23f2191-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessing competition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In assessing the state of competition under subsection (b)(1), the Commission shall consider all forms of competition, including the effect of intermodal competition, facilities-based competition, and competition from new and emergent communications services, including the provision of content and communications using the Internet.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd23f2192-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessing deployment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In assessing the state of deployment under subsection (b)(2), the Commission shall compile a list of geographical areas that are not served by any provider of advanced telecommunications capability.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd23f2193-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s163/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Considering small businesses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In assessing the state of competition under subsection (b)(1) and regulatory barriers under subsection (b)(3), the Commission shall consider market entry barriers for entrepreneurs and other small businesses in the communications marketplace in accordance with the national policy under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s257/b">section 257(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd23f2194-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title I, § 13, as added <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dP/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 115–141, div. P, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1087">132 Stat. 1087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
