<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idce35e5ed-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752"><num value="1752">§ 1752.</num><heading> Benefit for broadband service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5ee-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5ef-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Broadband internet access service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “broadband internet access service” has the meaning given such term in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5f0-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Broadband provider</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “broadband provider” means a provider of broadband internet access service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5f1-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Commission” means the Federal Communications Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5f2-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Connected device</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “connected device” means a laptop or desktop computer or a tablet.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5f3-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier”, with respect to a broadband provider, means the broadband provider is designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier under section 214(e) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s214/e">47 U.S.C. 214(e)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5f4-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible household</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “eligible household” means, regardless of whether the household or any member of the household receives support under subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), and regardless of whether any member of the household has any past or present arrearages with a broadband provider, a household in which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e5f5-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> at least one member of the household meets the qualifications in subsection (a) or (b) of section 54.409 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation) except that such subsection (a), including for purposes of such subsection (b), shall be applied by substituting “200 percent” for “135 percent”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e5f6-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> at least one member of the household has applied for and been approved to receive benefits under the free and reduced price lunch program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.) or the school breakfast program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1773">section 1773 of title 42</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e5f7-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> at least one member of the household has received a Federal Pell Grant under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a">section 1070a of title 20</ref> in the current award year, if such award is verifiable through the National Verifier or National Lifeline Accountability Database or the participating provider verifies eligibility under subsection (a)(2)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e5f8-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> at least one member of the household meets the eligibility criteria for a participating provider’s existing low-income program, subject to the requirements of subsection (a)(2)(B) and any other eligibility requirements the Commission may consider necessary for the public interest; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e5f9-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/6/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> at least one member of the household receives assistance through the special supplemental nutritional program for women, infants, and children established by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1786">section 1786 of title 42</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5fa-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Affordable connectivity benefit</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5fb-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the term “affordable connectivity benefit” means a monthly discount for an eligible household applied to the actual amount charged to such household, in an amount equal to such amount charged, but not more than $30, or, if an internet service offering is provided to an eligible household on Tribal land, not more than $75.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5fc-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> High-cost areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Commission shall, by regulation, establish a mechanism by which a participating provider in a high-cost area (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1702/a/2">section 1702(a)(2) of this title</ref>) may provide an affordable connectivity benefit in an amount up to the amount specified in subparagraph (A) for an internet service offering provided on Tribal land upon a showing that the applicability of the lower limit under subparagraph (A) to the provision of the affordable connectivity benefit by the provider would cause particularized economic hardship to the provider such that the provider may not be able to maintain the operation of part or all of its broadband network.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5fd-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Internet service offering</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “internet service offering” means, with respect to a broadband provider, broadband internet access service provided by such provider to a household.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5fe-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> National Lifeline Accountability Database</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “National Lifeline Accountability Database” has the meaning given such term in section 54.400 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e5ff-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> National Verifier</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “National Verifier” has the meaning given such term in section 54.400 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e600-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Participating provider</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “participating provider” means a broadband provider that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e601-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e602-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/11/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e603-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/11/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> meets requirements established by the Commission for participation in the Affordable Connectivity Program and is approved by the Commission under subsection (d)(2); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e604-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/a/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> elects to participate in the Affordable Connectivity Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e605-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Affordable Connectivity Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e606-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall establish a program, to be known as the “Affordable Connectivity Program”, under which the Commission shall, in accordance with this section, reimburse, using funds from the Affordable Connectivity Fund established in subsection (i), a participating provider for an affordable connectivity benefit, or an affordable connectivity benefit and a connected device, provided to an eligible household.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e607-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Verification of eligibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To verify whether a household is an eligible household, a participating provider shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e608-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> use the National Verifier or National Lifeline Accountability Database;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e609-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> rely upon an alternative verification process of the participating provider, if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e60a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the participating provider submits information as required by the Commission regarding the alternative verification process prior to seeking reimbursement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e60b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> not later than 7 days after receiving the information required under clause (i), the Commission—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce35e60c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> determines that the alternative verification process will be sufficient to avoid waste, fraud, and abuse; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce35e60d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> notifies the participating provider of the determination under subclause (I); or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e60e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> rely on a school to verify the eligibility of a household based on the participation of the household in the free and reduced price lunch program or the school breakfast program described in subsection (a)(6)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e60f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of National Verifier and National Lifeline Accountability Database</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e610-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> expedite the ability of all participating providers to access the National Verifier and National Lifeline Accountability Database for purposes of determining whether a household is an eligible household, without regard to whether a participating provider is designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e611-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ensure that the National Verifier and National Lifeline Accountability Database approve an eligible household to receive the affordable connectivity benefit not later than 2 days after the date of the submission of information necessary to determine if such household is an eligible household.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e612-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">From the Affordable Connectivity Fund established in subsection (i), the Commission shall reimburse a participating provider in an amount equal to the affordable connectivity benefit with respect to an eligible household that receives such benefit from such participating provider.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e613-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for connected device</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A participating provider that, in addition to providing the affordable connectivity benefit to an eligible household, supplies such household with a connected device may be reimbursed up to $100 from the Affordable Connectivity Fund established in subsection (i) for such connected device, if the charge to such eligible household is more than $10 but less than $50 for such connected device, except that a participating provider may receive reimbursement for no more than 1 connected device per eligible household.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e614-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification required</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To receive a reimbursement under paragraph (4) or (5), a participating provider shall certify to the Commission the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e615-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> That each eligible household for which the participating provider is seeking reimbursement for providing an internet service offering discounted by the affordable connectivity benefit—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e616-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> will not be required to pay an early termination fee if such eligible household elects to enter into a contract to receive such internet service offering if such household later terminates such contract;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e617-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> was not, after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, subject to a mandatory waiting period for such internet service offering based on having previously received broadband internet access service from such participating provider; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e618-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/6/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> will otherwise be subject to the participating provider’s generally applicable terms and conditions as applied to other customers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e619-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> That each eligible household for which the participating provider is seeking reimbursement for supplying such household with a connected device has not been and will not be charged $10 or less or $50 or more for such device.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e61a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A description of the process used by the participating provider to verify that a household is an eligible household, if the provider elects an alternative verification process under paragraph (2)(B), and that such verification process was designed to avoid waste, fraud, and abuse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e61b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement to allow customers to apply affordable connectivity benefit to any internet service offering</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e61c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A participating provider—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e61d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall allow an eligible household to apply the affordable connectivity benefit to any internet service offering of the participating provider at the same terms available to households that are not eligible households; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e61e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may not require the eligible household to submit to a credit check in order to apply the affordable connectivity benefit to an internet service offering of the participating provider.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e61f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonpayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall prevent a participating provider from terminating the provision of broadband internet access service to a subscriber after 90 days of nonpayment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e620-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Public awareness</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A participating provider, in collaboration with the applicable State agencies, public interest groups, and non-profit organizations, in order to increase the adoption of broadband internet access service by consumers, shall carry out public awareness campaigns in service areas that are designed to highlight—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e621-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the value and benefits of broadband internet access service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e622-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the existence of the Affordable Connectivity Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e623-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Oversight</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e624-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall establish a dedicated complaint process for consumers who participate in the Affordable Connectivity Program to file complaints about the compliance of participating providers with, including with respect to the quality of service received under, the Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e625-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall require a participating provider to supply information about the existence of the complaint process described in subparagraph (A) to subscribers who participate in the Affordable Connectivity Program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e626-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e627-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/9/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall act expeditiously to investigate potential violations of and enforce compliance with this section, including under clause (ii) of this subparagraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e628-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/9/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in enforcing compliance with this section, may impose forfeiture penalties under section 503 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s503">47 U.S.C. 503</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e629-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/9/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> shall regularly issue public reports about complaints regarding the compliance of participating providers with the Affordable Connectivity Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e62a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Information on Affordable Connectivity Program</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e62b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Participating providers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">When a customer subscribes to, or renews a subscription to, an internet service offering of a participating provider, the participating provider shall notify the customer about the existence of the Affordable Connectivity Program and how to enroll in the Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e62c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Commission shall collaborate with relevant Federal agencies, including to ensure relevant Federal agencies update their System of Records Notices, to ensure that a household that participates in any program that qualifies the household for the Affordable Connectivity Program is provided information about the Program, including how to enroll in the Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e62d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Commission outreach</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e62e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Commission may conduct outreach efforts to encourage eligible households to enroll in the Affordable Connectivity Program.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e62f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In carrying out clause (i), the Commission may—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce35e630-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> facilitate consumer research;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce35e631-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> conduct focus groups;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce35e632-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> engage in paid media campaigns;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce35e633-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> provide grants to outreach partners; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce35e634-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/10/C/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> provide an orderly transition for participating providers and consumers from the Emergency Broadband Benefit Program established under paragraph (1) (as that paragraph was in effect on the day before <date date="2021-11-15">November 15, 2021</date>) to the Affordable Connectivity Program.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e635-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Consumer protection issues</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e636-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Commission shall, after providing notice and opportunity for comment in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, promulgate rules to protect consumers who participate in, or seek to participate in, the Affordable Connectivity Program from—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e637-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> inappropriate upselling or downselling by a participating provider;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e638-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> inappropriate requirements that a consumer opt in to an extended service contract as a condition of participating in the Affordable Connectivity Program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e639-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> inappropriate restrictions on the ability of a consumer to switch internet service offerings or otherwise apply support from the Affordable Connectivity Program to a different internet service offering with a participating provider;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e63a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> inappropriate restrictions on the ability of a consumer to switch participating providers, other than a requirement that the customer return any customer premises equipment provided by a participating provider; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e63b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> similar restrictions that amount to unjust and unreasonable acts or practices that undermine the purpose, intent, or integrity of the Affordable Connectivity Program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e63c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/11/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In complying with this paragraph, the Commission may take advantage of the exceptions set forth in subsections (e) and (f).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e63d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12"><num value="12" class="bold">(12)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall adopt audit requirements to ensure that participating providers are in compliance with the requirements of this section and to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in the Affordable Connectivity Program. A finding of waste, fraud, or abuse or an improper payment (as such term is defined in section 2(d) of the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</ref> note)) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002073">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002073"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> identified by the Commission or the Inspector General of the Commission shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e63e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The name of the participating provider.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e63f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amount of funding made available from the Affordable Connectivity Fund to the participating provider.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e640-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The amount of funding determined to be an improper payment to a participating provider.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e641-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A description of to what extent funding made available from the Affordable Connectivity Fund that was an improper payment was used for a reimbursement for a connected device or a reimbursement for an internet service offering.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e642-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Whether, in the case of a connected device, such device, or the value thereof, has been recovered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e643-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Whether any funding from the Affordable Connectivity Fund was made available to a participating provider for an affordable connectivity benefit for a person outside the eligible household.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e644-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/12/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Whether any funding from the Affordable Connectivity Fund was made available to reimburse a participating provider for an affordable connectivity benefit made available to an eligible household in which all members of such household necessary to satisfy the eligibility requirements described in subsection (a)(6) were deceased.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e645-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/13"><num value="13" class="bold">(13)</num><heading class="bold"> Random audit required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Inspector General of the Commission shall conduct an audit of a representative sample of participating providers receiving reimbursements under the Affordable Connectivity Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e646-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/14"><num value="14" class="bold">(14)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of audit findings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 7 days after a finding made by the Commission under the requirements of paragraph (12), the Commission shall notify the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate with any information described in such paragraph that the Commission has obtained.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e647-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/b/15"><num value="15" class="bold">(15)</num><heading class="bold"> Expiration of Program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At the conclusion of the Affordable Connectivity Program, any participating eligible households shall be subject to a participating provider’s generally applicable terms and conditions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e648-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations required</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e649-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Commission shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e64a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Comment periods</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">As part of the rulemaking under paragraph (1), the Commission shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e64b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide a 20-day public comment period that begins not later than 5 days after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e64c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide a 20-day public reply comment period that immediately follows the period under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce35e64d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> during the comment periods under subparagraphs (A) and (B), seek comment on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e64e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the provision of assistance from the Affordable Connectivity Fund established in subsection (i) consistent with this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce35e64f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/c/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> other related matters.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e650-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility of providers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e651-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Relation to eligible telecommunications carrier designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission may not require a broadband provider to be designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier in order to be a participating provider.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e652-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited approval process</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e653-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Commission shall establish an expedited process by which the Commission approves as participating providers broadband providers that are not designated as eligible telecommunications carriers and elect to participate in the Affordable Connectivity Program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e654-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Commission shall automatically approve as a participating provider a broadband provider that has an established program as of <date date="2020-04-01">April 1, 2020</date>, that is widely available and offers internet service offerings to eligible households and maintains verification processes that are sufficient to avoid fraud, waste, and abuse.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e655-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall affect the collection, distribution, or administration of the Lifeline Assistance Program governed by the rules set forth in subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e656-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Part 54 regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the Commission from providing that the regulations in part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, shall apply in whole or in part to the Affordable Connectivity Program, shall not apply in whole or in part to such Program, or shall be modified in whole or in part for purposes of application to such Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e657-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s151">47 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.) or a regulation promulgated under such Act. The Commission shall enforce this section and the regulations promulgated under this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Communications Act of 1934 were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e658-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e659-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain rulemaking requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1"><ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">Section 553 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to a regulation promulgated under subsection (c) or a rulemaking proceeding to promulgate such a regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e65a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Paperwork Reduction Act requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A collection of information conducted or sponsored under the regulations required by subsection (c) shall not constitute a collection of information for the purposes of subchapter I of chapter 35 of title 44 (commonly referred to as the Paperwork Reduction Act).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e65b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Affordable Connectivity Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e65c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the Affordable Connectivity Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e65d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is appropriated to the Affordable Connectivity Fund, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $3,200,000,000 for fiscal year 2021, to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e65e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts in the Affordable Connectivity Fund shall be available to the Commission for reimbursements to participating providers under this section, and the Commission may use not more than 2 percent of such amounts to administer the Affordable Connectivity Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e65f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/i/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to universal service contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Reimbursements provided under this section shall be provided from amounts made available under this subsection and not from contributions under section 254(d) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s254/d">47 U.S.C. 254(d)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e660-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/i/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of Universal Service Administrative Company permitted</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall have the authority to avail itself of the services of the Universal Service Administrative Company to implement the Affordable Connectivity Program, including developing and processing reimbursements and distributing funds to participating providers.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce35e661-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s1752/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Safe harbor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may not enforce a violation of this section under section 501, 502, or 503 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s501">47 U.S.C. 501</ref>; 502; 503), or any rules of the Commission promulgated under such sections of such Act, if a participating provider demonstrates to the Commission that such provider relied in good faith on information provided to such provider to make the verification required by subsection (b)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idce35e662-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dN/tIX/s904">Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2129">134 Stat. 2129</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/a">Pub. L. 117–58, div. F, title V, § 60502(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1238">135 Stat. 1238</ref>, 1241.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idce35e663-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idce35e664-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idce35e665-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(6)(B), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-06-04/ch281">act June 4, 1946, ch. 281</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/230">60 Stat. 230</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 13 (§ 1751 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">section 1751 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2(d) of the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (b)(12), is <ref href="/us/pl/107/300/s2/d">section 2(d) of Pub. L. 107–300</ref>, <date date="2002-11-26">Nov. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2350">116 Stat. 2350</ref>, which was set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3321">section 3321 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/116/117/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 116–117, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-02">Mar. 2, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/133">134 Stat. 133</ref>. See, generally, subchapter IV of chapter 33 of Title 31.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Communications Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (g), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">act June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1064">48 Stat. 1064</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 5 (§ 151 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s609">section 609 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idce35e666-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idce35e667-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/1/A">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “during emergency period relating to COVID–19” after “service” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/2/D">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(2)(D)</ref>–(F), substituted, wherever appearing in text, “Affordable Connectivity” for “Emergency Broadband Benefit”, “Affordable” for “Emergency Broadband”, and “affordable connectivity” for “emergency broadband”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/A/i/I">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(A)(i)(I)</ref>, inserted before semicolon at end “except that such subsection (a), including for purposes of such subsection (b), shall be applied by substituting ‘200 percent’ for ‘135 percent’ ”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/A/i/II">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(A)(i)(II)</ref>–(IV), redesignated subpar. (D) as (C), struck out “or” at end, and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “at least one member of the household has experienced a substantial loss of income since <date date="2020-02-29">February 29, 2020</date>, that is documented by layoff or furlough notice, application for unemployment insurance benefits, or similar documentation or that is otherwise verifiable through the National Verifier or National Lifeline Accountability Database;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/A/i/III">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(A)(i)(III)</ref>, (V), redesignated subpar. (E) as (D), struck out “or COVID–19” before “program”, and substituted “; or” for period at end. Former subpar. (D) redesignated (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/A/i/VI">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(A)(i)(VI)</ref>, added subpar. (E). Former subpar. (E) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “$30” for “$50” and struck out “which shall be no more than the standard rate for an internet service offering and associated equipment,” after “such household,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/3/A">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(3)(A)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted heading, substituted “Subject to subparagraph (B), the term” for “The term”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/2/A">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Affordable connectivity” for “Emergency broadband” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/A/iii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(A)(iii)</ref>, struck out at end “, offered in the same manner, and on the same terms, as described in any of such provider’s offerings for broadband internet access service to such household, as on <date date="2020-12-01">December 1, 2020</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/1/B">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(1)(B)</ref>, redesignated par. (9) as (8) and struck out former par. (8) which defined “emergency period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, redesignated pars. (10) to (12) as (9) to (11), respectively. Former par. (9) redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12), (13). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, (iv), redesignated par. (13) as (12) and then struck it out. Prior to amendment, par. defined the term “standard rate”. Former par. (12) redesignated (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/2/B">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Affordable Connectivity” for “Emergency Broadband Benefit” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/1/C/i">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(1)(C)(i)</ref>, struck out “during the emergency period” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/1/C/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(1)(C)(ii)</ref>, struck out “during the emergency period” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/1/C/iii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(1)(C)(iii)</ref>, struck out “during the emergency period,” before “in addition to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, (iii), redesignated subpar. (B) as (A) and cls. (ii) to (iv) as (i) to (iii), respectively, and struck out former cl. (i) which read as follows: “has not been and will not be charged—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) for such offering, if the standard rate for such offering is less than or equal to the amount of the affordable connectivity benefit for such household; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(II) more for such offering than the difference between the standard rate for such offering and the amount of the affordable connectivity benefit for such household;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/B/i">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, struck out subpar. (A) which read as follows: “That the amount for which the participating provider is seeking reimbursement from the Affordable Connectivity Fund established in subsection (i) for providing an internet service offering to an eligible household is not more than the standard rate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(B) to (D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(b)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (B) to (D) as (A) to (C), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7) to (15). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/3/B">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(3)(B)</ref>, added pars. (7) to (11) and redesignated former pars. (7) to (10) as (12) to (15), respectively, and, in par. (14) as redesignated, substituted “paragraph (12)” for “paragraph (7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/a/2/C">Pub. L. 117–58, § 60502(a)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “Affordable” for “Emergency Broadband” in heading.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idce35e668-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idce35e669-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/b/1">Pub. L. 117–58, div. F, title V, § 60502(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1241">135 Stat. 1241</ref>, provided in part that the amendments made to this section by <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/1">section 60502(b)(1) of Pub. L. 117–58</ref> are effective on the date on which the Federal Communications Commission submits the certification required under <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/b/4">section 60502(b)(4) of Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, set out below, or <date date="2021-12-31">Dec. 31, 2021</date>, whichever is earlier.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce35e66a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Eligibility for the Affordable Connectivity Benefit; Transition; Certification</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/b/2">Pub. L. 117–58, div. F, title V, § 60502(b)(2)</ref>–(4), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1242">135 Stat. 1242</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/b/2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of amendment to eligibility</inline>.—</heading><content> A household that qualified for the Affordable Connectivity Program under section 904 of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1752">47 U.S.C. 1752</ref>] before the effective date in paragraph (1) [set out as a note above] and, as of that effective date, would, but for this subparagraph, see a reduction in the amount of the affordable connectivity benefit under the Program, shall, during the 60-day period beginning on that effective date, be eligible for the affordable connectivity benefit in the amount in effect with respect to that household, as of the day before that effective date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition</inline>.—</heading><content>After the effective date under paragraph (1), an eligible household that was participating in the Emergency Broadband Benefit Program under section 904 of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</ref>) on the day before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>] and qualifies for the Affordable Connectivity Program established under that section (as amended by this section) shall continue to have access to an affordable service offering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification required</inline>.—</heading><content>On the date on which the amounts appropriated under section 904(i)(2) of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1752/i/2">47 U.S.C. 1752(i)(2)</ref>] have been fully expended, the [Federal Communications] Commission shall submit to Congress a certification regarding that fact.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce35e66b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Broadband Transparency Rules</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/c">Pub. L. 117–58, div. F, title V, § 60502(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1243">135 Stat. 1243</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rules</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>], the [Federal Communications] Commission shall issue final rules regarding the annual collection by the Commission of data relating to the price and subscription rates of each internet service offering of a participating provider under the Affordable Connectivity Program established under section 904 of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1752">47 U.S.C. 1752</ref>] (as amended by this section) to which an eligible household subscribes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updates</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which rules are issued under paragraph (1), and when determined to be necessary by the Commission thereafter, the Commission shall revise the rules to verify the accuracy of data submitted pursuant to the rules.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Redundancy avoidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the Commission, in order to meet a requirement of this subsection, to duplicate an activity that the Commission is undertaking as of the date of enactment of this Act, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Commission refers to the activity in the rules issued under paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the activity meets the requirements of this subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Commission discloses the activity to the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of data.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public availability</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission shall make data relating to broadband internet access service collected under the rules issued under paragraph (1) available to the public in a commonly used electronic format without risking the disclosure of personally identifiable information or proprietary information, consistent with section 0.459 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of personally identifiable information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Commission—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> shall define the term ‘personally identifiable information’, for purposes of subparagraph (A) through notice and comment rulemaking; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> may not make any data available to the public under subparagraph (A) before completing the rulemaking under clause (i) of this subparagraph.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “broadband internet access service” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s60502/c">section 60502(c) of Pub. L. 117–58</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1751">section 1751 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce35e66c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/d">Pub. L. 117–58, div. F, title V, § 60502(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1243">135 Stat. 1243</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/d">“The [Federal Communications] Commission may issue such guidance, forms, instructions, or publications, or provide such technical assistance, as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the programs, projects, or activities authorized under this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] and the amendments made by this section, including to ensure that such programs, projects, or activities are completed in a timely and effective manner.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce35e66d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/e">Pub. L. 117–58, div. F, title V, § 60502(e)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1243">135 Stat. 1243</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/58/dF/tV/s60502/e">
<inline>“The Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Education, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>], enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Universal Service Administrative Company to provide for the expeditious sharing of data through the National Verifier (as that term is defined in section 54.400 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation), or any successor system, for the purposes of verifying consumer eligibility for the program established under section 904 of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s1752">47 U.S.C. 1752</ref>], as amended by this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, begin to share data under the memorandum of understanding described in paragraph (1) for the purposes described in that paragraph.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
