<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd2299d83-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s21"><num value="21">§ 21.</num><heading> Submarine cables; willful injury to; punishment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who shall willfully and wrongfully break or injure, or attempt to break or injure, or who shall in any manner procure, counsel, aid, abet, or be accessory to such breaking or injury, or attempt to break or injure, a submarine cable in such manner as to interrupt or embarrass, in whole or in part, telegraphic communication, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two years, or to a fine not exceeding $5,000, or to both fine and imprisonment, at the discretion of the court.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idd2299d84-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/act/1888-02-29/ch17/s1">Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/25/41">25 Stat. 41</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd2299d85-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd2299d86-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idd2299d87-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1888-02-29/ch17">Act Feb. 29, 1888, ch. 17</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/25/41">25 Stat. 41</ref>, which enacted sections 21 to 33 of this title, is popularly known as the “Submarine Cable Act”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2299d88-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Convention</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The protection of submarine cables was made the subject of an international convention between the United States and Germany, Argentine Confederation, Austria-Hungary, Belgium, Brazil, Costa Rica, Denmark, Dominican Republic, Spain, United States of Columbia, France, Great Britain, Guatemala, Greece, Italy, Turkey, Netherlands, Persia, Portugal, Roumania, Russia, Salvador, Servia, Sweden and Norway, Uruguay, and the British Colonies. It was concluded <date date="1884-03-14">Mar. 14, 1884</date>, ratified <date date="1885-01-26">Jan. 26, 1885</date>, ratifications exchanged <date date="1885-04-16">Apr. 16, 1885</date>, proclaimed <date date="1885-05-22">May 22, 1885</date>, and entered into force for the United States <date date="1888-05-01">May 1, 1888</date>. Its provisions were set forth in <ref href="/us/stat/24/989">24 Stat. 989</ref> to 1000.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
