<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcd9f9907-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224"><num value="224">§ 224.</num><heading> Pole attachments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f9908-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9909-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “utility” means any person who is a local exchange carrier or an electric, gas, water, steam, or other public utility, and who owns or controls poles, ducts, conduits, or rights-of-way used, in whole or in part, for any wire communications. Such term does not include any railroad, any person who is cooperatively organized, or any person owned by the Federal Government or any State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f990a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Federal Government” means the Government of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f990b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “State” means any State, territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f990c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “pole attachment” means any attachment by a cable television system or provider of telecommunications service to a pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way owned or controlled by a utility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f990d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For purposes of this section, the term “telecommunications carrier” (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s153">section 153 of this title</ref>) does not include any incumbent local exchange carrier as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s251/h">section 251(h) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f990e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Commission to regulate rates, terms, and conditions; enforcement powers; promulgation of regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f990f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section, the Commission shall regulate the rates, terms, and conditions for pole attachments to provide that such rates, terms, and conditions are just and reasonable, and shall adopt procedures necessary and appropriate to hear and resolve complaints concerning such rates, terms, and conditions. For purposes of enforcing any determinations resulting from complaint procedures established pursuant to this subsection, the Commission shall take such action as it deems appropriate and necessary, including issuing cease and desist orders, as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s312/b">section 312(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9910-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Commission shall prescribe by rule regulations to carry out the provisions of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f9911-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State regulatory authority over rates, terms, and conditions; preemption; certification; circumstances constituting State regulation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9912-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to apply to, or to give the Commission jurisdiction with respect to rates, terms, and conditions, or access to poles, ducts, conduits, and rights-of-way as provided in subsection (f), for pole attachments in any case where such matters are regulated by a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9913-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Each State which regulates the rates, terms, and conditions for pole attachments shall certify to the Commission that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcd9f9914-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> it regulates such rates, terms, and conditions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcd9f9915-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in so regulating such rates, terms, and conditions, the State has the authority to consider and does consider the interests of the subscribers of the services offered via such attachments, as well as the interests of the consumers of the utility services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9916-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, a State shall not be considered to regulate the rates, terms, and conditions for pole attachments—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcd9f9917-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> unless the State has issued and made effective rules and regulations implementing the State’s regulatory authority over pole attachments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcd9f9918-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> with respect to any individual matter, unless the State takes final action on a complaint regarding such matter—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcd9f9919-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> within 180 days after the complaint is filed with the State, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcd9f991a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> within the applicable period prescribed for such final action in such rules and regulations of the State, if the prescribed period does not extend beyond 360 days after the filing of such complaint.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f991b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of just and reasonable rates; “usable space” defined</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f991c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For purposes of subsection (b) of this section, a rate is just and reasonable if it assures a utility the recovery of not less than the additional costs of providing pole attachments, nor more than an amount determined by multiplying the percentage of the total usable space, or the percentage of the total duct or conduit capacity, which is occupied by the pole attachment by the sum of the operating expenses and actual capital costs of the utility attributable to the entire pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f991d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> As used in this subsection, the term “usable space” means the space above the minimum grade level which can be used for the attachment of wires, cables, and associated equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f991e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> This subsection shall apply to the rate for any pole attachment used by a cable television system solely to provide cable service. Until the effective date of the regulations required under subsection (e), this subsection shall also apply to the rate for any pole attachment used by a cable system or any telecommunications carrier (to the extent such carrier is not a party to a pole attachment agreement) to provide any telecommunications service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f991f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations governing charges; apportionment of costs of providing space</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9920-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commission shall, no later than 2 years after <date date="1996-02-08">February 8, 1996</date>, prescribe regulations in accordance with this subsection to govern the charges for pole attachments used by telecommunications carriers to provide telecommunications services, when the parties fail to resolve a dispute over such charges. Such regulations shall ensure that a utility charges just, reasonable, and nondiscriminatory rates for pole attachments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9921-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A utility shall apportion the cost of providing space on a pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way other than the usable space among entities so that such apportionment equals two-thirds of the costs of providing space other than the usable space that would be allocated to such entity under an equal apportionment of such costs among all attaching entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9922-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A utility shall apportion the cost of providing usable space among all entities according to the percentage of usable space required for each entity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9923-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The regulations required under paragraph (1) shall become effective 5 years after <date date="1996-02-08">February 8, 1996</date>. Any increase in the rates for pole attachments that result from the adoption of the regulations required by this subsection shall be phased in equal annual increments over a period of 5 years beginning on the effective date of such regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f9924-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Nondiscriminatory access</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9925-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A utility shall provide a cable television system or any telecommunications carrier with nondiscriminatory access to any pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way owned or controlled by it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcd9f9926-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a utility providing electric service may deny a cable television system or any telecommunications carrier access to its poles, ducts, conduits, or rights-of-way, on a non-discriminatory <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002005"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “nondiscriminatory”.</note> basis where there is insufficient capacity and for reasons of safety, reliability and generally applicable engineering purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f9927-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Imputation to costs of pole attachment rate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A utility that engages in the provision of telecommunications services or cable services shall impute to its costs of providing such services (and charge any affiliate, subsidiary, or associate company engaged in the provision of such services) an equal amount to the pole attachment rate for which such company would be liable under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f9928-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Modification or alteration of pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the owner of a pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way intends to modify or alter such pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way, the owner shall provide written notification of such action to any entity that has obtained an attachment to such conduit or right-of-way so that such entity may have a reasonable opportunity to add to or modify its existing attachment. Any entity that adds to or modifies its existing attachment after receiving such notification shall bear a proportionate share of the costs incurred by the owner in making such pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way accessible.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcd9f9929-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s224/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs of rearranging or replacing attachment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An entity that obtains an attachment to a pole, conduit, or right-of-way shall not be required to bear any of the costs of rearranging or replacing its attachment, if such rearrangement or replacement is required as a result of an additional attachment or the modification of an existing attachment sought by any other entity (including the owner of such pole, duct, conduit, or right-of-way).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcd9f992a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title II, § 224, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/234/s6">Pub. L. 95–234, § 6</ref>, <date date="1978-02-21">Feb. 21, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/35">92 Stat. 35</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/259/tI/s106">Pub. L. 97–259, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1091">96 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/549/s4">Pub. L. 98–549, § 4</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2801">98 Stat. 2801</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/414/tIII/s304/a/7">Pub. L. 103–414, title III, § 304(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4297">108 Stat. 4297</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 104–104, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/149">110 Stat. 149</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcd9f992b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcd9f992c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcd9f992d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s703/1">Pub. L. 104–104, § 703(1)</ref>, inserted first sentence and struck out former first sentence which read as follows: “The term ‘utility’ means any person whose rates or charges are regulated by the Federal Government or a State and who owns or controls poles, ducts, conduits, or rights-of-way used, in whole or in part, for wire communication.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s703/2">Pub. L. 104–104, § 703(2)</ref>, inserted “or provider of telecommunications service” after “system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s703/3">Pub. L. 104–104, § 703(3)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s703/4">Pub. L. 104–104, § 703(4)</ref>, inserted “, or access to poles, ducts, conduits, and rights-of-way as provided in subsection (f),” after “conditions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s703/5">Pub. L. 104–104, § 703(5)</ref>, substituted “the services offered via such attachments” for “cable television services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s703/6">Pub. L. 104–104, § 703(6)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s703/7">Pub. L. 104–104, § 703(7)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) to (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/414">Pub. L. 103–414</ref> substituted “The Commission” for “Within 180 days from <date date="1978-02-21">February 21, 1978</date>, the Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/549">Pub. L. 98–549</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/259">Pub. L. 97–259</ref> struck out subsec. (e) which provided that, upon expiration of 5-year period that began on <date date="1978-02-21">Feb. 21, 1978</date>, provisions of subsec. (d) of this section would cease to have any effect.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcd9f992e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcd9f992f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/549">Pub. L. 98–549</ref> effective 60 days after <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, except where otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/549/s9/a">section 9(a) of Pub. L. 98–549</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcd9f9930-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on thirtieth day after <date date="1978-02-21">Feb. 21, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/234/s7">section 7 of Pub. L. 95–234</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s152">section 152 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
