<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd26547a3-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s308"><num value="308">§ 308.</num><heading> Requirements for license</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd26547a4-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s308/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Writing; exceptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may grant construction permits and station licenses, or modifications or renewals thereof, only upon written application therefor received by it: <i>Provided</i>, That (1) in cases of emergency found by the Commission involving danger to life or property or due to damage to equipment, or (2) during a national emergency proclaimed by the President or declared by the Congress and during the continuance of any war in which the United States is engaged and when such action is necessary for the national defense or security or otherwise in furtherance of the war effort, or (3) in cases of emergency where the Commission finds, in the nonbroadcast services, that it would not be feasible to secure renewal applications from existing licensees or otherwise to follow normal licensing procedure, the Commission may grant construction permits and station licenses, or modifications or renewals thereof, during the emergency so found by the Commission or during the continuance of any such national emergency or war, in such manner and upon such terms and conditions as the Commission shall by regulation prescribe, and without the filing of a formal application, but no authorization so granted shall continue in effect beyond the period of the emergency or war requiring it: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Commission may issue by cable, telegraph, or radio a permit for the operation of a station on a vessel of the United States at sea, effective in lieu of a license until said vessel shall return to a port of the continental United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd26547a5-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s308/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All applications for station licenses, or modifications or renewals thereof, shall set forth such facts as the Commission by regulation may prescribe as to the citizenship, character, and financial, technical, and other qualifications of the applicant to operate the station; the ownership and location of the proposed station and of the stations, if any, with which it is proposed to communicate; the frequencies and the power desired to be used; the hours of the day or other periods of time during which it is proposed to operate the station; the purposes for which the station is to be used; and such other information as it may require. The Commission, at any time after the filing of such original application and during the term of any such license, may require from an applicant or licensee further written statements of fact to enable it to determine whether such original application should be granted or denied or such license revoked. Such application and/or such statement of fact shall be signed by the applicant and/or licensee in any manner or form, including by electronic means, as the Commission may prescribe by regulation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd26547a6-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s308/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Commercial communication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission in granting any license for a station intended or used for commercial communication between the United States or any Territory or possession, continental or insular, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and any foreign country, may impose any terms, conditions, or restrictions authorized to be imposed with respect to submarine-cable licenses by <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s35">section 35 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd26547a7-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s308/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Summary of complaints</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each applicant for the renewal of a commercial or noncommercial television license shall attach as an exhibit to the application a summary of written comments and suggestions received from the public and maintained by the licensee (in accordance with Commission regulations) that comment on the applicant’s programming, if any, and that are characterized by the commentor as constituting violent programming.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd26547a8-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title III, § 308, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1084">48 Stat. 1084</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-16/ch879/s6">July 16, 1952, ch. 879, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/714">66 Stat. 714</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/444/s3">Pub. L. 87–444, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-04-27">Apr. 27, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/63">76 Stat. 63</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/538/tII/s204/b">Pub. L. 102–538, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3543">106 Stat. 3543</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/414/tIII/s303/a/15">Pub. L. 103–414, title III, § 303(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4295">108 Stat. 4295</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/tII/s204/b">Pub. L. 104–104, title II, § 204(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/113">110 Stat. 113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd26547a9-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd26547aa-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd26547ab-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104">Pub. L. 104–104</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/414">Pub. L. 103–414</ref> made technical amendment to reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s35">section 35 of this title</ref> to correct reference to corresponding section of original act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/538">Pub. L. 102–538</ref> inserted before period at end “in any manner or form, including by electronic means, as the Commission may prescribe by regulation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/444">Pub. L. 87–444</ref> struck out requirement that applications or statements of fact were to be signed under oath or affirmation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1952—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1952-07-16">July 16, 1952</date>, § 6(a), provided that the Commission may grant construction permits and station licenses, or modifications or renewals, only upon written application except that during war or emergency periods no formal application need be filed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1952-07-16">July 16, 1952</date>, § 6(b), substituted “All applications for station licenses or modifications or renewals thereof, shall set forth” for “All such applications shall set forth”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd26547ac-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd26547ad-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/104/tII/s204/c">Pub. L. 104–104, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/113">110 Stat. 113</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/104/tII/s204/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s309">section 309 of this title</ref>] apply to applications filed after <date date="1995-05-01">May 1, 1995</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
