<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd281f6f9-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s357"><num value="357">§ 357.</num><heading> Safety information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd281f6fa-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s357/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmission of information concerning safety at sea</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The master of every ship of the United States, equipped with radio transmitting apparatus, which meets with dangerous ice, a dangerous derelict, a tropical storm, or any other direct danger to navigation, or encounters subfreezing air temperatures associated with gale force winds causing severe ice accretion on superstructures, or winds of force 10 or above on the Beaufort scale for which no storm warning has been received, shall cause to be transmitted all pertinent information relating thereto to ships in the vicinity and to the appropriate authorities on land, in accordance with rules and regulations issued by the Commission. When they consider it necessary, such authorities of the United States shall promptly bring the information received by them to the knowledge of those concerned, including interested foreign authorities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd281f6fb-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s357/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges for transmission of safety information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No charge shall be made by any ship or station in the mobile service of the United States for the transmission, receipt, or relay of the information designated in subsection (a) originating on a ship of the United States or of a foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd281f6fc-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s357/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement by Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The transmission by any ship of the United States, made in compliance with subsection (a), to any station which imposes a charge for the reception, relay, or forwarding of the required information, shall be free of cost to the ship concerned and any communication charges incurred by the ship for transmission, relay, or forwarding of the information may be certified to the Commission for reimbursement out of moneys appropriated to the Commission for that purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd281f6fd-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s357/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges for transmission of distress messages</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No charge shall be made by any ship or station in the mobile service of the United States for the transmission of distress messages and replies thereto in connection with situations involving the safety of life and property at sea.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd281f6fe-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s357/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Free services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any station or carrier may render free service in connection with situations involving the safety of life and property, including hydrographic reports, weather reports, reports regarding aids to navigation and medical assistance to injured or sick persons on ships and aircraft at sea. All free service permitted by this subsection shall be subject to such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe, which rules may limit such free service to the extent which the Commission finds desirable in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd281f6ff-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title III, § 359, formerly § 357, as added <ref href="/us/act/1937-05-20/ch229/s10/b">May 20, 1937, ch. 229, § 10(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/195">50 Stat. 195</ref>; renumbered § 359, <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-13/ch729/s2/a/1">Aug. 13, 1954, ch. 729, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/706">68 Stat. 706</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/121/s9">Pub. L. 89–121, § 9</ref>, <date date="1965-08-13">Aug. 13, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/516">79 Stat. 516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd281f700-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd281f701-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd281f702-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/121">Pub. L. 89–121</ref> directed the master of every ship of the United States equipped with radio transmitting apparatus which encounters subfreezing air temperatures associated with gale force winds causing severe ice accretion on superstructures, or winds of force 10 or above on the Beaufort scale for which no storm warning has been received to transmit the pertinent information relating thereto.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd281f703-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd281f704-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1937-05-20">May 20, 1937</date>, see section 16 of act <date date="1937-05-20">May 20, 1937</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s351">section 351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
