<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcde26ed8-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402"><num value="402">§ 402.</num><heading> Judicial review of Commission’s orders and decisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26ed9-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any proceeding to enjoin, set aside, annul, or suspend any order of the Commission under this chapter (except those appealable under subsection (b) of this section) shall be brought as provided by and in the manner prescribed in chapter 158 of title 28.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26eda-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Right to appeal</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appeals may be taken from decisions and orders of the Commission to the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia in any of the following cases:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26edb-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> By any applicant for a construction permit or station license, whose application is denied by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26edc-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> By any applicant for the renewal or modification of any such instrument of authorization whose application is denied by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26edd-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> By any party to an application for authority to transfer, assign, or dispose of any such instrument of authorization, or any rights thereunder, whose application is denied by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26ede-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> By any applicant for the permit required by <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s325">section 325 of this title</ref> whose application has been denied by the Commission, or by any permittee under said section whose permit has been revoked by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26edf-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> By the holder of any construction permit or station license which has been modified or revoked by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26ee0-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> By any other person who is aggrieved or whose interests are adversely affected by any order of the Commission granting or denying any application described in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (9) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26ee1-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> By any person upon whom an order to cease and desist has been served under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s312">section 312 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26ee2-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> By any radio operator whose license has been suspended by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26ee3-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> By any applicant for authority to provide interLATA services under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s271">section 271 of this title</ref> whose application is denied by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcde26ee4-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> By any person who is aggrieved or whose interests are adversely affected by a determination made by the Commission under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s618/a/3">section 618(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26ee5-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing notice of appeal; contents; jurisdiction; temporary orders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such appeal shall be taken by filing a notice of appeal with the court within thirty days from the date upon which public notice is given of the decision or order complained of. Such notice of appeal shall contain a concise statement of the nature of the proceedings as to which the appeal is taken; a concise statement of the reasons on which the appellant intends to rely, separately stated and numbered; and proof of service of a true copy of said notice and statement upon the Commission. Upon filing of such notice, the court shall have jurisdiction of the proceedings and of the questions determined therein and shall have power, by order, directed to the Commission or any other party to the appeal, to grant such temporary relief as it may deem just and proper. Orders granting temporary relief may be either affirmative or negative in their scope and application so as to permit either the maintenance of the status quo in the matter in which the appeal is taken or the restoration of a position or status terminated or adversely affected by the order appealed from and shall, unless otherwise ordered by the court, be effective pending hearing and determination of said appeal and compliance by the Commission with the final judgment of the court rendered in said appeal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26ee6-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice to interested parties; filing of record</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the filing of any such notice of appeal the appellant shall, not later than five days after the filing of such notice, notify each person shown by the records of the Commission to be interested in said appeal of the filing and pendency of the same. The Commission shall file with the court the record upon which the order complained of was entered, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26ee7-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Intervention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within thirty days after the filing of any such appeal any interested person may intervene and participate in the proceedings had upon said appeal by filing with the court a notice of intention to intervene and a verified statement showing the nature of the interest of such party, together with proof of service of true copies of said notice and statement, both upon appellant and upon the Commission. Any person who would be aggrieved or whose interest would be adversely affected by a reversal or modification of the order of the Commission complained of shall be considered an interested party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26ee8-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Records and briefs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The record and briefs upon which any such appeal shall be heard and determined by the court shall contain such information and material, and shall be prepared within such time and in such manner as the court may by rule prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26ee9-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Time of hearing; procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The court shall hear and determine the appeal upon the record before it in the manner prescribed by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s706">section 706 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26eea-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Remand</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event that the court shall render a decision and enter an order reversing the order of the Commission, it shall remand the case to the Commission to carry out the judgment of the court and it shall be the duty of the Commission, in the absence of the proceedings to review such judgment, to forthwith give effect thereto, and unless otherwise ordered by the court, to do so upon the basis of the proceedings already had and the record upon which said appeal was heard and determined.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26eeb-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Judgment for costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The court may, in its discretion, enter judgment for costs in favor of or against an appellant, or other interested parties intervening in said appeal, but not against the Commission, depending upon the nature of the issues involved upon said appeal and the outcome thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcde26eec-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s402/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Finality of decision; review by Supreme Court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The court’s judgment shall be final, subject, however, to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon writ of certiorari on petition therefor under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of title 28</ref>, by the appellant, by the Commission, or by any interested party intervening in the appeal, or by certification by the court pursuant to the provisions of that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcde26eed-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title IV, § 402, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1093">48 Stat. 1093</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1937-05-20/ch229">May 20, 1937, ch. 229</ref>, §§ 11–13, <ref href="/us/stat/50/197">50 Stat. 197</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s132">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 132</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/108">63 Stat. 108</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-16/ch879/s14">July 16, 1952, ch. 879, § 14</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/718">66 Stat. 718</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/791/s12">Pub. L. 85–791, § 12</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/945">72 Stat. 945</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/259/tI">Pub. L. 97–259, title I</ref>, §§ 121, 127(b), <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1097">96 Stat. 1097</ref>, 1099; <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tIV/s402/50">Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(50)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3361">98 Stat. 3361</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/tI/s151/b">Pub. L. 104–104, title I, § 151(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/107">110 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/260/tI/s104/d">Pub. L. 111–260, title I, § 104(d)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-08">Oct. 8, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2762">124 Stat. 2762</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcde26eee-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcde26eef-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcde26ef0-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">act June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1064">48 Stat. 1064</ref>, known as the Communications Act of 1934, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s609">section 609 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcde26ef1-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/111/260">Pub. L. 111–260</ref> added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s151/b/1">Pub. L. 104–104, § 151(b)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s151/b/2">Pub. L. 104–104, § 151(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> substituted “The” for “At the earliest convenient time the” and “706 of title 5” for “10(e) of the Administrative Procedure Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1009/e">5 U.S.C. 1009(e)</ref>]”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/259/s127/b">Pub. L. 97–259, § 127(b)</ref>, substituted “chapter 158 of title 28” for “Public Law 901, Eighty-first Congress, approved <date date="1950-12-29">December 29, 1950</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/259/s121">Pub. L. 97–259, § 121</ref>, substituted “appellant” for “Commission”, “filing of such notice” for “date of service upon it”, struck out “and shall thereafter permit any such person to inspect and make copies of said notice and statement of reasons therefor at the office of the Commission in the city of Washington” after “pendency of the same”, and substituted “The” for “Within thirty days after the filing of an appeal, the” before “Commission shall file”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/85/791">Pub. L. 85–791</ref> substituted “the record upon which the order complained of was entered, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>,” for “a copy of the order complained of, a full statement in writing of the facts and grounds relied upon by it in support of the order involved upon said appeal, and the originals or certified copies of all papers and evidence presented to and considered by it in entering said order” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1952—Act <date date="1952-07-16">July 16, 1952</date>, amended section generally to set up the procedure for the judicial review of the Commission’s orders and decisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, substituted “Title 28 of the United States Code” for “the Act of <date date="1913-10-22">October 22, 1913</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/38/219">38 Stat. 219</ref>)”, and “such Title 28” in lieu of “that Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1937—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1937-05-20">May 20, 1937</date>, § 11, inserted “, or suspending a radio operator’s license” after “or for modifications of an existing radio station license”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). Act <date date="1937-05-20">May 20, 1937</date>, § 12, added par. (3) relating to appeal from decisions in case of any radio operator whose license has been suspended by the Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1937-05-20">May 20, 1937</date>, § 13, inserted in last sentence “or order” after “upon the application”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcde26ef2-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idcde26ef3-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1934-06-07/ch426">Act June 7, 1934, ch. 426</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/926">48 Stat. 926</ref>, changed name of “Court of Appeals of the District of Columbia” to “United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcde26ef4-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> not applicable to cases pending on <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1657">section 1657 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcde26ef5-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1952 Amendment</heading><p>Section 19(2) of act <date date="1952-07-16">July 16, 1952</date>, provided that: <quotedContent>“The amendments made by this Act to section 402 of the Communications Act of 1934 [this section] (relating to judicial review of orders and decisions of the Commission) shall not apply with respect to any action or appeal which is pending before any court on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1952-07-16">July 16, 1952</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcde26ef6-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Administrative Orders Review Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Court of appeals exclusive jurisdiction respecting final orders of Federal Communications Commission made reviewable by subsec. (a) of this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2342">section 2342 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
