<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd2929939-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531"><num value="531">§ 531.</num><heading> Cable channels for public, educational, or governmental use</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd292993a-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to establish requirements with respect to designation or use of channel capacity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A franchising authority may establish requirements in a franchise with respect to the designation or use of channel capacity for public, educational, or governmental use only to the extent provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd292993b-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to require designation for public, educational, or governmental use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A franchising authority may in its request for proposals require as part of a franchise, and may require as part of a cable operator’s proposal for a franchise renewal, subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s546">section 546 of this title</ref>, that channel capacity be designated for public, educational, or governmental use, and channel capacity on institutional networks be designated for educational or governmental use, and may require rules and procedures for the use of the channel capacity designated pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd292993c-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A franchising authority may enforce any requirement in any franchise regarding the providing or use of such channel capacity. Such enforcement authority includes the authority to enforce any provisions of the franchise for services, facilities, or equipment proposed by the cable operator which relate to public, educational, or governmental use of channel capacity, whether or not required by the franchising authority pursuant to subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd292993d-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation of rules and procedures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any franchise under which channel capacity is designated under subsection (b), the franchising authority shall prescribe—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd292993e-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> rules and procedures under which the cable operator is permitted to use such channel capacity for the provision of other services if such channel capacity is not being used for the purposes designated, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd292993f-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> rules and procedures under which such permitted use shall cease.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd2929940-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Editorial control by cable operator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s544/d">section 544(d) of this title</ref>, a cable operator shall not exercise any editorial control over any public, educational, or governmental use of channel capacity provided pursuant to this section, except a cable operator may refuse to transmit any public access program or portion of a public access program which contains obscenity, indecency, or nudity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd2929941-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s531/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> “Institutional network” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “institutional network” means a communication network which is constructed or operated by the cable operator and which is generally available only to subscribers who are not residential subscribers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd2929942-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title VI, § 611, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/549/s2">Pub. L. 98–549, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2782">98 Stat. 2782</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/tV/s506/a">Pub. L. 104–104, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/136">110 Stat. 136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd2929943-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd2929944-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd2929945-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104">Pub. L. 104–104</ref> inserted before period at end “, except a cable operator may refuse to transmit any public access program or portion of a public access program which contains obscenity, indecency, or nudity”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd2929946-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd2929947-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 60 days after <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, except where otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/549/s9/a">section 9(a) of Pub. L. 98–549</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd2929948-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/385/s10/c">Pub. L. 102–385, § 10(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1486">106 Stat. 1486</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/385/s10/c">“Within 180 days following the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>], the Federal Communications Commission shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to enable a cable operator of a cable system to prohibit the use, on such system, of any channel capacity of any public, educational, or governmental access facility for any programming which contains obscene material, sexually explicit conduct, or material soliciting or promoting unlawful conduct.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
