<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcdebe50e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541"><num value="541">§ 541.</num><heading> General franchise requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdebe50f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to award franchises; public rights-of-way and easements; equal access to service; time for provision of service; assurances</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe510-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A franchising authority may award, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, 1 or more franchises within its jurisdiction; except that a franchising authority may not grant an exclusive franchise and may not unreasonably refuse to award an additional competitive franchise. Any applicant whose application for a second franchise has been denied by a final decision of the franchising authority may appeal such final decision pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s555">section 555 of this title</ref> for failure to comply with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe511-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Any franchise shall be construed to authorize the construction of a cable system over public rights-of-way, and through easements, which is within the area to be served by the cable system and which have been dedicated for compatible uses, except that in using such easements the cable operator shall ensure—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe512-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that the safety, functioning, and appearance of the property and the convenience and safety of other persons not be adversely affected by the installation or construction of facilities necessary for a cable system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe513-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that the cost of the installation, construction, operation, or removal of such facilities be borne by the cable operator or subscriber, or a combination of both; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe514-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that the owner of the property be justly compensated by the cable operator for any damages caused by the installation, construction, operation, or removal of such facilities by the cable operator.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe515-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In awarding a franchise or franchises, a franchising authority shall assure that access to cable service is not denied to any group of potential residential cable subscribers because of the income of the residents of the local area in which such group resides.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe516-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> In awarding a franchise, the franchising authority—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe517-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall allow the applicant’s cable system a reasonable period of time to become capable of providing cable service to all households in the franchise area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe518-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may require adequate assurance that the cable operator will provide adequate public, educational, and governmental access channel capacity, facilities, or financial support; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe519-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> may require adequate assurance that the cable operator has the financial, technical, or legal qualifications to provide cable service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdebe51a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> No cable service without franchise; exception under prior law</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe51b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except to the extent provided in paragraph (2) and subsection (f), a cable operator may not provide cable service without a franchise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe51c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) shall not require any person lawfully providing cable service without a franchise on <date date="1984-07-01">July 1, 1984</date>, to obtain a franchise unless the franchising authority so requires.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe51d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe51e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If a cable operator or affiliate thereof is engaged in the provision of telecommunications services—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe51f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such cable operator or affiliate shall not be required to obtain a franchise under this subchapter for the provision of telecommunications services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe520-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the provisions of this subchapter shall not apply to such cable operator or affiliate for the provision of telecommunications services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe521-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A franchising authority may not impose any requirement under this subchapter that has the purpose or effect of prohibiting, limiting, restricting, or conditioning the provision of a telecommunications service by a cable operator or an affiliate thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe522-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> A franchising authority may not order a cable operator or affiliate thereof—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe523-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to discontinue the provision of a telecommunications service, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe524-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to discontinue the operation of a cable system, to the extent such cable system is used for the provision of a telecommunications service, by reason of the failure of such cable operator or affiliate thereof to obtain a franchise or franchise renewal under this subchapter with respect to the provision of such telecommunications service.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe525-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Except as otherwise permitted by sections 531 and 532 of this title, a franchising authority may not require a cable operator to provide any telecommunications service or facilities, other than institutional networks, as a condition of the initial grant of a franchise, a franchise renewal, or a transfer of a franchise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdebe526-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Status of cable system as common carrier or utility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any cable system shall not be subject to regulation as a common carrier or utility by reason of providing any cable service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdebe527-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Informational tariffs; regulation by States; “State” defined</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe528-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A State or the Commission may require the filing of informational tariffs for any intrastate communications service provided by a cable system, other than cable service, that would be subject to regulation by the Commission or any State if offered by a common carrier subject, in whole or in part, to subchapter II of this chapter. Such informational tariffs shall specify the rates, terms, and conditions for the provision of such service, including whether it is made available to all subscribers generally, and shall take effect on the date specified therein.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe529-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to affect the authority of any State to regulate any cable operator to the extent that such operator provides any communication service other than cable service, whether offered on a common carrier or private contract basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcdebe52a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “State” has the meaning given it in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s153">section 153 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdebe52b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> State regulation of facilities serving subscribers in multiple dwelling units</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to affect the authority of any State to license or otherwise regulate any facility or combination of facilities which serves only subscribers in one or more multiple unit dwellings under common ownership, control, or management and which does not use any public right-of-way.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdebe52c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Local or municipal authority as multichannel video programming distributor</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No provision of this chapter shall be construed to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe52d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> prohibit a local or municipal authority that is also, or is affiliated with, a franchising authority from operating as a multichannel video programming distributor in the franchise area, notwithstanding the granting of one or more franchises by such franchising authority; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcdebe52e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s541/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> require such local or municipal authority to secure a franchise to operate as a multichannel video programming distributor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcdebe52f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title VI, § 621, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/549/s2">Pub. L. 98–549, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2786">98 Stat. 2786</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/385">Pub. L. 102–385</ref>, §§ 7(a)(1), (b), (c), <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1483">106 Stat. 1483</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s3/d/3">Pub. L. 104–104, § 3(d)(3)</ref>, title III, § 303(a), <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/61">110 Stat. 61</ref>, 124.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcdebe530-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcdebe531-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcdebe532-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (f), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">act June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1064">48 Stat. 1064</ref>, known as the Communications Act of 1934, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s609">section 609 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcdebe533-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s303/a">Pub. L. 104–104, § 303(a)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/s3/d/3">Pub. L. 104–104, § 3(d)(3)</ref>, substituted “section 153” for “section 153(v)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/385/s7/a/1">Pub. L. 102–385, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end “; except that a franchising authority may not grant an exclusive franchise and may not unreasonably refuse to award an additional competitive franchise. Any applicant whose application for a second franchise has been denied by a final decision of the franchising authority may appeal such final decision pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s555">section 555 of this title</ref> for failure to comply with this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/385/s7/b">Pub. L. 102–385, § 7(b)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/385/s7/c/1">Pub. L. 102–385, § 7(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “and subsection (f)” after “paragraph (2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/385/s7/c/2">Pub. L. 102–385, § 7(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcdebe534-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcdebe535-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/385">Pub. L. 102–385</ref> effective 60 days after <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/385/s28">section 28 of Pub. L. 102–385</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s325">section 325 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcdebe536-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 60 days after <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, except where otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/549/s9/a">section 9(a) of Pub. L. 98–549</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
