<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd29c0f95-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549"><num value="549">§ 549.</num><heading> Competitive availability of navigation devices</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd29c0f96-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Commercial consumer availability of equipment used to access services provided by multichannel video programming distributors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall, in consultation with appropriate industry standard-setting organizations, adopt regulations to assure the commercial availability, to consumers of multichannel video programming and other services offered over multichannel video programming systems, of converter boxes, interactive communications equipment, and other equipment used by consumers to access multichannel video programming and other services offered over multichannel video programming systems, from manufacturers, retailers, and other vendors not affiliated with any multichannel video programming distributor. Such regulations shall not prohibit any multichannel video programming distributor from also offering converter boxes, interactive communications equipment, and other equipment used by consumers to access multichannel video programming and other services offered over multichannel video programming systems, to consumers, if the system operator’s charges to consumers for such devices and equipment are separately stated and not subsidized by charges for any such service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd29c0f97-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of system security</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall not prescribe regulations under subsection (a) which would jeopardize security of multichannel video programming and other services offered over multichannel video programming systems, or impede the legal rights of a provider of such services to prevent theft of service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd29c0f98-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall waive a regulation adopted under subsection (a) for a limited time upon an appropriate showing by a provider of multichannel video programming and other services offered over multichannel video programming systems, or an equipment provider, that such waiver is necessary to assist the development or introduction of a new or improved multichannel video programming or other service offered over multichannel video programming systems, technology, or products. Upon an appropriate showing, the Commission shall grant any such waiver request within 90 days of any application filed under this subsection, and such waiver shall be effective for all service providers and products in that category and for all providers of services and products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd29e7f99-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Avoidance of redundant regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd29e7f9a-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Commercial availability determinations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Determinations made or regulations prescribed by the Commission with respect to commercial availability to consumers of converter boxes, interactive communications equipment, and other equipment used by consumers to access multichannel video programming and other services offered over multichannel video programming systems, before <date date="1996-02-08">February 8, 1996</date>, shall fulfill the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idd29e7f9b-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section affects section 64.702(e) of the Commission’s regulations (47 C.F.R. 64.702(e)) or other Commission regulations governing interconnection and competitive provision of customer premises equipment used in connection with basic common carrier communications services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd29e7f9c-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The regulations adopted under this section shall cease to apply when the Commission determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd29e7f9d-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the market for the multichannel video programming distributors is fully competitive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd29e7f9e-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the market for converter boxes, and interactive communications equipment, used in conjunction with that service is fully competitive; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd29e7f9f-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> elimination of the regulations would promote competition and the public interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idd29e7fa0-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s549/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Commission’s authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed as expanding or limiting any authority that the Commission may have under law in effect before <date date="1996-02-08">February 8, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd29e7fa1-4ef6-11f1-9110-db228fde61c5">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title VI, § 629, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/104/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 104–104, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1996-02-08">Feb. 8, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/125">110 Stat. 125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
