<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcdf581e4-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s604"><num value="604">§ 604.</num><heading> Effect of transfer</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdf581e5-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s604/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, contracts, licenses, and privileges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, contracts, licenses, and privileges which have been issued, made, or granted by the Interstate Commerce Commission, the Federal Radio Commission, or the Postmaster General, under any provision of law repealed or amended by this chapter or in the exercise of duties, powers, or functions transferred to the Commission by this chapter, and which are in effect at the time this section takes effect, shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or repealed by the Commission or by operation of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdf581e6-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s604/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All records transferred to the Commission under this chapter shall be available for use by the Commission to the same extent as if such records were originally records of the Commission. All final valuations and determinations of depreciation charges by the Interstate Commerce Commission with respect to common carriers engaged in radio or wire communication, and all orders of the Interstate Commerce Commission with respect to such valuations and determinations, shall have the same force and effect as though made by the Commission under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcdf581e7-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, title VII, § 704, formerly title VI, § 604, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1103">48 Stat. 1103</ref>; renumbered title VII, § 704, <ref href="/us/pl/98/549/s6/a">Pub. L. 98–549, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2804">98 Stat. 2804</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/414/tIII/s304/a/14">Pub. L. 103–414, title III, § 304(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4297">108 Stat. 4297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcdf581e8-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcdf581e9-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcdf581ea-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">act June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1064">48 Stat. 1064</ref>, known as the Communications Act of 1934, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s609">section 609 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcdf581eb-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/414">Pub. L. 103–414</ref> redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “Any proceeding, hearing, or investigation commenced or pending before the Federal Radio Commission, the Interstate Commerce Commission, or the Postmaster General, at the time of the organization of the Commission, shall be continued by the Commission in the same manner as though originally commenced before the Commission, if such proceeding, hearing, or investigation (1) involves the administration of duties, powers, and functions transferred to the Commission by this chapter, or (2) involves the exercise of jurisdiction similar to that granted to the Commission under the provisions of this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/414/s303/a/14/A">Pub. L. 103–414, § 303(a)(14)(A)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which read as follows: “The provisions of this chapter shall not affect suits commenced prior to the date of the organization of the Commission; and all such suits shall be continued, proceedings therein had, appeals therein taken and judgments therein rendered, in the same manner and with the same effect as if this chapter had not been passed. No suit, action, or other proceeding lawfully commenced by or against any agency or officer of the United States, in relation to the discharge of official duties, shall abate by reason of any transfer of authority, power, and duties from such agency or officer to the Commission under the provisions of this chapter, but the court, upon motion or supplemental petition filed at any time within twelve months after such transfer, showing the necessity for a survival of such suit, action, or other proceeding to obtain a settlement of the questions involved, may allow the same to be maintained by or against the Commission.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcdf581ec-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idcdf581ed-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Office of Postmaster General of Post Office Department abolished and functions, powers, and duties of Postmaster General transferred to United States Postal Service by <ref href="/us/pl/91/375/s4/a">Pub. L. 91–375, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/773">84 Stat. 773</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s201">section 201 of Title 39</ref>, Postal Service.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcdf581ee-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Interstate Commerce Commission and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Interstate Commerce Commission abolished and functions of Commission transferred, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, to Surface Transportation Board effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, by <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1302">section 1302 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>. References to Interstate Commerce Commission deemed to refer to Surface Transportation Board, a member or employee of the Board, or Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
