<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcdfa3d18-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s615a"><num value="615a">§ 615a.</num><heading> Service provider parity of protection</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdfa3d19-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s615a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Provider parity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A wireless carrier, IP-enabled voice service provider, or other emergency communications provider, and their officers, directors, employees, vendors, and agents, shall have immunity or other protection from liability in a State of a scope and extent that is not less than the scope and extent of immunity or other protection from liability that any local exchange company, and its officers, directors, employees, vendors, or agents, have under Federal and State law (whether through statute, judicial decision, tariffs filed by such local exchange company, or otherwise) applicable in such State, including in connection with an act or omission involving the release to a PSAP, emergency medical service provider or emergency dispatch provider, public safety, fire service or law enforcement official, or hospital emergency or trauma care facility of subscriber information related to emergency calls, emergency services, or other emergency communications services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdfa3d1a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s615a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> User parity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person using wireless 9–1–1 service, or making 9–1–1 communications via IP-enabled voice service or other emergency communications service, shall have immunity or other protection from liability of a scope and extent that is not less than the scope and extent of immunity or other protection from liability under applicable law in similar circumstances of a person using 9–1–1 service that is not via wireless 9–1–1 service, IP-enabled voice service, or other emergency communications service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdfa3d1b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s615a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> PSAP parity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In matters related to 9–1–1 communications via wireless 9–1–1 service, IP-enabled voice service, or other emergency communications service, a PSAP, and its employees, vendors, agents, and authorizing government entity (if any) shall have immunity or other protection from liability of a scope and extent that is not less than the scope and extent of immunity or other protection from liability under applicable law accorded to such PSAP, employees, vendors, agents, and authorizing government entity, respectively, in matters related to 9–1–1 communications that are not via wireless 9–1–1 service, IP-enabled voice service, or other emergency communications service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcdfa3d1c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s615a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis for enactment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section is enacted as an exercise of the enforcement power of the Congress under section 5 of the Fourteenth Amendment to the Constitution and the power of the Congress to regulate commerce with foreign nations, among the several States, and with Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcdfa3d1d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/81/s4">Pub. L. 106–81, § 4</ref>, <date date="1999-10-26">Oct. 26, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1288">113 Stat. 1288</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/283/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 110–283, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-23">July 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2624">122 Stat. 2624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcdfa3d1e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcdfa3d1f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idcdfa3d20-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999, and not as part of the Communications Act of 1934 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcdfa3d21-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/283/s201/a/1">Pub. L. 110–283, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Service provider parity of protection” for “Parity of protection for provision or use of wireless service” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/283/s201/a/2">Pub. L. 110–283, § 201(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “wireless carrier, IP-enabled voice service provider, or other emergency communications provider, and their officers” for “wireless carrier, and its officers” and “emergency calls, emergency services, or other emergency communications services” for “emergency calls or emergency services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/283/s201/a/3">Pub. L. 110–283, § 201(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “using wireless 9–1–1 service, or making 9–1–1 communications via IP-enabled voice service or other emergency communications service, shall” for “using wireless 9–1–1 service shall” and “that is not via wireless 9–1–1 service, IP-enabled voice service, or other emergency communications service” for “that is not wireless”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/110/283/s201/a/4">Pub. L. 110–283, § 201(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “9–1–1 communications via wireless 9–1–1 service, IP-enabled voice service, or other emergency communications service, a PSAP” for “wireless 9–1–1 communications, a PSAP” and “that are not via wireless 9–1–1 service, IP-enabled voice service, or other emergency communications service” for “that are not wireless”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
