<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idce089435-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902"><num value="902">§ 902.</num><heading> Establishment; assigned functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce089436-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce089437-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There shall be within the Department of Commerce an administration to be known as the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce089438-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Head of administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The head of the NTIA shall be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce089439-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Assigned functions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce08943a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s904/d">section 904(d) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall assign to the Assistant Secretary and the NTIA responsibility for the performance of the Secretary’s communications and information functions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce08943b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Communications and information functions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s904/d">section 904(d) of this title</ref>, the functions to be assigned by the Secretary under paragraph (1) include (but are not limited to) the following functions transferred to the Secretary by Reorganization Plan Number 1 of 1977 and Executive Order 12046:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08943c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The authority delegated by the President to the Secretary to assign frequencies to radio stations or classes of radio stations belonging to and operated by the United States, including the authority to amend, modify, or revoke such assignments, but not including the authority to make final disposition of appeals from frequency assignments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08943d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The authority to authorize a foreign government to construct and operate a radio station at the seat of Government of the United States, but only upon recommendation of the Secretary of State and after consultation with the Attorney General and the Chairman of the Commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08943e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Functions relating to the communications satellite system, including authority vested in the President by section 201(a) of the Communications Satellite Act of 1962 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s721/a">47 U.S.C. 721(a)</ref>) and delegated to the Secretary under Executive Order 12046, to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce08943f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> aid in the planning and development of the commercial communications satellite system and the execution of a national program for the operation of such a system;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089440-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> conduct a continuous review of all phases of the development and operation of such system, including the activities of the Corporation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089441-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> coordinate, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the activities of governmental agencies with responsibilities in the field of telecommunications, so as to ensure that there is full and effective compliance at all times with the policies set forth in the Communications Satellite Act of 1962 [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s701">47 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089442-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> make recommendations to the President and others as appropriate, with respect to steps necessary to ensure the availability and appropriate utilization of the communications satellite system for general governmental purposes in consonance with section 201(a)(6) of the Communications Satellite Act of 1962 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s721/a/6">47 U.S.C. 721(a)(6)</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002053">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002053"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089443-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> help attain coordinated and efficient use of the electromagnetic spectrum and the technical compatibility of the communications satellite system with existing communications facilities both in the United States and abroad;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089444-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> assist in the preparation of Presidential action documents for consideration by the President as may be appropriate under section 201(a) of the Communications Satellite Act of 1962 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s721/a">47 U.S.C. 721(a)</ref>), make necessary recommendations to the President in connection therewith, and keep the President informed with respect to the carrying out of the Communications Satellite Act of 1962 [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s701">47 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089445-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> serve as the chief point of liaison between the President and the Corporation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089446-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The authority to serve as the President’s principal adviser on telecommunications policies pertaining to the Nation’s economic and technological advancement and to the regulation of the telecommunications industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089447-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The authority to advise the Director of the Office of Management and Budget on the development of policies relating to the procurement and management of Federal telecommunications systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089448-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The authority to conduct studies and evaluations concerning telecommunications research and development and concerning the initiation, improvement, expansion, testing, operation, and use of Federal telecommunications systems and advising agencies of the results of such studies and evaluations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089449-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> Functions which involve—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce08944a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> developing and setting forth, in coordination with the Secretary of State and other interested agencies, plans, policies, and programs which relate to international telecommunications issues, conferences, and negotiations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce08944b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> coordinating economic, technical, operational, and related preparations for United States participation in international telecommunications conferences and negotiations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce08944c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> providing advice and assistance to the Secretary of State on international telecommunications policies to strengthen the position and serve the best interests of the United States in support of the Secretary of State’s responsibility for the conduct of foreign affairs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08944d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> The authority to provide for the coordination of the telecommunications activities of the executive branch and assist in the formulation of policies and standards for those activities, including (but not limited to) considerations of interoperability, privacy, security, spectrum use, and emergency readiness.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08944e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The authority to develop and set forth telecommunications policies pertaining to the Nation’s economic and technological advancement and to the regulation of the telecommunications industry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08944f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> The responsibility to ensure that the views of the executive branch on telecommunications matters are effectively presented to the Commission and, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to the Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089450-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> The authority to establish policies concerning spectrum assignments and use by radio stations belonging to and operated by the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089451-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><chapeau> Functions which involve—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089452-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/L/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> developing, in cooperation with the Commission, a comprehensive long-range plan for improved management of all electromagnetic spectrum resources;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089453-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/L/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> performing analysis, engineering, and administrative functions, including the maintenance of necessary files and data bases, as necessary for the performance of assigned functions for the management of electromagnetic spectrum resources;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089454-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/L/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> conducting research and analysis of electromagnetic propagation, radio systems characteristics, and operating techniques affecting the utilization of the electromagnetic spectrum in coordination with specialized, related research and analysis performed by other Federal agencies in their areas of responsibility; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce089455-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/L/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> conducting research and analysis in the general field of telecommunications sciences in support of assigned functions and in support of other Government agencies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089456-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> The authority to conduct studies and make recommendations concerning the impact of the convergence of computer and communications technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089457-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/N"><num value="N">(N)</num><content> The authority to coordinate Federal telecommunications assistance to State and local governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089458-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/O"><num value="O">(O)</num><content> The authority to conduct and coordinate economic and technical analyses of telecommunications policies, activities, and opportunities in support of assigned functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089459-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/P"><num value="P">(P)</num><content> The authority to contract for studies and reports relating to any aspect of assigned functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08945a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/Q"><num value="Q">(Q)</num><content> The authority to participate, as appropriate, in evaluating the capability of telecommunications resources, in recommending remedial actions, and in developing policy options.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08945b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/R"><num value="R">(R)</num><content> The authority to participate with the National Security Council and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy as they carry out their responsibilities under sections 4–1, 4–2, and 4–3 of Executive Order 12046, with respect to emergency functions, the national communication system, and telecommunications planning functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08945c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/S"><num value="S">(S)</num><content> The authority to establish coordinating committees pursuant to section 10 of Executive Order 11556.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08945d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/T"><num value="T">(T)</num><content> The authority to establish, as permitted by law, such interagency committees and working groups composed of representatives of interested agencies and consulting with such departments and agencies as may be necessary for the effective performance of assigned functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce08945e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/2/U"><num value="U">(U)</num><content> The responsibility to promote the best possible and most efficient use of electromagnetic spectrum resources across the Federal Government, subject to and consistent with the needs and missions of Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce08945f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional communications and information functions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to the functions described in paragraph (2), the Secretary under paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089460-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may assign to the NTIA the performance of functions under section 504(a) of the Communications Satellite Act of 1962 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s753/a">47 U.S.C. 753(a)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089461-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall assign to the NTIA the administration of the Public Telecommunications Facilities Program under sections 390 through 393 of this title, and the National Endowment for Children’s Educational Television under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s394">section 394 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce089462-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s902/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall assign to the NTIA responsibility for providing for the establishment, and overseeing operation, of a second-level Internet domain within the United States country code domain in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s941">section 941 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idce089463-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/538/tI/s103">Pub. L. 102–538, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3534">106 Stat. 3534</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/317/s3">Pub. L. 107–317, § 3</ref>, <date date="2002-12-04">Dec. 4, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2767">116 Stat. 2767</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/tVI/s6410">Pub. L. 112–96, title VI, § 6410</ref>, <date date="2012-02-22">Feb. 22, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/234">126 Stat. 234</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idce089464-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idce089465-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idce089466-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan Number 1 of 1977, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12046, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s305">section 305 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Communications Satellite Act of 1962, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(C)(iii), (vi), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/624">Pub. L. 87–624</ref>, <date date="1962-08-31">Aug. 31, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/419">76 Stat. 419</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 6 (§ 701 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s701">section 701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 201(a)(6) of the Communications Satellite Act of 1962, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(C)(iv), was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s721/a/6">section 721(a)(6) of this title</ref> and was omitted from the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 11556, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(S), which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s305">section 305 of this title</ref> was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12046, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s305">section 305 of this title</ref>. Section 10 of Ex. Ord. No. 11556 related to advisory committees established by the Director of the former Office of Telecommunications Policy.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idce089467-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (b)(2)(U). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96">Pub. L. 112–96</ref> added subpar. (U).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/317">Pub. L. 107–317</ref> added subpar. (C).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce089468-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subbsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce089469-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Spectrum Information Technology Modernization Efforts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dH/tXCII/s9203">Pub. L. 116–283, div. H, title XCII, § 9203</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4793">134 Stat. 4793</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dH/tXCII/s9203">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial Interagency Spectrum Information Technology Coordination</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information, in consultation with the Policy and Plans Steering Group, shall identify a process to establish goals, including parameters to measure the achievement of such goals, for the modernization of the infrastructure of covered agencies relating to managing the use of Federal spectrum by such agencies, which shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the standardization of data inputs, modeling algorithms, modeling and simulation processes, analysis tools with respect to Federal spectrum, assumptions, and any other tool to ensure interoperability and functionality with respect to such infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> other potential innovative technological capabilities with respect to such infrastructure, including cloud-based databases, artificial intelligence technologies, automation, and improved modeling and simulation capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> ways to improve the management of the use of Federal spectrum by covered agencies through such infrastructure, including by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> increasing the efficiency of such infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> addressing validation of usage with respect to such infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> increasing the accuracy of such infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> validating models used by such infrastructure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> monitoring and enforcing requirements that are imposed on covered agencies with respect to the use of Federal spectrum by covered agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> ways to improve the ability of covered agencies to meet mission requirements in congested environments with respect to Federal spectrum, including as part of automated adjustments to operations based on changing conditions in such environments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><chapeau> the creation of a time-based automated mechanism—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to share Federal spectrum between covered agencies to collaboratively and dynamically increase access to Federal spectrum by such agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> that could be scaled across Federal spectrum; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the collaboration between covered agencies necessary to ensure the interoperability of Federal spectrum.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Spectrum Information Technology Modernization.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information shall submit to Congress a report that contains a plan for the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (in this section referred to as the ‘NTIA’) to modernize and automate the infrastructure of the NTIA relating to managing the use of Federal spectrum by covered agencies so as to more efficiently manage such use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an assessment of the current, as of the date on which such report is submitted, infrastructure of the NTIA described in such paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an acquisition strategy for the modernized infrastructure of the NTIA described in such paragraph, including how such modernized infrastructure will enable covered agencies to be more efficient and effective in the use of Federal spectrum;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a timeline for the implementation of the modernization efforts described in such paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> plans detailing how the modernized infrastructure of the NTIA described in such paragraph will—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> enhance the security and reliability of such infrastructure so that the NTIA is in compliance with the requirements of subchapter II of chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, with respect to such infrastructure;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> improve data models and analysis tools to increase the efficiency of the spectrum use described in such paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><chapeau> enhance automation and workflows, and reduce the scope and level of manual effort, in order to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> administer the management of the spectrum use described in such paragraph; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> improve data quality and processing time; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> improve the timeliness of spectrum analyses and requests for information, including requests submitted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> an operations and maintenance plan with respect to the modernized infrastructure of the NTIA described in such paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><chapeau> a strategy for coordination between the covered agencies within the Policy and Plans Steering Group, which shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> a description of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> such coordination efforts, as in effect on the date on which such report is submitted; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> a plan for coordination of such efforts after the date on which such report is submitted, including with respect to the efforts described in subsection (c);</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> a plan for standardizing—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> electromagnetic spectrum analysis tools;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> modeling and simulation processes and technologies; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> databases to provide technical interference assessments that are usable across the Federal Government as part of a common spectrum management infrastructure for covered agencies; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> a plan for each covered agency to implement a modernization plan described in subsection (c)(1) that is tailored to the particular timeline of such agency;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> identification of manually intensive processes involved in managing Federal spectrum and proposed enhancements to such processes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> metrics to evaluate the success of the modernization efforts described in such paragraph and any similar future efforts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> an estimate of the cost of the modernization efforts described in such paragraph and any future maintenance with respect to the modernized infrastructure of the NTIA described in such paragraph, including the cost of any personnel and equipment relating to such maintenance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Agency Spectrum Information Technology Modernization.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the head of each covered agency shall submit to the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information and the Policy and Plans Steering Group a report that describes a plan for such agency to modernize the infrastructure of such agency with respect to the use of Federal spectrum by such agency so that such modernized infrastructure of such agency is interoperable with the modernized infrastructure of the NTIA, as described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report submitted by the head of a covered agency under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> an assessment of the current, as of the date on which such report is submitted, management capabilities of such agency with respect to the use of frequencies that are assigned to such agency, which shall include a description of any challenges faced by such agency with respect to such management;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a timeline for completion of the modernization efforts described in such paragraph;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> a description of potential innovative technological capabilities for the management of frequencies that are assigned to such agency, as determined under subsection (a);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> identification of agency-specific requirements or constraints relating to the infrastructure of such agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> identification of any existing, as of the date on which such report is submitted, systems of such agency that are duplicative of the modernized infrastructure of the NTIA, as described in subsection (b); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><chapeau> with respect to the report submitted by the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> a strategy for the integration of systems or the flow of data among the Armed Forces, the military departments, the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities, and other components of the Department of Defense;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> a plan for the implementation of solutions to the use of Federal spectrum by the Department of Defense involving information at multiple levels of classification; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> a strategy for addressing, within the modernized infrastructure of the Department of Defense described in such paragraph, the exchange of information between the Department of Defense and the NTIA in order to accomplish required processing of all Department of Defense domestic spectrum coordination and management activities; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> be submitted in an unclassified format, with a classified annex, as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification of congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon submission of a report under paragraph (1), the head of a covered agency shall notify Congress that such report has been submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">GAO Oversight</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, conduct a review of the infrastructure of covered agencies, as such infrastructure exists on the date of the enactment of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> upon submission of all of the reports required by subsection (c), begin conducting oversight of the implementation of the modernization plans submitted by the Assistant Secretary and covered agencies under subsections (b) and (c), respectively;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> not later than 2 years after the date on which the Comptroller General begins conducting oversight under paragraph (2), and biennially thereafter until <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>, submit a report regarding such oversight to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> with respect to the implementation of the modernization plan of the Department of Defense, the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with respect to the implementation of the modernization plans of all covered agencies, including the Department of Defense, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> until <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>, provide regular briefings to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> with respect to the application of this section to the Department of Defense, the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with respect to the application of this section to all covered agencies, including the Department of Defense, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘covered agency’—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> means any Federal entity that the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information determines is appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> includes the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Federal entity’ has the meaning given such term in section 113(<i>l</i>) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923">47 U.S.C. 923</ref>(<i>l</i>)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘Federal spectrum’ means frequencies assigned on a primary basis to a covered agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The term ‘infrastructure’ means information technology systems and information technologies, tools, and databases.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce08946a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program for Digital and Wireless Networks for Online Educational Programs of Study</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dB/tV/s536">Pub. L. 110–161, div. B, title V, § 536</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1932">121 Stat. 1932</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/tIX/s941/k/2/N">Pub. L. 110–315, title IX, § 941(k)(2)(N)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3468">122 Stat. 3468</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/315/tIX/s941/k/2/N">
<inline>“This section may be cited as the ‘ED 1.0 Act’.</inline>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘Administrator’ means the Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘eligible educational institution’ means an institution that is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a historically Black college or university;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a Hispanic-serving institution as that term is defined in section 502(a)(5) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1101a/a/5">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)(5)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a tribally controlled college or university as that term is defined in section 2(a)(4) of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1801/a/4">25 U.S.C. 1801(a)(4)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> an Alaska Native-serving institution as that term is defined in section 317(b)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1059d/b/2">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)(2)</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> a Native Hawaiian-serving institution as that term is defined in section 317(b)(4) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1059d/b/4">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)(4)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘historically Black college or university’ means a part B institution as that term is defined in section 322(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1061/2">20 U.S.C. 1061(2)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> There is established within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration a pilot program under which the Administrator shall award 9 grants to eligible educational institutions to enable the eligible educational institutions to develop digital and wireless networks for online educational programs of study within the eligible educational institutions. The Administrator shall award not less than 1 grant to each type of eligible educational institution, enumerated under subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Administrator shall award a total of 9 grants under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The Administrator shall make grant payments under this subsection in the amount of $500,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> In awarding grants under this subsection the Administrator shall give priority to an eligible educational institution that, according to the most recent data available (including data available from the Bureau of the Census), serves a county, or other appropriate political subdivision where no counties exist—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> in which 50 percent of the residents of the county, or other appropriate political subdivision where no counties exist, are members of a racial or ethnic minority;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> in which less than 18 percent of the residents of the county, or other appropriate political subdivision where no counties exist, have obtained a baccalaureate degree or a higher education;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> that has an unemployment rate of 7 percent or greater;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> in which 20 percent or more of the residents of the county, or other appropriate political subdivision where no counties exist, live in poverty;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> that has a negative population growth rate; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> that has a family income of not more than $32,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> In awarding grants under this subsection the Administrator shall give the highest priority to an eligible educational institution that meets the greatest number of requirements described in clauses (i) through (vi) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> An eligible educational institution receiving a grant under this subsection may use the grant funds—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to acquire equipment, instrumentation, networking capability, hardware, software, digital network technology, wireless technology, or wireless infrastructure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to develop and provide educational services, including faculty development; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to develop strategic plans for information technology investments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The Administrator shall not require an eligible educational institution to provide matching funds for a grant awarded under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Administrator shall consult with the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, on a quarterly basis regarding the pilot program assisted under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>], the Administrator shall submit to the committees described in subparagraph (A) a report evaluating the progress of the pilot program assisted under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $4,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The Administrator shall carry out this section only with amounts appropriated in advance specifically to carry out this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce08946b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Technology Protection Measures</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/4/dB/tXVII/s1703">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(4) [div. B, title XVII, § 1703]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–336, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/4/dB/tXVII/s1703">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>], the National Telecommunications and Information Administration shall initiate a notice and comment proceeding for purposes of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> evaluating whether or not currently available technology protection measures, including commercial Internet blocking and filtering software, adequately addresses the needs of educational institutions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> making recommendations on how to foster the development of measures that meet such needs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> evaluating the development and effectiveness of local Internet safety policies that are currently in operation after community input.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Technology protection measure</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘technology protection measure’ means a specific technology that blocks or filters Internet access to visual depictions that are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> obscene, as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1460">section 1460 of title 18</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> child pornography, as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2256">section 2256 of title 18</ref>, United States Code; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> harmful to minors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Harmful to minors</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘harmful to minors’ means any picture, image, graphic image file, or other visual depiction that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> taken as a whole and with respect to minors, appeals to a prurient interest in nudity, sex, or excretion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> depicts, describes, or represents, in a patently offensive way with respect to what is suitable for minors, an actual or simulated sexual act or sexual contact, actual or simulated normal or perverted sexual acts, or a lewd exhibition of the genitals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> taken as a whole, lacks serious literary, artistic, political, or scientific value as to minors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sexual act; sexual contact</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘sexual act’ and ‘sexual contact’ have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2246">section 2246 of title 18</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
