<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idce0fc0f6-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928"><num value="928">§ 928.</num><heading> Spectrum Relocation Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc0f7-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of Spectrum Relocation Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established on the books of the Treasury a separate fund to be known as the “Spectrum Relocation Fund” (in this section referred to as the “Fund”), which shall be administered by the Office of Management and Budget (in this section referred to as “OMB”), in consultation with the NTIA.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc0f8-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Crediting of receipts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Fund shall be credited with the amounts specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s309/j/8/D">section 309(j)(8)(D) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc0f9-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amounts in the Fund from auctions of eligible frequencies are authorized to be used to pay relocation or sharing costs of an eligible Federal entity incurring such costs with respect to relocation from or sharing of those frequencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc0fa-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Fund availability</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc0fb-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There are hereby appropriated from the Fund such sums as are required to pay the relocation or sharing costs specified in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc0fc-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">None of the funds provided under this subsection may be transferred to any eligible Federal entity—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc0fd-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> unless the eligible Federal entity has submitted a transition plan to the NTIA as required by paragraph (1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/h">section 923(h) of this title</ref>, the Technical Panel has found such plan sufficient under paragraph (4) of such section, and the NTIA has made available such plan on its website as required by paragraph (5) of such section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc0fe-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> unless the Director of OMB has determined, in consultation with the NTIA, the appropriateness of such costs and the timeline for relocation or sharing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc0ff-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> until 30 days after the Director of OMB has submitted to the Committees on Appropriations and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives for approval, to the Committees on Appropriations and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate for approval, and to the Comptroller General a detailed plan describing specifically how the sums transferred from the Fund will be used to pay relocation or sharing costs in accordance with such subsection and the timeline for such relocation or sharing.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Unless disapproved within 30 days, the amounts in the Fund shall be available immediately. If the plan is disapproved, the Director may resubmit a revised plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc100-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfers for pre-auction costs</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc101-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Director of OMB may transfer to an eligible Federal entity, at any time (including prior to a scheduled auction), such sums as may be available in the Fund to pay relocation or sharing costs related to pre-auction estimates or research, as such costs are described in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/g/3/A/iii">section 923(g)(3)(A)(iii) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc102-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No funds may be transferred pursuant to subparagraph (A) unless—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc103-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the notification provided under paragraph (2)(C) includes a certification from the Director of OMB that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc104-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> funds transferred before an auction will likely allow for timely implementation of relocation or sharing, thereby increasing net expected auction proceeds by an amount not less than the time value of the amount of funds transferred; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc105-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the auction is intended to occur not later than 8 years after transfer of funds; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc106-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the transition plan submitted by the eligible Federal entity under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/h/1">section 923(h)(1) of this title</ref> provides—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc107-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> to the fullest extent possible, for sharing and coordination of eligible frequencies with non-Federal users, including reasonable accommodation by the eligible Federal entity for the use of eligible frequencies by non-Federal users during the period that the entity is relocating its spectrum uses (in this clause referred to as the “transition period”);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc108-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for non-Federal users to be able to use eligible frequencies during the transition period in geographic areas where the eligible Federal entity does not use such frequencies;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc109-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> that the eligible Federal entity will, during the transition period, make itself available for negotiation and discussion with non-Federal users not later than 30 days after a written request therefor; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc10a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> that the eligible Federal entity will, during the transition period, make available to a non-Federal user with appropriate security clearances any classified information (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s798/b">section 798(b) of title 18</ref>) regarding the relocation process, on a need-to-know basis, to assist the non-Federal user in the relocation process with such eligible Federal entity or other eligible Federal entities.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc10b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability to certain costs</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc10c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Director of OMB may transfer under subparagraph (A) not more than $10,000,000 for costs incurred after <date date="2010-06-28">June 28, 2010</date>, but before <date date="2012-02-22">February 22, 2012</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc10d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/3/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplement not supplant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Any amounts transferred by the Director of OMB pursuant to clause (i) shall be in addition to any amounts that the Director of OMB may transfer for costs incurred on or after <date date="2012-02-22">February 22, 2012</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc10e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Reversion of unused funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any amounts in the Fund that are remaining after the payment of the relocation or sharing costs that are payable from the Fund shall revert to and be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury, for the sole purpose of deficit reduction, not later than 8 years after the date of the deposit of such proceeds to the Fund, unless within 60 days in advance of the reversion of such funds, the Director of OMB, in consultation with the NTIA, notifies the congressional committees described in paragraph (2)(C) that such funds are needed to complete or to implement current or future relocation or sharing arrangements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc10f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer to eligible Federal entities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc110-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce0fc111-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Amounts made available pursuant to subsection (d) shall be transferred to eligible Federal entities, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/g/1">section 923(g)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce0fc112-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> An eligible Federal entity may receive more than one such transfer, but if the sum of the subsequent transfer or transfers exceeds 10 percent of the original transfer—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc113-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such subsequent transfers are subject to prior approval by the Director of OMB as required by subsection (d)(2)(B);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc114-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the notice to the committees containing the plan required by subsection (d)(2)(C) shall be not less than 45 days prior to the date of the transfer that causes such excess above 10 percent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc115-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such notice shall include, in addition to such plan, an explanation of need for such subsequent transfer or transfers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce0fc116-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Such transferred amounts shall be credited to the appropriations account of the eligible Federal entity which has incurred, or will incur, such costs, and shall, subject to paragraph (2), remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce0fc117-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> At the request of an eligible Federal entity, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (in this subsection referred to as “OMB”) may transfer the amount under subparagraph (A) immediately—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc118-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> after the frequencies are reallocated by competitive bidding under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s309/j">section 309(j) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc119-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of an incumbent Federal entity that is incurring relocation or sharing costs to accommodate sharing spectrum frequencies with another Federal entity, after the frequencies from which the other eligible Federal entity is relocating are reallocated by competitive bidding under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s309/j">section 309(j) of this title</ref>, without regard to the availability of such sums in the Fund.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce0fc11a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Prior to the deposit of proceeds into the Fund from an auction, the Director of OMB may borrow from the Treasury the amount under subparagraph (A) for a transfer under subparagraph (D). The Treasury shall immediately be reimbursed, without interest, from funds deposited into the Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc11b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Retransfer to fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An eligible Federal entity that has received such amounts shall report its expenditures to OMB and shall transfer any amounts in excess of actual relocation or sharing costs back to the Fund immediately after the NTIA has notified the Commission that the relocation of the entity or implementation of the sharing arrangement by the entity is complete, or has determined that such entity has unreasonably failed to complete such relocation or the implementation of such arrangement in accordance with the timeline required by subsection (d)(2)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc11c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional payments from Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc11d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Amounts available</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsections (c) through (e), after <date date="2012-02-22">February 22, 2012</date>, there are appropriated from the Fund and available to the Director of OMB for use in accordance with paragraph (2) not more than 10 percent of the amounts deposited in the Fund from auctions occurring after such date of licenses for the use of spectrum vacated by eligible Federal entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc11e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc11f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director of OMB, in consultation with the NTIA, may use amounts made available under paragraph (1) to make payments to eligible Federal entities that are implementing a transition plan submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/h/1">section 923(h)(1) of this title</ref> in order to encourage such entities to complete the implementation more quickly, thereby encouraging timely access to the eligible frequencies that are being reallocated for exclusive non-Federal use or shared use.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc120-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of any payment by the Director of OMB under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc121-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such payment shall be based on the market value of the eligible frequencies, the timeliness with which the eligible Federal entity clears its use of such frequencies, and the need for such frequencies in order for the entity to conduct its essential missions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc122-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the eligible Federal entity shall use such payment for the purposes specified in clauses (i) through (v) of <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/g/3/A">section 923(g)(3)(A) of this title</ref> to achieve comparable capability of systems affected by the reallocation of eligible frequencies from Federal use to exclusive non-Federal use or to shared use;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc123-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such payment may not be made if the amount remaining in the Fund after such payment will be less than 10 percent of the winning bids in the auction of the spectrum with respect to which the Federal entity is incurring relocation or sharing costs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc124-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/f/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> such payment may not be made until 30 days after the Director of OMB has notified the congressional committees described in subsection (d)(2)(C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc125-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional payments for research and development and planning activities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc126-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Amounts available</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsections (c) through (e)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc127-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> there are appropriated from the Fund on <date date="2015-11-02">November 2, 2015</date>, and available to the Director of OMB for use in accordance with paragraph (2), not more than $500,000,000 from amounts in the Fund on <date date="2015-11-02">November 2, 2015</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce0fc128-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> there are appropriated from the Fund after <date date="2015-11-02">November 2, 2015</date>, and available to the Director of OMB for use in accordance with such paragraph, not more than 10 percent of the amounts deposited in the Fund after <date date="2015-11-02">November 2, 2015</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc129-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of amounts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc12a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director of OMB may use amounts made available under paragraph (1) to make payments requested by Federal entities for research and development, engineering studies, economic analyses, activities with respect to systems, or other planning activities intended to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the spectrum use of Federal entities in order to make available frequencies described in subparagraph (C) for reallocation for non-Federal use or shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof, and for auction in accordance with such reallocation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc12b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Systems that improve efficiency and effectiveness of Federal spectrum use</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of a payment under subparagraph (A) for activities with respect to systems that improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the spectrum use of Federal entities, such systems include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc12c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Systems that have increased functionality or that increase the ability of a Federal entity to accommodate spectrum sharing with non-Federal entities.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc12d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Systems that consolidate functions or services that have been provided using separate systems.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc12e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Non-spectrum technology or systems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc12f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Frequencies described</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The frequencies described in this subparagraph are, with respect to a payment under subparagraph (A), frequencies that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc130-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are assigned to a Federal entity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc131-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> at the time of the activities conducted with such payment, are not identified for auction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc132-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director of OMB may not make a payment to a Federal entity under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc133-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> unless—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc134-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the Federal entity has submitted to the Technical Panel established under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/h/3">section 923(h)(3) of this title</ref> a plan describing the activities that the Federal entity will conduct with such payment;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc135-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the Technical Panel has approved such plan under subparagraph (E); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc136-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/D/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the Director of OMB has submitted the plan approved under subparagraph (E) to the congressional committees described in subsection (d)(2)(C); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce0fc137-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> until 60 days have elapsed after submission of the plan under clause (i)(III).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc138-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Review by technical panel</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc139-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than 120 days after a Federal entity submits a plan under subparagraph (D)(i)(I) to the Technical Panel established under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/h/3">section 923(h)(3) of this title</ref>, the Technical Panel shall approve or disapprove such plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idce0fc13a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria for review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In considering whether to approve or disapprove a plan under this subparagraph, the Technical Panel shall consider whether—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce0fc13b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> the activities that the Federal entity will conduct with the payment will—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idce0fc13c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> increase the probability of relocation from or sharing of Federal spectrum;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idce0fc13d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> facilitate an auction intended to occur not later than 8 years after the payment; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idce0fc13e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E/ii/I/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> increase the net expected auction proceeds in an amount not less than the time value of the amount of the payment; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idce120a2f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/g/2/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the transfer will leave sufficient amounts in the Fund for the other purposes of the Fund.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a30-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Prioritization of payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining whether to make payments under subsections (f) and (g), the Director of OMB shall, to the extent practicable, prioritize payments under subsection (g).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a31-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on use of Funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No amounts in the Fund on the day before <date date="2012-02-22">February 22, 2012</date>, may be used for any purpose except—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a32-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to pay the relocation or sharing costs incurred by eligible Federal entities in order to relocate from the frequencies the auction of which generated such amounts; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a33-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s928/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to pay relocation or sharing costs related to pre-auction estimates or research, in accordance with subsection (d)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idce120a34-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/538/tI/s118">Pub. L. 102–538, title I, § 118</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/108/494/tII/s204">Pub. L. 108–494, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3994">118 Stat. 3994</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/8/dG/tI/s1301/a">Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/829">123 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/tVI/s6702">Pub. L. 112–96, title VI, § 6702</ref>, <date date="2012-02-22">Feb. 22, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/252">126 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tX/s1005/a">Pub. L. 114–74, title X, § 1005(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/622">129 Stat. 622</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dP/tVI">Pub. L. 115–141, div. P, title VI</ref>, §§ 612, 613, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1109">132 Stat. 1109</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idce120a35-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idce120a36-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idce120a37-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(3)(B)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s612">Pub. L. 115–141, § 612</ref>, substituted “8 years” for “5 years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(D), (E). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s613">Pub. L. 115–141, § 613</ref>, added subpars. (D) and (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/74">Pub. L. 114–74</ref> added subsecs. (g) and (h) and redesignated former subsec. (g) as (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/1">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(1)</ref>, substituted “relocation or sharing costs” for “relocation costs” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/2">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The amounts in the Fund from auctions of eligible frequencies are authorized to be used to pay relocation or sharing costs, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/g/3">section 923(g)(3) of this title</ref>, of an eligible Federal entity incurring such costs with respect to relocation from those frequencies.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/3/A/iv">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(3)(A)(iv)</ref>, added subpar. (A). Former subpar. (A) redesignated (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/3/A/i">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(3)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “or sharing” before the semicolon.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/3/A/iii">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(3)(A)(iii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (A) as (B). Former subpar. (B) redesignated (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “or sharing” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/3/A/iii">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(3)(A)(iii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (B) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/3/B">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(3)(B)</ref>, (C), added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Any auction proceeds in the Fund that are remaining after the payment of the relocation or sharing costs that are payable from the Fund shall revert to and be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury not later than 8 years after the date of the deposit of such proceeds to the Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/3/C">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(3)(C)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/4/A/i">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(4)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “subsection (d)(2)(B)” for “subsection (d)(2)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/4/A/ii">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(4)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “subsection (d)(2)(C)” for “subsection (d)(2)(B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/4/B">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “relocation of the entity or implementation of the sharing arrangement by the entity” for “entity’s relocation” and “subsection (d)(2)(B)” for “subsection (d)(2)(A)” and inserted “or the implementation of such arrangement” after “such relocation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/112/96/s6702/5">Pub. L. 112–96, § 6702(5)</ref>, added subsecs. (f) and (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (e)(1)(B)(ii) to (iv). <ref href="/us/pl/111/8">Pub. L. 111–8</ref> inserted “and” after semicolon in cl. (ii), substituted period for “; and” in cl. (iii), and struck out cl. (iv) which read as follows: “the Comptroller General shall, within 30 days after receiving such plan, review such plan and submit to such committees an assessment of the explanation for the subsequent transfer or transfers.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idce120a38-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce120a39-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/494/tII/s207">Pub. L. 108–494, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="2004-12-23">Dec. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3996">118 Stat. 3996</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/494/tII/s207">
<inline>“The National Telecommunications and Information Administration shall submit an annual report to the Committees on Appropriations and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committees on Appropriations and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Comptroller General on—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the progress made in adhering to the timelines applicable to relocation from eligible frequencies required under [former] section 118(d)(2)(A) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act [now <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s928/d/2/B">47 U.S.C. 928(d)(2)(B)</ref>], separately stated on a communication system-by-system basis and on an auction-by-auction basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> with respect to each relocated communication system and auction, a statement of the estimate of relocation costs required under section 113(g)(4) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s923/g/4">47 U.S.C. 923(g)(4)</ref>], the actual relocations costs incurred, and the amount of such costs paid from the Spectrum Relocation Fund.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
