<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idce120a3f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941"><num value="941">§ 941.</num><heading> Child-friendly second-level Internet domain</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a40-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The NTIA shall require the registry selected to operate and maintain the United States country code Internet domain to establish, operate, and maintain a second-level domain within the United States country code domain that provides access only to material that is suitable for minors and not harmful to minors (in this section referred to as the “new domain”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a41-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions of contracts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a42-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial registry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The NTIA shall not exercise any option periods under any contract between the NTIA and the initial registry to operate and maintain the United States country code Internet domain unless the initial registry agrees, during the 90-day period beginning upon <date date="2002-12-04">December 4, 2002</date>, to carry out, and to operate the new domain in accordance with, the requirements under subsection (c). Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent the initial registry of the United States country code Internet domain from participating in the NTIA’s process for selecting a successor registry or to prevent the NTIA from awarding, to the initial registry, the contract to be successor registry subject to the requirements of paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a43-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Successor registries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The NTIA shall not enter into any contract for operating and maintaining the United States country code Internet domain with any successor registry unless such registry enters into an agreement with the NTIA, during the 90-day period after selection of such registry, that provides for the registry to carry out, and the new domain to operate in accordance with, the requirements under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a44-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements of new domain</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The registry and new domain shall be subject to the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a45-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Written content standards for the new domain, except that the NTIA shall not have any authority to establish such standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a46-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Written agreements with each registrar for the new domain that require that use of the new domain is in accordance with the standards and requirements of the registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a47-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Written agreements with registrars, which shall require registrars to enter into written agreements with registrants, to use the new domain in accordance with the standards and requirements of the registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a48-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Rules and procedures for enforcement and oversight that minimize the possibility that the new domain provides access to content that is not in accordance with the standards and requirements of the registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a49-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A process for removing from the new domain any content that is not in accordance with the standards and requirements of the registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a4a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> A process to provide registrants to the new domain with an opportunity for a prompt, expeditious, and impartial dispute resolution process regarding any material of the registrant excluded from the new domain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a4b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Continuous and uninterrupted service for the new domain during any transition to a new registry selected to operate and maintain new domain or the United States country code domain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a4c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Procedures and mechanisms to promote the accuracy of contact information submitted by registrants and retained by registrars in the new domain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a4d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Operationality of the new domain not later than one year after <date date="2002-12-04">December 4, 2002</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a4e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Written agreements with registrars, which shall require registrars to enter into written agreements with registrants, to prohibit two-way and multiuser interactive services in the new domain, unless the registrant certifies to the registrar that such service will be offered in compliance with the content standards established pursuant to paragraph (1) and is designed to reduce the risk of exploitation of minors using such two-way and multiuser interactive services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a4f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Written agreements with registrars, which shall require registrars to enter into written agreements with registrants, to prohibit hyperlinks in the new domain that take new domain users outside of the new domain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a50-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/c/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> Any other action that the NTIA considers necessary to establish, operate, or maintain the new domain in accordance with the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a51-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Option periods for initial registry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The NTIA shall grant the initial registry the option periods available under the contract between the NTIA and the initial registry to operate and maintain the United States country code Internet domain if, and may not grant such option periods unless, the NTIA finds that the initial registry has satisfactorily performed its obligations under this Act and under the contract. Nothing in this section shall preempt or alter the NTIA’s authority to terminate such contract for the operation of the United States country code Internet domain for cause or for convenience.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a52-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of registry and other entities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a53-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Only to the extent that such entities carry out functions under this section, the following entities are deemed to be interactive computer services for purposes of section 230(c) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s230/c">47 U.S.C. 230(c)</ref>):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce120a54-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The registry that operates and maintains the new domain.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce120a55-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any entity that contracts with such registry to carry out functions to ensure that content accessed through the new domain complies with the limitations applicable to the new domain.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce120a56-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any registrar for the registry of the new domain that is operating in compliance with its agreement with the registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a57-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings provision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to affect the applicability of any other provision of title II of the Communications Act of 1934 [<ref href="/us/usc/t47/s201">47 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.] to the entities covered by subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a58-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Education</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The NTIA shall carry out a program to publicize the availability of the new domain and to educate the parents of minors regarding the process for utilizing the new domain in combination and coordination with hardware and software technologies that provide for filtering or blocking. The program under this subsection shall be commenced not later than 30 days after the date that the new domain first becomes operational and accessible by the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a59-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with Federal Government</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The registry selected to operate and maintain the new domain shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a5a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consult with appropriate agencies of the Federal Government regarding procedures and actions to prevent minors and families who use the new domain from being targeted by adults and other children for predatory behavior, exploitation, or illegal actions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idce120a5b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> based upon the consultations conducted pursuant to paragraph (1), establish such procedures and take such actions as the registry may deem necessary to prevent such targeting.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The consultations, procedures, and actions required under this subsection shall be commenced not later than 30 days after the date that the new domain first becomes operational and accessible by the public.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a5c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The registry shall prepare, on an annual basis, a report on the registry’s monitoring and enforcement procedures for the new domain. The registry shall submit each such report, setting forth the results of the review of its monitoring and enforcement procedures for the new domain, to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a5d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of new domain</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the NTIA finds, pursuant to its own review or upon a good faith petition by the registry, that the new domain is not serving its intended purpose, the NTIA shall instruct the registry to suspend operation of the new domain until such time as the NTIA determines that the new domain can be operated as intended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a5e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce120a5f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Harmful to minors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “harmful to minors” means, with respect to material, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce120a60-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the average person, applying contemporary community standards, would find, taking the material as a whole and with respect to minors, that it is designed to appeal to, or is designed to pander to, the prurient interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce120a61-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the material depicts, describes, or represents, in a manner patently offensive with respect to minors, an actual or simulated sexual act or sexual contact, an actual or simulated normal or perverted sexual act, or a lewd exhibition of the genitals or post-pubescent female breast; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce147b62-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> taken as a whole, the material lacks serious, literary, artistic, political, or scientific value for minors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce147b63-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Minor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “minor” means any person under 13 years of age.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce147b64-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Registry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “registry” means the registry selected to operate and maintain the United States country code Internet domain.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce147b65-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Successor registry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “successor registry” means any entity that enters into a contract with the NTIA to operate and maintain the United States country code Internet domain that covers any period after the termination or expiration of the contract to operate and maintain the United States country code Internet domain, and any option periods under such contract, that was signed on <date date="2001-10-26">October 26, 2001</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idce147b66-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Suitable for minors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “suitable for minors” means, with respect to material, that it—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce147b67-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is not psychologically or intellectually inappropriate for minors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idce147b68-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> serves—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce147b69-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the educational, informational, intellectual, or cognitive needs of minors; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idce147b6a-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8" identifier="/us/usc/t47/s941/j/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the social, emotional, or entertainment needs of minors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idce147b6b-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/538/tI/s157">Pub. L. 102–538, title I, § 157</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/317/s4">Pub. L. 107–317, § 4</ref>, <date date="2002-12-04">Dec. 4, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2767">116 Stat. 2767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idce147b6c-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idce147b6d-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idce147b6e-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/102/538">Pub. L. 102–538</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3533">106 Stat. 3533</ref>, known as the Telecommunications Authorization Act of 1992. Title I of the Act, known as the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act, is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Communications Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (e)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch652">act June 19, 1934, ch. 652</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1064">48 Stat. 1064</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 201 et seq.) of chapter 5 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s609">section 609 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idce147b6f-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idce147b70-7553-11f1-8811-da7bbbed8cd8"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings and Purposes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/317/s2">Pub. L. 107–317, § 2</ref>, <date date="2002-12-04">Dec. 4, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2766">116 Stat. 2766</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/317/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the World Wide Web presents a stimulating and entertaining opportunity for children to learn, grow, and develop educationally and intellectually;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Internet technology also makes available an extensive amount of information that is harmful to children, as studies indicate that a significant portion of all material available on the Internet is related to pornography;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> young children, when trying to use the World Wide Web for positive purposes, are often presented—either mistakenly or intentionally—with material that is inappropriate for their age, which can be extremely frustrating for children, parents, and educators;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> exposure of children to material that is inappropriate for them, including pornography, can distort the education and development of the Nation’s youth and represents a serious harm to American families that can lead to a host of other problems for children, including inappropriate use of chat rooms, physical molestation, harassment, and legal and financial difficulties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> young boys and girls, older teens, troubled youth, frequent Internet users, chat room participants, online risk takers, and those who communicate online with strangers are at greater risk for receiving unwanted sexual solicitation on the Internet;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> studies have shown that 19 percent of youth (ages 10 to 17) who used the Internet regularly were the targets of unwanted sexual solicitation, but less than 10 percent of the solicitations were reported to the police;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> children who come across illegal content should report it to the congressionally authorized CyberTipline, an online mechanism developed by the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, for citizens to report sexual crimes against children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> the CyberTipline has received more than 64,400 reports, including reports of child pornography, online enticement for sexual acts, child molestation (outside the family), and child prostitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> although the computer software and hardware industries, and other related industries, have developed innovative ways to help parents and educators restrict material that is harmful to minors through parental control protections and self-regulation, to date such efforts have not provided a national solution to the problem of minors accessing harmful material on the World Wide Web;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> the creation of a ‘green-light’ area within the United States country code Internet domain, that will contain only content that is appropriate for children under the age of 13, is analogous to the creation of a children’s section within a library and will promote the positive experiences of children and families in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> while custody, care, and nurture of the child reside first with the parent, the protection of the physical and psychological well-being of minors by shielding them from material that is harmful to them is a compelling governmental interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of this Act [see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>] are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to facilitate the creation of a second-level domain within the United States country code Internet domain for the location of material that is suitable for minors and not harmful to minors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to ensure that the National Telecommunications and Information Administration oversees the creation of such a second-level domain and ensures the effective and efficient establishment and operation of the new domain.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
