<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id128bd9b6-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s110"><num value="110">§ 110.</num><heading> Same; definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in sections 105–109 of this title—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128bd9b7-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s110/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The term “person” shall have the meaning assigned to it in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3797">section 3797 of title 26</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128bd9b8-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s110/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The term “sales or use tax” means any tax levied on, with respect to, or measured by, sales, receipts from sales, purchases, storage, or use of tangible personal property, except a tax with respect to which the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t4/s104">section 104 of this title</ref> are applicable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128bd9b9-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s110/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The term “income tax” means any tax levied on, with respect to, or measured by, net income, gross income, or gross receipts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128bd9ba-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s110/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The term “State” includes any Territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128bd9bb-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s110/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The term “Federal area” means any lands or premises held or acquired by or for the use of the United States or any department, establishment, or agency, of the United States; and any Federal area, or any part thereof, which is located within the exterior boundaries of any State, shall be deemed to be a Federal area located within such State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id128bd9bc-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-30/ch389">July 30, 1947, ch. 389</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/645">61 Stat. 645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id128bd9bd-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id128bd9be-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id128bd9bf-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3797">Section 3797 of title 26</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a), is a reference to section 3797 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, which was repealed by section 7851 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, Title 26, and is covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7701/a/1">section 7701(a)(1) of Title 26</ref>. The Internal Revenue Code of 1954 was redesignated the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>. For table of comparisons of the 1939 Code to the 1986 Code, see Table I preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code. See also <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7852/b">section 7852(b) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, for provision that references in any other law to a provision of the 1939 Code, unless expressly incompatible with the intent thereof, shall be deemed a reference to the corresponding provision of the 1986 Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
