<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id128e231b-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119"><num value="119">§ 119.</num><heading> Electronic databases for nationwide standard numeric jurisdictional codes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128e231c-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Electronic Database.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id128e231d-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provision of database</inline>.—</heading><content>A State may provide an electronic database to a home service provider or, if a State does not provide such an electronic database to home service providers, then the designated database provider may provide an electronic database to a home service provider.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id128e231e-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Format</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id128e231f-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Such electronic database, whether provided by the State or the designated database provider, shall be provided in a format approved by the American National Standards Institute’s Accredited Standards Committee X12, that, allowing for de minimis deviations, designates for each street address in the State, including to the extent practicable, any multiple postal street addresses applicable to one street location, the appropriate taxing jurisdictions, and the appropriate code for each taxing jurisdiction, for each level of taxing jurisdiction, identified by one nationwide standard numeric code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id128e2320-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such electronic database shall also provide the appropriate code for each street address with respect to political subdivisions which are not taxing jurisdictions when reasonably needed to determine the proper taxing jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id128e2321-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The nationwide standard numeric codes shall contain the same number of numeric digits with each digit or combination of digits referring to the same level of taxing jurisdiction throughout the United States using a format similar to FIPS 55–3 or other appropriate standard approved by the Federation of Tax Administrators and the Multistate Tax Commission, or their successors. Each address shall be provided in standard postal format.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128e2322-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice; Updates</inline>.—</heading><content>A State or designated database provider that provides or maintains an electronic database described in subsection (a) shall provide notice of the availability of the then current electronic database, and any subsequent revisions thereof, by publication in the manner normally employed for the publication of informational tax, charge, or fee notices to taxpayers in such State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id128e2323-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c" identifier="/us/usc/t4/s119/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">User Held Harmless</inline>.—</heading><content>A home service provider using the data contained in an electronic database described in subsection (a) shall be held harmless from any tax, charge, or fee liability that otherwise would be due solely as a result of any error or omission in such database provided by a State or designated database provider. The home service provider shall reflect changes made to such database during a calendar quarter not later than 30 days after the end of such calendar quarter for each State that issues notice of the availability of an electronic database reflecting such changes under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id128e2324-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/252/s2/a">Pub. L. 106–252, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-07-28">July 28, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/627">114 Stat. 627</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id128e2325-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id128e2326-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id128e2327-f87d-11ef-b94d-97e317d2120c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Application of Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="2000-07-28">July 28, 2000</date>, and applicable only to customer bills issued after the first day of the first month beginning more than 2 years after <date date="2000-07-28">July 28, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/252/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 106–252</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t4/s116">section 116 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
