<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4ca31205-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159"><num value="10159">§ 10159.</num><heading> Law enforcement training programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31206-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “certified training program or course” means a program or course using 1 or more of the training curricula developed or identified under section 10381(n)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002005"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title, or equivalents to such training curricula—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4ca31207-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that is provided by the Attorney General under section 10381(n)(3) <sup>1</sup> of this title; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4ca31208-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> that is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31209-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provided by a public or private entity, including the personnel of a law enforcement agency or law enforcement training academy of a State or unit of local government who have been trained to offer training programs or courses under section 10381(n)(3) <sup>1</sup> of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3120a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> certified by the Attorney General under section 10381(n)(2) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3120b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3120c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the Attorney General completes the activities required by paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 10381(n) <sup>1</sup> of this title, the Attorney General shall, from amounts made available to fund training programs pursuant to subsection (h), make grants to States for use by the State or a unit of government located in the State to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3120d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> pay for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca3120e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> costs associated with conducting a certified training program or course or, subject to paragraph (2), a certified training program or course that provides continuing education; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca3120f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> attendance by law enforcement officers or covered mental health professionals at a certified training program or course, including a course provided by a law enforcement training academy of a State or unit of local government;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31210-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> procure a certified training program or course or, subject to paragraph (2), a certified training program or course that provides continuing education on 1 or more of the topics described in section 10381(n)(1)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31211-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the case of a law enforcement agency of a unit of local government that employs fewer than 50 employees (determined on a full-time equivalent basis), pay for the costs of overtime accrued as a result of the attendance of a law enforcement officer or covered mental health professional at a certified training program or course for which the costs associated with conducting the certified training program or course are paid using amounts provided under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31212-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> pay for the costs of developing mechanisms to comply with the reporting requirements established under subsection (d), in an amount not to exceed 5 percent of the total amount of the grant award; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31213-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> pay for the costs associated with participation in the voluntary National Use-of-Force Data Collection of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, in an amount not to exceed 5 percent of the total amount of the grant award, if a law enforcement agency of the State or unit of local government is not already reporting to the National Use-of-Force Data Collection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31214-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for use for continuing education</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31215-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “covered topic” means a topic covered under the curricula developed or identified under clause (i), (ii), or (iv) of section 10381(n)(1)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31216-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement to provide initial training</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State or unit of local government shall ensure that all officers who have been employed with the State or unit of local government for at least 2 years have received training as part of a certified training program or course on all covered topics before the State or unit of local government uses amounts received under a grant under paragraph (1) for continuing education with respect to any covered topic.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31217-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Start date of availability of funding</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31218-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/2/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), a State or unit of local government may not use amounts received under a grant under paragraph (1) for continuing education with respect to a covered topic until the date that is 2 years after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31219-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A State or unit of local government may use amounts received under a grant under paragraph (1) for continuing education with respect to a covered topic during the 2-year period beginning on <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, if the State or unit of local government has complied with subparagraph (B) using amounts available to the State or unit of local government other than amounts received under a grant under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3121a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintaining relationships with local mental health organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State or unit of local government that receives funds under this section shall establish and maintain relationships between law enforcement officers and local mental health organizations and health care services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3121b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3121c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Of the total amount appropriated to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Attorney General shall allocate funds to each State in proportion to the total number of law enforcement officers in the State that are employed by the State or a unit of local government within the State, as compared to the total number of law enforcement officers in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3121d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Retention of funds for training for State law enforcement officers proportional to number of State officers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each fiscal year, each State may retain, for use for the purposes described in this section, from the total amount of funds provided to the State under paragraph (1) an amount that is not more than the amount that bears the same ratio to such total amount as the ratio of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3121e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the total number of law enforcement officers employed by the State; to</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3121f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the total number of law enforcement officers in the State that are employed by the State or a unit of local government within the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31220-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of funds for training for local law enforcement officers</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31221-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State shall make available to units of local government in the State for the purposes described in this section the amounts remaining after a State retains funds under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31222-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional uses</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State may, with the approval of a unit of local government, use the funds allocated to the unit of local government under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31223-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to facilitate offering a certified training program or course or, subject to subsection (b)(2), a certified training program or course that provide <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002006"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “provides”.</note> continuing education in 1 or more of the topics described in section 10381(n)(1)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title to law enforcement officers employed by the unit of local government; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31224-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for the costs of training local law enforcement officers, including through law enforcement training academies of States and units of local government, to conduct a certified training program or course.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31225-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Attorney General, in consultation with relevant law enforcement agencies of States and units of local government, associations that represent individuals with mental or behavioral health diagnoses or individuals with disabilities, labor organizations, professional law enforcement organizations, local law enforcement labor and representative organizations, law enforcement trade associations, mental health and suicide prevention organizations, family advocacy organizations, and civil rights and civil liberties groups, shall develop criteria governing the allocation of funds to units of local government under this paragraph, which shall ensure that the funds are distributed as widely as practicable in terms of geographical location and to both large and small law enforcement agencies of units of local government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31226-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/c/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Announcement of allocations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after the date on which a State receives an award under paragraph (1), the State shall announce the allocations of funds to units of local government under subparagraph (A). A State shall submit to the Attorney General a report explaining any delays in the announcement of allocations under this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31227-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31228-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Units of local government</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any unit of local government that receives funds from a State under subsection (c)(3) for a certified training program or course shall submit to the State or the Attorney General an annual report with respect to the first fiscal year during which the unit of local government receives such funds and each of the 2 fiscal years thereafter that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31229-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall include the number of law enforcement officers employed by the unit of local government that have completed a certified training program or course, including a certified training program or course provided on or before the date on which the Attorney General begins certifying training programs and courses under section 10381(n)(2) <sup>1</sup> of this title, the topics covered in those courses, and the number of officers who received training in each topic;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3122a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may, at the election of the unit of local government, include the number of law enforcement officers employed by the unit of local government that have completed a certified training program or course using funds provided from a source other than the grants described under subsection (b), the topics covered in those courses, and the number of officers who received training in each topic;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3122b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall include the total number of law enforcement officers employed by the unit of local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3122c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> shall include a description of any barriers to providing training on the topics described in section 10381(n)(1)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3122d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> shall include information gathered through—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca3122e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> pre-training and post-training tests that assess relevant knowledge and skills covered in the training curricula, as specified in section 10381(n)(1) <sup>1</sup> of this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca3122f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> follow-up evaluative assessments to determine the degree to which participants in the training apply, in their jobs, the knowledge and skills gained in the training; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31230-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> shall include the amount of funds received by the unit of local government under subsection (c)(3) and a tentative plan for training all law enforcement officers employed by the unit of local government using available and anticipated funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31231-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> States</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State receiving funds under this section shall submit to the Attorney General—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31232-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any report the State receives from a unit of local government under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31233-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> if the State retains funds under subsection (c)(2) for a fiscal year, a report by the State for that fiscal year, and each of the 2 fiscal years thereafter—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31234-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> indicating the number of law enforcement officers employed by the State that have completed a certified training program or course, including a certified training program or course provided on or before the date on which the Attorney General begins certifying training programs or courses under section 10381(n)(2) <sup>1</sup> of this title, the topics covered in those courses, and the number of officers who received training in each topic, including, at the election of the State, a certified training program or course using funds provided from a source other than the grants described under subsection (b);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31235-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> indicating the total number of law enforcement officers employed by the State;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31236-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> providing information gathered through—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4ca31237-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> pre-training and post-training tests that assess relevant knowledge and skills covered in the training curricula, as specified in section 10381(n)(1) <sup>1</sup> of this title; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4ca31238-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> follow-up evaluative assessments to determine the degree to which participants in the training apply, in their jobs, the knowledge and skills gained in the training;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31239-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> discussing any barriers to providing training on the topics described in section 10381(n)(1)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca3123a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> indicating the amount of funding retained by the State under subsection (c)(2) and providing a tentative plan for training all law enforcement officers employed by the State using available and anticipated funds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3123b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting tools</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, the Attorney General shall develop a portal through which the data required under paragraphs (1) and (2) may be collected and submitted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3123c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports on the use of de-escalation tactics and other techniques</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3123d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, relevant law enforcement agencies of States and units of local government, associations that represent individuals with mental or behavioral health diagnoses or individuals with disabilities, labor organizations, professional law enforcement organizations, local law enforcement labor and representative organizations, law enforcement trade associations, mental health and suicide prevention organizations, family advocacy organizations, and civil rights and civil liberties groups, shall establish—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca3123e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> reporting requirements on interactions in which de-escalation tactics and other techniques in curricula developed or identified under section 10381(n)(1) <sup>1</sup> of this title are used by each law enforcement agency that receives funding under this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca3123f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> mechanisms for each law enforcement agency to submit such reports to the Department of Justice.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31240-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The requirements developed under subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31241-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> specify—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4ca31242-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> the circumstances under which an interaction shall be reported, considering—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id4ca31243-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/i/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the cost of collecting and reporting the information; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id4ca31244-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/i/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><chapeau> the value of that information for determining whether—</chapeau><subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="id4ca31245-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/i/I/bb/AA"><num value="AA">(AA)</num><content> the objectives of the training have been met; and</content>
</subitem>
<subitem style="-uslm-lc:I02" class="indent6" id="id4ca31246-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/i/I/bb/BB"><num value="BB">(BB)</num><content> the training reduced or eliminated the risk of serious physical injury to officers, subjects, and third parties; and</content>
</subitem>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4ca31247-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the demographic and other relevant information about the officer and subjects involved in the interaction that shall be included in such a report; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4ca31248-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> require such reporting be done in a manner that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4ca31249-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is in compliance with all applicable Federal and State confidentiality laws; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4ca3124a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> does not disclose the identities of law enforcement officers, subjects, or third parties.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3124b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of reporting requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the entities specified under subparagraph (A), shall review and consider updates to the reporting requirements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3124c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to report</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3124d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An entity receiving funds under this section that fails to file a report as required under paragraph (1) or (2), as applicable and as determined by the Attorney General, shall not be eligible to receive funds under this section for a period of 2 fiscal years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3124e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/d/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to prohibit a State that fails to file a report as required under paragraph (2), and is not eligible to receive funds under this section, from making funding available to a unit of local government of the State under subsection (c)(3), if the unit of local government has complied with the reporting requirements.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3124f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Attorney General reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31250-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2022-12-27">December 27, 2022</date>, and each year thereafter in which grants are made under this section, the Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress on the implementation of activities carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31251-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, information on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31252-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the number, amounts, and recipients of awards the Attorney General has made or intends to make using funds authorized under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31253-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the selection criteria the Attorney General has used or intends to use to select recipients of awards using funds authorized under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31254-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the number of law enforcement officers of a State or unit of local government who were not able to receive training on the topics described in section 10381(n)(1)(A) <sup>1</sup> of this title due to unavailability of funds and the amount of funds that would be required to complete the training; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31255-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the nature, frequency, and amount of information that the Attorney General has collected or intends to collect under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31256-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Privacy protections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A report under paragraph (1) shall not disclose the identities of individual law enforcement officers who received, or did not receive, training under a certified training program or course.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31257-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> National Institute of Justice study</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31258-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Study and report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after the first grant award using funds authorized under this section, the National Institute of Justice shall conduct a study of the implementation of training under a certified training program or course in at least 6 jurisdictions representing an array of agency sizes and geographic locations, which shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31259-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a process evaluation of training implementation, which shall include an analysis of the share of officers who participated in the training, the degree to which the training was administered in accordance with the curriculum, and the fidelity with which the training was applied in the field; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca3125a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an impact evaluation of the training, which shall include an analysis of the impact of the training on interactions between law enforcement officers and the public, any factors that prevent or preclude law enforcement officers from successfully de-escalating law enforcement interactions, and any recommendations on modifications to the training curricula and methods that could improve outcomes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3125b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> National Institute of Justice access to portal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purposes of preparing the report under paragraph (1), the National Institute of Justice shall have direct access to the portal developed under subsection (d)(3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3125c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Privacy protections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The study under paragraph (1) shall not disclose the identities of individual law enforcement officers who received, or did not receive, training under a certified training program or course.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3125d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not more than 1 percent of the amount appropriated to carry out this section during any fiscal year shall be made available to conduct the study under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3125e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> GAO report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca3125f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Study and report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 3 years after the first grant award using funds authorized under this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall review the grant program under this section and submit to Congress a report assessing the grant program, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31260-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the process for developing and identifying curricula under section 10381(n)(1) <sup>1</sup> of this title, including the effectiveness of the consultation by the Attorney General with the agencies, associations, and organizations identified under section 10381(n)(1)(C) <sup>1</sup> of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31261-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the certification of training programs and courses under section 10381(n)(2) <sup>1</sup> of this title, including the development of the process for certification and its implementation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31262-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the training of law enforcement personnel under section 10381(n)(3) <sup>1</sup> of this title, including the geographic distribution of the agencies that employ the personnel receiving the training and the sizes of those agencies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31263-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the allocation of funds under subsection (c), including the geographic distribution of the agencies that receive funds and the degree to which both large and small agencies receive funds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4ca31264-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the amount of funding distributed to agencies compared with the amount appropriated under this section, the amount spent for training, and whether plans have been put in place by the recipient agencies to use unspent available funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31265-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> GAO access to portal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purposes of preparing the report under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall have direct access to the portal developed under subsection (d)(3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4ca31266-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4ca31267-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2025; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4ca31268-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10159/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4ca31269-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/351/tI/s508">Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 508</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/117/325/s2/c/2">Pub. L. 117–325, § 2(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4444">136 Stat. 4444</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4ca3126a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4ca3126b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4ca3126c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10381/n">Section 10381(n) of this title</ref>, referred to in text, was redesignated section 10381(<i>o</i>) of this title by <ref href="/us/pl/118/64/s3">Pub. L. 118–64, § 3</ref>, <date date="2024-05-24">May 24, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1435">138 Stat. 1435</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id4ca3126d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/90/351/s508">section 508 of Pub. L. 90–351</ref> was renumbered section 509 and had been classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3758">section 3758 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to being omitted from the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/90/351/s508">section 508 of Pub. L. 90–351</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVI/s6091/a">Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6091(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4335">102 Stat. 4335</ref>, related to distribution of grants to local government, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/109/162/tXI/s1111/a/1">Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1111(a)(1)</ref>, (d), <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3094">119 Stat. 3094</ref>, 3102, applicable with respect to the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, and each fiscal year thereafter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
