<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4cb89510-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10287"><num value="10287">§ 10287.</num><heading> Funds available for appeals and expenses of representation of hearing examiners</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On and after <date date="2007-12-26">December 26, 2007</date>, funds available to conduct appeals under section 1205(c) of the 1968 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10285/c">34 U.S.C. 10285(c)</ref>], which includes all claims processing, shall be available also for the same under subpart 2 of such part L [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10301">34 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.] and under any statute authorizing payment of benefits described under subpart 1 [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10281">34 U.S.C. 10281</ref> et seq.] thereof, and for appeals from final determinations of the Bureau (under such part or any such statute) to the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, which shall have exclusive jurisdiction thereof, and for expenses of representation of hearing examiners (who shall be presumed irrebuttably to enjoy quasi-judicial immunity in the discharge of their duties under such part or any such statute) in connection with litigation against them arising from such discharge: <i>Provided further</i>, That, on and after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>, as to each such statute—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cb89511-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10287/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the provisions of section 1001(a)(4) of such title I (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3793/a/4">42 U.S.C. 3793(a)(4)</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002022">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002022"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> shall apply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cb89512-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10287/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> payment (consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10286">section 10286 of this title</ref>) shall be made only upon a determination by the Bureau that the facts legally warrant the payment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cb89513-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10287/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any reference to section 1202 of such title I [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10282">34 U.S.C. 10282</ref>] shall be deemed to be a reference to paragraphs (2) and (3) of such section 1202:</content>
</paragraph>

<proviso style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0"><i>Provided further</i>, That, on and after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>, no appeal shall bring any final determination of the Bureau before any court for review unless notice of appeal is filed (within the time specified herein and in the manner prescribed for appeal to United States courts of appeals from United States district courts) not later than 90 days after the date on which the Bureau serves notice of the final determination: <i>Provided further</i>, That any regulations promulgated by the Bureau under such part (or any such statute) before, on, or after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>, shall apply to any matter pending on, or filed or accruing after, the effective date specified in the regulations.</proviso>
<sourceCredit id="id4cb89514-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dB/tII">Pub. L. 110–161, div. B, title II</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1912">121 Stat. 1912</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tX/s1086/c">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1086(c)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1968">126 Stat. 1968</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4cb89515-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4cb89516-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4cb89517-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The 1968 Act, referred to in text, is the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, <ref href="/us/pl/90/351">Pub. L. 90–351</ref>, <date date="1968-06-19">June 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/197">82 Stat. 197</ref>. Section 1205(c) of the Act is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10285/c">section 10285(c) of this title</ref>. Subparts 1 and 2 of such part L means subparts 1 and 2 of part L of title I of the Act which are classified generally to this part and part B (§ 10301 et seq.) of this subchapter. Sections 1001(a)(4) and 1202 of such title I mean sections 1001(a)(4) and 1202 of title I of the Act, which are classified to sections 10261(a)(4) and 10282, respectively, of this title. Paragraphs (2) and (3) of such section 1202 mean pars. (2) and (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10282">section 10282 of this title</ref>, which were redesignated subsec. (a)(2) and (3), respectively, of that section by <ref href="/us/pl/115/36/s5/1">Pub. L. 115–36, § 5(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-06-02">June 2, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/852">131 Stat. 852</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1968 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4cb89518-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2008, and also as part of the Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008, and the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008, and not as part of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3796c–2">section 3796c–2 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4cb89519-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—<ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> substituted “final determinations” for “final decisions”, struck out “(including those, and any related matters, pending)” after “exclusive jurisdiction thereof”, and inserted three provisos at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4cb8951a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4cb8951b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> effective <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, and applicable to matters pending on <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, or filed or accruing after that date, with certain exceptions, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1086/d">section 1086(d) of Pub. L. 112–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10251">section 10251 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
