<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4cb895b3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10333"><num value="10333">§ 10333.</num><heading> Applications to receive grants</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To request a grant under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10332">section 10332 of this title</ref>, the chief executive officer of a State or unit of local government shall submit to the Director an application at such time and in such form as the Director may require. Such application shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cb895b4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10333/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a certification that Federal funds made available under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10332">section 10332 of this title</ref> will not be used to supplant State or local funds, but will be used to increase the amounts of such funds that would, in the absence of such funds, be made available for criminal proceedings for the violation of laws relating to the abuse of children; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cb895b5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10333/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a certification that funds required to pay the non-Federal portion of the cost of equipment and personnel training for which such grant is made shall be in addition to funds that would otherwise be made available by the recipients of grant funds for criminal proceedings for the violation of laws relating to the abuse of children.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id4cb895b6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/351/tI/s1403">Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 1403</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/647/tII/s241/a/2">Pub. L. 101–647, title II, § 241(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4810">104 Stat. 4810</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tIV/s40156/c/3">Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40156(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1923">108 Stat. 1923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4cb895b7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4cb895b8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4cb895b9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3796aa–2">section 3796aa–2 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4cb895ba-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref>, in introductory provisions inserted “or unit of local government” after “of a State”, in par. (1) inserted “and” at end, in par. (2) substituted a period for the semicolon at end, and struck out pars. (3) and (4) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) an assurance that the State application described in this section, and any amendment to such application, has been submitted for review to the State legislature or its designated body (for purposes of this section, such application or amendment shall be deemed to be reviewed if the State legislature or such body does not review such application or amendment within the 60-day period beginning on the date such application or amendment is so submitted); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) an assurance that the State application and any amendment thereto was made public before submission to the Bureau and, to the extent provided under State law or established procedure, an opportunity to comment thereon was provided to citizens and to neighborhood and community groups.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4cb895bb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id4cb895bc-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Effective <date date="2000-08-01">Aug. 1, 2000</date>, all functions of Director of Bureau of Justice Assistance, other than those enumerated in section 10142(3) to (6) of this title, transferred to Assistant Attorney General for Office of Justice Programs, see section 1000(a)(1) [title I, § 108(b)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10141">section 10141 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
