<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4cc95ed8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10471"><num value="10471">§ 10471.</num><heading> Grant authority</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make grants to States, State courts, local courts, units of local government, and Indian tribal governments, acting directly or through agreements with other public or nonprofit entities, for not more than 100 programs that involve—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cc95ed9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10471/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> continuing judicial supervision, including periodic review, over preliminarily qualified offenders with mental illness, mental retardation, or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders, who are charged with misdemeanors or nonviolent offenses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cc95eda-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10471/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> the coordinated delivery of services, which includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cc95edb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10471/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> specialized training of law enforcement and judicial personnel to identify and address the unique needs of a mentally ill or mentally retarded offender;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cc95edc-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10471/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> voluntary outpatient or inpatient mental health treatment, in the least restrictive manner appropriate, as determined by the court, that carries with it the possibility of dismissal of charges or reduced sentencing upon successful completion of treatment, or court-ordered assisted outpatient treatment when the court has determined such treatment to be necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cc95edd-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10471/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> centralized case management involving the consolidation of all of a mentally ill or mentally retarded defendant’s cases, including violations of probation, and the coordination of all mental health treatment plans and social services, including life skills training, such as housing placement, vocational training, education, job placement, health care, and relapse prevention for each participant who requires such services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cc95ede-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10471/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> continuing supervision of treatment plan compliance for a term not to exceed the maximum allowable sentence or probation for the charged or relevant offense and, to the extent practicable, continuity of psychiatric care at the end of the supervised period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id4cc95edf-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/351/tI/s2201">Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2201</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/515/s3/a">Pub. L. 106–515, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2399">114 Stat. 2399</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tXIV/s14002/a">Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title XIV, § 14002(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1288">130 Stat. 1288</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4cc95ee0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4cc95ee1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4cc95ee2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3796ii">section 3796ii of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id4cc95ee3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/90/351/tI/s2201">section 2201 of title I of Pub. L. 90–351</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tV/s50001/a/3">Pub. L. 103–322, title V, § 50001(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1956">108 Stat. 1956</ref>, related to grant authority, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)]</ref> [title I, § 114(b)(1)(A)], <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321">110 Stat. 1321</ref>, 1321–21; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior <ref href="/us/pl/90/351/s2201">section 2201 of Pub. L. 90–351</ref> was renumbered section 2601 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10541">section 10541 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4cc95ee4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Par. (2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255">Pub. L. 114–255</ref> inserted before period at end “, or court-ordered assisted outpatient treatment when the court has determined such treatment to be necessary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4cc95ee5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4cc95ee6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Federal Drug and Mental Health Courts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tXIV/s14003">Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title XIV, § 14003</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1289">130 Stat. 1289</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tXIV/s14003">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> the term ‘eligible offender’ means a person who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> previously or currently has been diagnosed by a qualified mental health professional as having a mental illness, mental retardation, or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> manifests obvious signs of mental illness, mental retardation, or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders during arrest or confinement or before any court;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> comes into contact with the criminal justice system or is arrested or charged with an offense that is not—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a crime of violence, as defined under applicable State law or in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3156">section 3156 of title 18</ref>, United States Code; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a serious drug offense, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s924/e/2/A">section 924(e)(2)(A) of title 18</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is determined by a judge to be eligible; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the term ‘mental illness’ means a diagnosable mental, behavioral, or emotional disorder—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> of sufficient duration to meet diagnostic criteria within the most recent edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders published by the American Psychiatric Association; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> that has resulted in functional impairment that substantially interferes with or limits 1 or more major life activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Program</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>], the Attorney General shall establish a pilot program to determine the effectiveness of diverting eligible offenders from Federal prosecution, Federal probation, or a Bureau of Prisons facility, and placing such eligible offenders in drug or mental health courts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Specifications</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The pilot program established under subsection (b) shall involve—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> continuing judicial supervision, including periodic review, of program participants who have a substance abuse problem or mental illness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the integrated administration of services and sanctions, which shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> mandatory periodic testing, as appropriate, for the use of controlled substances or other addictive substances during any period of supervised release or probation for each program participant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> substance abuse treatment for each program participant who requires such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> diversion, probation, or other supervised release with the possibility of prosecution, confinement, or incarceration based on noncompliance with program requirements or failure to show satisfactory progress toward completing program requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> programmatic offender management, including case management, and aftercare services, such as relapse prevention, health care, education, vocational training, job placement, housing placement, and child care or other family support services for each program participant who requires such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> outpatient or inpatient mental health treatment, as ordered by the court, that carries with it the possibility of dismissal of charges or reduced sentencing upon successful completion of such treatment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><chapeau> centralized case management, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the consolidation of all cases, including violations of probations, of the program participant; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> coordination of all mental health treatment plans and social services, including life skills and vocational training, housing and job placement, education, health care, and relapse prevention for each program participant who requires such services; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> continuing supervision of treatment plan compliance by the program participant for a term not to exceed the maximum allowable sentence or probation period for the charged or relevant offense and, to the extent practicable, continuity of psychiatric care at the end of the supervised period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation; Duration</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The pilot program established under subsection (b) shall be conducted—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in not less than 1 United States judicial district, designated by the Attorney General in consultation with the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, as appropriate for the pilot program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> during fiscal year 2017 through fiscal year 2021.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Criteria for Designation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Before making a designation under subsection (d)(1), the Attorney General shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> obtain the approval, in writing, of the United States Attorney for the United States judicial district being designated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> obtain the approval, in writing, of the chief judge for the United States judicial district being designated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> determine that the United States judicial district being designated has adequate behavioral health systems for treatment, including substance abuse and mental health treatment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance From Other Federal Entities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrative Office of the United States Courts and the United States Probation Offices shall provide such assistance and carry out such functions as the Attorney General may request in monitoring, supervising, providing services to, and evaluating eligible offenders placed in a drug or mental health court under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall monitor the drug and mental health courts under this section, and shall submit a report to Congress on the outcomes of the program at the end of the period described in subsection (d)(2).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4cc95ee7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/515/s2">Pub. L. 106–515, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2399">114 Stat. 2399</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/515/s2">
<inline>“Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> fully 16 percent of all inmates in State prisons and local jails suffer from mental illness, according to a July, 1999 report, conducted by the Bureau of Justice Statistics;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> between 600,000 and 700,000 mentally ill persons are annually booked in jail alone, according to the American Jail Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> estimates say 25 to 40 percent of America’s mentally ill will come into contact with the criminal justice system, according to National Alliance for the Mentally Ill;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> 75 percent of mentally ill inmates have been sentenced to time in prison or jail or probation at least once prior to their current sentence, according to the Bureau of Justice Statistics in July, 1999; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Broward County, Florida and King County, Washington, have created separate Mental Health Courts to place nonviolent mentally ill offenders into judicially monitored inpatient and outpatient mental health treatment programs, where appropriate, with positive results.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
