<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4cd78f2b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10653"><num value="10653">§ 10653.</num><heading> Creation of a TBI and PTSD training for first responders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cd78f2c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10653/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="2022-08-16">August 16, 2022</date>, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, in consultation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall solicit best practices regarding techniques to interact with persons who have a traumatic brain injury, an acquired brain injury, or post-traumatic stress disorder from first responder, brain injury, veteran, and mental health organizations, health care and mental health providers, hospital emergency departments, and other relevant stakeholders, and shall develop crisis intervention training tools for use by first responders (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10705">section 10705 of this title</ref>) that provide—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cd78f2d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10653/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> information on the conditions and symptoms of a traumatic brain injury, an acquired brain injury, and post-traumatic stress disorder;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cd78f2e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10653/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> techniques to interact with persons who have a traumatic brain injury, an acquired brain injury, or post-traumatic stress disorder; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cd78f2f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10653/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> information on how to recognize persons who have a traumatic brain injury, an acquired brain injury, or post-traumatic stress disorder.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cd78f30-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10653/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of training tools at Law Enforcement Mental Health Learning Sites</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall ensure that not less than one Law Enforcement Mental Health Learning Site designated by the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance uses the training tools developed under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cd78f31-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10653/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Police Mental Health Collaboration Toolkit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall make the training tools developed under subsection (a) available as part of the Police-Mental Health Collaboration Toolkit provided by the Bureau of Justice Assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4cd78f32-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/351/tI/s2993">Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2993</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/117/170/s3/2">Pub. L. 117–170, § 3(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-16">Aug. 16, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2092">136 Stat. 2092</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4cd78f33-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4cd78f34-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4cd78f35-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/170/s2">Pub. L. 117–170, § 2</ref>, <date date="2022-08-16">Aug. 16, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2091">136 Stat. 2091</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/170/s2">
<inline>“Congress finds the following:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, there were approximately 2.9 million traumatic brain injury-related emergency department visits, hospitalizations, and deaths in the United States in 2014.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Effects of traumatic brain injury (TBI) can be short-term or long-term, and include impaired thinking or memory, movement, vision or hearing, or emotional functioning, such as personality changes or depression.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Currently, between 3.2 million and 5.3 million persons are living with a TBI-related disability in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> About 7 or 8 percent of Americans will experience post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) at some point in their lives, and about 8 million adults have PTSD during the course of a given year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> TBI and PTSD have been recognized as the signature injuries of the Wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> According to the Department of Defense, 383,000 men and women deployed to Iraq and Afghanistan sustained a brain injury while in the line of duty between 2000 and 2018.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Approximately 13.5 percent of Operations Iraqi Freedom and Enduring Freedom veterans screen positive for PTSD, according to the Department of Veteran Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> About 12 percent of Gulf War Veterans have PTSD in a given year while about 30 percent of Vietnam Veterans have had PTSD in their lifetime.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> Physical signs of TBI can include motor impairment, dizziness or poor balance, slurred speech, impaired depth perception, or impaired verbal memory, while physical signs of PTSD can include agitation, irritability, hostility, hypervigilance, self-destructive behavior, fear, severe anxiety, or mistrust.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> Physical signs of TBI and PTSD often overlap with physical signs of alcohol or drug impairment, which complicate a first responder’s ability to quickly and effectively identify an individual’s condition.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
