<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4cda0092-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751"><num value="10751">§ 10751.</num><heading> Grant authorization</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cda0093-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may make grants under this subchapter to States, Indian Tribes, units of local government, and community-based nonprofit organizations for the purpose of providing clinical services for people with serious mental illness and substance use disorders that establish treatment, suicide prevention, and continuity of recovery in the community upon release from the correctional facility.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cda0094-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A grant awarded under this subchapter shall be used to support—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cda0095-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> programs involving criminal and juvenile justice agencies, mental health agencies, community-based organizations that focus on reentry, and community-based behavioral health providers that improve clinical stabilization during pre-trial detention and incarceration and continuity of care leading to recovery in the community by providing services and supports that may include peer support services, enrollment in healthcare, and introduction to long-acting injectable medications or, as clinically indicated, other medications, by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda0096-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> providing training and education for criminal and juvenile justice agencies, mental health agencies, and community-based behavioral health providers on interventions that support—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4cda0097-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> engagement in recovery supports and services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4cda0098-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> access to medication while in an incarcerated setting; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4cda0099-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> continuity of care during reentry into the community;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda009a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ensuring that individuals with serious mental illness are provided appropriate access to evidence-based recovery supports that may include peer support services, medication (including long-acting injectable medications where clinically appropriate), and psycho-social therapies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda009b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> offering technical assistance to criminal justice agencies on how to modify their administrative and clinical processes to accommodate evidence-based interventions, such as long-acting injectable medications and other recovery supports; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda009c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> participating in data collection activities specified by the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cda009d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> programs that support cooperative efforts between criminal and juvenile justice agencies, mental health agencies, and community-based behavioral health providers to establish or enhance serious mental illness recovery support by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda009e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> strengthening or establishing crisis response services delivered by hotlines, mobile crisis teams, crisis stabilization and triage centers, peer support specialists, public safety officers, community-based behavioral health providers, and other stakeholders, including by providing technical support for interventions that promote long-term recovery;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda009f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> engaging criminal and juvenile justice agencies, mental health agencies and community-based behavioral health providers, preliminary qualified offenders, and family and community members in program design, program implementation, and training on crisis response services, including connection to recovery services and supports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda00a0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> examining health care reimbursement issues that may pose a barrier to ensuring the long-term financial sustainability of crisis response services and interventions that promote long-term engagement with recovery services and supports; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cda00a1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> participating in data collection activities specified by the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cda00a2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> programs that provide training and additional resources to criminal and juvenile justice agencies, mental health agencies, and community-based behavioral health providers on serious mental illness, suicide prevention strategies, recovery engagement strategies, and the special health and social needs of justice-involved individuals who are living with serious mental illness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cda00a3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that serious mental illness treatment and recovery support services provided under this grant program incorporate evidence-based approaches that facilitate long-term engagement in recovery services and supports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cda00a4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Behavioral health provider defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “behavioral health provider” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cda00a5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a community mental health center that meets the criteria under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s300x–2/c">section 300x–2(c) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cda00a6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s10751/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a certified community behavioral health clinic described in section 223(d) of the Protecting Access to Medicare Act of 2014 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4cda00a7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/351/tI/s3051">Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 3051</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/116/281/s2/a">Pub. L. 116–281, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3381">134 Stat. 3381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4cda00a8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4cda00a9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4cda00aa-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 223(d) of the Protecting Access to Medicare Act of 2014, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/113/93/s223/d">section 223(d) of Pub. L. 113–93</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396a">section 1396a of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4cda00ab-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id4cda00ac-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of <ref href="/us/pl/116/281">Pub. L. 116–281</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, as the “Crisis Stabilization and Community Reentry Act of 2020”, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/281/s1">section 1 of Pub. L. 116–281</ref>, set out as a Short Title of 2020 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
