<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4cdebaac-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116"><num value="11116">§ 11116.</num><heading> Coordinating Council on Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cdebaad-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; membership</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebaae-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is hereby established, as an independent organization in the executive branch of the Federal Government a Coordinating Council on Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention composed of the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, the Assistant Secretary for Immigration and Customs Enforcement, such other officers of Federal agencies who hold significant decisionmaking authority as the President may designate, and individuals appointed under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebaaf-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Ten members shall be appointed, without regard to political affiliation, to the Council in accordance with this paragraph from among individuals who are practitioners in the field of juvenile justice and who are not officers or employees of the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Three members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, after consultation with the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Three members shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate, after consultation with the minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Three members shall be appointed by the President.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> One member shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate, in consultation with the Vice Chairman of that Committee and the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebab7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Of the members appointed under each of clauses (i), (ii), and (iii)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cdebab8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> 1 shall be appointed for a term of 1 year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cdebab9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> 1 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cdebaba-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/C/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> 1 shall be appointed for a term of 3 years;</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">as designated at the time of appointment.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebabb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Except as provided in clause (iii), a vacancy arising during the term for which an appointment is made may be filled only for the remainder of such term.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebabc-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/a/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> After the expiration of the term for which a member is appointed, such member may continue to serve until a successor is appointed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cdebabd-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Chairman and Vice Chairman</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall serve as Chairman of the Council. The Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention shall serve as Vice Chairman of the Council. The Vice Chairman shall act as Chairman in the absence of the Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cdebabe-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebabf-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The function of the Council shall be to coordinate all Federal juvenile delinquency programs (in cooperation with State and local juvenile justice programs) all Federal programs and activities that detain or care for unaccompanied juveniles, and all Federal programs relating to missing and exploited children. The Council shall examine how the separate programs can be coordinated among Federal, State, and local governments to better serve at-risk children and juveniles and shall make recommendations to the President, and to the Congress, at least annually with respect to the coordination of overall policy and development of objectives and priorities for all Federal juvenile delinquency programs and activities and all Federal programs and activities that detain or care for unaccompanied juveniles. The Council shall review the programs and practices of Federal agencies and report on the degree to which Federal agency funds are used for purposes which are consistent or inconsistent with the mandates of the core requirements. The Council shall review, and make recommendations with respect to, any joint funding proposal undertaken by the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention and any agency represented on the Council. The Council shall review the reasons why Federal agencies take juveniles into custody and shall make recommendations regarding how to improve Federal practices and facilities for holding juveniles in custody.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4cdebac0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In addition to performing their functions as members of the Council, the members appointed under subsection (a)(2) shall collectively, on an annual basis—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cdebac1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> make recommendations regarding the development of the objectives, priorities, and the long-term plan, and the implementation of overall policy and the strategy to carry out such plan, referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11114/a/1">section 11114(a)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4cdebac2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> not later than 120 days after the completion of the last meeting of the Council during any fiscal year, submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cdebac3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> contains the recommendations described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cdebac4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> includes a detailed account of the activities conducted by the Council during the fiscal year, including a complete detailed accounting of expenses incurred by the Council to conduct operations in accordance with this section;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cdebac5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> is published on the websites of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Council, and the Department of Justice; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cdebac6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/c/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> is in addition to the annual report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11117">section 11117 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cdebac7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Council shall meet at least quarterly.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cdebac8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of personnel or staff support by Administrator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall, with the approval of the Council, appoint such personnel or staff support as the Administrator considers necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cdebac9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Expenses of Council members; reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Members appointed under subsection (a)(2) shall serve without compensation. Members of the Council shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in carrying out the duties of the Council.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cdebaca-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s11116/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Of sums available to carry out this part, not more than $200,000 shall be available to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4cdebacb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/415/tII/s206">Pub. L. 93–415, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1116">88 Stat. 1116</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/237/s4/c/5/D">Pub. L. 94–237, § 4(c)(5)(D)</ref>, <date date="1976-03-19">Mar. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/244">90 Stat. 244</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/115/s3/a/3/A">Pub. L. 95–115, § 3(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (5), (d), <date date="1977-10-03">Oct. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1048-1050">91 Stat. 1048–1050</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/509">Pub. L. 96–509</ref>, §§ 8, 19(f), <date date="1980-12-08">Dec. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2753">94 Stat. 2753</ref>, 2763; <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s623">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 623</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2110">98 Stat. 2110</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7251(b), 7252(b)(2), 7254, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4435-4437">102 Stat. 4435–4437</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/586/s2/d">Pub. L. 102–586, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4985">106 Stat. 4985</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tIV/s405/k">Pub. L. 103–82, title IV, § 405(k)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/922">107 Stat. 922</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tII/s12206">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title II, § 12206</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1872">116 Stat. 1872</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/211/tII/s246/b">Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 246(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-29">July 29, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2296">124 Stat. 2296</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/tII/s202">Pub. L. 115–385, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5128">132 Stat. 5128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4cdebacc-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4cdebacd-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4cdebace-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5616">section 5616 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Some section numbers or references in amendment notes below reflect the classification of such sections or references prior to editorial reclassification.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4cdebacf-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/s202/1/A">Pub. L. 115–385, § 202(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, the Secretary of the Interior,” after “the Secretary of Health and Human Services,” and substituted “Assistant Secretary for Immigration and Customs Enforcement” for “Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/s202/1/B">Pub. L. 115–385, § 202(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Federal Government” for “United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/s202/2/A">Pub. L. 115–385, § 202(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “the core requirements” for “paragraphs (12)(A), (13), and (14) of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11133/a">section 11133(a) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/s202/2/B/i">Pub. L. 115–385, § 202(2)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “, on an annual basis” after “collectively” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/s202/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 115–385, § 202(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “not later than 180 days after <date date="1992-11-04">November 4, 1992</date>, submit such recommendations to the Administrator, the Chairman of the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Chairman of the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/211/s246/b/1">Pub. L. 111–211, § 246(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Ten” for “Nine”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/111/211/s246/b/2">Pub. L. 111–211, § 246(b)(2)</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273">Pub. L. 107–273</ref> substituted “Education and the Workforce” for “Education and Labor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> substituted “the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service” for “the Director of the ACTION Agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/586/s2/d/1/A">Pub. L. 102–586, § 2(d)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Director of the ACTION Agency, the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, such other officers of Federal agencies who hold significant decisionmaking authority as the President may designate, and individuals appointed under paragraph (2)” for “the Director of the Office of Community Services, the Director of the Office of Drug Abuse Policy, the Director of the ACTION Agency, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, the Commissioner of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Director for the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitation Services, the Commissioner for the Administration for Children, Youth, and Families, and the Director of the Youth Development Bureau, or their respective designees, the Assistant Attorney General who heads the Office of Justice Programs, the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Director of the National Institute of Justice, and representatives of such other agencies as the President shall designate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/586/s2/d/1/B">Pub. L. 102–586, § 2(d)(1)(B)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “Any individual designated under this section shall be selected from individuals who exercise significant decisionmaking authority in the Federal agency involved.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/586/s2/d/2">Pub. L. 102–586, § 2(d)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted “(in cooperation with State and local juvenile justice programs) all Federal programs and activities that detain or care for unaccompanied juveniles,”, “shall examine how the separate programs can be coordinated among Federal, State, and local governments to better serve at-risk children and juveniles and” and “and all Federal programs and activities that detain or care for unaccompanied juveniles”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/586/s2/d/3">Pub. L. 102–586, § 2(d)(3)</ref>, inserted “Members appointed under subsection (a)(2) shall serve without compensation.” before “Members of the Council” and struck out “who are employed by the Federal Government full time” before “shall be”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, §§ 7251(b), 7252(b)(2), struck out “(hereinafter referred to as the ‘Council’)” after “Coordinating Council on Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention” and “the Deputy Administrator of the Institute for Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention,” after “Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7254/a/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7254(a)(1)</ref>–(3), struck out “, in consultation with the Advisory Board on Missing Children,” after “programs and” in first sentence, substituted “shall” for “is authorized to” and “paragraphs (12)(A), (13), and (14) of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s5633/a">section 5633(a) of this title</ref>” for “section 5633(a)(12)(A) and (13) of this title” in third sentence, and inserted at end “The Council shall review the reasons why Federal agencies take juveniles into custody and shall make recommendations regarding how to improve Federal practices and facilities for holding juveniles in custody.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7254/b">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7254(b)</ref>, struck out provision that annual report required by <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s5614/b/5">section 5614(b)(5) of this title</ref> include a description of the activities of the Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7254/c">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7254(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (g) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (g) read as follows: “To carry out the purposes of this section there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary, not to exceed $200,000 for each fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s623/a">Pub. L. 98–473, § 623(a)</ref>, substituted “Office of Community Services” for “Community Services Administration”, “Assistant Attorney General who heads the Office of Justice Programs” for “Director of the Office of Justice Assistance, Research, and Statistics”, and “Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance” for “Administrator of the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s623/b">Pub. L. 98–473, § 623(b)</ref>, substituted “delinquency programs and, in consultation with the Advisory Board on Missing Children, all Federal programs relating to missing and exploited children” for “delinquency programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s623/c">Pub. L. 98–473, § 623(c)</ref>, substituted “the Administrator” for “he” before “considers necessary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s623/d">Pub. L. 98–473, § 623(d)</ref>, substituted “$200,000” for “$500,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/509">Pub. L. 96–509</ref>, §§ 8(a), 19(f)(1), substituted “the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Director of the Community Services Administration, the Director of the Office of Drug Abuse Policy, the Director of the ACTION Agency, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, the Commissioner of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Director of the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitation Services, the Commissioner for the Administration for Children, Youth, and Families, and the Director of the Youth Development Bureau, or their respective designees, the Director of the Office of Justice Assistance, Research and Statistics, the Administrator of the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration, the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Deputy Administrator of the Institute for Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Director of the National Institute of Justice, and representatives” for “the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Secretary of Labor, the Director of the Office of Drug Abuse Policy, the Commissioner of the Office of Education, the Director of the ACTION Agency, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, or their respective designees, the Associate Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Deputy Associate Administrator of the Institute for Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, and representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/509/s19/f/2">Pub. L. 96–509, § 19(f)(2)</ref>, struck out “Associate” before “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/509/s8/b">Pub. L. 96–509, § 8(b)</ref>, provided that the Coordinating Council make its annual recommendations to the Congress as well as the President and that the Coordinating Council review and make recommendations with respect to any joint funding proposal undertaken by the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention and any agency represented on the Council and struck out “the Attorney General and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/509/s8/c">Pub. L. 96–509, § 8(c)</ref>, substituted “at least quarterly” for “a minimum of four times per year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/509">Pub. L. 96–509</ref>, §§ 8(d), 19(f)(3), substituted “The Administrator shall” for “The Associate Administrator may”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/509/s8/e">Pub. L. 96–509, § 8(e)</ref>, placed a limit of $500,000 for each fiscal year on the amount authorized to be appropriated to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/115/s3/a/3/A">Pub. L. 95–115, § 3(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (5), (d)(1), inserted references to the Commissioner of the Office of Education and the Director of the ACTION Agency, and substituted “Associate” for “Assistant” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/115/s3/a/3/A">Pub. L. 95–115, § 3(a)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “Associate” for “Assistant”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/115/s3/d/2">Pub. L. 95–115, § 3(d)(2)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to review functions of the Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/115/s3/d/3">Pub. L. 95–115, § 3(d)(3)</ref>, substituted “four” for “six”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/115/s3/d/4">Pub. L. 95–115, § 3(d)(4)</ref>, redesignated former par. (3) as entire subsec. (e) and, as so redesignated, inserted “or staff support” after “personnel” and substituted “Associate Administrator” for “Executive Secretary”. Former pars. (1) and (2), which related to appointment and responsibilities of the Executive Secretary, respectively, were struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/237">Pub. L. 94–237</ref> substituted “Office of Drug Abuse Policy” for “Special Action Office for Drug Abuse Prevention”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4ce12bd0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4ce12bd1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/385">Pub. L. 115–385</ref> not applicable with respect to funds appropriated for any fiscal year that begins before <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/385/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 115–385</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11102">section 11102 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4ce12bd2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/273">Pub. L. 107–273</ref> effective on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins after <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, and applicable only with respect to fiscal years beginning on or after the first day of the first fiscal year that begins after <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s12223">section 12223 of Pub. L. 107–273</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11101">section 11101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4ce12bd3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82">Pub. L. 103–82</ref> effective <date date="1994-04-04">Apr. 4, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s406/b">section 406(b) of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4ce12bd4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> effective <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7296/a">section 7296(a) of Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11101">section 11101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4ce12bd5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> effective <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s670/a">section 670(a) of Pub. L. 98–473</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11101">section 11101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4ce12bd6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/115">Pub. L. 95–115</ref> effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/415/s263/c">section 263(c) of Pub. L. 93–415</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/95/115">Pub. L. 95–115</ref> and repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII/s7266/2">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7266(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4449">102 Stat. 4449</ref>, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11101">section 11101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4ce12bd7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (c)(1) of this section relating to the Council making recommendations to Congress at least annually, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and item 1 on page 159 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4ce12bd8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of Title 8</ref>, Aliens and Nationality.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
