<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4cf8f949-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106"><num value="12106">§ 12106.</num><heading> Formula for grants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cf8f94a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of violent offender incarceration grants under section 12103</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4cf8f94b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Formula allocation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">85 percent of the amount available for grants under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103">section 12103 of this title</ref> for any fiscal year shall be allocated as follows (except that a State may not receive more than 9 percent of the total amount of funds made available under this paragraph):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cf8f94c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 0.75 percent shall be allocated to each State that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103/a">section 12103(a) of this title</ref>, except that the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, if eligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103/a">section 12103(a) of this title</ref>, shall each be allocated 0.05 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cf8f94d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amount remaining after application of subparagraph (A) shall be allocated to each State that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103/b">section 12103(b) of this title</ref>, in the ratio that the number of part 1 violent crimes reported by such State to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the 3 years preceding the year in which the determination is made, bears to the average annual number of part 1 violent crimes reported by all States that meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103/b">section 12103(b) of this title</ref> to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the 3 years preceding the year in which the determination is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4cf8f94e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional allocation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">15 percent of the amount available for grants under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103">section 12103 of this title</ref> for any fiscal year shall be allocated to each State that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103/c">section 12103(c) of this title</ref> as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cf8f94f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 3.0 percent shall be allocated to each State that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103/c">section 12103(c) of this title</ref>, except that the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, if eligible under such subsection, shall each be allocated 0.03 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4cf8f950-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amount remaining after application of subparagraph (A) shall be allocated to each State that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12103/c">section 12103(c) of this title</ref>, in the ratio that the number of part 1 violent crimes reported by such State to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the 3 years preceding the year in which the determination is made, bears to the average annual number of part 1 violent crimes reported by all States that meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12102/c">section 12102(c) of this title</ref> to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the 3 years preceding the year in which the determination is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cf8f951-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of truth-in-sentencing grants under section 12104</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amounts available for grants for <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12104">section 12104 of this title</ref> shall be allocated to each State that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12104">section 12104 of this title</ref> in the ratio that the average annual number of part 1 violent crimes reported by such State to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the 3 years preceding the year in which the determination is made bears to the average annual number of part 1 violent crimes reported by States that meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12104">section 12104 of this title</ref> to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the 3 years preceding the year in which the determination is made, except that a State may not receive more than 25 percent of the total amount available for such grants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cf8f952-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Unavailable data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If data regarding part 1 violent crimes in any State is substantially inaccurate or is unavailable for the 3 years preceding the year in which the determination is made, the Attorney General shall utilize the best available comparable data regarding the number of violent crimes for the previous year for the State for the purposes of allocation of funds under this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4cf8f953-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s12106/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional compacts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining the amount of funds that States organized as a regional compact may receive, the Attorney General shall first apply the formula in either subsection (a) or (b) and (c) of this section to each member State of the compact. The States organized as a regional compact may receive the sum of the amounts so determined.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4cf8f954-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tII/s20106">Pub. L. 103–322, title II, § 20106</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)]</ref> [title I, § 114(a)], <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321">110 Stat. 1321</ref>, 1321–18; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4cf8f955-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4cf8f956-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4cf8f957-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13706">section 13706 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id4cf8f958-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s20106">section 20106 of Pub. L. 103–322</ref>, title II, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1818">108 Stat. 1818</ref>, related to technical assistance and training prior to the general amendment of subtitle A of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/104/134">Pub. L. 104–134</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
