<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4d1cadcf-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102"><num value="20102">§ 20102.</num><heading> Crime victim compensation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d1cadd0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Director; grants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4d1cadd1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Director shall make an annual grant from the Fund to an eligible crime victim compensation program of 75 percent of the amounts awarded during the preceding fiscal year, other than amounts awarded for property damage. Except as provided in paragraph (4), a grant under this section shall be used by such program only for awards of compensation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4d1cadd2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the sums available in the Fund for grants under this section are insufficient to provide grants as provided in paragraph (1), the Director shall make, from the sums available, a grant to each eligible crime victim compensation program so that all such programs receive the same percentage of the amounts awarded by such program during the preceding fiscal year, other than amounts awarded for property damage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4d1cadd3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For the purposes of calculating amounts awarded in the previous fiscal year under this subsection, the Director shall not require eligible crime victim compensation programs to deduct recovery costs or collections from restitution or from subrogation for payment under a civil lawsuit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4d1cadd4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Not more than 5 percent of a grant made under this section may be used for training purposes and the administration of the State crime victim compensation program receiving the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d1cadd5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible crime victim compensation programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A crime victim compensation program is an eligible crime victim compensation program for the purposes of this section if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadd6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> such program is operated by a State and offers compensation to victims and survivors of victims of criminal violence, including drunk driving and domestic violence for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d1cadd7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> medical expenses attributable to a physical injury resulting from compensable crime, including expenses for mental health counseling and care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d1cadd8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> loss of wages attributable to a physical injury resulting from a compensable crime; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d1cadd9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> funeral expenses attributable to a death resulting from a compensable crime;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadda-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such program promotes victim cooperation with the reasonable requests of law enforcement authorities, except if a program determines such cooperation may be impacted due to a victim’s age, physical condition, psychological state, cultural or linguistic barriers, or any other health or safety concern that jeopardizes the victim’s wellbeing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1caddb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> such State certifies that grants received under this section will not be used to supplant State funds otherwise available to provide crime victim compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1caddc-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> such program, as to compensable crimes occurring within the State, makes compensation awards to victims who are nonresidents of the State on the basis of the same criteria used to make awards to victims who are residents of such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1caddd-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> such program provides compensation to victims of Federal crimes occurring within the State on the same basis that such program provides compensation to victims of State crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadde-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> such program provides compensation to residents of the State who are victims of crimes occurring outside the State if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d1caddf-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the crimes would be compensable crimes had they occurred inside that State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d1cade0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the places the crimes occurred in are States not having eligible crime victim compensation programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cade1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> such program does not, except pursuant to rules issued by the program to prevent unjust enrichment of the offender, deny compensation to any victim because of that victim’s familial relationship to the offender, or because of the sharing of a residence by the victim and the offender;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cade2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> such program does not provide compensation to any person who has been convicted of an offense under Federal law with respect to any time period during which the person is delinquent in paying a fine, other monetary penalty, or restitution imposed for the offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cade3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> beginning not later than 3 years after <date date="2022-03-15">March 15, 2022</date>, such program—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d1cade4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> provides a waiver for any application filing deadline imposed by the program for a crime victim if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4d1cade5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/9/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the crime victim is otherwise eligible for compensation; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4d1cade6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/9/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the delay in filing the application was a result of a delay in the testing of, or a delay in the DNA profile matching from, a sexual assault forensic examination kit or biological material collected as evidence related to a sexual offense; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d1cade7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not require the crime victim to undergo an appeals process to have the application of the crime victim considered for a filing deadline waiver under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cade8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> such program provides such other information and assurances related to the purposes of this section as the Director may reasonably require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d1cade9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusion from income, resources, and assets for purposes of means tests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law (other than title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/107/42">Public Law 107–42</ref>), for the purpose of any maximum allowed income, resource, or asset eligibility requirement in any Federal, State, or local government program using Federal funds that provides medical or other assistance (or payment or reimbursement of the cost of such assistance), any amount of crime victim compensation that the applicant receives through a crime victim compensation program under this section shall not be included in the income, resources, or assets of the applicant, nor shall that amount reduce the amount of the assistance available to the applicant from Federal, State, or local government programs using Federal funds, unless the total amount of assistance that the applicant receives from all such programs is sufficient to fully compensate the applicant for losses suffered as a result of the crime.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d1cadea-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadeb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “property damage” does not include damage to prosthetic devices, eyeglasses or other corrective lenses, or dental devices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadec-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “medical expenses” includes, to the extent provided under the eligible crime victim compensation program, expenses for eyeglasses or other corrective lenses, for dental services and devices and prosthetic devices, and for services rendered in accordance with a method of healing recognized by the law of the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1caded-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “compensable crime” means a crime the victims of which are eligible for compensation under the eligible crime victim compensation program, and includes crimes, whose victims suffer death or personal injury, that are described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s247">section 247 of title 18</ref>, driving while intoxicated, and domestic violence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadee-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other possession or territory of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadef-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “recovery costs” means expenses for personnel directly involved in the recovery efforts to obtain collections from restitution or from subrogation for payment under a civil law suit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d1cadf0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to certain Federal programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, if the compensation paid by an eligible crime victim compensation program would cover costs that a Federal program, including the program established under title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/107/42">Public Law 107–42</ref>, or a federally financed State or local program, would otherwise pay,— <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002150">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002150"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note></chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadf1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such crime victim compensation program shall not pay that compensation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d1cadf2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20102/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the other program shall make its payments without regard to the existence of the crime victim compensation program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4d1cadf3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s1403">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 1403</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2171">98 Stat. 2171</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7123(b)(1)–(3), 7125, 7126, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4421-4423">102 Stat. 4421–4423</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXIII">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXIII</ref>, §§ 230202, 230203, title XXXIII, § 330025(b), <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2079">108 Stat. 2079</ref>, 2151; <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/tII">Pub. L. 104–132, title II</ref>, §§ 233(a), (b), 234(a)(1), (b), <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1244">110 Stat. 1244</ref>, 1245; <ref href="/us/pl/104/155/s5">Pub. L. 104–155, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-07-03">July 3, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1394">110 Stat. 1394</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tVI/s622/a">Pub. L. 107–56, title VI, § 622(a)</ref>–(e)(1), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/371">115 Stat. 371</ref>, 372; <ref href="/us/pl/109/162/tXI/s1133/a">Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1133(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3108">119 Stat. 3108</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/27/s2/b">Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-07-22">July 22, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/301">135 Stat. 301</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/tXIII">Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1311, 1316(b), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/935">136 Stat. 935</ref>, 939.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4d1cadf4-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d1cadf5-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4d1cadf6-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/107/42">Public Law 107–42</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (e), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40101">section 40101 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4d1cadf7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10602">section 10602 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4d1cadf8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s1311">Pub. L. 117–103, § 1311</ref>, substituted “paragraph (4)” for “paragraph (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9), (10). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s1316/b">Pub. L. 117–103, § 1316(b)</ref>, added par. (9) and redesignated former par. (9) as (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/27/s2/b/1/A">Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “75 percent” for “40 percent in fiscal year 2002 and of 60 percent in subsequent fiscal years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/27/s2/b/1/B">Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(b)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “of 40 percent in fiscal year 2002 and of 60 percent in subsequent fiscal years” after “to provide grants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/27/s2/b/1/C">Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(b)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/27/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “authorities, except if a program determines such cooperation may be impacted due to a victim’s age, physical condition, psychological state, cultural or linguistic barriers, or any other health or safety concern that jeopardizes the victim’s wellbeing;” for “authorities;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/117/27/s2/b/3">Pub. L. 117–27, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/162">Pub. L. 109–162</ref> inserted “training purposes and” after “may be used for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s622/a">Pub. L. 107–56, § 622(a)</ref>, inserted “in fiscal year 2002 and of 60 percent in subsequent fiscal years” after “40 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s622/b">Pub. L. 107–56, § 622(b)</ref>, which directed striking out “are outside the United States (if the compensable crime is terrorism, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2331">section 2331 of title 18</ref>), or”, was executed by striking out “are outside of the United States (if the compensable crime is terrorism, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2331">section 2331 of title 18</ref>), or” after “the places the crimes occurred in” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s622/c">Pub. L. 107–56, § 622(c)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “Notwithstanding any other law, for the purpose of any maximum allowed income eligibility requirement in any Federal, State, or local government program using Federal funds that provides medical or other assistance (or payment or reimbursement of the cost of such assistance) that becomes necessary to an applicant for such assistance in full or in part because of the commission of a crime against the applicant, as determined by the Director, any amount of crime victim compensation that the applicant receives through a crime victim compensation program under this section shall not be included in the income of the applicant until the total amount of assistance that the applicant receives from all such programs is sufficient to fully compensate the applicant for losses suffered as a result of the crime.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s622/d/1">Pub. L. 107–56, § 622(d)(1)</ref>, struck out “crimes involving terrorism,” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t18/s247">section 247 of title 18</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s622/d/2">Pub. L. 107–56, § 622(d)(2)</ref>, inserted “the United States Virgin Islands,” after “the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s622/e/1">Pub. L. 107–56, § 622(e)(1)</ref>, inserted “including the program established under title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/107/42">Public Law 107–42</ref>,” after “Federal program,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s233/b">Pub. L. 104–132, § 233(b)</ref>, inserted “are outside of the United States (if the compensable crime is terrorism, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2331">section 2331 of title 18</ref>), or” before “are States not having”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s234/a/1">Pub. L. 104–132, § 234(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (8) and redesignated former par. (8) as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s234/b">Pub. L. 104–132, § 234(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/155">Pub. L. 104–155</ref> inserted “crimes, whose victims suffer death or personal injury, that are described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s247">section 247 of title 18</ref>,” after “includes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s233/a">Pub. L. 104–132, § 233(a)</ref>, substituted “crimes involving terrorism, driving while intoxicated,” for “driving while intoxicated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s230203/a">Pub. L. 103–322, § 230203(a)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (3), a grant” for “A grant” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s230203/b">Pub. L. 103–322, § 230203(b)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s330025/b">Pub. L. 103–322, § 330025(b)</ref>, inserted before semicolon at end “for—” and subpars. (A) to (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/s230202">Pub. L. 103–322, § 230202</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, §§ 7123(b)(1), (2), 7125(b), substituted “Director” for “Attorney General” and “40 percent” for “35 percent” in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7125/c/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7125(c)(1)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “such program is operated by a State and offers compensation to victims of crime and survivors of victims of crime for—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) medical expenses attributable to a physical injury resulting from compensable crime, including expenses for mental health counseling and care;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) loss of wages attributable to a physical injury resulting from a compensable crime; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) funeral expenses attributable to a death resulting from a compensable crime;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7125/d">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7125(d)</ref>, amended par. (5) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (5) read as follows: “such program provides compensation to victims of crimes occurring within such State that would be compensable crimes, but for the fact that such crimes are subject to Federal jurisdiction, on the same basis that such program provides compensation to victims of compensable crimes; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7125/a/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7125(a)(1)</ref>, added pars. (6) and (7). Former par. (6) redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, §§ 7123(b)(3), 7125(a)(2), redesignated par. (6) as (8) and substituted “Director” for “Attorney General”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7125/e">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7125(e)</ref>, struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “A State crime victim compensation program in effect on the date grants may first be made under this section shall be deemed an eligible crime victim compensation program for the purposes of this section until the day after the close of the first regular session of the legislature of that State that begins after such date.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7126/a">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7126(a)</ref>, inserted reference to eyeglasses or other corrective lenses.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7126/b">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7126(b)</ref>, inserted reference to eyeglasses or other corrective lenses and inserted comma after “prosthetic devices”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7125/c/2">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7125(c)(2)</ref>, inserted reference to driving while intoxicated and domestic violence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4d1cadf9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4d1cadfa-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2022 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/103">Pub. L. 117–103</ref> not effective until Oct. 1 of the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/s4/a">section 4(a) of div. W of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s6851">section 6851 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4d1cadfb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/tII/s233/d">Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 233(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1245">110 Stat. 1245</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/119/tI/s120">Pub. L. 105–119, title I, § 120</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2468">111 Stat. 2468</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/119/tI/s120">“This section [amending this section] and the amendments made by this section shall take effect <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4d1cadfc-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> not applicable with respect to a State compensation program that was an eligible State crime victim compensation program on <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, until <date date="1991-10-01">Oct. 1, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7129">section 7129 of Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20101">section 20101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4d1cadfd-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/132/s234/a/1">Section 234(a)(1) of Pub. L. 104–132</ref></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/132/tII/s234/a/2">Pub. L. 104–132, title II, § 234(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-24">Apr. 24, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1245">110 Stat. 1245</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/132/tII/s234/a/2">“Section 1403(b)(8) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20102/b/8">34 U.S.C. 20102(b)(8)</ref>], as added by paragraph (1) of this section, shall not be applied to deny victims compensation to any person until the date on which the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, issues a written determination that a cost-effective, readily available criminal debt payment tracking system operated by the agency responsible for the collection of criminal debt has established cost-effective, readily available communications links with entities that administer Federal victim compensation programs that are sufficient to ensure that victim compensation is not denied to any person except as authorized by law.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
