<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4d21903c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124"><num value="20124">§ 20124.</num><heading> Enhancing culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21903d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21903e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Of the amounts appropriated under certain grant programs identified in paragraph (2), the Attorney General, through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall take 15 percent of such appropriated amounts for the program under paragraph (2)(A) and 5 percent of such appropriated amounts for the programs under subparagraphs (B) through (E) of paragraph (2) and combine them to establish a new grant program to enhance culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Grants made under this new program shall be administered by the Director. The requirements of the grant programs identified in paragraph (2) shall not apply to this new grant program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21903f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Programs covered</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The programs covered by paragraph (1) are the programs carried out under the following provisions:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219040-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10461">Section 10461 of this title</ref> (Grants to Encourage Arrest Policies and Enforcement of Protection Orders).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219041-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20121">Section 20121 of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002157">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002157"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> (Legal Assistance for Victims).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219042-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12341">Section 12341 of this title</ref> (Rural Domestic Violence, Dating Violence, Sexual Assault, Stalking, and Child Abuse Enforcement Assistance).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219043-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14041a">Section 14041a of title 42</ref> (Enhanced Training and Services to End Violence Against Women Later in Life).<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219044-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20122">Section 20122 of this title</ref> (Education, Training, and Enhanced Services to End Violence Against and Abuse of Women with Disabilities).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d219045-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to the amounts made available under paragraph (1), there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d219046-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4d219047-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Of the total amount available for grants under this section, not less than 40 percent of such funds shall be allocated for programs or projects that meaningfully address non-intimate partner relationship sexual assault.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4d219048-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/a/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding 12291(b)(11) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002158">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002158"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”.</note> of this title, the Director may allocate a portion of funds described in subparagraph (A) to enhanced technical assistance relating to non-intimate partner sexual assault if the Office on Violence Against Women does not receive sufficient qualified applications proposing to address non-intimate partner relationship sexual assault.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d219049-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose of program and grants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21904a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General program purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The purpose of the program required by this section is to promote:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d21904b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The maintenance and replication of existing successful services in domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking community-based programs providing culturally specific services and other resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d21904c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The development of innovative culturally specific strategies and projects to enhance access to services and resources for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21904d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes for which grants may be used</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall make grants to community-based programs for the purpose of enhancing culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Grants under the program shall support community-based efforts to address distinctive cultural responses to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d21904e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> working with State and local governments and social service agencies to develop and enhance effective strategies to provide culturally specific services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d21904f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> increasing communities’ capacity to provide culturally specific resources and support for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking crimes and their families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219050-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> strengthening criminal justice interventions, by providing training for law enforcement, prosecution, courts, probation, and correctional facilities on culturally specific responses to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219051-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> enhancing traditional services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking through the leadership of culturally specific programs offering services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219052-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> working in cooperation with the community to develop education and prevention strategies highlighting culturally specific issues and resources regarding victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219053-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> providing culturally specific programs for children exposed to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219054-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> providing culturally specific resources and services that address the safety, economic, housing, and workplace needs of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including emergency assistance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d219055-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> examining the dynamics of culture and its impact on victimization and healing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d219056-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance and training</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall provide technical assistance and training to grantees of this and other programs under this Act regarding the development and provision of effective culturally specific community-based services by entering into cooperative agreements or contracts with an organization or organizations having a demonstrated expertise in and whose primary purpose is addressing the development and provision of culturally specific community-based services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Not less than 1 such organization shall have demonstrated expertise primarily in domestic violence services, and not less than 1 such organization shall have demonstrated expertise primarily in non-intimate partner sexual assault services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d219057-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible entities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Eligible entities for grants under this Section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002159">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002159"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d219058-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> community-based programs whose primary purpose is providing culturally specific services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d219059-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> community-based programs whose primary purpose is providing culturally specific services who can partner with a program having demonstrated expertise in serving victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21905a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall issue a biennial report on the distribution of funding under this section, the progress made in replicating and supporting increased services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources, and the types of culturally accessible programs, strategies, technical assistance, and training developed or enhanced through this program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21905b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall award a contract or cooperative agreement to evaluate programs under this section to an entity with the demonstrated expertise in and primary goal of providing enhanced cultural access to services and resources for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21905c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-exclusivity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this Section <sup>3</sup> shall be interpreted to exclude culturally specific community-based programs from applying to other grant programs authorized under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d21905d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20124/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions and grant conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section the definitions and grant conditions in <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12291">section 12291 of this title</ref> shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4d21905e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/162/tI/s121">Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2991">119 Stat. 2991</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/271">Pub. L. 109–271</ref>, §§ 1(c)(3), 2(k), <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/751">120 Stat. 751</ref>, 753; <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/tI/s109">Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/80">127 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/tI/s108">Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title I, § 108</ref>, title IX, § 901(e), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/852">136 Stat. 852</ref>, 911.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4d21905f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d219060-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4d219061-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20121">Section 20121 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(B), was in the original “Section 14201 of division B of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3796gg–6">42 U.S.C. 3796gg–6</ref>)”, which was translated as meaning “Section 1201 of division B of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3796gg–6">42 U.S.C. 3796gg–6</ref>)”, which is <ref href="/us/pl/106/386/dB/tII/s1201">section 1201 of title II of div. B of Pub. L. 106–386</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. <ref href="/us/pl/106/386/dB/tII/s1201">Section 1201 of title II of div. B of Pub. L. 106–386</ref> was classified as <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3796gg–6">section 3796gg–6 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20121">section 20121 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The parenthetical reference “(Enhanced Training and Services to End Violence Against Women Later in Life)” appearing after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14041a">Section 14041a of title 42</ref>” in subsec. (a)(2)(D), probably should be “(Enhanced Training and Services to End Violence Against and Abuse of Women Later in Life)”. <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14041a">Section 14041a of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, was omitted in the general amendment of Part G of subchapter III of chapter 136 of Title 42 by <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/tII/s204/a">Pub. L. 113–4, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/82">127 Stat. 82</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (b)(3) and (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/109/162">Pub. L. 109–162</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2960">119 Stat. 2960</ref>, known as the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2006 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4d219062-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14045a">section 14045a of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4d219063-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s901/e">Pub. L. 117–103, § 901(e)</ref>, substituted “the Office on Violence Against Women” for “the Violence Against Women Office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s108/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 117–103, § 108(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “shall take 15 percent of such appropriated amounts for the program under paragraph (2)(A) and 5 percent of such appropriated amounts for the programs under subparagraphs (B) through (E) of paragraph (2)” for “shall take 5 percent of such appropriated amounts”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s108/1/A/i">Pub. L. 117–103, § 108(1)(A)(i)</ref>, which directed substitution of “paragraph (2)” for “paragraph (a)(2) of this subsection”, was executed by making the substitution for “paragraph (a)(2) of this Section”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s108/1/B">Pub. L. 117–103, § 108(1)(B)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s108/2">Pub. L. 117–103, § 108(2)</ref>, inserted at end “Not less than 1 such organization shall have demonstrated expertise primarily in domestic violence services, and not less than 1 such organization shall have demonstrated expertise primarily in non-intimate partner sexual assault services.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/s108/3">Pub. L. 117–103, § 108(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsecs. (f) to (h) as (e) to (g), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (e). Prior to amendment, text of subsec. (e) read as follows: “The Director shall award grants for a 2-year period, with a possible extension of another 2 years to implement projects under the grant.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—<ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s109/1">Pub. L. 113–4, § 109(1)</ref>–(3), struck out “and linguistically” after “culturally” in section catchline and wherever appearing in text and struck out “and linguistic” after “cultural” in subsecs. (b)(2) and (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s109/4">Pub. L. 113–4, § 109(4)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which related to covered programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s109/5">Pub. L. 113–4, § 109(5)</ref>, struck out “linguistic and” before “culturally”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/271/s2/k/1">Pub. L. 109–271, § 2(k)(1)</ref>, inserted “The requirements of the grant programs identified in paragraph (2) shall not apply to this new grant program.” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/271/s2/k/2">Pub. L. 109–271, § 2(k)(2)</ref>, which directed substituting “, including—” and subpars. (A) to (H) for the period, was executed by making the substitution for the period at the end to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/271/s1/c/3">Pub. L. 109–271, § 1(c)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4d219064-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4d219065-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2022 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/103">Pub. L. 117–103</ref> not effective until Oct. 1 of the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/s4/a">section 4(a) of div. W of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s6851">section 6851 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4d219066-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/4">Pub. L. 113–4</ref> not effective until the beginning of the fiscal year following <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 113–4</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2261">section 2261 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id4d219067-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section not effective until the beginning of fiscal year 2007, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/162/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 109–162</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2006 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10261">section 10261 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
