<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4d2d7735-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503"><num value="20503">§ 20503.</num><heading> Grant program for notification and communications systems along highways and major transportation routes for recovery of abducted children</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7736-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Program required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall carry out a program to provide grants to States for the development or enhancement of notification or communications systems along highways and at airports, maritime ports, border crossing areas and checkpoints, and ports of exit from the United States for alerts and other information for the recovery of abducted children.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7737-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Development grants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7738-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may make a grant to a State under this subsection for the development of a State program for the use of changeable message signs or other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children. The State program shall provide for the planning, coordination, and design of systems, protocols, and message sets that support the coordination and communication necessary to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7739-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A grant under this subsection may be used by a State for the following purposes:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d2d773a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To develop general policies and procedures to guide the use of changeable message signs or other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d2d773b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To develop guidance or policies on the content and format of alert messages to be conveyed on changeable message signs or other traveler information systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d2d773c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> To coordinate State, regional, and local plans for the use of changeable message signs or other transportation related issues.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d2d773d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> To plan secure and reliable communications systems and protocols among public safety and transportation agencies or modify existing communications systems to support the notification of motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d2d773e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> To plan and design improved systems for communicating with motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers, including the capability for issuing wide area alerts to motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d2d773f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> To plan systems and protocols to facilitate the efficient issuance of child abduction notification and other key information to motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers during off-hours.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d2d7740-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> To provide training and guidance to transportation authorities to facilitate appropriate use of changeable message signs and other traveler information systems for the notification of motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7741-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation grants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7742-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may make a grant to a State under this subsection for the implementation of a program for the use of changeable message signs or other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children. A State shall be eligible for a grant under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the State has developed a State program in accordance with subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7743-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A grant under this subsection may be used by a State to support the implementation of systems that use changeable message signs or other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children. Such support may include the purchase and installation of changeable message signs or other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7744-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7745-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Federal share of the cost of any activities funded by a grant under this section may not exceed 80 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7746-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, or the Virgin Islands of the United States is unable to comply with the requirement under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall waive such requirement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7747-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution of grant amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, distribute grants under this section equally among the States that apply for a grant under this section within the time period prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7748-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe requirements, including application requirements, for the receipt of grants under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d7749-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this chapter, the term “State” means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, American Samoa, Guam, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d774a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023. Such amounts shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d774b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Study of State programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d774c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct a study to examine State barriers to the adoption and implementation of State programs for the use of communications systems along highways for alerts and other information for the recovery of abducted children.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4d2d774d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20503/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2003-04-30">April 30, 2003</date>, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the results of the study, together with any recommendations the Secretary determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4d2d774e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/21/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 108–21, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2003-04-30">Apr. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/662">117 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dH/tC/s10001/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. H, title C, § 10001(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4861">134 Stat. 4861</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4d2d774f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d2d7750-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4d2d7751-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5791b">section 5791b of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4d2d7752-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “and major transportation routes” after “along highways” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “(referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’)” after “Secretary of Transportation” and “and at airports, maritime ports, border crossing areas and checkpoints, and ports of exit from the United States” after “along highways”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/C/i">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers” for “other motorist information systems to notify motorists” and inserted “, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers” after “necessary to notify motorists”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/C/ii/I">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(C)(ii)(I)</ref>, substituted “other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers” for “other motorist information systems to notify motorists”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/C/ii/II">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(C)(ii)(II)</ref>, inserted “, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers” after “support the notification of motorists”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/C/ii/III">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(C)(ii)(III)</ref>, inserted “, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers” after “motorists” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/C/ii/IV">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(C)(ii)(IV)</ref>, (V), inserted “, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers” after “motorists”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/D">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers” for “other motorist information systems” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/E">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(E)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Federal share of the cost of any activities funded by a grant under this section may not exceed 80 percent.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/F">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(F)</ref>, substituted “In this chapter” for “In this section” and “American Samoa, Guam, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory of the United States” for “or Puerto Rico”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s10001/b/1/G">Pub. L. 116–283, § 10001(b)(1)(G)</ref>, substituted “each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023” for “fiscal year 2004”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
