<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4d34a3c7-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913"><num value="20913">§ 20913.</num><heading> Registry requirements for sex offenders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d34a3c8-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A sex offender shall register, and keep the registration current, in each jurisdiction where the offender resides, where the offender is an employee, and where the offender is a student. For initial registration purposes only, a sex offender shall also register in the jurisdiction in which convicted if such jurisdiction is different from the jurisdiction of residence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d34a3c9-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial registration</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The sex offender shall initially register—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d34a3ca-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> before completing a sentence of imprisonment with respect to the offense giving rise to the registration requirement; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d34a3cb-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not later than 3 business days after being sentenced for that offense, if the sex offender is not sentenced to a term of imprisonment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d34a3cc-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Keeping the registration current</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A sex offender shall, not later than 3 business days after each change of name, residence, employment, or student status, appear in person in at least 1 jurisdiction involved pursuant to subsection (a) and inform that jurisdiction of all changes in the information required for that offender in the sex offender registry. That jurisdiction shall immediately provide that information to all other jurisdictions in which the offender is required to register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d34a3cd-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial registration of sex offenders unable to comply with subsection (b)</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General shall have the authority to specify the applicability of the requirements of this subchapter to sex offenders convicted before the enactment of this chapter or its implementation in a particular jurisdiction, and to prescribe rules for the registration of any such sex offenders and for other categories of sex offenders who are unable to comply with subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d34a3ce-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s20913/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> State penalty for failure to comply</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each jurisdiction, other than a Federally recognized Indian tribe, shall provide a criminal penalty that includes a maximum term of imprisonment that is greater than 1 year for the failure of a sex offender to comply with the requirements of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4d34a3cf-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/248/tI/s113">Pub. L. 109–248, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/593">120 Stat. 593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4d34a3d0-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d34a3d1-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4d34a3d2-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (d) and (e), was in the original “this title”, meaning title I of <ref href="/us/pl/109/248">Pub. L. 109–248</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/590">120 Stat. 590</ref>, known as the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Short Title of 2006 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (d), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/109/248">Pub. L. 109–248</ref>, <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/587">120 Stat. 587</ref>, known as the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006, which was approved <date date="2006-07-27">July 27, 2006</date>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2006 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4d34a3d3-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s16913">section 16913 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
