<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4d3bcf05-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114"><num value="21114">§ 21114.</num><heading> Duties and functions of task forces</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State or local ICAC task force that is part of the national program of task forces shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf06-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consist of State and local investigators, prosecutors, forensic specialists, and education specialists who are dedicated to addressing the goals of such task force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf07-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> work consistently toward achieving the purposes described in <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s21113">section 21113 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf08-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> engage in reactive and proactive investigations, conduct digital forensic examinations, and engage in effective prosecutions of Internet crimes against children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf09-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provide forensic, preventive, and investigative assistance to parents, educators, prosecutors, law enforcement, and others concerned with Internet crimes against children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf0a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> develop multijurisdictional, multiagency responses and partnerships to Internet crimes against children offenses through ongoing informational, administrative, and technological support to other State and local law enforcement agencies, as a means for such agencies to acquire the necessary knowledge, personnel, and specialized equipment to investigate and prosecute such offenses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf0b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> participate in nationally coordinated investigations in any case in which the Attorney General determines such participation to be necessary, as permitted by the available resources of such task force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf0c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> establish or adopt investigative and prosecution standards, consistent with established norms, to which such task force shall comply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf0d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> investigate, seek prosecution with respect to, and identify child victims from leads relating to Internet crimes against children, including CyberTipline reports, with prioritization determined according to circumstances and by each task force, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s21112">section 21112 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf0e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> maintain—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d3bcf0f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such reports and records as are required under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d3bcf10-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such other reports and records as determined by the Attorney General; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d3bcf11-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s21114/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> seek to comply with national standards regarding the investigation and prosecution of Internet crimes against children, as set forth by the Attorney General, to the extent such standards are consistent with the law of the State where the task force is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id4d3bcf12-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/401/tI/s104">Pub. L. 110–401, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4235">122 Stat. 4235</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXII/s8202/d">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXII, § 8202(d)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1843">139 Stat. 1843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4d3bcf13-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d3bcf14-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4d3bcf15-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17614">section 17614 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d3bcf16-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4d3bcf17-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8202/d/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8202(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “reactive and” before “proactive”, “conduct digital” before “forensic examinations”, and “engage in” before “effective prosecutions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (8). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8202/d/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8202(d)(2)</ref>, added par. (8) and struck out former par. (8) which read as follows: “investigate, and seek prosecution on, tips related to Internet crimes against children, including tips from Operation Fairplay, the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established in <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s21115">section 21115 of this title</ref>, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children’s CyberTipline, ICAC task forces, and other Federal, State, and local agencies, with priority being given to investigative leads that indicate the possibility of identifying or rescuing child victims, including investigative leads that indicate a likelihood of seriousness of offense or dangerousness to the community;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (9) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8202/d/3">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8202(d)(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated pars. (10) and (11) as (9) and (10), respectively, and struck out former par. (9) which read as follows: “develop procedures for handling seized evidence;”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
