<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4d539d3e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902"><num value="40902">§ 40902.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d3f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Approximately 916,000 individuals were prohibited from purchasing a firearm for failing a background check between <date date="1998-11-30">November 30, 1998</date>, (the date the National Instant Criminal Background Check System (NICS) began operating) and <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d40-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> From <date date="1998-11-30">November 30, 1998</date>, through <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>, nearly 49,000,000 Brady background checks were processed through NICS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d41-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Although most Brady background checks are processed through NICS in seconds, many background checks are delayed if the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) does not have automated access to complete information from the States concerning persons prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d42-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nearly 21,000,000 criminal records are not accessible by NICS and millions of criminal records are missing critical data, such as arrest dispositions, due to data backlogs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d43-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The primary cause of delay in NICS background checks is the lack of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d539d44-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> updates and available State criminal disposition records; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d539d45-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> automated access to information concerning persons prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm because of mental illness, restraining orders, or misdemeanor convictions for domestic violence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d46-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> Automated access to this information can be improved by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d539d47-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> computerizing information relating to criminal history, criminal dispositions, mental illness, restraining orders, and misdemeanor convictions for domestic violence; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4d539d48-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> making such information available to NICS in a usable format.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d49-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Helping States to automate these records will reduce delays for law-abiding gun purchasers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d4a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> On <date date="2002-03-12">March 12, 2002</date>, the senseless shooting, which took the lives of a priest and a parishioner at the Our Lady of Peace Church in Lynbrook, New York, brought attention to the need to improve information-sharing that would enable Federal and State law enforcement agencies to conduct a complete background check on a potential firearm purchaser. The man who committed this double murder had a prior disqualifying mental health commitment and a restraining order against him, but passed a Brady background check because NICS did not have the necessary information to determine that he was ineligible to purchase a firearm under Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d539d4b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s40902/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> On <date date="2007-04-16">April 16, 2007</date>, a student with a history of mental illness at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University shot to death 32 students and faculty members, wounded 17 more, and then took his own life. The shooting, the deadliest campus shooting in United States history, renewed the need to improve information-sharing that would enable Federal and State law enforcement agencies to conduct complete background checks on potential firearms purchasers. In spite of a proven history of mental illness, the shooter was able to purchase the two firearms used in the shooting. Improved coordination between State and Federal authorities could have ensured that the shooter’s disqualifying mental health information was available to NICS.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id4d539d4c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/180/s2">Pub. L. 110–180, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-01-08">Jan. 8, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2559">121 Stat. 2559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4d539d4d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d539d4e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4d539d4f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s922">section 922 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
