<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4d5ac977-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505"><num value="41505">§ 41505.</num><heading> Organized retail theft database</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d5ac978-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> National data</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4d5ac979-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Attorney General and the Federal Bureau of Investigation, in consultation with the retail community, shall establish a task force to combat organized retail theft and provide expertise to the retail community for the establishment of a national database or clearinghouse housed and maintained in the private sector to track and identify where organized retail theft type crimes are being committed in the United Sates.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002222">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002222"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “States”.</note> The national database shall allow Federal, State, and local law enforcement officials as well as authorized retail companies (and authorized associated retail databases) to transmit information into the database electronically and to review information that has been submitted electronically.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4d5ac97a-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Attorney General shall make available funds to provide for the ongoing administrative and technological costs to federal law enforcement agencies participating in the database project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4d5ac97b-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance of the Office of Justice Programs may make grants to help provide for the administrative and technological costs to State and local law enforcement agencies participating in the data base <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002223">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002223"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “database”.</note> project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d5ac97c-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2009, $5,000,000 for educating and training federal law enforcement regarding organized retail theft, for investigating, apprehending and prosecuting individuals engaged in organized retail theft, and for working with the private sector to establish and utilize the database described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4d5ac97d-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of organized retail theft</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, “organized retail theft” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d5ac97e-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the violation of a State prohibition on retail merchandise theft or shoplifting, if the violation consists of the theft of quantities of items that would not normally be purchased for personal use or consumption and for the purpose of reselling the items or for reentering the items into commerce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d5ac97f-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the receipt, possession, concealment, bartering, sale, transport, or disposal of any property that is know <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002224">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002224"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “known”.</note> or should be known to have been taken in violation of paragraph (1); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4d5ac980-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d" identifier="/us/usc/t34/s41505/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the coordination, organization, or recruitment of persons to undertake the conduct described in paragraph (1) or (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4d5ac981-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/162/tXI/s1105">Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="2006-01-05">Jan. 5, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3092">119 Stat. 3092</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/271/s8/a">Pub. L. 109–271, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-12">Aug. 12, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/766">120 Stat. 766</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4d5ac982-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4d5ac983-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4d5ac984-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s509">section 509 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4d5ac985-5dcd-11f1-b11b-9e551e93f87d"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/271">Pub. L. 109–271</ref> substituted “The Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance of the Office of Justice Programs may” for “The Attorney General through the Bureau of Justice Assistance in the Office of Justice may”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
