<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id620e41af-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s13d"><num value="13d">§ 13d.</num><heading> Limits on use of appropriated funds by Bureau for general or other welfare assistance</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, no part of any appropriation (except trust funds) to the Bureau of Indian Affairs may be used directly or by contract for general or other welfare assistance (except child welfare assistance) payments (1) for other than essential needs (specifically identified in regulations of the Secretary or in regulations of the State public welfare agency pursuant to the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s301">42 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.] adopted by reference in the Secretary’s regulations) which could not be reasonably expected to be met from financial resources or income (including funds held in trust) available to the recipient individual which are not exempted under law from consideration in determining eligibility for or the amount of Federal financial assistance or (2) for individuals who are eligible for general public welfare assistance available from a State except to the extent the Secretary of the Interior determines that such payments are required under sections 6(b)(2), 6(i), and 9(b) of the Maine Indian Claims Settlement Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/stat/94/1793">94 Stat. 1793</ref>, 1794, 1796; <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1725/b/2">25 U.S.C. 1725(b)(2)</ref>, 1725(i), 1728(b)).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002001"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id620e41b0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tI/s101/c/tI/s100">Pub. L. 98–473, title I, § 101(c) [title I, § 100]</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1837">98 Stat. 1837</ref>, 1848.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id620e41b1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id620e41b2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id620e41b3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 7 (§ 301 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 6(b)(2), 6(i), and 9(b) of the Maine Indian Claims Settlement Act of 1980, referred to in text, are sections 6(b)(2), (i) and 9(b) of <ref href="/us/pl/96/420">Pub. L. 96–420</ref>, which were classified to sections 1725(b)(2), (i) and 1728(b) of this title prior to omission from the Code as being of special and not general application.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
