<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6261b8da-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h"><num value="1621h">§ 1621h.</num><heading> Mental health prevention and treatment services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b8db-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> National plan for Indian Mental Health Services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6261b8dc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Not later than 120 days after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Service, shall develop and publish in the Federal Register a final national plan for Indian Mental Health Services. The plan shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8dd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> an assessment of the scope of the problem of mental illness and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior, including child abuse and family violence, among Indians, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6261b8de-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the number of Indians served by the Service who are directly or indirectly affected by such illness or behavior, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6261b8df-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an estimate of the financial and human cost attributable to such illness or behavior;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an assessment of the existing and additional resources necessary for the prevention and treatment of such illness and behavior; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an estimate of the additional funding needed by the Service to meet its responsibilities under the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6261b8e2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall submit a copy of the national plan to the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b8e3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Memorandum of agreement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall develop and enter into a memorandum of agreement under which the Secretaries shall, among other things—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> determine and define the scope and nature of mental illness and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior, including child abuse and family violence, among Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> make an assessment of the existing Federal, tribal, State, local, and private services, resources, and programs available to provide mental health services for Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> make an initial determination of the unmet need for additional services, resources, and programs necessary to meet the needs identified pursuant to paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> ensure that Indians, as citizens of the United States and of the States in which they reside, have access to mental health services to which all citizens have access;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8e9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> determine the right of Indians to participate in, and receive the benefit of, such services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8ea-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> take actions necessary to protect the exercise of such right;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8eb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> delineate the responsibilities of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Service, including mental health identification, prevention, education, referral, and treatment services (including services through multidisciplinary resource teams), at the central, area, and agency and service unit levels to address the problems identified in paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8ec-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> provide a strategy for the comprehensive coordination of the mental health services provided by the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Service to meet the needs identified pursuant to paragraph (1), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6261b8ed-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the coordination of alcohol and substance abuse programs of the Service, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, and the various tribes (developed under the Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2401">25 U.S.C. 2401</ref> et seq.]) with the mental health initiatives pursuant to this chapter, particularly with respect to the referral and treatment of dually-diagnosed individuals requiring mental health and substance abuse treatment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6261b8ee-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ensuring that Bureau of Indian Affairs and Service programs and services (including multidisciplinary resource teams) addressing child abuse and family violence are coordinated with such non-Federal programs and services;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8ef-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> direct appropriate officials of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Service, particularly at the agency and service unit levels, to cooperate fully with tribal requests made pursuant to subsection (d); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6261b8f0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> provide for an annual review of such agreement by the two Secretaries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b8f1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Community mental health plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6261b8f2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The governing body of any Indian tribe may, at its discretion, adopt a resolution for the establishment of a community mental health plan providing for the identification and coordination of available resources and programs to identify, prevent, or treat mental illness or dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior, including child abuse and family violence, among its members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6261b8f3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In furtherance of a plan established pursuant to paragraph (1) and at the request of a tribe, the appropriate agency, service unit, or other officials of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Service shall cooperate with, and provide technical assistance to, the tribe in the development of such plan. Upon the establishment of such a plan and at the request of the tribe, such officials, as directed by the memorandum of agreement developed pursuant to subsection (c), shall cooperate with the tribe in the implementation of such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6261b8f4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Two or more Indian tribes may form a coalition for the adoption of resolutions and the establishment and development of a joint community mental health plan under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6261b8f5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary, acting through the Service, may make grants to Indian tribes adopting a resolution pursuant to paragraph (1) to obtain technical assistance for the development of a community mental health plan and to provide administrative support in the implementation of such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b8f6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Behavioral health training and community education programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b8f7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Study; list</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Service, and the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with Indian tribes and tribal organizations, shall conduct a study and compile a list of the types of staff positions specified in paragraph (2) whose qualifications include, or should include, training in the identification, prevention, education, referral, or treatment of mental illness, or dysfunctional and self destructive behavior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b8f8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Positions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The positions referred to in paragraph (1) are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6261b8f9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> staff positions within the Bureau of Indian Affairs, including existing positions, in the fields of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6261b8fa-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> elementary and secondary education;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6261b8fb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> social services and family and child welfare;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6261b8fc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> law enforcement and judicial services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id6261b8fd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> alcohol and substance abuse;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6261b8fe-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> staff positions within the Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6261b8ff-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> staff positions similar to those identified in subparagraphs (A) and (B) established and maintained by Indian tribes and tribal organizations (without regard to the funding source).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b900-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Training criteria</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b901-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The appropriate Secretary shall provide training criteria appropriate to each type of position identified in paragraphs (2)(A) and (2)(B) and ensure that appropriate training has been, or shall be provided to any individual in any such position. With respect to any such individual in a position identified pursuant to paragraph (2)(C), the respective Secretaries shall provide appropriate training to, or provide funds to, an Indian tribe or tribal organization for training of appropriate individuals. In the case of positions funded under a contract or compact under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450">25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002050">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002050"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the appropriate Secretary shall ensure that such training costs are included in the contract or compact, as the Secretary determines necessary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b902-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Position specific training criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Position specific training criteria shall be culturally relevant to Indians and Indian tribes and shall ensure that appropriate information regarding traditional health care practices is provided.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6261b903-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Community education on mental illness</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Service shall develop and implement, on request of an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization, or assist the Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization to develop and implement, a program of community education on mental illness. In carrying out this paragraph, the Service shall, upon request of an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization, provide technical assistance to the Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization to obtain and develop community educational materials on the identification, prevention, referral, and treatment of mental illness and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a04-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>, the Secretary shall develop a plan under which the Service will increase the health care staff providing behavioral health services by at least 500 positions within 5 years after <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>, with at least 200 of such positions devoted to child, adolescent, and family services. The plan developed under this paragraph shall be implemented under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a05-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Staffing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a06-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 90 days after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall develop a plan under which the Service will increase the health care staff providing mental health services by at least 500 positions within five years after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, with at least 200 of such positions devoted to child, adolescent, and family services. Such additional staff shall be primarily assigned to the service unit level for services which shall include outpatient, emergency, aftercare and follow-up, and prevention and education services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a07-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The plan developed under paragraph (1) shall be implemented under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a08-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff recruitment and retention</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a09-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide for the recruitment of the additional personnel required by subsection (f) and the retention of all Service personnel providing mental health services. In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to practitioners providing mental health services to children and adolescents with mental health problems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a0a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall develop a program providing for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a0b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the payment of bonuses (which shall not be more favorable than those provided for under sections 1616i and 1616j of this title) for service in hardship posts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a0c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the repayment of loans (for which the provisions of repayment contracts shall not be more favorable than the repayment contracts under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1616a">section 1616a of this title</ref>) for health professions education as a recruitment incentive; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a0d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a system of postgraduate rotations as a retention incentive.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a0e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> This subsection shall be carried out in coordination with the recruitment and retention programs under subchapter I.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a0f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Mental Health Technician program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a10-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall establish and maintain a Mental Health Technician program within the Service which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a11-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provides for the training of Indians as mental health technicians; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a12-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> employs such technicians in the provision of community-based mental health care that includes identification, prevention, education, referral, and treatment services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a13-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In carrying out paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall provide high standard paraprofessional training in mental health care necessary to provide quality care to the Indian communities to be served. Such training shall be based upon a curriculum developed or approved by the Secretary which combines education in the theory of mental health care with supervised practical experience in the provision of such care.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a14-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall supervise and evaluate the mental health technicians in the training program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a15-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary shall ensure that the program established pursuant to this subsection involves the utilization and promotion of the traditional Indian health care and treatment practices of the Indian tribes to be served.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a16-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Mental health research</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Service and in consultation with the National Institute of Mental Health, shall enter into contracts with, or make grants to, appropriate institutions for the conduct of research on the incidence and prevalence of mental disorders among Indians on Indian reservations and in urban areas. Research priorities under this subsection shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a17-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the inter-relationship and inter-dependence of mental disorders with alcoholism, suicide, homicides, accidents, and the incidence of family violence, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a18-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the development of models of prevention techniques.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The effect of the inter-relationships and interdependencies referred to in paragraph (1) on children, and the development of prevention techniques under paragraph (2) applicable to children, shall be emphasized.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a19-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Facilities assessment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within one year after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Service, shall make an assessment of the need for inpatient mental health care among Indians and the availability and cost of inpatient mental health facilities which can meet such need. In making such assessment, the Secretary shall consider the possible conversion of existing, under-utilized service hospital beds into psychiatric units to meet such need.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a1a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Service shall develop methods for analyzing and evaluating the overall status of mental health programs and services for Indians and shall submit to the President, for inclusion in each report required to be transmitted to the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>, a report on the mental health status of Indians which shall describe the progress being made to address mental health problems of Indian communities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a1b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Mental health demonstration grant program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a1c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, acting through the Service, is authorized to make grants to Indian tribes and inter-tribal consortia to pay 75 percent of the cost of planning, developing, and implementing programs to deliver innovative community-based mental health services to Indians. The 25 percent tribal share of such cost may be provided in cash or through the provision of property or services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a1d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may award a grant for a project under paragraph (1) to an Indian tribe or inter-tribal consortium which meets the following criteria:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a1e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The project will address significant unmet mental health needs among Indians.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a1f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The project will serve a significant number of Indians.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a20-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The project has the potential to deliver services in an efficient and effective manner.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a21-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The tribe or consortium has the administrative and financial capability to administer the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a22-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The project will deliver services in a manner consistent with traditional Indian healing and treatment practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a23-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The project is coordinated with, and avoids duplication of, existing services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a24-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the Secretary shall, in evaluating applications for grants for projects to be operated under any contract entered into with the Service under the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321">25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.], use the same criteria that the Secretary uses in evaluating any other application for such a grant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a25-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary may only award one grant under this subsection with respect to a service area until the Secretary has awarded grants for all service areas with respect to which the Secretary receives applications during the application period, as determined by the Secretary, which meet the criteria specified in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a26-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Not later than 180 days after the close of the term of the last grant awarded pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report evaluating the effectiveness of the innovative community-based projects demonstrated pursuant to this subsection. Such report shall include findings and recommendations, if any, relating to the reorganization of the programs of the Service for delivery of mental health services to Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a27-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/k/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Grants made pursuant to this section may be expended over a period of three years and no grant may exceed $1,000,000 for the fiscal years involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a28-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Licensing requirement for mental health care workers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person employed as a psychologist, social worker, or marriage and family therapist for the purpose of providing mental health care services to Indians in a clinical setting under the authority of this chapter or through a contract pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321">25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.] shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a29-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of a person employed as a psychologist, be licensed as a clinical psychologist or working under the direct supervision of a licensed clinical psychologist;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a2a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the case of a person employed as a social worker, be licensed as a social worker or working under the direct supervision of a licensed social worker; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a2b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of a person employed as a marriage and family therapist, be licensed as a marriage and family therapist or working under the direct supervision of a licensed marriage and family therapist.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62642a2c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Intermediate adolescent mental health services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a2d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary, acting through the Service, may make grants to Indian tribes and tribal organizations to provide intermediate mental health services to Indian children and adolescents, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a2e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> inpatient and outpatient services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a2f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> emergency care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a30-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> suicide prevention and crisis intervention; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a31-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> prevention and treatment of mental illness, and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior, including child abuse and family violence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a32-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Funds provided under this subsection may be used—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a33-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to construct or renovate an existing health facility to provide intermediate mental health services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a34-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to hire mental health professionals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a35-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to staff, operate, and maintain an intermediate mental health facility, group home, or youth shelter where intermediate mental health services are being provided; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62642a36-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to make renovations and hire appropriate staff to convert existing hospital beds into adolescent psychiatric units.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a37-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Funds provided under this subsection may not be used for the purposes described in section 1621<i>o</i>(b)(1) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a38-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An Indian tribe or tribal organization receiving a grant under this subsection shall ensure that intermediate adolescent mental health services are coordinated with other tribal, Service, and Bureau of Indian Affairs mental health, alcohol and substance abuse, and social services programs on the reservation of such tribe or tribal organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62642a39-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1621h/m/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish criteria for the review and approval of applications for grants made pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62642a3a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/437/tII/s209">Pub. L. 94–437, title II, § 209</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/630/tV/s503/b">Pub. L. 101–630, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4557">104 Stat. 4557</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/tII">Pub. L. 102–573, title II</ref>, §§ 205, 217(b)(4), title IX, § 902(3), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4547">106 Stat. 4547</ref>, 4559, 4591; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10221/a">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10221(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/935">124 Stat. 935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62642a3b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62642a3c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62642a3d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (b)(6)(A), is subtitle C of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-137">100 Stat. 3207–137</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 26 (§ 2401 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of subtitle C to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2401">section 2401 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b)(6)(A) and (<i>l</i>), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/94/437">Pub. L. 94–437</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1400">90 Stat. 1400</ref>, known as the Indian Health Care Improvement Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450">25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.), referred to in subsec. (d)(3)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, which was classified principally to subchapter II (§ 450 et seq.) of chapter 14 of this title prior to editorial reclassification as chapter 46 (§ 5301 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Self-Determination Act, referred to in subsecs. (k)(3) and (<i>l</i>), is title I of <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2206">88 Stat. 2206</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 5321 et seq.) of chapter 46 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62642a3e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref> is based on sections 101(b)(2) and 127 of title I of S. 1790, One Hundred Eleventh Congress, as reported by the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate in Dec. 2009, which were enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10221/a">section 10221(a) of Pub. L. 111–148</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62642a3f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref> added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which related to mental health training and community education programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref> struck out par. (6) which authorized appropriations for fiscal years 1993 to 2000.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s902/3/A">Pub. L. 102–573, § 902(3)(A)</ref>, made technical amendment to section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s902/3/B">Pub. L. 102–573, § 902(3)(B)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (b). Prior to amendment, no subsec. (b) had been enacted.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 217(b)(4)(A), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and struck out par. (5) which authorized appropriations of $500,000 for fiscal year 1991 and $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec. Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 217(b)(4)(A), (D), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (e) as (d), substituted “this section” for “this subsection” in par. (3)(B), and struck out par. (6) which authorized appropriations of $500,000 for fiscal year 1991 and $5,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec., with certain amounts to be allocated for community education. Former subsec. (d) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s902/3/B">Pub. L. 102–573, § 902(3)(B)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 217(b)(4)(A), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (g) as (f) and struck out par. (4) which appropriated $1,200,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec. Former subsec. (f) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 217(b)(4)(A), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (h) as (g) and struck out par. (5) which authorized appropriation of $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 for purposes of providing training required under this subsec. Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 217(b)(4)(B), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (i) as (h), struck out par. (1) designation before “The Secretary, acting”, redesignated subpars. (A) and (B) as pars. (1) and (2), respectively, substituted “paragraph (1)” and “paragraph (2)” for “subparagraph (A)” and “subparagraph (B)”, respectively, in closing provisions, and struck out former par. (2) which authorized appropriation of $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec., to remain available until expended. Former subsec. (h) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 217(b)(4)(C), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (j) as (i), struck out par. (1) designation before “Within one year”, and struck out par. (2) which authorized appropriation of $500,000 for fiscal year 1992 to make the assessment required by this subsec. Former subsec. (i) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 205(1), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (k) as (j) and substituted “submit to the President, for inclusion in each report required to be transmitted to the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1671">section 1671 of this title</ref>, a report” for “submit to the Congress an annual report”. Former subsec. (j) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573">Pub. L. 102–573</ref>, §§ 217(b)(4)(E), 902(3)(B), redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (k), and in par. (6) substituted “section” for “subsection” in second sentence and struck out first sentence which authorized appropriations of $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1991 and $3,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out purposes of this subsec. Former subsec. (k) redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (<i>l</i>), (m). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s205/2">Pub. L. 102–573, § 205(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (<i>l</i>) and (m). Former subsec. (<i>l</i>) redesignated (k).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id62642a40-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id62642a41-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Statement of Purposes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/630/tV/s503/a">Pub. L. 101–630, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4556">104 Stat. 4556</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/630/tV/s503/a">
<inline>“The purposes of this section [enacting this section] are to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> authorize and direct the Indian Health Service to develop a comprehensive mental health prevention and treatment program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> provide direction and guidance relating to mental illness and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior, including child abuse and family violence, to those Federal, tribal, State, and local agencies responsible for programs in Indian communities in areas of health care, education, social services, child and family welfare, alcohol and substance abuse, law enforcement, and judicial services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> assist Indian tribes to identify services and resources available to address mental illness and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> provide authority and opportunities for Indian tribes to develop and implement, and coordinate with, community-based mental health programs which include identification, prevention, education, referral, and treatment services, including through multidisciplinary resource teams;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> ensure that Indians, as citizens of the United States and of the States in which they reside, have the same access to mental health services to which all such citizens have access; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> modify or supplement existing programs and authorities in the areas identified in paragraph (2).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
