<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id626d9f5f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d"><num value="1647d">§ 1647d.</num><heading> Navajo Nation medicaid agency feasibility study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9f60-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct a study to determine the feasibility of treating the Navajo Nation as a State for the purposes of title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.], to provide services to Indians living within the boundaries of the Navajo Nation through an entity established having the same authority and performing the same functions as single-State medicaid agencies responsible for the administration of the State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9f61-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consider the feasibility of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f62-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assigning and paying all expenditures for the provision of services and related administration funds, under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.], to Indians living within the boundaries of the Navajo Nation that are currently paid to or would otherwise be paid to the State of Arizona, New Mexico, or Utah;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f63-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing assistance to the Navajo Nation in the development and implementation of such entity for the administration, eligibility, payment, and delivery of medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f64-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> providing an appropriate level of matching funds for Federal medical assistance with respect to amounts such entity expends for medical assistance for services and related administrative costs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f65-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> authorizing the Secretary, at the option of the Navajo Nation, to treat the Navajo Nation as a State for the purposes of title XIX <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002080"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Social Security Act (relating to the State children’s health insurance program) under terms equivalent to those described in paragraphs (2) through (4).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002081">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002081"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be paragraphs “(1) through (3).”.</note></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9f66-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later then 3 years after <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs and Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f67-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the results of the study under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f68-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a summary of any consultation that occurred between the Secretary and the Navajo Nation, other Indian Tribes, the States of Arizona, New Mexico, and Utah, counties which include Navajo Lands, and other interested parties, in conducting this study;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f69-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> projected costs or savings associated with establishment of such entity, and any estimated impact on services provided as described in this section in relation to probable costs or savings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f6a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1647d/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> legislative actions that would be required to authorize the establishment of such entity if such entity is determined by the Secretary to be feasible.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id626d9f6b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/437/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 94–437, title IV, § 411</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10221/a">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10221(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/935">124 Stat. 935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id626d9f6c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id626d9f6d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id626d9f6e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Title XIX of the Act is classified generally to subchapter XIX (§ 1396 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Title XIX of the Social Security Act (relating to the State children’s health insurance program), referred to in subsec. (b)(4), probably means title XXI of the Act, which is classified generally to subchapter XXI (§ 1397aa et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42 and relates to the State Children’s Health Insurance Program. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id626d9f6f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/437/s411">Section 411 of Pub. L. 94–437</ref> is based on section 159 of title I of S. 1790, One Hundred Eleventh Congress, as reported by the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate in Dec. 2009, which was enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10221/a">section 10221(a) of Pub. L. 111–148</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
