<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id626d9f82-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653"><num value="1653">§ 1653.</num><heading> Contracts and grants for provision of health care and referral services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9f83-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>, the Secretary, through the Service, shall enter into contracts with, or make grants to, urban Indian organizations for the provision of health care and referral services for urban Indians residing in the urban centers in which such organizations are situated. Any such contract or grant shall include requirements that the urban Indian organization successfully undertake to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f84-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> estimate the population of urban Indians residing in the urban center in which such organization is situated who are or could be recipients of health care or referral services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f85-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> estimate the current health status of urban Indians residing in such urban center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f86-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> estimate the current health care needs of urban Indians residing in such urban center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f87-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identify all public and private health services resources within such urban center which are or may be available to urban Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f88-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> determine the use of public and private health services resources by the urban Indians residing in such urban center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f89-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> assist such health services resources in providing services to urban Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f8a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> assist urban Indians in becoming familiar with and utilizing such health services resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f8b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> provide basic health education, including health promotion and disease prevention education, to urban Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f8c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> establish and implement training programs to accomplish the referral and education tasks set forth in paragraphs (6) through (8) of this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f8d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> identify gaps between unmet health needs of urban Indians and the resources available to meet such needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f8e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> make recommendations to the Secretary and Federal, State, local, and other resource agencies on methods of improving health service programs to meet the needs of urban Indians; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f8f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> where necessary, provide, or enter into contracts for the provision of, health care services for urban Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9f90-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria for selection of organizations to enter into contracts or receive grants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, through the Service, shall by regulation prescribe the criteria for selecting urban Indian organizations to enter into contracts or receive grants under this section. Such criteria shall, among other factors, include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f91-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the extent of unmet health care needs of urban Indians in the urban center involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f92-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the size of the urban Indian population in the urban center involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f93-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the accessibility to, and utilization of, health care services (other than services provided under this subchapter) by urban Indians in the urban center involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f94-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> the extent, if any, to which the activities set forth in subsection (a) would duplicate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id626d9f95-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any previous or current public or private health services project in an urban center that was or is funded in a manner other than pursuant to this subchapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id626d9f96-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any project funded under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f97-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the capability of an urban Indian organization to perform the activities set forth in subsection (a) and to enter into a contract with the Secretary or to meet the requirements for receiving a grant under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f98-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the satisfactory performance and successful completion by an urban Indian organization of other contracts with the Secretary under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f99-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the appropriateness and likely effectiveness of conducting the activities set forth in subsection (a) in an urban center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f9a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the extent of existing or likely future participation in the activities set forth in subsection (a) by appropriate health and health-related Federal, State, local, and other agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9f9b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants for health promotion and disease prevention services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall facilitate access to, or provide, health promotion and disease prevention services for urban Indians through grants made to urban Indian organizations administering contracts entered into pursuant to this section or receiving grants under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9f9c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants for immunization services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9f9d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall facilitate access to, or provide, immunization services for urban Indians through grants made to urban Indian organizations administering contracts entered into pursuant to this section or receiving grants under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9f9e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In making any grant to carry out this subsection, the Secretary shall take into consideration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9f9f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the size of the urban Indian population to be served;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fa0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the immunization levels of the urban Indian population, particularly the immunization levels of infants, children, and the elderly;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fa1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the utilization by the urban Indians of alternative resources from State and local governments for no-cost or low-cost immunization services to the general population; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fa2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the capability of the urban Indian organization to carry out services pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9fa3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “immunization services” means services to provide without charge immunizations against vaccine-preventable diseases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9fa4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants for mental health services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9fa5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall facilitate access to, or provide, mental health services for urban Indians through grants made to urban Indian organizations administering contracts entered into pursuant to this section or receiving grants under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9fa6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A grant may not be made under this subsection to an urban Indian organization until that organization has prepared, and the Service has approved, an assessment of the mental health needs of the urban Indian population concerned, the mental health services and other related resources available to that population, the barriers to obtaining those services and resources, and the needs that are unmet by such services and resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9fa7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Grants may be made under this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fa8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to prepare assessments required under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fa9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to provide outreach, educational, and referral services to urban Indians regarding the availability of direct mental health services, to educate urban Indians about mental health issues and services, and effect coordination with existing mental health providers in order to improve services to urban Indians;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9faa-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to provide outpatient mental health services to urban Indians, including the identification and assessment of illness, therapeutic treatments, case management, support groups, family treatment, and other treatment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fab-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/e/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to develop innovative mental health service delivery models which incorporate Indian cultural support systems and resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id626d9fac-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants for prevention and treatment of child abuse</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9fad-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall facilitate access to, or provide, services for urban Indians through grants to urban Indian organizations administering contracts entered into pursuant to this section or receiving grants under subsection (a) to prevent and treat child abuse (including sexual abuse) among urban Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9fae-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A grant may not be made under this subsection to an urban Indian organization until that organization has prepared, and the Service has approved, an assessment that documents the prevalence of child abuse in the urban Indian population concerned and specifies the services and programs (which may not duplicate existing services and programs) for which the grant is requested.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9faf-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Grants may be made under this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fb0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to prepare assessments required under paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fb1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for the development of prevention, training, and education programs for urban Indian populations, including child education, parent education, provider training on identification and intervention, education on reporting requirements, prevention campaigns, and establishing service networks of all those involved in Indian child protection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fb2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to provide direct outpatient treatment services (including individual treatment, family treatment, group therapy, and support groups) to urban Indians who are child victims of abuse (including sexual abuse) or adult survivors of child sexual abuse, to the families of such child victims, and to urban Indian perpetrators of child abuse (including sexual abuse).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id626d9fb3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> In making grants to carry out this subsection, the Secretary shall take into consideration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fb4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the support for the urban Indian organization demonstrated by the child protection authorities in the area, including committees or other services funded under the Indian Child Welfare Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1901">25 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq.), if any;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fb5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the capability and expertise demonstrated by the urban Indian organization to address the complex problem of child sexual abuse in the community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id626d9fb6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1653/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the assessment required under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id626d9fb7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/437/tV/s503">Pub. L. 94–437, title V, § 503</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/713/tV/s501">Pub. L. 100–713, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1988-11-23">Nov. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4821">102 Stat. 4821</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/630/tV/s505">Pub. L. 101–630, title V, § 505</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4564">104 Stat. 4564</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/tV">Pub. L. 102–573, title V</ref>, §§ 501(b)(1), 505(b)(1), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4567">106 Stat. 4567</ref>, 4570.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id626d9fb8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id626d9fb9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id626d9fba-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Child Welfare Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (f)(4)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/608">Pub. L. 95–608</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3069">92 Stat. 3069</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 21 (§ 1901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id626d9fbb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1653, <ref href="/us/pl/94/437/tV/s503">Pub. L. 94–437, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1410">90 Stat. 1410</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/537/s7">Pub. L. 96–537, § 7</ref>, <date date="1980-12-17">Dec. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3177">94 Stat. 3177</ref>, related to contract eligibility, prior to the general revision of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/100/713">Pub. L. 100–713</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id626d9fbc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s501/b/1/G">Pub. L. 102–573, § 501(b)(1)(G)</ref>, inserted “and grants” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s501/b/1/A">Pub. L. 102–573, § 501(b)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “, or make grants to,” after “contracts with” and “or grant” after “such contract”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s501/b/1/B">Pub. L. 102–573, § 501(b)(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “or receive grants” after “enter into contracts” in introductory provisions and “or to meet the requirements for receiving a grant” after “Secretary” in par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s505/b/1/A">Pub. L. 102–573, § 505(b)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out par. (1) designation before “The Secretary, acting” and struck out par. (2) which authorized appropriation of $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s501/b/1/C">Pub. L. 102–573, § 501(b)(1)(C)</ref>, inserted before period at end “or receiving grants under subsection (a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s501/b/1/D">Pub. L. 102–573, § 501(b)(1)(D)</ref>, inserted before period at end “or receiving grants under subsection (a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s505/b/1/B">Pub. L. 102–573, § 505(b)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which authorized appropriation of $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s501/b/1/E">Pub. L. 102–573, § 501(b)(1)(E)</ref>, inserted before period at end “or receiving grants under subsection (a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s505/b/1/C">Pub. L. 102–573, § 505(b)(1)(C)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which authorized appropriations of $500,000 for fiscal year 1991 and $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s501/b/1/F">Pub. L. 102–573, § 501(b)(1)(F)</ref>, inserted “or receiving grants under subsection (a)” after “pursuant to this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/s505/b/1/D">Pub. L. 102–573, § 505(b)(1)(D)</ref>, struck out par. (5) which authorized appropriations of $500,000 for fiscal year 1991 and $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 to carry out this subsec.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsecs. (c) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/630">Pub. L. 101–630</ref> added subsecs. (c) to (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id626d9fbd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id626d9fbe-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Facilities Assessment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/630/tV/s506/a">Pub. L. 101–630, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4566">104 Stat. 4566</ref>, directed the Secretary to conduct a survey of all facilities used by contractors under title V of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1651">25 U.S.C. 1651</ref> et seq.) and submit a report to Congress on the survey not later than one year after <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, containing information for each location on safety and building codes, lease restrictions and requirements, and an assessment of any building deficiencies and recommendations for improvements.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
