<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6270112b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b"><num value="1665b">§ 1665b.</num><heading> Memoranda of agreement with the Department of the Interior</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6270112c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>, the Secretary, acting through the Service, and the Secretary of the Interior shall develop and enter into a memoranda <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002086"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “memorandum”.</note> of agreement, or review and update any existing memoranda of agreement, as required by section 4205 of the Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2411">25 U.S.C. 2411</ref>) under which the Secretaries address the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6270112d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The scope and nature of mental illness and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior, including child abuse and family violence, among Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6270112e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The existing Federal, tribal, State, local, and private services, resources, and programs available to provide behavioral health services for Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6270112f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The unmet need for additional services, resources, and programs necessary to meet the needs identified pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701130-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701131-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The right of Indians, as citizens of the United States and of the States in which they reside, to have access to behavioral health services to which all citizens have access.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701132-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The right of Indians to participate in, and receive the benefit of, such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701133-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The actions necessary to protect the exercise of such right.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701134-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The responsibilities of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Service, including mental illness identification, prevention, education, referral, and treatment services (including services through multidisciplinary resource teams), at the central, area, and agency and Service unit, Service area, and headquarters levels to address the problems identified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701135-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> A strategy for the comprehensive coordination of the behavioral health services provided by the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Service to meet the problems identified pursuant to paragraph (1), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62701136-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the coordination of alcohol and substance abuse programs of the Service, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, and Indian tribes and tribal organizations (developed under the Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2401">25 U.S.C. 2401</ref> et seq.)) with behavioral health initiatives pursuant to this chapter, particularly with respect to the referral and treatment of dually diagnosed individuals requiring behavioral health and substance abuse treatment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62701137-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ensuring that the Bureau of Indian Affairs and Service programs and services (including multidisciplinary resource teams) addressing child abuse and family violence are coordinated with such non-Federal programs and services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701138-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Directing appropriate officials of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Service, particularly at the agency and Service unit levels, to cooperate fully with tribal requests made pursuant to community behavioral health plans adopted under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1665a/c">section 1665a(c) of this title</ref> and section 4206 of the Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2412">25 U.S.C. 2412</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62701139-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Providing for an annual review of such agreement by the Secretaries which shall be provided to Congress and Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6270113a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific provisions required</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The memoranda of agreement updated or entered into pursuant to subsection (a) shall include specific provisions pursuant to which the Service shall assume responsibility for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6272813b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the determination of the scope of the problem of alcohol and substance abuse among Indians, including the number of Indians within the jurisdiction of the Service who are directly or indirectly affected by alcohol and substance abuse and the financial and human cost;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6272813c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an assessment of the existing and needed resources necessary for the prevention of alcohol and substance abuse and the treatment of Indians affected by alcohol and substance abuse; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6272813d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> an estimate of the funding necessary to adequately support a program of prevention of alcohol and substance abuse and treatment of Indians affected by alcohol and substance abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6272813e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1665b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each memorandum of agreement entered into or renewed (and amendments or modifications thereto) under subsection (a) shall be published in the Federal Register. At the same time as publication in the Federal Register, the Secretary shall provide a copy of such memoranda, amendment, or modification to each Indian tribe, tribal organization, and urban Indian organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6272813f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/437/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 94–437, title VII, § 703</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10221/a">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10221(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/935">124 Stat. 935</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62728140-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62728141-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62728142-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (a)(6)(A), is subtitle C of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-137">100 Stat. 3207–137</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 26 (§ 2401 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of subtitle C to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2401">section 2401 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(6)(A), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/94/437">Pub. L. 94–437</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1400">90 Stat. 1400</ref>, known as the Indian Health Care Improvement Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62728143-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/437/s703">Section 703 of Pub. L. 94–437</ref> is based on section 181 of title I of S. 1790, One Hundred Eleventh Congress, as reported by the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate in Dec. 2009, which was enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10221/a">section 10221(a) of Pub. L. 111–148</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id62728144-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1665b, <ref href="/us/pl/94/437/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 94–437, title VII, § 703</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/573/tVII/s702/a">Pub. L. 102–573, title VII, § 702(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4573">106 Stat. 4573</ref>, related to Indian women treatment programs, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1665f">section 1665f of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
