<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id620e41f6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s17"><num value="17">§ 17.</num><heading> Use of Bureau facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id620e41f7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s17/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may permit tribal governments and organizations and student organizations to use Bureau of Indian Affairs equipment, land, buildings, and other structures if such use does not interfere with the purpose for which they are administered by the Bureau and when such use benefits Indians or Federal or federally funded programs. The Secretary may charge the user for the cost of the utilities and other expenses incurred for the use. The amounts collected shall be credited to the appropriation or fund from which the expenses are paid and shall be available until the end of the fiscal year following the fiscal year in which collected. The Secretary’s decision to not permit a use under this section is final and shall not be subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id620e41f8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s17/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority provided by this section is in addition to, and not in derogation of, any other authority available to the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id620e41f9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s17/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation of liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The payment of any fee, or agreement to pay costs, to the Secretary shall not in any way or to any extent limit the right of the United States to rely upon sovereign immunity or any State or Federal statute limiting liability or damages from injuries sustained in connection with use under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id620e41fa-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/297/tV/s5405">Pub. L. 100–297, title V, § 5405</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/417">102 Stat. 417</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/427/s25">Pub. L. 100–427, § 25</ref>, <date date="1988-09-09">Sept. 9, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1613">102 Stat. 1613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id620e41fb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id620e41fc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id620e41fd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/427/s25/a">Pub. L. 100–427, § 25(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The Secretary of the Interior may permit tribal, student, and other non-Federal organizations to use facilities, lands, and equipment administered by the Bureau of Indian Affairs if such use does not interfere with the purpose for which the facilities, land, and equipment are administered by the Bureau. The Secretary of the Interior may charge the user for the actual or estimated additional cost of utilities or other expenses incurred because of the use and the amounts collected shall be credited to the appropriation or fund from which the expenses are paid.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/427/s25/b">Pub. L. 100–427, § 25(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6210b2fe-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id6210b2ff-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date and applicability of section, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/297/s6303">section 6303 of Pub. L. 100–297</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1988 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1071">section 1071 of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
