<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6280b26f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813"><num value="1813">§ 1813.</num><heading> Construction of new facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6280b270-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to any tribally controlled college or university for which the report of the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1812/a">section 1812(a) of this title</ref> identifies a need for new construction, the Secretary shall, subject to appropriations and on the basis of an application submitted in accordance with such requirements as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation, provide grants for such construction in accordance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6280b271-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to be eligible for a grant under this section, a tribally controlled college or university—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6280b272-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> must be a current recipient of grants under section 1805 or 1807 of this title, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6280b273-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> must be accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting agency listed by the Secretary of Education pursuant to the last sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of title 20</ref>, except that such requirement may be waived if the Secretary determines that there is a reasonable expectation that such college or university will be fully accredited within eighteen months. In any case where such a waiver is granted, grants under this section shall be available only for planning and development of proposals for construction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6280b274-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum amount of grant; waiver of restriction</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6280b275-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), grants for construction under this section shall not exceed 80 per centum of the cost of such construction, except that no tribally controlled college or university shall be required to expend more than $400,000 in fulfillment of the remaining 20 per centum. For the purpose of providing its required portion of the cost of such construction, a tribally controlled college or university may use funds provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6280b276-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, the requirements of paragraph (1) in the case of any tribally controlled college or university which demonstrates that neither such college or university nor the tribal government with which it is affiliated have sufficient resources to comply with such requirements. The Secretary shall base a decision on whether to grant such a waiver solely on the basis of the following factors: (A) tribal population; (B) potential student population; (C) the rate of unemployment among tribal members; (D) tribal financial resources; and (E) other factors alleged by the college or university to have a bearing on the availability of resources for compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1) and which may include the educational attainment of tribal members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6280b277-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to use facility in approved manner; title to vest in United States; settlement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, within twenty years after completion of construction of a facility which has been constructed in whole or in part with a grant made available under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6280b278-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the facility ceases to be used by the applicant in a public or nonprofit capacity as an academic facility, unless the Secretary determines that there is good cause for releasing the institution from this obligation, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6280b279-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the tribe with which the applicant is affiliated fails to use the facility for a public purpose approved by the tribal government in furtherance of the general welfare of the community served by the tribal government,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">title to the facility shall vest in the United States and the applicant (or such tribe if such tribe is the successor in title to the facility) shall be entitled to recover from the United States an amount which bears the same ratio to the present value of the facility as the amount of the applicant’s contribution (excluding any funds provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s13">section 13 of this title</ref>) bore to the original cost of the facility. Such value shall be determined by agreement of the parties or by action brought in the United States district court for the district in which such facility is located.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6280b27a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Religious use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No construction assisted with funds under this section shall be used for religious worship or a sectarian activity or for a school or department of divinity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6280b27b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> “Construction” and “academic facilities” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6280b27c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “construction” includes reconstruction or renovation (as such terms are defined in the first sentence of subparagraph (B) of section 1132e–1(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002112">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002112"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 20); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6280b27d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1813/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “academic facilities” has the meaning provided such term under section 1132e–1(1) <sup>1</sup> of title 20.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6280b27e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/471/tI/s113">Pub. L. 95–471, title I, § 113</ref>, formerly § 112, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1329">92 Stat. 1329</ref>; renumbered § 113 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/192">Pub. L. 98–192</ref>, §§ 4(a)(1), 12, <date date="1983-12-01">Dec. 1, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1336">97 Stat. 1336</ref>, 1340; <ref href="/us/pl/99/428/s6/b">Pub. L. 99–428, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-09-30">Sept. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/983">100 Stat. 983</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/a/8/C">Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(8)(C)</ref>, title IX, § 901(b)(5), (7), (12), <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1619">112 Stat. 1619</ref>, 1828.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6280b27f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6280b280-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6280b281-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1132e–1">Section 1132e–1 of title 20</ref>, referred to in subsec. (f), was omitted in the general revision of subchapter VII (§ 1132a et seq.) of chapter 28 of Title 20, Education, by <ref href="/us/pl/99/498/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 99–498, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1520">100 Stat. 1520</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6280b282-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s901/b/5">Pub. L. 105–244, § 901(b)(5)</ref>, substituted “college or university” for “community college”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s901/b/5">Pub. L. 105–244, § 901(b)(5)</ref>, substituted “college or university” for “community college” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, §§ 102(a)(8)(C), 901(b)(7), substituted “section 1001” for “section 1141(a)” and “such college or university” for “such college”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s901/b/5">Pub. L. 105–244, § 901(b)(5)</ref>, substituted “college or university” for “community college” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s901/b/5">Pub. L. 105–244, § 901(b)(5)</ref>, (7), (12), in introductory provisions, substituted “controlled college or university” for “controlled community college” and “such college or university” for “such college” and, in subpar. (E), substituted “the college or university” for “the college”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/428">Pub. L. 99–428</ref> substituted “Secretary under” for “Administrator of General Services under”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/192">Pub. L. 98–192</ref> amended section generally, substituting provision authorizing grants for construction of new facilities, establishing eligibility requirements for grants, maximum amounts of grants, waiver of amount restriction, results of failure to use facilities in an approved manner, and prohibition of religious use of such facilities, and defining “construction” and “academic facilities” for provision requiring Secretary of the Interior to conduct a detailed survey and study of academic facilities needs of tribally controlled community colleges and report to Congress not later than <date date="1979-11-01">Nov. 1, 1979</date>, the results of such survey and study.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6280b283-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6280b284-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-01">Oct. 1, 1998</date>, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
