<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62832436-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1911"><num value="1911">§ 1911.</num><heading> Indian tribe jurisdiction over Indian child custody proceedings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62832437-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1911/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusive jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An Indian tribe shall have jurisdiction exclusive as to any State over any child custody proceeding involving an Indian child who resides or is domiciled within the reservation of such tribe, except where such jurisdiction is otherwise vested in the State by existing Federal law. Where an Indian child is a ward of a tribal court, the Indian tribe shall retain exclusive jurisdiction, notwithstanding the residence or domicile of the child.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62832438-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1911/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of proceedings; declination by tribal court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any State court proceeding for the foster care placement of, or termination of parental rights to, an Indian child not domiciled or residing within the reservation of the Indian child’s tribe, the court, in the absence of good cause to the contrary, shall transfer such proceeding to the jurisdiction of the tribe, absent objection by either parent, upon the petition of either parent or the Indian custodian or the Indian child’s tribe: <i>Provided</i>, That such transfer shall be subject to declination by the tribal court of such tribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62832439-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1911/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State court proceedings; intervention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any State court proceeding for the foster care placement of, or termination of parental rights to, an Indian child, the Indian custodian of the child and the Indian child’s tribe shall have a right to intervene at any point in the proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6283243a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1911/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Full faith and credit to public acts, records, and judicial proceedings of Indian tribes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States, every State, every territory or possession of the United States, and every Indian tribe shall give full faith and credit to the public acts, records, and judicial proceedings of any Indian tribe applicable to Indian child custody proceedings to the same extent that such entities give full faith and credit to the public acts, records, and judicial proceedings of any other entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6283243b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/608/tI/s101">Pub. L. 95–608, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3071">92 Stat. 3071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
