<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62859479-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931"><num value="1931">§ 1931.</num><heading> Grants for on or near reservation programs and child welfare codes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6285947a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of purpose; scope of programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to make grants to Indian tribes and organizations in the establishment and operation of Indian child and family service programs on or near reservations and in the preparation and implementation of child welfare codes. The objective of every Indian child and family service program shall be to prevent the breakup of Indian families and, in particular, to insure that the permanent removal of an Indian child from the custody of his parent or Indian custodian shall be a last resort. Such child and family service programs may include, but are not limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6285947b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a system for licensing or otherwise regulating Indian foster and adoptive homes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6285947c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the operation and maintenance of facilities for the counseling and treatment of Indian families and for the temporary custody of Indian children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6285947d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> family assistance, including homemaker and home counselors, day care, afterschool care, and employment, recreational activities, and respite care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6285947e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> home improvement programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6285947f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the employment of professional and other trained personnel to assist the tribal court in the disposition of domestic relations and child welfare matters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62859480-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> education and training of Indians, including tribal court judges and staff, in skills relating to child and family assistance and service programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62859481-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> a subsidy program under which Indian adoptive children may be provided support comparable to that for which they would be eligible as foster children, taking into account the appropriate State standards of support for maintenance and medical needs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62859482-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> guidance, legal representation, and advice to Indian families involved in tribal, State, or Federal child custody proceedings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62859483-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1931/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-Federal matching funds for related Social Security or other Federal financial assistance programs; assistance for such programs unaffected; State licensing or approval for qualification for assistance under federally assisted program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds appropriated for use by the Secretary in accordance with this section may be utilized as non-Federal matching share in connection with funds provided under titles IV–B and XX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s620">42 U.S.C. 620</ref> et seq., 1397 et seq.] or under any other Federal financial assistance programs which contribute to the purpose for which such funds are authorized to be appropriated for use under this chapter. The provision or possibility of assistance under this chapter shall not be a basis for the denial or reduction of any assistance otherwise authorized under titles IV–B and XX of the Social Security Act or any other federally assisted program. For purposes of qualifying for assistance under a federally assisted program, licensing or approval of foster or adoptive homes or institutions by an Indian tribe shall be deemed equivalent to licensing or approval by a State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62859484-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/608/tII/s201">Pub. L. 95–608, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3075">92 Stat. 3075</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62859485-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62859486-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62859487-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Titles IV–B and XX of the Social Security Act are classified generally to part B (§ 620 et seq.) of subchapter IV and subchapter XX (§ 1397 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
