<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62098640-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1a"><num value="1a">§ 1a.</num><heading> Delegation of powers and duties by Secretary of the Interior and Commissioner of Indian Affairs</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of facilitating and simplifying the administration of the laws governing Indian affairs, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to delegate, from time to time, and to the extent and under such regulations as he deems proper, his powers and duties under said laws to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, insofar as such powers and duties relate to action in individual cases arising under general regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to law. Subject to the supervision and direction of the Secretary, the Commissioner is authorized to delegate, in like manner, any powers and duties so delegated to him by the Secretary, or vested in him by law, to the assistant commissioners, or the officer in charge of any branch, division, office, or agency of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, insofar as such powers and duties relate to action in individual cases arising under general regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior or the Commissioner of Indian Affairs pursuant to law. Such delegated powers shall be exercised subject to appeal to the Secretary, under regulations to be prescribed by him, or, as from time to time determined by him, to the Deputy Secretary or to an Assistant Secretary of the Department of the Interior, or to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs. The Secretary or the Commissioner, as the case may be, may at any time revoke the whole or any part of a delegation made pursuant to this section, but no such revocation shall be given retroactive effect. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to abrogate or curtail any authority to make delegations conferred by any other provision of law, nor shall anything in this section be deemed to convey authority to delegate any power to issue regulations.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id62098641-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-08/ch907">Aug. 8, 1946, ch. 907</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/939">60 Stat. 939</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/509/tV/s529/tI/s112/c">Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 112(c)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1427">104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1454.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62098642-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62098643-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62098644-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref> substituted “Deputy Secretary” for “Under Secretary” before “or to an Assistant Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id62098645-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id62098646-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref> effective on first day of first pay period beginning on or after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, with continued service by incumbent Under Secretary of the Interior, see section 529 [title I, § 112(e)(1), (2)(B)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3404">section 3404 of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id62098647-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assistant Commissioners</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">An assistant commissioner was authorized by a provision of <ref href="/us/act/1914-07-16/ch141/s1">act July 16, 1914, ch. 141, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/490">38 Stat. 490</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id62098648-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id62098649-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
