<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62917b9f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2102"><num value="2102">§ 2102.</num><heading> Minerals Agreements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62917ba0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2102/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization for tribes; approval by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any Indian tribe, subject to the approval of the Secretary and any limitation or provision contained in its constitution or charter, may enter into any joint venture, operating, production sharing, service, managerial, lease or other agreement, or any amendment, supplement or other modification of such agreement (hereinafter referred to as a “Minerals Agreement”) providing for the exploration for, or extraction, processing, or other development of, oil, gas, uranium, coal, geothermal, or other energy or nonenergy mineral resources (hereinafter referred to as “mineral resources”) in which such Indian tribe owns a beneficial or restricted interest, or providing for the sale or other disposition of the production or products of such mineral resources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62917ba1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2102/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion of individual holdings; approval by parties and Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any Indian owning a beneficial or restricted interest in mineral resources may include such resources in a tribal Minerals Agreement subject to the concurrence of the parties and a finding by the Secretary that such participation is in the best interest of the Indian.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62917ba2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/382/s3">Pub. L. 97–382, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-12-22">Dec. 22, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1938">96 Stat. 1938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
