<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62917be2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203"><num value="2203">§ 2203.</num><heading> Adoption of land consolidation plan with approval of Secretary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62917be3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of purpose; sales or exchanges: terms and conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any tribe, acting through its governing body, is authorized, with the approval of the Secretary to adopt a land consolidation plan providing for the sale or exchange of any tribal lands or interest in lands for the purpose of eliminating undivided fractional interests in Indian trust or restricted lands or consolidating its tribal landholdings: <i>Provided</i>, That—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62917be4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> except as provided by subsection (c), the sale price or exchange value received by the tribe for land or interests in land covered by this section shall be no less than within 10 per centum of the fair market value as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62917be5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the tribal land involved in an exchange is of greater or lesser value than the land for which it is being exchanged, the tribe may accept or give cash in such exchange in order to equalize the values of the property exchanged;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62917be6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any proceeds from the sale of land or interests in land or proceeds received by the tribe to equalize an exchange made pursuant to this section shall be used exclusively for the purchase of other land or interests in land;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62917be7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Secretary shall maintain a separate trust account for each tribe selling or exchanging land pursuant to this section consisting of the proceeds of the land sales and exchanges and shall release such funds only for the purpose of buying lands under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62917be8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> any tribe may retain the mineral rights to such sold or exchanged lands and the Secretary shall assist such tribe in determining the value of such mineral rights and shall take such value into consideration in determining the fair market value of such lands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62917be9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Conveyancing requirement; specific findings for nonexecution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary must execute such instrument of conveyance needed to effectuate a sale or exchange of tribal lands made pursuant to an approved tribal land consolidation plan unless he makes a specific finding that such sale or exchange is not in the best interest of the tribe or is not in compliance with the tribal land consolidation plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62917bea-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2203/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Below market value conveyance of Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma homesites</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may execute instruments of conveyance for less than fair market value to effectuate the transfer of lands used as homesites held, on <date date="1991-12-17">December 17, 1991</date>, by the United States in trust for the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma. Only the lands used as homesites, and described in the land consolidation plan of the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma approved by the Secretary on <date date="1987-02-06">February 6, 1987</date>, shall be subject to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62917beb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/459/tII/s204">Pub. L. 97–459, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2517">96 Stat. 2517</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/608/s1/1">Pub. L. 98–608, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3171">98 Stat. 3171</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/238/s3">Pub. L. 102–238, § 3</ref>, <date date="1991-12-17">Dec. 17, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1908">105 Stat. 1908</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62917bec-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62917bed-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62917bee-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/238/s3/1">Pub. L. 102–238, § 3(1)</ref>, substituted “(1) except as provided by subsection (c), the sale price” for “(1) the sale price”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/238/s3/2">Pub. L. 102–238, § 3(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/608">Pub. L. 98–608</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally, substituting “: <i>Provided</i>, That—” for period at end and inserting five numbered pars., thereby correcting errors originally contained in this section as enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/97/459">Pub. L. 97–459</ref>, the text of which had a portion of section 204 appearing in section 206 (classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2205">section 2205 of this title</ref>) as the result of inadvertent error in the execution of committee amendments (see House Report No. 97–908, <date date="1982-09-30">Sept. 30, 1982</date>) to the bill. <ref href="/us/pl/97/459">Pub. L. 97–459</ref> enacted subsec. (a) as ending with “tribal landholdings.”, and included portion of section 204 containing proviso and five numbered pars. within text of section 206.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/608">Pub. L. 98–608</ref> included subsec. (b) within this section and substituted a period for the dash after “tribal land consolidation plan”, thereby correcting errors originally contained in this section as enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/97/459">Pub. L. 97–459</ref>, which, as the result of inadvertent error in the execution of committee amendments (see House Report No. 97–908, <date date="1982-09-30">Sept. 30, 1982</date>) to the bill, enacted subsec. (b) as part of <ref href="/us/pl/97/459/s206/b">section 206(b) of Pub. L. 97–459</ref> and ended it with “tribal land consolidation plan—”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
