<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id621f0af8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s231"><num value="231">§ 231.</num><heading> Enforcement of State laws affecting health and education; entry of State employees on Indian lands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, under such rules and regulations as he may prescribe, shall permit the agents and employees of any State to enter upon Indian tribal lands, reservations, or allotments therein (1) for the purpose of making inspection of health and educational conditions and enforcing sanitation and quarantine regulations or (2) to enforce the penalties of State compulsory school attendance laws against Indian children, and parents, or other persons in loco parentis except that this subparagraph (2) shall not apply to Indians of any tribe in which a duly constituted governing body exists until such body has adopted a resolution consenting to such application.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id621f0af9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1929-02-15/ch216">Feb. 15, 1929, ch. 216</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/1185">45 Stat. 1185</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-09/ch930">Aug. 9, 1946, ch. 930</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/962">60 Stat. 962</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id621f0afa-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id621f0afb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id621f0afc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Act <date date="1946-08-09">Aug. 9, 1946</date>, permitted proper State officers to invoke penalties of State compulsory school attendance against Indian children, their parents, or other persons in loco parentis.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id621f0afd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id621f0afe-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
