<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id629af1cb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401"><num value="2401">§ 2401.</num><heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1cc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Federal Government has a historical relationship and unique legal and moral responsibility to Indian tribes and their members,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1cd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> included in this responsibility is the treaty, statutory, and historical obligation to assist the Indian tribes in meeting the health and social needs of their members,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1ce-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> alcoholism and alcohol and substance abuse is the most severe health and social problem facing Indian tribes and people today and nothing is more costly to Indian people than the consequences of alcohol and substance abuse measured in physical, mental, social, and economic terms,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1cf-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> alcohol and substance abuse is the leading generic risk factor among Indians, and Indians die from alcoholism at over 4 times the age-adjusted rates for the United States population and alcohol and substance misuse results in a rate of years of potential life lost nearly 5 times that of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> 4 of the top 10 causes of death among Indians are alcohol and drug related injuries (18 percent of all deaths), chronic liver disease and cirrhosis (5 percent), suicide (3 percent), and homicide (3 percent),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> primarily because deaths from unintentional injuries and violence occur disproportionately among young people, the age-specific death rate for Indians is approximately double the United States rate for the 15 to 45 age group,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Indians between the ages of 15 and 24 years of age are more than 2 times as likely to commit suicide as the general population and approximately 80 percent of those suicides are alcohol-related,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Indians between the ages of 15 and 24 years of age are twice as likely as the general population to die in automobile accidents, 75 percent of which are alcohol-related,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> the Indian Health Service, which is charged with treatment and rehabilitation efforts, has directed only 1 percent of its budget for alcohol and substance abuse problems,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> the Bureau of Indian Affairs, which has responsibility for programs in education, social services, law enforcement, and other areas, has assumed little responsibility for coordinating its various efforts to focus on the epidemic of alcohol and substance abuse among Indian people,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> this lack of emphasis and priority continues despite the fact that Bureau of Indian Affairs and Indian Health Service officials publicly acknowledge that alcohol and substance abuse among Indians is the most serious health and social problem facing the Indian people, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id629af1d7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2401/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> the Indian tribes have the primary responsibility for protecting and ensuring the well-being of their members and the resources made available under this chapter will assist Indian tribes in meeting that responsibility.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id629af1d8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/570/tIV/s4202">Pub. L. 99–570, title IV, § 4202</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-137">100 Stat. 3207–137</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id629af1d9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id629af1da-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id629af1db-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in par. (12), was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle C of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-137">100 Stat. 3207–137</ref>, known as the Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of subtitle C to the Code, see Short Title note below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id629d61dc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id629d61dd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/570/tIV/s4201">Pub. L. 99–570, title IV, § 4201</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-137">100 Stat. 3207–137</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/570/tIV/s4201">“This subtitle [subtitle C (§§ 4201–4230) of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref>, enacting this chapter, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1302">section 1302 of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1302">section 1302 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Indian Alcohol and Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 1986’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id629d61de-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction for <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tII/s2219">Pub. L. 100–690, title II, § 2219</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4222">102 Stat. 4222</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/690/tII/s2219">“Except as otherwise provided in this Act or the amendments made by this Act [see Tables for classification], nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to affect the obligation of the United States to any Indian or Indian tribe arising out of any treaty, statute, Executive order, or the trust responsibility of the United States owing to such Indian or Indian tribe. Nothing in this section shall exempt any individual Indian from the sanctions of ‘user accountability’ provided for elsewhere in this Act: <i>Provided</i>, That no individual Indian shall be denied any benefit under Federal Indian programs comparable to those ‘means tested’ safety net programs otherwise excluded under this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
