<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id629fd3ff-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2454"><num value="2454">§ 2454.</num><heading> Model Indian Juvenile Code</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, either directly or by contract, shall provide for the development of a Model Indian Juvenile Code which shall be consistent with the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11101">34 U.S.C. 11101</ref> et seq.] and which shall include provisions relating to the disposition of cases involving Indian youth arrested or detained by Bureau of Indian Affairs or tribal law enforcement personnel for alcohol or drug related offenses. The development of such model code <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002160">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002160"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Model Code”.</note> shall be accomplished in cooperation with Indian organizations having an expertise or knowledge in the field of law enforcement and judicial procedure and in consultation with Indian tribes. Upon completion of the Model Code, the Secretary shall make copies available to each Indian tribe.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id629fd400-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/570/tIV/s4221">Pub. L. 99–570, title IV, § 4221</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-147">100 Stat. 3207–147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id629fd401-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id629fd402-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id629fd403-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/93/415">Pub. L. 93–415</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1109">88 Stat. 1109</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 111 (§ 11101 et seq.) of Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1974 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of Title 34</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
