<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62a6d87d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711"><num value="2711">§ 2711.</num><heading> Management contracts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d87e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Class II gaming activity; information on operators</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62a6d87f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to the approval of the Chairman, an Indian tribe may enter into a management contract for the operation and management of a class II gaming activity that the Indian tribe may engage in under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2710/b/1">section 2710(b)(1) of this title</ref>, but, before approving such contract, the Chairman shall require and obtain the following information:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d880-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the name, address, and other additional pertinent background information on each person or entity (including individuals comprising such entity) having a direct financial interest in, or management responsibility for, such contract, and, in the case of a corporation, those individuals who serve on the board of directors of such corporation and each of its stockholders who hold (directly or indirectly) 10 percent or more of its issued and outstanding stock;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d881-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of any previous experience that each person listed pursuant to subparagraph (A) has had with other gaming contracts with Indian tribes or with the gaming industry generally, including specifically the name and address of any licensing or regulatory agency with which such person has had a contract relating to gaming; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d882-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a complete financial statement of each person listed pursuant to subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62a6d883-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any person listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall be required to respond to such written or oral questions that the Chairman may propound in accordance with his responsibilities under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62a6d884-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of this chapter, any reference to the management contract described in paragraph (1) shall be considered to include all collateral agreements to such contract that relate to the gaming activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d885-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chairman may approve any management contract entered into pursuant to this section only if he determines that it provides at least—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d886-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> for adequate accounting procedures that are maintained, and for verifiable financial reports that are prepared, by or for the tribal governing body on a monthly basis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d887-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for access to the daily operations of the gaming to appropriate tribal officials who shall also have a right to verify the daily gross revenues and income made from any such tribal gaming activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d888-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> for a minimum guaranteed payment to the Indian tribe that has preference over the retirement of development and construction costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d889-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> for an agreed ceiling for the repayment of development and construction costs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d88a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> for a contract term not to exceed five years, except that, upon the request of an Indian tribe, the Chairman may authorize a contract term that exceeds five years but does not exceed seven years if the Chairman is satisfied that the capital investment required, and the income projections, for the particular gaming activity require the additional time; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d88b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> for grounds and mechanisms for terminating such contract, but actual contract termination shall not require the approval of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d88c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Fee based on percentage of net revenues</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62a6d88d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Chairman may approve a management contract providing for a fee based upon a percentage of the net revenues of a tribal gaming activity if the Chairman determines that such percentage fee is reasonable in light of surrounding circumstances. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, such fee shall not exceed 30 percent of the net revenues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62a6d88e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Upon the request of an Indian tribe, the Chairman may approve a management contract providing for a fee based upon a percentage of the net revenues of a tribal gaming activity that exceeds 30 percent but not 40 percent of the net revenues if the Chairman is satisfied that the capital investment required, and income projections, for such tribal gaming activity require the additional fee requested by the Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d88f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Period for approval; extension</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">By no later than the date that is 180 days after the date on which a management contract is submitted to the Chairman for approval, the Chairman shall approve or disapprove such contract on its merits. The Chairman may extend the 180-day period by not more than 90 days if the Chairman notifies the Indian tribe in writing of the reason for the extension. The Indian tribe may bring an action in a United States district court to compel action by the Chairman if a contract has not been approved or disapproved within the period required by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d890-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Disapproval</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chairman shall not approve any contract if the Chairman determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d891-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> any person listed pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62a6d892-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is an elected member of the governing body of the Indian tribe which is the party to the management contract;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62a6d893-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has been or subsequently is convicted of any felony or gaming offense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62a6d894-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has knowingly and willfully provided materially important false statements or information to the Commission or the Indian tribe pursuant to this chapter or has refused to respond to questions propounded pursuant to subsection (a)(2); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62a6d895-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> has been determined to be a person whose prior activities, criminal record if any, or reputation, habits, and associations pose a threat to the public interest or to the effective regulation and control of gaming, or create or enhance the dangers of unsuitable, unfair, or illegal practices, methods, and activities in the conduct of gaming or the carrying on of the business and financial arrangements incidental thereto;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d896-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the management contractor has, or has attempted to, unduly interfere or influence for its gain or advantage any decision or process of tribal government relating to the gaming activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d897-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the management contractor has deliberately or substantially failed to comply with the terms of the management contract or the tribal gaming ordinance or resolution adopted and approved pursuant to this chapter; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62a6d898-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a trustee, exercising the skill and diligence that a trustee is commonly held to, would not approve the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d899-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Modification or voiding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chairman, after notice and hearing, shall have the authority to require appropriate contract modifications or may void any contract if he subsequently determines that any of the provisions of this section have been violated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d89a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest in land</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No management contract for the operation and management of a gaming activity regulated by this chapter shall transfer or, in any other manner, convey any interest in land or other real property, unless specific statutory authority exists and unless clearly specified in writing in said contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d89b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority of the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s81">section 81 of this title</ref>, relating to management contracts regulated pursuant to this chapter, is hereby transferred to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62a6d89c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s2711/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigation fee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall require a potential contractor to pay a fee to cover the cost of the investigation necessary to reach a determination required in subsection (e) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62a6d89d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/497/s12">Pub. L. 100–497, § 12</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2479">102 Stat. 2479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62a6d89e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62a6d89f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62a6d8a0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3), (e)(1)(C), (3), (g), and (h), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/100/497">Pub. L. 100–497</ref>, <date date="1988-10-17">Oct. 17, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2467">102 Stat. 2467</ref>, known as the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s2701">section 2701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
