<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id621f0b4c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s272"><num value="272">§ 272.</num><heading> Superintendent of Indian schools</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a person of knowledge and experience in the management, training, and practical education of children, to be Superintendent of Indian Schools, whose duty it shall be to visit and inspect the schools in which Indians are taught in whole or in part from appropriations from the United States Treasury, and report to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, what, in his judgment, are the defects, if any, in any of them, in system, in administration, or in means for the most effective advancement of the pupils therein toward civilization and self-support, and what changes are needed to remedy such defects as may exist, and to perform such other duties in connection with Indian schools as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id621f0b4d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1889-03-02/ch412/s10">Mar. 2, 1889, ch. 412, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/25/1003">25 Stat. 1003</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id621f0b4e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id621f0b4f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id621f0b50-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
