<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id622154a7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s292b"><num value="292b">§ 292b.</num><heading> Establishment of single system of education in Alaska; transfer of Indian schools to State of Alaska</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Bureau of Indian Affairs shall not expend any other funds for the operation of any secondary education program or facility in the State of Alaska after <date date="1983-06-30">June 30, 1983</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That while consultation concerning day school transfers to the State of Alaska will continue with affected villages, local concurrence is not required in this continuing effort to establish a single system of education envisioned by the State’s constitution: <i>Provided further</i>, That after <date date="1984-06-30">June 30, 1984</date>, the Bureau of Indian Affairs shall fund no more than ten day schools in Alaska: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Bureau of Indian Affairs shall not fund any schools in Alaska after <date date="1985-06-30">June 30, 1985</date>: <i>Provided further</i>, That $9,350,000 of such amount shall be available until expended for transfer to the State of Alaska to assist in the rehabilitation or reconstruction of Bureau-owned schools which are transferred to the State: <i>Provided further</i>, That the $9,350,000 appropriated in <ref href="/us/pl/97/394">Public Law 97–394</ref> available to the State of Alaska to assist in the rehabilitation of Bureau-owned schools which are transferred to the State may also be used for reconstruction: <i>Provided further</i>, That when any Alaska day school operated by contract is transferred, the State shall assume any existing contract pertaining to the operation or maintenance of such school for a minimum of two years or until the expiration of the negotiated contract, whichever comes first: <i>Provided further</i>, That nothing in the foregoing shall preclude assistance otherwise available under the Act of <date date="1934-04-16">April 16, 1934</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/48/596">48 Stat. 596</ref>) as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s452">25 U.S.C. 452</ref> et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002014">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002014"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or any other Act to such schools on the same basis as other public schools.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id622154a8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/63/tI">Pub. L. 98–63, title I</ref>, <date date="1983-07-30">July 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/326">97 Stat. 326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id622154a9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id622154aa-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id622154ab-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Other funds, referred to in text, means funds other than the appropriation of $22,000,000 made available to the Bureau of Indian Affairs for transfer to the State of Alaska for the benefit of Alaska Native secondary students under the headings “Bureau of Indian Affairs” and “Operation of Indian Programs” in chapter VII of <ref href="/us/pl/98/63/tI">Pub. L. 98–63, title I</ref>, <date date="1983-07-30">July 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/326">97 Stat. 326</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">$9,350,000 of such amount, referred to in text, means $9,350,000 of the $53,150,000 appropriated as an additional amount for the operation of Indian programs by the Bureau of Indian Affairs under the headings “Bureau of Indian Affairs” and “Operation of Indian Programs” in chapter VII of <ref href="/us/pl/98/63/tI">Pub. L. 98–63, title I</ref>, <date date="1983-07-30">July 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/326">97 Stat. 326</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/394">Public Law 97–394</ref>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/97/394">Pub. L. 97–394</ref>, <date date="1982-12-30">Dec. 30, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1966">96 Stat. 1966</ref>. Provisions of that act relating to an appropriation of $9,350,000 available to the State of Alaska (<ref href="/us/stat/96/1974">96 Stat. 1974</ref>) are not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1934-04-16">April 16, 1934</date>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1934-04-16/ch147">act Apr. 16, 1934, ch. 147</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/596">48 Stat. 596</ref>, popularly known as the Johnson-O’Malley Act, which was classified generally to section 452 et seq. of this title prior to editorial reclassification as sections 5342 et seq. of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
