<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6223c50d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s305c"><num value="305c">§ 305c.</num><heading> Appropriation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated out of any sums in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated such sums as may be necessary to defray the expenses of the Board and carry out the purposes and provisions of this Act. All income derived by the Board from any source shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States and shall constitute a special fund which is appropriated and made available until expended for carrying out the purposes and provisions of this Act. Out of the funds available to it at any time the Board may authorize such expenditures, consistent with the provisions of this Act, as it may determine to be necessary for the accomplishment of the purposes and objectives of this Act.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6223c50e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-27/ch748/s4">Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/892">49 Stat. 892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6223c50f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6223c510-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id6223c511-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-27/ch748">act Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 748</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/891">49 Stat. 891</ref>, which is classified generally to section 305 et seq. of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id6223c512-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6223c513-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
