<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62ba12b7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307"><num value="3307">§ 3307.</num><heading> Administrative provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62ba12b8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62ba12b9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Role of Director</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Applications for grants under this subchapter, and all application modifications, shall be reviewed and approved by personnel under the direction and control of the Director of the Office of Indian Education Programs. Required reports shall be submitted to education personnel under the direction and control of the Director of such Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62ba12ba-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All provisions of sections 5, 6, 7, 105, 109, and 110 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450c">25 U.S.C. 450c</ref> et seq.),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002215">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002215"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> except those provisions pertaining to indirect costs and length of contract, shall apply to grants provided under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62ba12bb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to issue regulations relating to the discharge of duties specifically assigned to the Secretary by this subchapter. In all other matters relating to the details of planning, development, implementing, and evaluating grants under this subchapter, the Secretary shall not issue regulations. Regulations issued pursuant to this subchapter shall not have the standing of a Federal statute for the purposes of judicial review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62ba12bc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Retrocession</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever an Indian tribe requests retrocession of any program for which assistance is provided under this subchapter, such retrocession shall become effective upon a date specified by the Secretary not more than 120 days after the date on which the tribe requests the retrocession, or such later date as may be mutually agreed upon by the Secretary and the tribe. If such a program is retroceded, the Secretary shall provide to any Indian tribe served by such program at least the same quantity and quality of services that would have been provided under such program at the level of funding provided under this subchapter prior to the retrocession. The tribal governing body requesting the retrocession shall specify whether the retrocession shall be to a contract administered by the tribe, or a tribal entity, under the authority of the Indian Self-Determination Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321">25 U.S.C. 5321</ref> et seq.] or to a Bureau administered program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62ba12bd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62ba12be-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62ba12bf-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3307/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The terms “Indian” and “Indian tribe” have the same meaning given those terms in sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002216">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002216"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> 4(d) and (e), respectively, of the Indian Self Determination and Education Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304/d">25 U.S.C. 5304(d)</ref>, (e)].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62ba12c0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/325/tXIII/s1317">Pub. L. 102–325, title XIII, § 1317</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/802">106 Stat. 802</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62ba12c1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62ba12c2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62ba12c3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 5, 6, 7, 105, 109, and 110 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450c">25 U.S.C. 450c</ref> et seq.), referred to in subsec. (c), are sections 5, 6, 7, 105, 109, and 110 of <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, which were classified to sections 450c, 450d, 450e, 450j, 450m, and 450m–1, respectively, of this title prior to editorial reclassification as sections 5305, 5306, 5307, 5324, 5330, and 5331, respectively, of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Self-Determination Act, referred to in subsec. (e), is title I of <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2206">88 Stat. 2206</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 5321 et seq.) of chapter 46 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62ba12c4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a) of this section, which required the Secretary to submit a biennial report to Congress on programs established under this subchapter, terminated, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance. See, also, page 79 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
