<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62c3887c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703"><num value="3703">§ 3703.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3887d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Indian agricultural lands” means Indian land, including farmland and rangeland, but excluding Indian forest land, that is used for the production of agricultural products, and Indian lands occupied by industries that support the agricultural community, regardless of whether a formal inspection and land classification has been conducted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3887e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The term “agricultural product” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c3887f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> crops grown under cultivated conditions whether used for personal consumption, subsistence, or sold for commercial benefit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38880-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> domestic livestock, including cattle, sheep, goats, horses, buffalo, swine, reindeer, fowl, or other animal specifically raised and utilized for food or fiber or as beast of burden;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38881-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> forage, hay, fodder, feed grains, crop residues and other items grown or harvested for the feeding and care of livestock, sold for commercial profit, or used for other purposes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38882-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> other marketable or traditionally used materials authorized for removal from Indian agricultural lands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c38883-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The term “agricultural resource” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38884-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all the primary means of production, including the land, soil, water, air, plant communities, watersheds, human resources, natural and physical attributes, and man-made developments, which together comprise the agricultural community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38885-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all the benefits derived from Indian agricultural lands and enterprises, including cultivated and gathered food products, fibers, horticultural products, dyes, cultural or religious condiments, medicines, water, aesthetic, and other traditional values of agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c38886-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “agricultural resource management plan” means a plan developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s3711/b">section 3711(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c38887-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c38888-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “farmland” means Indian land excluding Indian forest land that is used for production of food, feed, fiber, forage and seed oil crops, or other agricultural products, and may be either dryland, irrigated, or irrigated pasture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c38889-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “Indian forest land” means forest land as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s3103/3">section 3103(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3888a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “Indian” means an individual who is a member of an Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3888b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> The term “Indian land” means land that is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c3888c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> held in trust by the United States for an Indian tribe; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c3888d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> owned by an Indian or Indian tribe and is subject to restrictions against alienation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3888e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3888f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “integrated resource management plan” means the plan developed pursuant to the process used by tribal governments to assess available resources and to provide identified holistic management objectives that include quality of life, production goals and landscape descriptions of all designated resources that may include (but not be limited to) water, fish, wildlife, forestry, agriculture, minerals, and recreation, as well as community and municipal resources, and may include any previously adopted tribal codes and plans related to such resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c38890-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><chapeau> The term “land management activity” means all activities, accomplished in support of the management of Indian agricultural lands, including (but not limited to)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38891-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> preparation of soil and range inventories, farmland and rangeland management plans, and monitoring programs to evaluate management plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38892-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> agricultural lands and on-farm irrigation delivery system development, and the application of state of the art, soil and range conservation management techniques to restore and ensure the productive potential of Indian lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38893-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> protection against agricultural pests, including development, implementation, and evaluation of integrated pest management programs to control noxious weeds, undesirable vegetation, and vertebrate or invertebrate agricultural pests;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38894-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/12/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> administration and supervision of agricultural leasing and permitting activities, including determination of proper land use, carrying capacities, and proper stocking rates of livestock, appraisal, advertisement, negotiation, contract preparation, collecting, recording, and distributing lease rental receipts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38895-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/12/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> technical assistance to individuals and tribes engaged in agricultural production or agribusiness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38896-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/12/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> educational assistance in agriculture, natural resources, land management and related fields of study, including direct assistance to tribally-controlled community colleges in developing and implementing curriculum for vocational, technical, and professional course work.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c38897-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><chapeau> The term “Indian landowner” means the Indian or Indian tribe that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38898-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/13/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> owns such Indian land, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62c38899-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/13/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is the beneficiary of the trust under which such Indian land is held by the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3889a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The term “rangeland” means Indian land, excluding Indian forest land, on which the native vegetation is predominantly grasses, grass-like plants, forbs, half-shrubs or shrubs suitable for grazing or browsing use, and includes lands revegetated naturally or artificially to provide a forage cover that is managed as native vegetation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c3889b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3703/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id62c3889c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/177/s4">Pub. L. 103–177, § 4</ref>, <date date="1993-12-03">Dec. 3, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2012">107 Stat. 2012</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62c3889d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62c3889e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62c3889f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, referred to in par. (10), is <ref href="/us/pl/92/203">Pub. L. 92–203</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/688">85 Stat. 688</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1601 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">section 1601 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
