<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6234670e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s385c"><num value="385c">§ 385c.</num><heading> Appropriation and disposition of power revenues</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Revenues collected after <date date="1946-08-07">August 7, 1946</date>, from power operations on each Indian irrigation project and deposited into the Treasury for credit to miscellaneous receipts pursuant to section 4 of the Permanent Appropriation Repeal Act, 1934 (<ref href="/us/stat/48/1227">48 Stat. 1227</ref>), or pursuant to other provisions of law, are authorized to be appropriated annually, in specific or in indefinite amounts, equal to the collections so credited, for the following purposes in connection with the respective projects from which such revenues are derived: (1) Payment of the expenses of operating and maintaining the power system; (2) creation and maintenance of reserve funds to be available for making repairs and replacements to, defraying emergency expenses for, and insuring continuous operation of the power system, the fund for each project to be maintained at such level, within limits set by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, as may from time to time be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior; (3) amortization, in accordance with the repayment provisions of the applicable statutes or contracts, of construction costs allocated to be returned from power revenues; and (4) payment of other expenses and obligations chargeable to power revenues to the extent required or permitted by law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6234670f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-07/ch802/s3">Aug. 7, 1946, ch. 802, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/895">60 Stat. 895</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 7959, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2085">84 Stat. 2085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62346710-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62346711-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62346712-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 4 of the Permanent Appropriation Repeal Act, 1934, referred to in text, is section 4 of <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch756">act June 26, 1934, ch. 756</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1227">48 Stat. 1227</ref>, which was classified to section 725c of former Title 31, and was omitted from the Code in the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258">Pub. L. 97–258</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62346713-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s725s–3">section 725s–3 of Title 31</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id62346714-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id62346715-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All functions vested by law (including reorganization plan) in Bureau of the Budget or Director of Bureau of the Budget transferred to President by section 101 of Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1970, eff. <date date="1970-07-01">July 1, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 7959, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2085">84 Stat. 2085</ref>. Section 102 of Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1970, redesignated Bureau of the Budget as Office of Management and Budget.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
