<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6234673d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s390"><num value="390">§ 390.</num><heading> Concessions on reservoir sites and other lands in Indian irrigation projects; leases for agricultural, grazing, and other purposes</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior be, and he is hereby, authorized, in his discretion, to grant concessions on reservoir sites, reserves for canals or flowage areas, and other lands under his jurisdiction which have been withdrawn or otherwise acquired in connection with the San Carlos, Fort Hall, Flathead, and Duck Valley or Western Shoshone irrigation projects for the benefit in whole or in part of Indians, and to lease such lands for agricultural, grazing, or other purposes: <i>Provided</i>, That no lands so leased shall be eligible for benefit payments under the crop control program, or the soil conservation act: <i>Provided further</i>, That such concessions may be granted or lands leased by the Secretary of the Interior under such rules, regulations, and laws as govern his administration of the public domain as far as applicable, for such considerations, monetary or otherwise, and for such periods of time as he may deem proper, the term of no concession to exceed a period of ten years: <i>Provided further</i>, That the funds derived from such concessions or leases, except funds so derived from Indian tribal property withdrawn for irrigation purposes and for which the tribe has not been compensated, shall be available for expenditure in accordance with the existing laws in the operation and maintenance of the irrigation projects with which they are connected. Any funds derived from reserves for which the tribe has not been compensated shall be deposited to the credit of the proper tribe: <i>Provided further</i>, That where tribal lands of any Indian tribe organized under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5123">section 5123 of this title</ref>, have been withdrawn or reserved for the purposes hereinbefore mentioned, such lands may be leased or concessions may be granted thereon only by the proper tribal authorities, upon such conditions and subject to such limitations as may be set forth in the constitution and bylaws or charter of the respective tribes: <i>Provided further</i>, That concessions for recreation and fish and wildlife purposes on San Carlos Lake may be granted only by the governing body of the San Carlos Apache Tribe upon such conditions and subject to such limitations as may be set forth in the constitution and bylaws of such Tribe.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6234673e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-04-04/ch63">Apr. 4, 1938, ch. 63</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/193">52 Stat. 193</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/575/tXXXVII/s3710/e">Pub. L. 102–575, title XXXVII, § 3710(e)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-30">Oct. 30, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4750">106 Stat. 4750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6234673f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62346740-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62346741-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/575">Pub. L. 102–575</ref> inserted before period at end “: <i>Provided further</i>, That concessions for recreation and fish and wildlife purposes on San Carlos Lake may be granted only by the governing body of the San Carlos Apache Tribe upon such conditions and subject to such limitations as may be set forth in the constitution and bylaws of such Tribe”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id62346742-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id62346743-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/575/tXXXVII/s3711">Pub. L. 102–575, title XXXVII, § 3711</ref>, <date date="1992-10-30">Oct. 30, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4751">106 Stat. 4751</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/435/s13">Pub. L. 103–435, § 13</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4572">108 Stat. 4572</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/91/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 104–91, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/14">110 Stat. 14</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/261/s3">Pub. L. 104–261, § 3</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3176">110 Stat. 3176</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/18/tII/s5003/a">Pub. L. 105–18, title II, § 5003(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1997-06-12">June 12, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/181">111 Stat. 181</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/18/tII/s5003/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date of Authorization</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The authorization contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s3708/b">section 3708(b) of this title</ref> [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4748">106 Stat. 4748</ref>] shall become effective as of the date the Secretary causes to be published in the Federal Register a statement of findings [The statement was published in the Federal Register on <date date="1999-12-28">Dec. 28, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 72674.] that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Secretary has fulfilled the requirements of sections 3704 and 3706 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4742">106 Stat. 4742</ref>, 4745];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Roosevelt Water Conservation District subcontract for agricultural water service from CAP has been revised and executed as provided in section 3705(b) [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4744">106 Stat. 4744</ref>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the funds authorized by section 3707(c) [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4748">106 Stat. 4748</ref>] have been appropriated and deposited into the Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the contract referred to in section 3707(a)(2) [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4747">106 Stat. 4747</ref>] has been amended;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the State of Arizona has appropriated and deposited into the Fund $3,000,000 as required by the Agreement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the stipulations attached to the Agreement as Exhibits ‘D’ and ‘E’ have been approved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the Agreement has been modified, to the extent it is in conflict with this title [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1524">section 1524 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1524">section 1524 of Title 43</ref>], and has been executed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the actions described in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7) of subsection (a) of this section have not occurred by <date date="1999-03-31">March 31, 1999</date>, subsections (c) and (d) of section 3704 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4743">106 Stat. 4743</ref>], subsections (a) and (b) of section 3705 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4744">106 Stat. 4744</ref>], section 3706 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4745">106 Stat. 4745</ref>], subsections (a)(2), (c), (d), and (f) of section 3707 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4747">106 Stat. 4747</ref>], subsections (b) and (c) of section 3708 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4748">106 Stat. 4748</ref>], and subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (g), (h), (j), and (<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s3710">section 3710 of this title</ref> [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4750">106 Stat. 4750</ref>, subsec. (e) amends this section], together with any contracts entered into pursuant to any such section or subsection, shall not be effective on and after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="1992-10-30">Oct. 30, 1992</date>], and any funds appropriated pursuant to section 3707(c) [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4748">106 Stat. 4748</ref>], and remaining unobligated and unexpended on the date of the enactment of this title, shall immediately revert to the Treasury, as general revenues, and any funds appropriated by the State of Arizona pursuant to the Agreement, and remaining unobligated and unexpended on the date of the enactment of this title, shall immediately revert to the State of Arizona.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, if the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s3705">section 3705 of this title</ref> have been otherwise accomplished pursuant to provisions of the Act of <date date="1988-10-20">October 20, 1988</date> [<ref href="/us/pl/100/512">Pub. L. 100–512</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2549">102 Stat. 2549</ref>], the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not be construed as affecting such subsections.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extension for River System General Adjudication</inline>.—</heading><content>If, at any time prior to <date date="1999-03-31">March 31, 1999</date>, the Secretary notifies the Committee on Indian Affairs of the United States Senate or the Committee on Resources in the United States House of Representatives that the Settlement Agreement, as executed by the Secretary, has been submitted to the Superior Court of the State of Arizona in and for Maricopa County for consideration and approval as part of the General Adjudication of the Gila River System and Source, the [sic] <date date="1999-03-31">March 31, 1999</date>, referred to in subsection (b)(1) shall be deemed to be changed to <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>. [The Secretary notified the Committees on <date date="1999-03-30">Mar. 30, 1999</date>.]”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/102/575/s3711">section 3711 of Pub. L. 102–575</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/575/s3703">section 3703 of Pub. L. 102–575</ref>, title XXXVII, <date date="1992-10-30">Oct. 30, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4741">106 Stat. 4741</ref>, as amended.]</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/104/91/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 104–91, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/14">110 Stat. 14</ref>, provided that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“(1) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending <ref href="/us/pl/102/575/s3711">section 3711 of Pub. L. 102–575</ref>, set out above] shall take effect as of <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“(2) <inline class="small-caps">Lapsed provisions of law and contracts</inline>.—The provisions of subsections (c) and (d) of section 3704 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4743">106 Stat. 4743</ref>], subsections (a) and (b) of section 3705 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4744">106 Stat. 4744</ref>], section 3706 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4745">106 Stat. 4745</ref>], subsections (a)(2), (c), (d), and (f) of section 3707 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4747">106 Stat. 4747</ref>], subsections (b) and (c) of section 3708 [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4748">106 Stat. 4748</ref>], and subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (g), (h), (j), and (<i>l</i>) of section 3710 of such Act [<ref href="/us/stat/106/4750">106 Stat. 4750</ref>, subsec. (e) amends this section], together with each contract entered into pursuant to any such section or subsection (with the consent of the non-Federal parties thereto), shall be effective on and after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-01-06">Jan. 6, 1996</date>], subject to the <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>, deadline specified in such section 3711(b)(1), as amended by subsection (a) of this section [<ref href="/us/pl/102/575/s3711/b/1">section 3711(b)(1) of Pub. L. 102–575</ref>, set out above].”]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
