<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62c84352-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904"><num value="3904">§ 3904.</num><heading> Authority of Director of Indian Health Service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62c84353-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Reservation inventory</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62c84354-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon request by an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity, the Director shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c84355-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conduct an inventory and evaluation of the contents of open dumps on the Indian lands or Alaska Native lands which are subject to the authority of the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c84356-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> determine the relative severity of the threat to public health and the environment posed by each dump based on information available to the Director and the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity unless the Director, in consultation with the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity, determines that additional actions such as soil testing or water monitoring would be appropriate in the circumstances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c84357-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> develop cost estimates for the closure and postclosure maintenance of such dumps.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62c84358-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The inventory and evaluation authorized under paragraph (1)(A) shall be carried out cooperatively with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. The Director shall obtain the concurrence of the Administrator in the determination of relative severity made under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62c84359-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon completion of the activities required to be performed pursuant to subsection (a), the Director shall, subject to subsection (c), provide financial and technical assistance to the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity to carry out the activities necessary to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c8435a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> close such dumps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62c8435b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provide for postclosure maintenance of such dumps.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62c8435c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s3904/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All assistance provided pursuant to subsection (b) shall be made available on a site-specific basis in accordance with priorities developed by the Director. Priorities on specific Indian lands or Alaska Native lands shall be developed in consultation with the Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity. The priorities shall take into account the relative severity of the threat to public health and the environment posed by each open dump and the availability of funds necessary for closure and postclosure maintenance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62c8435d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/399/s5">Pub. L. 103–399, § 5</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4166">108 Stat. 4166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
