<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62d90b60-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354"><num value="4354">§ 4354.</num><heading> Native American tourism and branding enhancement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62d90b61-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The head of each agency shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b62-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> take actions that help empower Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and Native Hawaiian organizations to showcase the heritage, foods, traditions, history, and continuing vitality of Native American communities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b63-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> support the efforts of Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and Native Hawaiian organizations—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62d90b64-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to identify and enhance or maintain traditions and cultural features that are important to sustain the distinctiveness of the local Native American community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62d90b65-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to provide visitor experiences that are authentic and respectful;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b66-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide assistance to interpret the connections between the indigenous peoples of the United States and the national identity of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b67-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> enhance efforts to promote understanding and respect for diverse cultures and subcultures in the United States and the relevance of those cultures to the national brand of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b68-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> enter into appropriate memoranda of understanding and establish public-private partnerships to ensure that arriving domestic travelers at airports and arriving international visitors at ports of entry are welcomed in a manner that both showcases and respects the diversity of Native American communities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62d90b69-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent practicable, grant programs relating to travel, recreation, or tourism administered by the Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts, Chairman of the National Endowment for the Humanities, or the head of an agency with assets or resources relating to travel, recreation, or tourism promotion or branding enhancement for which Indian tribes, tribal organizations, or Native Hawaiian organizations are eligible may be used—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b6a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to support the efforts of Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and Native Hawaiian organizations to tell the story of Native Americans as the First Peoples of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b6b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to use the arts and humanities to help revitalize Native communities, promote economic development, increase livability, and present the uniqueness of the United States to visitors in a way that celebrates the diversity of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b6c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62d90b6d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Smithsonian</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Advisory Council and the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution shall work with Indian tribes, tribal organizations, Native Hawaiian organizations, and nonprofit organizations to establish long-term partnerships with non-Smithsonian museums and educational and cultural organizations—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b6e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to share collections, exhibitions, interpretive materials, and educational strategies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62d90b6f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s4354/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to conduct joint research and collaborative projects that would support tourism efforts for Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and Native Hawaiian organizations and carry out the intent of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62d90b70-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/221/s5">Pub. L. 114–221, § 5</ref>, <date date="2016-09-23">Sept. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/850">130 Stat. 850</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
