<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62d90b83-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5103"><num value="5103">§ 5103.</num><heading> Restoration of lands to tribal ownership</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62d90b84-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5103/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of existing rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, if he shall find it to be in the public interest, is authorized to restore to tribal ownership the remaining surplus lands of any Indian reservation heretofore opened, or authorized to be opened, to sale, or any other form of disposal by Presidential proclamation, or by any of the public-land laws of the United States: <i>Provided, however</i>, That valid rights or claims of any persons to any lands so withdrawn existing on the date of the withdrawal shall not be affected by this Act: <i>Provided further</i>, That this section shall not apply to lands within any reclamation project heretofore authorized in any Indian reservation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62d90b85-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5103/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Papago Indians; permits for easements, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62d90b86-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5103/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>, (2) Repealed. <ref href="/us/act/1955-05-27/ch106/s1">May 27, 1955, ch. 106, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/67">69 Stat. 67</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62d90b87-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5103/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Water reservoirs, charcos, water holes, springs, wells, or any other form of water development by the United States or the Papago Indians shall not be used for mining purposes under the terms of this Act, except under permit from the Secretary of the Interior approved by the Papago Indian Council: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing herein shall be construed as interfering with or affecting the validity of the water rights of the Indians of this reservation: <i>Provided further</i>, That the appropriation of living water heretofore or hereafter affected, by the Papago Indians is recognized and validated subject to all the laws applicable thereto.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62d90b88-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5103/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing herein contained shall restrict the granting or use of permits for easements or rights-of-way; or ingress or egress over the lands for all proper and lawful purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62d90b89-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/ch576/s3">June 18, 1934, ch. 576, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/984">48 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1937-08-28/ch866">Aug. 28, 1937, ch. 866</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/862">50 Stat. 862</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-05-27/ch106/s1">May 27, 1955, ch. 106, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/67">69 Stat. 67</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62d90b8a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62d90b8b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62d90b8c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Heretofore”, referred to in subsec. (a), means before <date date="1934-06-18">June 18, 1934</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b)(3), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/ch576">act June 18, 1934, ch. 576</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/984">48 Stat. 984</ref>, popularly known as the Indian Reorganization Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5101">section 5101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62d90b8d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s463">section 463 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62d90b8e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Subsec. (b)(1). Act <date date="1955-05-27">May 27, 1955</date>, repealed par. (1) which restored lands of Papago Indian Reservation to exploration and location.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). Act <date date="1955-05-27">May 27, 1955</date>, repealed par. (2) which required person desiring a mineral patent to pay $1 per acre in lieu of annual rental.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). Act <date date="1955-05-27">May 27, 1955</date>, struck out provisions relating to authority to issue or promulgate rules or regulations in conflict with Executive Order of <date date="1917-02-01">Feb. 1, 1917</date> or act of <date date="1931-02-21">Feb. 21, 1931</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/46/1202">46 Stat. 1202</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1937—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1937-08-28">Aug. 28, 1937</date>, designated existing provisions of first par. as subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). Act <date date="1937-08-28">Aug. 28, 1937</date>, designated existing provisions of first par. as par. (1), substituted “damages shall be paid to the superintendent or other officer in charge of the reservation for the credit of the owner thereof” for “damages shall be paid to the Papago Tribe” and “to be the fair and reasonable value of such improvement” for “but not to exceed the cost of said improvements” and struck out “and payments derived from damages or rentals shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Papago Tribe” after “mining operations,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). Act <date date="1937-08-28">Aug. 28, 1937</date>, designated existing provisions of first par. as par. (2), inserted “pay to the superintendent or other officer in charge of the reservation, for” before “deposit”, substituted “<i>Provided</i>, That an applicant for patent shall also pay to the Secretary or other officer in charge of the said reservation for the credit of the owner” for “<i>Provided further</i>, That patentee shall also pay into the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Papago Tribe” substituted “but the sum thus deposited, except for a deduction of rental at the annual rate hereinbefore provided, shall be refunded to the applicant in the event that patent is not acquired” for “the payment of $1.00 per acre for surface use to be refunded to patentee in the event that patent is not acquired” after “determination by the Secretary of the Interior, but not to exceed the cost thereof”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). Act <date date="1937-08-28">Aug. 28, 1937</date>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). Act <date date="1937-08-28">Aug. 28, 1937</date>, designated second par. as par. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id62d90b8f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id62d90b90-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Papago Indian Reservation</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1955-05-27/ch106/s1">Act May 27, 1955, ch. 106, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/67">69 Stat. 67</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1955-05-27/ch106/s1">“That the provisions with respect to subjection of mineral lands within the Papago Indian Reservation to exploration, location, and entry under the mining laws of the United States in the Executive order dated <date date="1917-02-01">February 1, 1917</date>, creating the Papago Indian Reservation, and in the third proviso in <ref href="/us/act/1931-02-21/s1">section 1 of the Act of February 21, 1931</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/46/1202">46 Stat. 1202</ref>), and the provisions of subsection (b)(1) and (2) and of the remainder, following the word ‘purposes,’ of subsection (b)(4) of <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/s3">section 3 of the Act of June 18, 1934</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/48/984">48 Stat. 984</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s461–479">25 U.S.C. 461–479</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5101–512">25 U.S.C. 5101–512</ref>9]), as amended by the Act of August 26 [28], 1937 (<ref href="/us/stat/50/862">50 Stat. 862</ref>, 863; <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s463">25 U.S.C. 463</ref> [now <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5103">25 U.S.C. 5103</ref>]) [this section], are hereby repealed, all tribal lands within the Papago Indian Reservation are hereby withdrawn from all forms of exploration, location, and entry under such laws, the minerals underlying such lands are hereby made a part of the reservation to be held in trust by the United States for the Papago Indian Tribe, and such minerals shall be subject to lease for mining purposes pursuant to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1938-05-11">May 11, 1938</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/52/347">52 Stat. 347</ref>) [sections 396a to 396g of this title]: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of this Act shall not be applicable to lands within the Papago Indian Reservation for which a mineral patent has heretofore been issued or to a claim that has been validly initiated before the date of this Act and thereafter maintained under the mining laws of the United States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id62d90b91-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id62d90b92-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all other officers of Department of the Interior and functions of all agencies and employees of Department, with two exceptions, transferred to Secretary of the Interior, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions by any of those officers, agencies, and employees, by Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
