<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62ddc6f0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5204"><num value="5204">§ 5204.</num><heading> Cooperative associations; charter; purposes; voting rights</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any ten or more Indians, as determined by the official tribal rolls, or Indian descendants of such enrolled members, or Indians as defined in the Act of <date date="1934-06-18">June 18, 1934</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/48/984">48 Stat. 984</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5101">25 U.S.C. 5101</ref> et seq.], who reside within the State of Oklahoma in convenient proximity to each other may receive from the Secretary of the Interior a charter as a local cooperative association for any one or more of the following purposes: Credit administration, production, marketing, consumers’ protection, or land management. The provisions of this chapter, the regulations of the Secretary of the Interior, and the charters of the cooperative associations issued pursuant thereto shall govern such cooperative associations: <i>Provided</i>, That in those matters not covered by this chapter, regulations, or charters, the laws of the State of Oklahoma, if applicable, shall govern. In any stock or nonstock cooperative association no one member shall have more than one vote, and membership therein shall be open to all Indians residing within the prescribed district.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id62ddc6f1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-06-26/ch831/s4">June 26, 1936, ch. 831, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1967">49 Stat. 1967</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62ddc6f2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62ddc6f3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62ddc6f4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1934-06-18">June 18, 1934</date>, referred to in text, popularly known as the Indian Reorganization Act, is classified generally to chapter 45 (§ 5101 et seq.) of this title. Provisions of the Act defining “Indian” appear in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5129">section 5129 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5101">section 5101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62ddc6f5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s504">section 504 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
