<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62e0377b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5306"><num value="5306">§ 5306.</num><heading> Criminal activities involving grants, contracts, etc.; penalties</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever, being an officer, director, agent, or employee of, or connected in any capacity with, any recipient of a contract, subcontract, grant, or subgrant pursuant to this chapter or the Act of <date date="1934-04-16">April 16, 1934</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/48/596">48 Stat. 596</ref>), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5342">25 U.S.C. 5342</ref> et seq.], embezzles, willfully misapplies, steals, or obtains by fraud any of the money, funds, assets, or property which are the subject of such a grant, subgrant, contract, or subcontract, shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than two years, or both, but if the amount so embezzled, misapplied, stolen, or obtained by fraud does not exceed $100, he shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id62e0377c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s6">Pub. L. 93–638, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2205">88 Stat. 2205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62e0377d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62e0377e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62e0377f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, known as the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1934-04-16">April 16, 1934</date>, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1934-04-16/ch147">act Apr. 16, 1934, ch. 147</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/596">48 Stat. 596</ref>, popularly known as the Johnson-O’Malley Act, which is classified generally to section 5342 et seq. of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62e03780-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450d">section 450d of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
