<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62e281e2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323"><num value="5323">§ 5323.</num><heading> Retention of Federal employee coverage, rights and benefits by employees of tribal organizations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281e3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> to (d) Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281e4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible employees; Federal employee programs subject to retention</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 8347(<i>o</i>), 8713, and 8914 of title 5, executive order, or administrative regulation, an employee serving under an appointment not limited to one year or less who leaves Federal employment to be employed by a tribal organization, the city of St. Paul, Alaska, the city of St. George, Alaska, upon incorporation, or the Village Corporations of St. Paul and St. George Islands established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1607">section 1607 of title 43</ref>, in connection with governmental or other activities which are or have been performed by employees in or for Indian communities is entitled, if the employee and the tribal organization so elect, to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e281e5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> To retain coverage, rights, and benefits under subchapter I of chapter 81 (“Compensation for Work Injuries”) of title 5, and for this purpose his employment with the tribal organization shall be deemed employment by the United States. However, if an injured employee, or his dependents in case of his death, receives from the tribal organization any payment (including an allowance, gratuity, payment under an insurance policy for which the premium is wholly paid by the tribal organization, or other benefit of any kind) on account of the same injury or death, the amount of that payment shall be credited against any benefit payable under subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5, as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e281e6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> payments on account of injury or disability shall be credited against disability compensation payable to the injured employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e281e7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> payments on account of death shall be credited against death compensation payable to dependents of the deceased employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e281e8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To retain coverage, rights, and benefits under chapter 83 (“Retirement”) or chapter 84 (“Federal Employees Retirement System”) of title 5, if necessary employee deductions and agency contributions in payment for coverage, rights, and benefits for the period of employment with the tribal organization are currently deposited in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8348">section 8348 of title 5</ref>); and the period during which coverage, rights, and benefits are retained under this paragraph is deemed creditable service under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of title 5</ref>. Days of unused sick leave to the credit of an employee under a formal leave system at the time the employee leaves Federal employment to be employed by a tribal organization remain to his credit for retirement purposes during covered service with the tribal organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e281e9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To retain coverage, rights, and benefits under chapter 89 (“Health Insurance”) of title 5, if necessary employee deductions and agency contributions in payment for the coverage, rights, and benefits for the period of employment with the tribal organization are currently deposited in the Employee’s Health Benefit Fund (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8909">section 8909 of title 5</ref>); and the period during which coverage, rights, and benefits are retained under this paragraph is deemed service as an employee under chapter 89 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e281ea-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> To retain coverage, rights, and benefits under chapter 87 (“Life Insurance”) of title 5, if necessary employee deductions and agency contributions in payment for the coverage, rights, and benefits for the period of employment with the tribal organizations are currently deposited in the Employee’s Life Insurance Fund (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8714">section 8714 of title 5</ref>); and the period during which coverage, rights, and benefits are retained under this paragraph is deemed service as an employee under chapter 87 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281eb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposit by tribal organization of employee deductions and agency contributions in appropriate funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">During the period an employee is entitled to the coverage, rights, and benefits pursuant to the preceding subsection, the tribal organization employing such employee shall deposit currently in the appropriate funds the employee deductions and agency contributions required by paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of such preceding subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281ec-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Election for retention by employee and tribal organization before date of employment by tribal organization; transfer of employee to another tribal organization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An employee who is employed by a tribal organization under subsection (e) of this section and such tribal organization shall make the election to retain the coverages, rights, and benefits in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of such subsection (e) before the date of his employment by a tribal organization. An employee who is employed by a tribal organization under subsection (e) of this section shall continue to be entitled to the benefits of such subsection if he is employed by another tribal organization to perform service in activities of the type described in such subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281ed-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> “Employee” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of subsections (e), (f), and (g) of this section, the term “employee” means an employee as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105">section 2105 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281ee-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation of implementation regulations by President</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may prescribe regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of subsections (e), (f), (g), and (h) of this section and to protect and assure the compensation, retirement, insurance, leave, reemployment rights, and such other similar civil service employment rights as he finds appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281ef-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional employee employment rights</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Anything in sections 205 and 207 of title 18 to the contrary notwithstanding—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e281f0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an officer or employee of the United States assigned to a tribal organization (as defined in section 5304(<i>l</i>) of this title) or an inter-tribal consortium (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5381">section 5381 of this title</ref>), as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3372">section 3372 of title 5</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s48">section 48 of this title</ref> may act as agent or attorney for, and appear on behalf of, such tribal organization or inter-tribal consortium in connection with any matter related to a tribal governmental activity or Federal Indian program or service pending before any department, agency, court, or commission, including any matter in which the United States is a party or has a direct and substantial interest: <i>Provided</i>, That such officer or employee must advise in writing the head of the department, agency, court, or commission with which the officer or employee is dealing or appearing on behalf of the tribal organization or inter-tribal consortium of any personal and substantial involvement with the matter involved; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e281f1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a former officer or employee of the United States who is carrying out official duties as an employee or as an elected or appointed official of a tribal organization (as defined in section 5304(<i>l</i>) of this title) or inter-tribal consortium (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5381">section 5381 of this title</ref>) may act as agent or attorney for, and appear on behalf of, such tribal organization or intra-tribal consortium in connection with any matter related to a tribal governmental activity or Federal Indian program or service pending before any department, agency, court, or commission, including any matter in which the United States is a party or has a direct and substantial interest: <i>Provided</i>, That such former officer or employee must advise in writing the head of the department, agency, court, or commission with which the former officer or employee is dealing or appearing on behalf of the tribal organization or inter-tribal consortium of any personal and substantial involvement that he or she may have had as an officer or employee of the United States in connection with the matter involved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281f2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold">, (l) Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e281f3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5323/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Conversion to career appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The status of an Indian (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5129">section 5129 of this title</ref>) appointed (except temporary appointments) to the Federal service under an excepted appointment under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5116">section 5116 of this title</ref>, or any other provision of law granting a preference to Indians in personnel actions, shall be converted to a career appointment in the competitive service after three years of continuous service and satisfactory performance. The conversion shall not alter the Indian’s eligibility for preference in personnel actions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62e281f4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/638/tI/s104">Pub. L. 93–638, title I, § 104</ref>, formerly § 105, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2208">88 Stat. 2208</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/702/tII/s210/a">Pub. L. 89–702, title II, § 210(a)</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/129/s2">Pub. L. 98–129, § 2</ref>, <date date="1983-10-14">Oct. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/843">97 Stat. 843</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/221/s3/a">Pub. L. 99–221, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-26">Dec. 26, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1735">99 Stat. 1735</ref>; renumbered § 104 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/472/tII/s203">Pub. L. 100–472, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1988-10-05">Oct. 5, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2290">102 Stat. 2290</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/301/s2/a/6">Pub. L. 101–301, § 2(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-24">May 24, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/206">104 Stat. 206</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/81/tI/s104/b">Pub. L. 110–81, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/740">121 Stat. 740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62e281f5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62e281f6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62e281f7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450i">section 450i of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 93–638</ref>. Subsecs. (a) to (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 93–638</ref> are classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3371">section 3371 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2004b">section 2004b of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3806">section 3806 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4762">section 4762 of Title 42</ref>, respectively. Subsecs. (k) and (<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 93–638</ref> are classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3372">section 3372 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id62e281f8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 93–638</ref> was renumbered section 103 by <ref href="/us/pl/100/472">Pub. L. 100–472</ref> and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5322">section 5322 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62e281f9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/110/81">Pub. L. 110–81</ref> amended subsec. (j) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Anything in sections 205 and 207 of title 18 to the contrary notwithstanding, officers and employees of the United States assigned to an Indian tribe as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3372">section 3372 of title 5</ref>, or <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s48">section 48 of this title</ref> and former officers and employees of the United States employed by Indian tribes may act as agents or attorneys for or appear on behalf of such tribes in connection wth [sic] any matter pending before any department, agency, court, or commission, including any matter in which the United States is a party or has a direct and substantial interest: <i>Provided</i>, That each such officer or employee or former officer or employee must advise in writing the head of the department, agency, court, or commission with which he is dealing or appearing on behalf of the tribe of any personal and substantial involvement he may have had as an officer or employee of the United States in connection with the matter involved.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/101/301">Pub. L. 101–301</ref> substituted “an Indian (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5129">section 5129 of this title</ref>) appointed (except temporary appointments)” for “an Indian appointed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/472/s203/b">Pub. L. 100–472, § 203(b)</ref>, (c), amended subsecs. (a) and (b). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/472/s203/d">Pub. L. 100–472, § 203(d)</ref>, (e), in introductory provisions, substituted “Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 8347(<i>o</i>), 8713, and 8914 of title 5” for “Notwithstanding any other law” and struck out “on or before <date date="1988-12-31">December 31, 1988</date>” after “title 43”, and in par. (2), inserted “or chapter 84 (‘Federal Employees Retirement System’)”. Notwithstanding directory language that the substitution of “Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 8347(<i>o</i>), 8713, and 8914 of title 5” be made in par. (2) of subsec. (e), the substitution was made in introductory provisions of subsec. (e) to reflect the probable intent of Congress because the language replaced appeared only in those introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/100/472/s203/f">Pub. L. 100–472, § 203(f)</ref>, added subsecs. (k) and (<i>l</i>). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/100/472/s203/f">Pub. L. 100–472, § 203(f)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/221">Pub. L. 99–221</ref> substituted “1988” for “1985”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/702/s210/a">Pub. L. 89–702, § 210(a)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/98/129">Pub. L. 98–129</ref>, inserted “, the city of St. Paul, Alaska, the city of St. George, Alaska, upon incorporation, or the Village Corporations of St. Paul and St. George Islands established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1607">section 1607 of title 43</ref>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id62e281fa-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id62e281fb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/81/tI/s105/d">Pub. L. 110–81, title I, § 105(d)</ref>, <date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/741">121 Stat. 741</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/81/tI/s105/d">“The amendments made by section 104 [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s207">section 207 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-09-14">Sept. 14, 2007</date>], except that section 104(j)(2) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323/j/2">25 U.S.C. 5323(j)(2)</ref>] (as amended by section 104(b)) shall apply to individuals who leave Federal office or employment to which such amendments apply on or after the 60th day after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id62e281fc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pribilof Island Natives Employed by Federal Government on <date date="1983-10-28">October 28, 1983</date></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/702/tII/s210/b">Pub. L. 89–702, title II, § 210(b)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/98/129/s2">Pub. L. 98–129, § 2</ref>, <date date="1983-10-14">Oct. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/844">97 Stat. 844</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/129/s2">“Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any Native of the Pribilof Islands employed by the Federal government on <date date="1983-10-28">October 28, 1983</date>, shall be deemed to have been covered under chapters 81, 83, 85 and 87 of title 5, United States Code, on such date for the purposes of determining eligibility for continuity of benefits under <ref href="/us/act/1975-01-04/s105/e">section 105(e) of the Act of January 4, 1975</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Public Law 93–638</ref>), known as the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e">25 U.S.C. 5323(e)</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id62e281fd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id62e281fe-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11899. Providing for Protection of Certain Civil Service Employment Rights of Federal Personnel Who Leave Federal Employment To Be Employed by Tribal Organizations</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11899, <date date="1976-01-26">Jan. 26, 1976</date>, 41 F.R. 3459, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12107, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1055; Ex. Ord. No. 12608, <date date="1987-09-09">Sept. 9, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 34617, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by section 105(i) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/stat/88/2210">88 Stat. 2210</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450i">25 U.S.C. 450i</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323">25 U.S.C. 5323</ref>], <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3301">section 3301 of title 5</ref> of the United States Code, <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and as President of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. The Office of Personnel Management is hereby designated and empowered to exercise, without approval, ratification, or other action by the President, but after consultation with the Department of the Interior and the Department of Health and Human Services, the authority vested in the President by Section 105(i) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323/i">25 U.S.C. 5323(i)</ref>] (hereinafter referred to as the Act), to issue regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of subsections (e)(2), (e)(3), (e)(4), (f), (g) and (h) of section 105 of the act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/2">25 U.S.C. 5323(e)(2)</ref>, (3), (4), (f), (g), (h)], to carry out the provisions of subsection (e)(1) of section 105 of the act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/1">25 U.S.C. 5323(e)(1)</ref>] pertains to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8151">section 8151 of title 5</ref> of the United States Code, and to protect and assure any other civil service employment rights which it finds appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. The Office of Personnel Management shall, after consultation with the Department of the Interior and the Department of Health and Human Services, issue regulations, as it deems appropriate, providing for the establishment, granting, and exercise of reemployment rights for employees who leave Federal employment for employment by an Indian tribal organization under provisions of the act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. The Secretary of Labor is hereby designated and empowered to exercise, without approval, ratification, or other action by the President, the authority vested in the President by section 105(i) of the act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323/i">25 U.S.C. 5323(i)</ref>] to issue regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of section 105(e)(1) of the act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5323/e/1">25 U.S.C. 5323(e)(1)</ref>], except as provided in section 1 of this order.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
