<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62e73ccb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5329"><num value="5329">§ 5329.</num><heading> Contract or grant specifications</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e73ccc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5329/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each self-determination contract entered into under this chapter shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73ccd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5329/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> contain, or incorporate by reference, the provisions of the model agreement described in subsection (c) of this section (with modifications where indicated and the blanks appropriately filled in), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cce-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5329/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> subject to subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321">section 5321 of this title</ref>, contain such other provisions as are agreed to by the parties.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e73ccf-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5329/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments; Federal records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may make payments pursuant to section 1(b)(6) of such model agreement. As provided in section 1(b)(7) of the model agreement, the records of the tribal government or tribal organization specified in such section shall not be considered Federal records for purposes of chapter 5 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62e73cd0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5329/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Model agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The model agreement referred to in subsection (a)(1) of this section reads as follows:</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467" id="id62e73cd1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE SECRETARY AND THE ______ TRIBAL GOVERNMENT.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62e73cd2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/a"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority and Purpose.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cd3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/a/1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>This agreement, denoted a Self-Determination Contract (referred to in this agreement as the ‘Contract’), is entered into by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this agreement as the ‘Secretary’), for and on behalf of the United States pursuant to title I of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450">25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002265">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002265"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and by the authority of the ______ tribal government or tribal organization (referred to in this agreement as the ‘Contractor’). The provisions of title I of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450">25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002265">1</ref> are incorporated in this agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cd4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/a/2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>Each provision of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450">25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.) <sup>1</sup> and each provision of this Contract shall be liberally construed for the benefit of the Contractor to transfer the funding and the following related functions, services, activities, and programs (or portions thereof), that are otherwise contractable under section 102(a) of such Act, including all related administrative functions, from the Federal Government to the Contractor: (List functions, services, activities, and programs).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62e73cd5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms, Provisions, and Conditions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cd6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to section 105(c)(1) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450j/c/1">25 U.S.C. 450j(c)(1)</ref>),<sup>1</sup> the term of this contract shall be __ years. Pursuant to section 105(d)(1) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450j/d">25 U.S.C. 450j(d)</ref>) <sup>1</sup>, upon the election by the Contractor, the period of this Contract shall be determined on the basis of a calendar year, unless the Secretary and the Contractor agree on a different period in the annual funding agreement incorporated by reference in subsection (f)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cd7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>This Contract shall become effective upon the date of the approval and execution by the Contractor and the Secretary, unless the Contractor and the Secretary agree on an effective date other than the date specified in this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cd8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/3"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program standard</inline>.—</heading><content>The Contractor agrees to administer the program, services, functions and activities (or portions thereof) listed in subsection (a)(2) of the Contract in conformity with the following standards: (list standards).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cd9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/4"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding amount</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall make available to the Contractor the total amount specified in the annual funding agreement incorporated by reference in subsection (f)(2). Such amount shall not be less than the applicable amount determined pursuant to section 106(a) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450j–1">25 U.S.C. 450j–1</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cda-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/5"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation of costs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Contractor shall not be obligated to continue performance that requires an expenditure of funds in excess of the amount of funds awarded under this Contract. If, at any time, the Contractor has reason to believe that the total amount required for performance of this Contract or a specific activity conducted under this Contract would be greater than the amount of funds awarded under this Contract, the Contractor shall provide reasonable notice to the appropriate Secretary. If the appropriate Secretary does not take such action as may be necessary to increase the amount of funds awarded under this Contract, the Contractor may suspend performance of the Contract until such time as additional funds are awarded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cdb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cdc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Payments to the Contractor under this Contract shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cdd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6/A/i"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> be made as expeditiously as practicable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cde-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> include financial arrangements to cover funding during periods covered by joint resolutions adopted by Congress making continuing appropriations, to the extent permitted by such resolutions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cdf-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Quarterly, semiannual, lump-sum, and other methods of payment.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73ce0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6/B/i"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to section 108(b) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, for each fiscal year covered by this Contract, the Secretary shall make available to the Contractor the funds specified for the fiscal year under the annual funding agreement incorporated by reference pursuant to subsection (f)(2) by paying to the Contractor, on a quarterly basis, one-quarter of the total amount provided for in the annual funding agreement for that fiscal year, in a lump-sum payment or as semiannual payments, or any other method of payment authorized by law, in accordance with such method as may be requested by the Contractor and specified in the annual funding agreement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73ce1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Method of quarterly payment</inline>.—</heading><content>If quarterly payments are specified in the annual funding agreement incorporated by reference pursuant to subsection (f)(2), each quarterly payment made pursuant to clause (i) shall be made on the first day of each quarter of the fiscal year, except that in any case in which the Contract year coincides with the Federal fiscal year, payment for the first quarter shall be made not later than the date that is 10 calendar days after the date on which the Office of Management and Budget apportions the appropriations for the fiscal year for the programs, services, functions, and activities subject to this Contract.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73ce2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>Chapter 39 of title 31, United States Code, shall apply to the payment of funds due under this Contract and the annual funding agreement referred to in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73ce3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/7"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records and monitoring.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73ce4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/7/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except for previously provided copies of tribal records that the Secretary demonstrates are clearly required to be maintained as part of the recordkeeping system of the Department of the Interior or the Department of Health and Human Services (or both), records of the Contractor shall not be considered Federal records for purposes of chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73ce5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/7/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recordkeeping system</inline>.—</heading><content>The Contractor shall maintain a recordkeeping system and, upon reasonable advance request, provide reasonable access to such records to the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73ce6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/7/C"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of contractor</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Contractor shall be responsible for managing the day-to-day operations conducted under this Contract and for monitoring activities conducted under this Contract to ensure compliance with the Contract and applicable Federal requirements. With respect to the monitoring activities of the Secretary, the routine monitoring visits shall be limited to not more than two performance monitoring visits for this Contract by the head of each operating division, departmental bureau, or departmental agency, or duly authorized representative of such head unless—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73ce7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/7/C/i"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the Contractor agrees to one or more additional visits; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73ce8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/7/C/ii"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the appropriate official determines that there is reasonable cause to believe that grounds for reassumption of the Contract, suspension of Contract payments, or other serious Contract performance deficiency may exist.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">No additional visit referred to in clause (ii) shall be made until such time as reasonable advance notice that includes a description of the nature of the problem that requires the additional visit has been given to the Contractor.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73ce9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Property.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cea-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>As provided in section 105(f) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450j/f">25 U.S.C. 450j(f)</ref>),<sup>1</sup> at the request of the Contractor, the Secretary may make available, or transfer to the Contractor, all reasonably divisible real property, facilities, equipment, and personal property that the Secretary has used to provide or administer the programs, services, functions, and activities covered by this Contract. A mutually agreed upon list specifying the property, facilities, and equipment so furnished shall also be prepared by the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Contractor, and periodically revised by the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73ceb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records</inline>.—</heading><content>The Contractor shall maintain a record of all property referred to in subparagraph (A) or other property acquired by the Contractor under section 105(f)(2)(A) of such Act for purposes of replacement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cec-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8/C"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Joint use agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon the request of the Contractor, the Secretary and the Contractor shall enter into a separate joint use agreement to address the shared use by the parties of real or personal property that is not reasonably divisible.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73ced-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8/D"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of property</inline>.—</heading><content>The Contractor is granted the authority to acquire such excess property as the Contractor may determine to be appropriate in the judgment of the Contractor to support the programs, services, functions, and activities operated pursuant to this Contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cee-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8/E"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Confiscated or excess property</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall assist the Contractor in obtaining such confiscated or excess property as may become available to tribes, tribal organizations, or local governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cef-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8/F"><num value="F">“(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Screener identification card</inline>.—</heading><content>A screener identification card (General Services Administration form numbered 2946) shall be issued to the Contractor not later than the effective date of this Contract. The designated official shall, upon request, assist the Contractor in securing the use of the card.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cf0-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/8/G"><num value="G">“(G)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Capital equipment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Contractor shall determine the capital equipment, leases, rentals, property, or services the Contractor requires to perform the obligations of the Contractor under this subsection, and shall acquire and maintain records of such capital equipment, property rentals, leases, property, or services through applicable procurement procedures of the Contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cf1-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/9"><num value="9">“(9)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of funds</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funds provided under this Contract—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cf2-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/9/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> shall remain available until expended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cf3-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/9/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> with respect to such funds, no further—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cf4-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/9/B/i"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> approval by the Secretary, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cf5-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/9/B/ii"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> justifying documentation from the Contractor,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be required prior to the expenditure of such funds.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cf6-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/10"><num value="10">“(10)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transportation</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning on the effective date of this Contract, the Secretary shall authorize the Contractor to obtain interagency motor pool vehicles and related services for performance of any activities carried out under this Contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cf7-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/11"><num value="11">“(11)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal program guidelines, manuals, or policy directives</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as specifically provided in the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450">25 U.S.C. 450</ref> et seq.) <sup>1</sup> the Contractor is not required to abide by program guidelines, manuals, or policy directives of the Secretary, unless otherwise agreed to by the Contractor and the Secretary, or otherwise required by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73cf8-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12"><num value="12">“(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disputes.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cf9-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Third-party mediation defined</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of this Contract, the term ‘third-party mediation’ means a form of mediation whereby the Secretary and the Contractor nominate a third party who is not employed by or significantly involved with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Contractor, to serve as a third-party mediator to mediate disputes under this Contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cfa-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternative procedures</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In addition to, or as an alternative to, remedies and procedures prescribed by section 110 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450m–1">25 U.S.C. 450m–1</ref>),<sup>1</sup> the parties to this Contract may jointly—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cfb-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12/B/i"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> submit disputes under this Contract to third-party mediation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cfc-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12/B/ii"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> submit the dispute to the adjudicatory body of the Contractor, including the tribal court of the Contractor;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cfd-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12/B/iii"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> submit the dispute to mediation processes provided for under the laws, policies, or procedures of the Contractor; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73cfe-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12/B/iv"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> use the administrative dispute resolution processes authorized in subchapter IV of chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73cff-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/12/C"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of decisions</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall be bound by decisions made pursuant to the processes set forth in subparagraph (B), except that the Secretary shall not be bound by any decision that significantly conflicts with the interests of Indians or the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d00-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/13"><num value="13">“(13)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative procedures of contractor</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to the Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968 (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1301">25 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.), the laws, policies, and procedures of the Contractor shall provide for administrative due process (or the equivalent of administrative due process) with respect to programs, services, functions, and activities that are provided by the Contractor pursuant to this Contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d01-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/14"><num value="14">“(14)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Successor annual funding agreement.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d02-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/14/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Negotiations for a successor annual funding agreement, provided for in subsection (f)(2), shall begin not later than 120 days prior to the conclusion of the preceding annual funding agreement. Except as provided in section 105(c)(2) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450j/c/2">25 U.S.C. 450j(c)(2)</ref>) <sup>1</sup> the funding for each such successor annual funding agreement shall only be reduced pursuant to section 106(b) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450j–1/b">25 U.S.C. 450j–1(b)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d03-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/14/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall prepare and supply relevant information, and promptly comply with any request by the Contractor for information that the Contractor reasonably needs to determine the amount of funds that may be available for a successor annual funding agreement, as provided for in subsection (f)(2) of this Contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d04-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/15"><num value="15">“(15)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contract requirements; approval by secretary.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d05-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/15/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), for the term of the Contract, section 2103 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s81">25 U.S.C. 81</ref>), <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/s16">section 16 of the Act of June 18, 1934</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/48/987">48 Stat. 987</ref>, chapter 576; <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s476">25 U.S.C. 476</ref>),<sup>1</sup> and the Act of <date date="1952-07-03">July 3, 1952</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s82a">25 U.S.C. 82a</ref>), shall not apply to any contract entered into in connection with this Contract.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d06-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/15/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each Contract entered into by the Contractor with a third party in connection with performing the obligations of the Contractor under this Contract shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73d07-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/15/B/i"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> be in writing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73d08-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/15/B/ii"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> identify the interested parties, the authorities of such parties, and purposes of the Contract;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73d09-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/15/B/iii"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> state the work to be performed under the Contract; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e73d0a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/b/15/B/iv"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> state the process for making any claim, the payments to be made, and the terms of the Contract, which shall be fixed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62e73d0b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Obligation of the Contractor.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d0c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c/1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contract performance</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (d)(2), the Contractor shall perform the programs, services, functions, and activities as provided in the annual funding agreement under subsection (f)(2) of this Contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d0d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c/2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amount of funds</inline>.—</heading><content>The total amount of funds to be paid under this Contract pursuant to section 106(a) shall be determined in an annual funding agreement entered into between the Secretary and the Contractor, which shall be incorporated into this Contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d0e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c/3"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contracted programs</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the availability of appropriated funds, the Contractor shall administer the programs, services, functions, and activities identified in this Contract and funded through the annual funding agreement under subsection (f)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d0f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c/4"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Trust services for individual indians.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d10-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c/4/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent that the annual funding agreement provides funding for the delivery of trust services to individual Indians that have been provided by the Secretary, the Contractor shall maintain at least the same level of service as the Secretary provided for such individual Indians, subject to the availability of appropriated funds for such services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d11-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c/4/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Trust services to individual indians</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of this paragraph only, the term ‘trust services for individual Indians’ means only those services that pertain to land or financial management connected to individually held allotments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d12-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/c/5"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fair and uniform services</inline>.—</heading><content>The Contractor shall provide services under this Contract in a fair and uniform manner and shall provide access to an administrative or judicial body empowered to adjudicate or otherwise resolve complaints, claims, and grievances brought by program beneficiaries against the Contractor arising out of the performance of the Contract.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62e73d13-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/d"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Obligation of the United States.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d14-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/d/1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Trust responsibility.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d15-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/d/1/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The United States reaffirms the trust responsibility of the United States to the ______ Indian tribe(s) to protect and conserve the trust resources of the Indian tribe(s) and the trust resources of individual Indians.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d16-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/d/1/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction of contract</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this Contract may be construed to terminate, waive, modify, or reduce the trust responsibility of the United States to the tribe(s) or individual Indians. The Secretary shall act in good faith in upholding such trust responsibility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d17-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/d/2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Good faith</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent that health programs are included in this Contract, and within available funds, the Secretary shall act in good faith in cooperating with the Contractor to achieve the goals set forth in the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1601">25 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d18-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/d/3"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Programs retained</inline>.—</heading><content>As specified in the annual funding agreement, the United States hereby retains the programs, services, functions, and activities with respect to the tribe(s) that are not specifically assumed by the Contractor in the annual funding agreement under subsection (f)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62e73d19-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/e"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Provisions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d1a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/e/1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designated officials</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than the effective date of this Contract, the United States shall provide to the Contractor, and the Contractor shall provide to the United States, a written designation of a senior official to serve as a representative for notices, proposed amendments to the Contract, and other purposes for this Contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d1b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/e/2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contract modifications or amendment.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d1c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/e/2/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no modification to this Contract shall take effect unless such modification is made in the form of a written amendment to the Contract, and the Contractor and the Secretary provide written consent for the modification.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e73d1d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/e/2/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The addition of supplemental funds for programs, functions, and activities (or portions thereof) already included in the annual funding agreement under subsection (f)(2), and the reduction of funds pursuant to section 106(b)(2), shall not be subject to subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e73d1e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/e/3"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Officials not to benefit</inline>.—</heading><content>No Member of Congress, or resident commissioner, shall be admitted to any share or part of any contract executed pursuant to this Contract, or to any benefit that may arise from such contract. This paragraph may not be construed to apply to any contract with a third party entered into under this Contract if such contract is made with a corporation for the general benefit of the corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e9ad1f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/e/4"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covenant against contingent fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The parties warrant that no person or selling agency has been employed or retained to solicit or secure any contract executed pursuant to this Contract upon an agreement or understanding for a commission, percentage, brokerage, or contingent fee, excepting bona fide employees or bona fide established commercial or selling agencies maintained by the Contractor for the purpose of securing business.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id62e9ad20-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/f"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Attachments.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e9ad21-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/f/1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Approval of contract</inline>.—</heading><content>Unless previously furnished to the Secretary, the resolution of the ______ Indian tribe(s) authorizing the contracting of the programs, services, functions, and activities identified in this Contract is attached to this Contract as attachment 1.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62e9ad22-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/f/2"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual funding agreement.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e9ad23-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/f/2/A"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The annual funding agreement under this Contract shall only contain—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e9ad24-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> terms that identify the programs, services, functions, and activities to be performed or administered, the general budget category assigned, the funds to be provided, and the time and method of payment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62e9ad25-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> subject to subsections (a) and (b) of section 102 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321">25 U.S.C. 5321</ref>), such other provisions, including a brief description of the programs, services, functions, and activities to be performed (including those supported by financial resources other than those provided by the Secretary), to which the parties agree.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62e9ad26-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s1/f/2/B"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Incorporation by reference</inline>.—</heading><content>The annual funding agreement is hereby incorporated in its entirety in this Contract and attached to this Contract as attachment 2.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<sourceCredit id="id62e9ad27-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/638/tI/s108">Pub. L. 93–638, title I, § 108</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/413/tI/s103">Pub. L. 103–413, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4260">108 Stat. 4260</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/568/tVIII/s812/a">Pub. L. 106–568, title VIII, § 812(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2917">114 Stat. 2917</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/180/tII/s205">Pub. L. 116–180, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2020-10-21">Oct. 21, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/881">134 Stat. 881</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62e9ad28-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62e9ad29-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62e9ad2a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, known as the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, referred to in the provisions of subsec. (c) setting out the model agreement, is <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, which was classified principally to subchapter II (§ 450 et seq.) of chapter 14 of this title prior to editorial reclassification as this chapter. Title I of the Act was classified principally to part A (§ 450f et seq.) of chapter 14 of this title prior to editorial reclassification as this subchapter. Sections 105, 106, and 110 of the Act were classified to sections 450j, 450j–1, and 450m–1, respectively, of this title prior to editorial reclassification as sections 5324, 5325, and 5331, respectively, of this title. Section 102(a) of the Act is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321/a">section 5321(a) of this title</ref>. Section 108(b) of the Act is classified to subsec. (b) of this section. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968, referred to in section 1(b)(13) of the provisions of subsec. (c) setting out the model agreement, is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/90/284">Pub. L. 90–284</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/77">82 Stat. 77</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1301 et seq.) of chapter 15 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/s16">Section 16 of the Act of June 18, 1934</ref>, referred to in section 1(b)(15)(A) of the provisions of subsec. (c) setting out the model agreement, is section 16 of <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/ch576">act June 18, 1934, ch. 576</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/987">48 Stat. 987</ref>, which was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s476">section 476 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification as <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5123">section 5123 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of <date date="1952-07-03">July 3, 1952</date>, referred to in section 1(b)(15)(A) of the provisions of subsec. (c) setting out the model agreement, is <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-03/ch549">act July 3, 1952, ch. 549</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/323">66 Stat. 323</ref>, which enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s82a">section 82a of this title</ref> and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s82a">section 82a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Health Care Improvement Act, referred to in section 1(d)(2) of the provisions of subsec. (c) setting out the model agreement, is <ref href="/us/pl/94/437">Pub. L. 94–437</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1400">90 Stat. 1400</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 18 (§ 1601 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1601">section 1601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62e9ad2b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to section 450<i>l</i> of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id62e9ad2c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 93–638</ref> was renumbered section 5(f) and was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450c/f">section 450c(f) of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification as <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5305/f">section 5305(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62e9ad2d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/180/s205/1">Pub. L. 116–180, § 205(1)</ref>, inserted “subject to subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321">section 5321 of this title</ref>,” before “contain”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/180/s205/3">Pub. L. 116–180, § 205(3)</ref>, substituted “two performance monitoring visits” for “one performance monitoring visit” in the introductory provisions of section 1(b)(7)(C) of the provisions setting out the model agreement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/180/s205/2">Pub. L. 116–180, § 205(2)</ref>, inserted “subject to subsections (a) and (b) of section 102 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5321">25 U.S.C. 5321</ref>),” before “such other provisions” in section 1(f)(2)(A)(ii) of the provisions setting out the model agreement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/568">Pub. L. 106–568</ref> substituted “, <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/s16">section 16 of the Act of June 18, 1934</ref>” for “and <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-18/s16">section 16 of the Act of June 18, 1934</ref>” and “and the Act of <date date="1952-07-03">July 3, 1952</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s82a">25 U.S.C. 82a</ref>), shall not apply” for “shall not apply” in section 1(b)(15)(A) of the provisions setting out the model agreement.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id62e9ad2e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id62e9ad2f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Quarterly Payments of Funds to Tribes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 105–83, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1997-11-14">Nov. 14, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1590">111 Stat. 1590</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/83/tIII/s311">“Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/pl/103/413">Public Law 103–413</ref> [see Short Title of 1994 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>], quarterly payments of funds to tribes and tribal organizations under annual funding agreements pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/93/638/s108">section 108 of Public Law 93–638</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5329">25 U.S.C. 5329</ref>], as amended, beginning in fiscal year 1998 and therafter [sic], may be made on the first business day following the first day of a fiscal quarter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/d/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(d) [title III, § 311]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-181">110 Stat. 3009–181</ref>, 3009–221.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101/c/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(c) [title III, § 311]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-156">110 Stat. 1321–156</ref>, 1321–197; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
