<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62e9ad50-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5341"><num value="5341">§ 5341.</num><heading> Donations for Indians; use of gifts; annual report to Congress</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior may accept donations of funds or other property for the advancement of the Indian race, and he may use the donated property in accordance with the terms of the donation in furtherance of any program authorized by other provision of law for the benefit of Indians. An annual report shall be made to the Congress on donations received and allocations made from such donations. This report shall include administrative costs and other pertinent data.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id62e9ad51-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1931-02-14/ch171">Feb. 14, 1931, ch. 171</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1106">46 Stat. 1106</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/333">Pub. L. 90–333</ref>, <date date="1968-06-08">June 8, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/171">82 Stat. 171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62e9ad52-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62e9ad53-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62e9ad54-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Johnson-O’Malley Act which comprises this subchapter, nor as part of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s451">section 451 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id62e9ad55-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/333">Pub. L. 90–333</ref> expanded area of permissible uses to which Secretary may put donated property by substituting provisions allowing inclusion of programs otherwise authorized by law intended to benefit Indians for provisions limiting permissible uses to programs otherwise authorized by law only if it could be shown that property would benefit a particular Indian institution or individual, and inserted provisions for an annual report to Congress on donations received and allocations made from such donations.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id62e9ad56-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id62e9ad57-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in this section relating to making an annual report to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and page 113 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
