<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id62f0da5f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387"><num value="5387">§ 5387.</num><heading> Provisions relating to the Secretary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da60-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Mandatory provisions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da61-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Health status reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Compacts or funding agreements negotiated between the Secretary and an Indian tribe shall include a provision that requires the Indian tribe to report on health status and service delivery—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62f0da62-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to the extent such data is not otherwise available to the Secretary and specific funds for this purpose are provided by the Secretary under the funding agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62f0da63-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if such reporting shall impose minimal burdens on the participating Indian tribe and such requirements are promulgated under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5397">section 5397 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da64-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reassumption</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da65-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Compacts or funding agreements negotiated between the Secretary and an Indian tribe shall include a provision authorizing the Secretary to reassume operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portions thereof) and associated funding if there is a specific finding relative to that program, service, function, or activity (or portion thereof) of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da66-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> imminent endangerment of the public health caused by an act or omission of the Indian tribe, and the imminent endangerment arises out of a failure to carry out the compact or funding agreement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da67-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> gross mismanagement with respect to funds transferred to a tribe by a compact or funding agreement, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with the Inspector General, as appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da68-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall not reassume operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portions thereof) unless—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da69-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Secretary has first provided written notice and a hearing on the record to the Indian tribe; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da6a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Indian tribe has not taken corrective action to remedy the imminent endangerment to public health or gross mismanagement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da6b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da6c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), the Secretary may, upon written notification to the Indian tribe, immediately reassume operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portion thereof) if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id62f0da6d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the Secretary makes a finding of imminent substantial and irreparable endangerment of the public health caused by an act or omission of the Indian tribe; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id62f0da6e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the endangerment arises out of a failure to carry out the compact or funding agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da6f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Reassumption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the Secretary reassumes operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portion thereof) under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall provide the Indian tribe with a hearing on the record not later than 10 days after such reassumption.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da70-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/a/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In any hearing or appeal involving a decision to reassume operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portion thereof), the Secretary shall have the burden of proof of demonstrating by clear and convincing evidence the validity of the grounds for the reassumption.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da71-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Final offer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event the Secretary and a participating Indian tribe are unable to agree, in whole or in part, on the terms of a compact or funding agreement (including funding levels), the Indian tribe may submit a final offer to the Secretary. Not more than 45 days after such submission, or within a longer time agreed upon by the Indian tribe, the Secretary shall review and make a determination with respect to such offer. In the absence of a timely rejection of the offer, in whole or in part, made in compliance with subsection (c) of this section, the offer shall be deemed agreed to by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da72-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Rejection of final offers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da73-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary rejects an offer made under subsection (b) of this section (or one or more provisions or funding levels in such offer), the Secretary shall provide—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62f0da74-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> a timely written notification to the Indian tribe that contains a specific finding that clearly demonstrates, or that is supported by a controlling legal authority, that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da75-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of funds proposed in the final offer exceeds the applicable funding level to which the Indian tribe is entitled under this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da76-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the program, function, service, or activity (or portion thereof) that is the subject of the final offer is an inherent Federal function that cannot legally be delegated to an Indian tribe;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da77-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the Indian tribe cannot carry out the program, function, service, or activity (or portion thereof) in a manner that would not result in significant danger or risk to the public health; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id62f0da78-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the Indian tribe is not eligible to participate in self-governance under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5383">section 5383 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62f0da79-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> technical assistance to overcome the objections stated in the notification required by subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62f0da7a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Indian tribe with a hearing on the record with the right to engage in full discovery relevant to any issue raised in the matter and the opportunity for appeal on the objections raised, except that the Indian tribe may, in lieu of filing such appeal, directly proceed to initiate an action in a Federal district court pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5331/a">section 5331(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id62f0da7b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the Indian tribe with the option of entering into the severable portions of a final proposed compact or funding agreement, or provision thereof, (including a lesser funding amount, if any), that the Secretary did not reject, subject to any additional alterations necessary to conform the compact or funding agreement to the severed provisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da7c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of exercising certain option</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If an Indian tribe exercises the option specified in paragraph (1)(D), that Indian tribe shall retain the right to appeal the Secretary’s rejection under this section, and subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of that paragraph shall only apply to that portion of the proposed final compact, funding agreement, or provision thereof that was rejected by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da7d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Burden of proof</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to any hearing or appeal or civil action conducted pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall have the burden of demonstrating by clear and convincing evidence the validity of the grounds for rejecting the offer (or a provision thereof) made under subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da7e-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Good faith</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the negotiation of compacts and funding agreements the Secretary shall at all times negotiate in good faith to maximize implementation of the self-governance policy. The Secretary shall carry out this subchapter in a manner that maximizes the policy of tribal self-governance, in a manner consistent with the purposes specified in section 3 of the Tribal Self-Governance Amendments of 2000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da7f-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Savings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent that programs, functions, services, or activities (or portions thereof) carried out by Indian tribes under this subchapter reduce the administrative or other responsibilities of the Secretary with respect to the operation of Indian programs and result in savings that have not otherwise been included in the amount of tribal shares and other funds determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5388/c">section 5388(c) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall make such savings available to the Indian tribes, inter-tribal consortia, or tribal organizations for the provision of additional services to program beneficiaries in a manner equitable to directly served, contracted, and compacted programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da80-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Trust responsibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is prohibited from waiving, modifying, or diminishing in any way the trust responsibility of the United States with respect to Indian tribes and individual Indians that exists under treaties, Executive orders, other laws, or court decisions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id62f0da81-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Decisionmaker</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A decision that constitutes final agency action and relates to an appeal within the Department of Health and Human Services conducted under subsection (c) of this section shall be made either—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62f0da82-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> by an official of the Department who holds a position at a higher organizational level within the Department than the level of the departmental agency in which the decision that is the subject of the appeal was made; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id62f0da83-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s5387/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> by an administrative judge.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id62f0da84-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/638/tV/s507">Pub. L. 93–638, title V, § 507</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/260/s4">Pub. L. 106–260, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-08-18">Aug. 18, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/719">114 Stat. 719</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id62f0da85-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id62f0da86-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id62f0da87-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 3 of the Tribal Self-Governance Amendments of 2000, referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/106/260/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 106–260</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5381">section 5381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id62f0da88-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s458aaa–6">section 458aaa–6 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
