<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id620bf777-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa" identifier="/us/usc/t25/s7"><num value="7">§ 7.</num><heading> Fees for furnishing certified copies of records</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of Indian Affairs shall have the custody of said seal, and shall furnish certified copies of any such records, books, maps, or papers belonging to or on the files of said office, to any person applying therefor who shall comply with the requirements of said office, upon the payment by such parties at the rate of 10 cents per hundred words, and $1 for copies of maps or plats, and the additional sum of 25 cents for the Commissioner’s certificate of verification, with the seal of said office; and one of the employees of said office shall be designated by the Commissioner as the receiving clerk, and the amounts so received shall, under the direction of the Commissioner, be paid into the Treasury of the United States; but fees shall not be demanded for such authenticated copies as may be required by the officers of any branch of the Government or by any Indian who shall satisfy the Commissioner by satisfactory legal evidence that he or she is not able, by reason of poverty, to pay such fees, nor for such unverified copies as the Commissioner in his discretion may deem proper to furnish.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id620bf778-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1892-07-26/ch256/s4">July 26, 1892, ch. 256, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/27/273">27 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/310/tII/s229/b">Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 229(b)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/208">86 Stat. 208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id620bf779-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id620bf77a-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id620bf77b-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—<ref href="/us/pl/92/310">Pub. L. 92–310</ref> struck out provisions which required the receiving clerk to give a bond in the sum of $1,000.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id620bf77c-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id620bf77d-4962-11f1-add1-b56d3fa293fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1262">64 Stat. 1262</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
