<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id44cadee0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250"><num value="1250">§ 1250.</num><heading> Gain from dispositions of certain depreciable realty</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadee1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadee2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional depreciation after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadee3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If section 1250 property is disposed of after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>, then the applicable percentage of the lower of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadee4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that portion of the additional depreciation (as defined in subsection (b)(1) or (4)) attributable to periods after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>, in respect of the property, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadee5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the excess of the amount realized (in the case of a sale, exchange, or involuntary conversion), or the fair market value of such property (in the case of any other disposition), over the adjusted basis of such property,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">shall be treated as gain which is ordinary income. Such gain shall be recognized notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadee6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable percentage</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “applicable percentage” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadee7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of section 1250 property with respect to which a mortgage is insured under section 221(d)(3) or 236 of the National Housing Act, or housing financed or assisted by direct loan or tax abatement under similar provisions of State or local laws and with respect to which the owner is subject to the restrictions described in section 1039(b)(1)(B) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990), 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month the property was held after the date the property was held 100 full months;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadee8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of dwelling units which, on the average, were held for occupancy by families or individuals eligible to receive subsidies under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, as amended, or under the provisions of State or local law authorizing similar levels of subsidy for lower-income families, 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month the property was held after the date the property was held 100 full months;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadee9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in the case of section 1250 property with respect to which a depreciation deduction for rehabilitation expenditures was allowed under section 167(k), 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month in excess of 100 full months after the date on which such property was placed in service;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadeea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> in the case of section 1250 property with respect to which a loan is made or insured under title V of the Housing Act of 1949, 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month the property was held after the date the property was held 100 full months; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadeeb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/1/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> in the case of all other section 1250 property, 100 percent.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">In the case of a building (or a portion of a building devoted to dwelling units), if, on the average, 85 percent or more of the dwelling units contained in such building (or portion thereof) are units described in clause (ii), such building (or portion thereof) shall be treated as property described in clause (ii). Clauses (i), (ii), and (iv) shall not apply with respect to the additional depreciation described in subsection (b)(4) which was allowed under section 167(k).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadeec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional depreciation after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, and before <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadeed-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If section 1250 property is disposed of after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, and the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) exceeds the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(i), then the applicable percentage of the lower of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadeee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that portion of the additional depreciation attributable to periods after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, and before <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>, in respect of the property, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadeef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the excess of the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) over the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(i),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">shall also be treated as gain which is ordinary income. Such gain shall be recognized notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadef0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable percentage</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “applicable percentage” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadef1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of section 1250 property disposed of pursuant to a written contract which was, on <date date="1969-07-24">July 24, 1969</date>, and at all times thereafter, binding on the owner of the property, 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month the property was held after the date the property was held 20 full months;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadef2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of section 1250 property with respect to which a mortgage is insured under section 221(d)(3) or 236 of the National Housing Act, or housing financed or assisted by direct loan or tax abatement under similar provisions of State or local laws, and with respect to which the owner is subject to the restrictions described in section 1039(b)(1)(B) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990), 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month the property was held after the date the property was held 20 full months;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadef3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in the case of residential rental property (as defined in section 167(j)(2)(B)) other than that covered by clauses (i) and (ii), 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month the property was held after the date the property was held 100 full months;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadef4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> in the case of section 1250 property with respect to which a depreciation deduction for rehabilitation expenditures was allowed under section 167(k), 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month in excess of 100 full months after the date on which such property was placed in service; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadef5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> in the case of all other section 1250 property, 100 percent.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">Clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) shall not apply with respect to the additional depreciation described in subsection (b)(4).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadef6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional depreciation before <date date="1970-01-01">January 1, 1970</date></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadef7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If section 1250 property is disposed of after <date date="1963-12-31">December 31, 1963</date>, and the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) exceeds the sum of the amounts determined under paragraphs (1)(A)(i) and (2)(A)(i), then the applicable percentage of the lower of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadef8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that portion of the additional depreciation attributable to periods before <date date="1970-01-01">January 1, 1970</date>, in respect of the property, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadef9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the excess of the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) over the sum of the amounts determined under paragraphs (1)(A)(i) and (2)(A)(i),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">shall also be treated as gain which is ordinary income. Such gain shall be recognized notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadefa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable percentage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “applicable percentage” means 100 percent minus 1 percentage point for each full month the property was held after the date on which the property was held for 20 full months.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadefb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, any reference to section 167(k) or 167(j)(2)(B) shall be treated as a reference to such section as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadefc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For reduction in the case of corporations on capital gain treatment under this section, see section 291(a)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadefd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional depreciation defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadefe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “additional depreciation” means, in the case of any property, the depreciation adjustments in respect of such property; except that, in the case of property held more than one year, it means such adjustments only to the extent that they exceed the amount of the depreciation adjustments which would have resulted if such adjustments had been determined for each taxable year under the straight line method of adjustment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadeff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Property held by lessee</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a lessee, in determining the depreciation adjustments which would have resulted in respect of any building erected (or other improvement made) on the leased property, or in respect of any cost of acquiring the lease, the lease period shall be treated as including all renewal periods. For purposes of the preceding sentence—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cadf00-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “renewal period” means any period for which the lease may be renewed, extended, or continued pursuant to an option exercisable by the lessee, but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cadf01-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the inclusion of renewal periods shall not extend the period taken into account by more than ⅔ of the period on the basis of which the depreciation adjustments were allowed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf02-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Depreciation adjustments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “depreciation adjustments” means, in respect of any property, all adjustments attributable to periods after <date date="1963-12-31">December 31, 1963</date>, reflected in the adjusted basis of such property on account of deductions (whether in respect of the same or other property) allowed or allowable to the taxpayer or to any other person for exhaustion, wear and tear, obsolescence, or amortization (other than amortization under section 168 (as in effect before its repeal by the Tax Reform Act of 1976), 169, 185 (as in effect before its repeal by the Tax Reform Act of 1986), 188 (as in effect before its repeal by the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990), 190, or 193). For purposes of the preceding sentence, if the taxpayer can establish by adequate records or other sufficient evidence that the amount allowed as a deduction for any period was less than the amount allowable, the amount taken into account for such period shall be the amount allowed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf03-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional depreciation attributable to rehabilitation expenditures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “additional depreciation” also means, in the case of section 1250 property with respect to which a depreciation or amortization deduction for rehabilitation expenditures was allowed under section 167(k) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) or 191 (as in effect before its repeal by the Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981), the depreciation or amortization adjustments allowed under such section to the extent attributable to such property, except that, in the case of such property held for more than one year after the rehabilitation expenditures so allowed were incurred, it means such adjustments only to the extent that they exceed the amount of the depreciation adjustments which would have resulted if such adjustments had been determined under the straight line method of adjustment without regard to the useful life permitted under section 167(k) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) or 191 (as in effect before its repeal by the Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf04-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Method of computing straight line adjustments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the depreciation adjustments which would have resulted for any taxable year under the straight line method shall be determined—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cadf05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of property to which section 168 applies, by determining the adjustments which would have resulted for such year if the taxpayer had elected the straight line method for such year using the recovery period applicable to such property, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cadf06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case any property to which section 168 does not apply, if a useful life (or salvage value) was used in determining the amount allowable as a deduction for any taxable year, by using such life (or value).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Section 1250 property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “section 1250 property” means any real property (other than section 1245 property, as defined in section 1245(a)(3)) which is or has been property of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation provided in section 167.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions and limitations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Gifts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subsection (a) shall not apply to a disposition by gift.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfers at death</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in section 691 (relating to income in respect of a decedent), subsection (a) shall not apply to a transfer at death.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain tax-free transactions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the basis of property in the hands of a transferee is determined by reference to its basis in the hands of the transferor by reason of the application of section 332, 351, 361, 721, or 731, then the amount of gain taken into account by the transferor under subsection (a) shall not exceed the amount of gain recognized to the transferor on the transfer of such property (determined without regard to this section). Except as provided in paragraph (6), this paragraph shall not apply to a disposition to an organization (other than a cooperative described in section 521) which is exempt from the tax imposed by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Like kind exchanges; involuntary conversions, etc.</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf0d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Recognition limit</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If property is disposed of and gain (determined without regard to this section) is not recognized in whole or in part under section 1031 or 1033, then the amount of gain taken into account by the transferor under subsection (a) shall not exceed the greater of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf0e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of gain recognized on the disposition (determined without regard to this section), increased as provided in subparagraph (B), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf0f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount determined under subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf10-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Increase for certain stock</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">With respect to any transaction, the increase provided by this subparagraph is the amount equal to the fair market value of any stock purchased in a corporation which (but for this paragraph) would result in nonrecognition of gain under section 1033(a)(2)(A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf11-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment where insufficient section 1250 property is acquired</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">With respect to any transaction, the amount determined under this subparagraph shall be the excess of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf12-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of gain which would (but for this paragraph) be taken into account under subsection (a), over</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf13-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the fair market value (or cost in the case of a transaction described in section 1033(a)(2)) of the section 1250 property acquired in the transaction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf14-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis of property acquired</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of property purchased by the taxpayer in a transaction described in section 1033(a)(2), in applying section 1033(b)(2), such sentence <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002177">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002177"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> shall be applied—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf15-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> first solely to section 1250 properties and to the amount of gain not taken into account under subsection (a) by reason of this paragraph, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf16-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> then to all purchased properties to which such sentence applies and to the remaining gain not recognized on the transaction as if the cost of the section 1250 properties were the basis of such properties computed under clause (i).</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">In the case of property acquired in any other transaction to which this paragraph applies, rules consistent with the preceding sentence shall be applied under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf17-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/4/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional depreciation with respect to property disposed of</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of any transaction described in section 1031 or 1033, the additional depreciation in respect of the section 1250 property acquired which is attributable to the section 1250 property disposed of shall be an amount equal to the amount of the gain which was not taken into account under subsection (a) by reason of the application of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf18-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Property distributed by a partnership to a partner</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf19-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this section, the basis of section 1250 property distributed by a partnership to a partner shall be deemed to be determined by reference to the adjusted basis of such property to the partnership.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf1a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional depreciation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In respect of any property described in subparagraph (A), the additional depreciation attributable to periods before the distribution by the partnership shall be—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf1b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of the gain to which subsection (a) would have applied if such property had been sold by the partnership immediately before the distribution at its fair market value at such time and the applicable percentage for the property had been 100 percent, reduced by</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cadf1c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if section 751(b) applied to any part of such gain, the amount of such gain to which section 751(b) would have applied if the applicable percentage for the property had been 100 percent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf1d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfers to tax-exempt organization where property will be used in unrelated business</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf1e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The second sentence of paragraph (3) shall not apply to a disposition of section 1250 property to an organization described in section 511(a)(2) or 511(b)(2) if, immediately after such disposition, such organization uses such property in an unrelated trade or business (as defined in section 513).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf1f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Later change in use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If any property with respect to the disposition of which gain is not recognized by reason of subparagraph (A) ceases to be used in an unrelated trade or business of the organization acquiring such property, such organization shall be treated for purposes of this section as having disposed of such property on the date of such cessation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf20-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/d/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreclosure dispositions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If any section 1250 property is disposed of by the taxpayer pursuant to a bid for such property at foreclosure or by operation of an agreement or of process of law after there was a default on indebtedness which such property secured, the applicable percentage referred to in paragraph (1)(B), (2)(B), or (3)(B) of subsection (a), as the case may be, shall be determined as if the taxpayer ceased to hold such property on the date of the beginning of the proceedings pursuant to which the disposition occurred, or, in the event there are no proceedings, such percentage shall be determined as if the taxpayer ceased to hold such property on the date, determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, on which such operation of an agreement or process of law, pursuant to which the disposition occurred, began.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf21-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Holding period</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of determining the applicable percentage under this section, the provisions of section 1223 shall not apply, and the holding period of section 1250 property shall be determined under the following rules:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf22-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Beginning of holding period</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The holding period of section 1250 property shall be deemed to begin—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cadf23-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of property acquired by the taxpayer, on the day after the date of acquisition, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cadf24-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of property constructed, reconstructed, or erected by the taxpayer, on the first day of the month during which the property is placed in service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf25-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Property with transferred basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the basis of property acquired in a transaction described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (d) is determined by reference to its basis in the hands of the transferor, then the holding period of the property in the hands of the transferee shall include the holding period of the property in the hands of the transferor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf26-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for property which is substantially improved</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf27-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount treated as ordinary income</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, in the case of a disposition of section 1250 property, the property is treated as consisting of more than one element by reason of paragraph (3), then the amount taken into account under subsection (a) in respect of such section 1250 property as ordinary income shall be the sum of the amounts determined under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cadf28-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Ordinary income attributable to an element</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the amount taken into account for any element shall be the sum of a series of amounts determined for the periods set forth in subsection (a), with the amount for any such period being determined by multiplying—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cd2819-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount which bears the same ratio to the lower of the amounts specified in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (a)(1)(A), in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (a)(2)(A), or in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (a)(3)(A), as the case may be, for the section 1250 property as the additional depreciation for such element attributable to such period bears to the sum of the additional depreciation for all elements attributable to such period, by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cd281a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the applicable percentage for such element for such period.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, determinations with respect to any element shall be made as if it were a separate property.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cd281b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Property consisting of more than one element</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In applying this subsection in the case of any section 1250 property, there shall be treated as a separate element—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cd281c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> each separate improvement,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cd281d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if, before completion of section 1250 property, units thereof (as distinguished from improvements) were placed in service, each such unit of section 1250 property, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44cd281e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the remaining property which is not taken into account under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44cd281f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Property which is substantially improved</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cd2820-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “separate improvement” means each improvement added during the 36–month period ending on the last day of any taxable year to the capital account for the property, but only if the sum of the amounts added to such account during such period exceeds the greatest of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cd2821-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 25 percent of the adjusted basis of the property,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cd2822-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 10 percent of the adjusted basis of the property, determined without regard to the adjustments provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 1016(a), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cd2823-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> $5,000.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">For purposes of clauses (i) and (ii), the adjusted basis of the property shall be determined as of the beginning of the first day of such 36–month period, or of the holding period of the property (within the meaning of subsection (e)), whichever is the later.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cd2824-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Improvements in any taxable year shall be taken into account for purposes of subparagraph (A) only if the sum of the amounts added to the capital account for the property for such taxable year exceeds the greater of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cd2825-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> $2,000, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44cd2826-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> one percent of the adjusted basis referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii), determined, however, as of the beginning of such taxable year.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">For purposes of this section, if the amount added to the capital account for any separate improvement does not exceed the greater of clause (i) or (ii), such improvement shall be treated as placed in service on the first day, of a calendar month, which is closest to the middle of the taxable year.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44cd2827-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/f/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Improvement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “improvement” means, in the case of any section 1250 property, any addition to capital account for such property after the initial acquisition or after completion of the property.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cd2828-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments to basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as he may deem necessary to provide for adjustments to the basis of property to reflect gain recognized under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44cd2829-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1250/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of section</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall apply notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id44cd282a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s231/a">Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 231(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/100">78 Stat. 100</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tV/s521/b">Pub. L. 91–172, title V, § 521(b)</ref>, (c), (e), title VII, § 704(b)(5), title IX, § 910(b), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/652">83 Stat. 652</ref>, 653, 670, 720; <ref href="/us/pl/92/178/tIII/s303/c/3">Pub. L. 92–178, title III, § 303(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/522">85 Stat. 522</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/625/s5/c">Pub. L. 93–625, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2112">88 Stat. 2112</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/81/s2/b">Pub. L. 94–81, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/417">89 Stat. 417</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 94–455, title II, § 202(a)</ref>–(c)(1), (2), title XIX, §§ 1901(b)(3)(K), (31)(A), (B), (E), 1906(b)(13)(A), 1951(c)(2)(C), title XXI, §§ 2122(b)(4), 2124(a)(3)(D), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1527">90 Stat. 1527</ref>, 1529, 1530, 1793, 1799, 1800, 1834, 1840, 1915, 1918; <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tIV">Pub. L. 95–600, title IV</ref>, §§ 404(c)(7), 405(c)(4), title VII, § 701(f)(3)(C), (E), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2870">92 Stat. 2870</ref>, 2871, 2901; <ref href="/us/pl/96/222/tI/s107/a/1/D">Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 107(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/222">94 Stat. 222</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/tII/s251/a/2/D">Pub. L. 96–223, title II, § 251(a)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/287">94 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tII">Pub. L. 97–34, title II</ref>, §§ 204(e), 212(d)(2)(F), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/223">95 Stat. 223</ref>, 239; <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/tI/s102/a/7">Pub. L. 97–448, title I, § 102(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2368">96 Stat. 2368</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tVII/s712/a/1/B">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 712(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/946">98 Stat. 946</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tII/s242/b/2">Pub. L. 99–514, title II, § 242(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2181">100 Stat. 2181</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1002/a/1">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3352">102 Stat. 3352</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7831/b">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7831(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2426">103 Stat. 2426</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, §§ 11801(c)(6)(F), (8)(I), (15), 11812(b)(11), (12), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-524">104 Stat. 1388–524</ref>, 1388–527, 1388–536; <ref href="/us/pl/104/7/s2/b">Pub. L. 104–7, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-04-11">Apr. 11, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/93">109 Stat. 93</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1702/h/18">Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1702(h)(18)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1874">110 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tIII/s312/d/10">Pub. L. 105–34, title III, § 312(d)(10)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/840">111 Stat. 840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tVI/s6023/12">Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6023(12)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/825">112 Stat. 825</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXIII/s1331/b/3">Pub. L. 109–58, title XIII, § 1331(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1024">119 Stat. 1024</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s402/a/7">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 402(a)(7)</ref>, (h), <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2610">119 Stat. 2610</ref>, 2611; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/a/174">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(174)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1192">132 Stat. 1192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id44cd282b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id44cd282c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id44cd282d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 221 and 236 of the National Housing Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B)(i), (2)(B)(ii), are classified to sections 1715<i>l</i> and 1715z–1, respectively, of Title 12, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(B)(i), (2)(B)(ii), (4) and (b)(4), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, which was approved <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B)(ii), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Housing Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B)(iv), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">act July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/413">63 Stat. 413</ref>. Title V of the Housing Act of 1949 is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1471 et seq.) of chapter 8A of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">section 1441 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tax Reform Act of 1976, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1520">90 Stat. 1520</ref>. Section 1951(a)(4)(A) of the Act repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tax Reform Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2085">100 Stat. 2085</ref>. Section 242(a) of the Act repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s185">section 185 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is title XI of <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-400">104 Stat. 1388–400</ref>. Section 11801(a)(13) of the Act repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s188">section 188 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981, referred to in subsec. (b)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/172">95 Stat. 172</ref>. <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s191">Section 191 of this title</ref> was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s212/d/1">section 212(d)(1) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Such sentence, referred to in subsec. (d)(4)(D), probably should be a reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1033/b/2">section 1033(b)(2) of this title</ref>, following the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s6023/12">Pub. L. 105–206, § 6023(12)</ref>, which substituted “section 1033(b)(2)” for “the last sentence of section 1033(b)” in the preceding reference. See 1998 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id44cd282e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> substituted “paragraph (6)” for “paragraph (9)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s402/h">Pub. L. 109–135, § 402(h)</ref>, struck out “or by section 179D” after “190, or 193)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1331/b/3">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1331(b)(3)</ref>, inserted “or by section 179D” after “190, or 193)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s402/a/7/A">Pub. L. 109–135, § 402(a)(7)(A)</ref>, redesignated pars. (6) to (8) as (5) to (7), respectively, and struck out heading and text of former par. (5). Text read as follows: “Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules consistent with paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection and with subsections (e) and (f) shall apply in the case of transactions described in section 1081 (relating to exchanges in obedience to SEC orders).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s402/a/7/B">Pub. L. 109–135, § 402(a)(7)(B)</ref>, substituted “or (3)” for “(3), or (5)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (d)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206">Pub. L. 105–206</ref> substituted “section 1033(b)(2)” for “the last sentence of section 1033(b)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (d)(7) to (10). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s312/d/10/A">Pub. L. 105–34, § 312(d)(10)(A)</ref>, redesignated pars. (9) and (10) as (7) and (8), respectively, and struck out heading and text of former par. (7). Text read as follows: “Subsection (a) shall not apply to a disposition of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) property to the extent used by the taxpayer as his principal residence (within the meaning of section 1034, relating to rollover of gain on sale of principal residence), and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) property in respect of which the taxpayer meets the age and ownership requirements of section 121 (relating to one-time exclusion of gain from sale of principal residence by individual who has attained age 55) but only to the extent that he meets the use requirements of such section in respect of such property.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s312/d/10/B">Pub. L. 105–34, § 312(d)(10)(B)</ref>, struck out heading and text of par. (3). Text read as follows: “If the basis of property acquired in a transaction described in paragraph (7) of subsection (d) is determined by reference to the basis in the hands of the taxpayer of other property, then the holding period of the property acquired shall include the holding period of such other property.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> struck out par. (4) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) <inline class="small-caps">Qualified low-income housing</inline>.—The holding period of any section 1250 property acquired which is described in subsection (d)(8)(E)(i) shall include the holding period of the corresponding element of section 1250 property disposed of.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/7">Pub. L. 104–7</ref> struck out “1071 and” before “1081 transactions” in heading and “section 1071 (relating to gain from sale or exchange to effectuate policies of FCC) or” before “section 1081” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(i), (2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11801/c/15/A">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11801(c)(15)(A)</ref>, which directed the insertion of “(as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990)” after “section 1039(b)(1)(B)” in pars. (1)(A)(i) and (2)(B)(ii) of subsec. (a), was executed to pars. (1)(B)(i) and (2)(B)(ii) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11812/b/11">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11812(b)(11)</ref>, added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11801/c/6/F">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11801(c)(6)(F)</ref>, substituted “188 (as in effect before its repeal by the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990),” for “188,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11812/b/12">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11812(b)(12)</ref>, substituted “section 167(k) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990)” for “section 167(k)” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11801/c/8/I">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11801(c)(8)(I)</ref>, struck out “371(a), 374(a),” after “332, 351, 361,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11801/c/15/B">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11801(c)(15)(B)</ref>, struck out par. (8) which related to the treatment of gain from the disposition of qualified low-income housing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11801/c/15/C">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11801(c)(15)(C)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (h) and (i) as (g) and (h), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (g) which provided special rules for qualified low-income housing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7831/b/1">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7831(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “of property to which section 168 applies” for “of recovery property”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7831/b/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7831(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “to which section 168 does not apply” for “which is not recovery property”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (d)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> struck out par. (11) which related to section 1245 recovery property.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> inserted “(as in effect before its repeal by the Tax Reform Act of 1986)” after “185”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s102/a/7/B">Pub. L. 97–448, § 102(a)(7)(B)</ref>, struck out last sentence providing that, for purposes of defining “additional depreciation”, if a useful life (or salvage value) was used in determining the amount allowed as a deduction for any taxable year, such life (or value) was to be used in determining the depreciation adjustments which would have resulted for such year under the straight line method.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s102/a/7/A">Pub. L. 97–448, § 102(a)(7)(A)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s212/d/2/F">Pub. L. 97–34, § 212(d)(2)(F)</ref>, inserted “(as in effect before its repeal by the Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981)” after “section 167(k) or 191” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s204/e">Pub. L. 97–34, § 204(e)</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/96/222">Pub. L. 96–222</ref> inserted “which was allowed under section 167(k)” at end of last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> inserted reference to section 193.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s701/f/3/C">Pub. L. 95–600, § 701(f)(3)(C)</ref>, struck out reference to section 191.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s701/f/3/E">Pub. L. 95–600, § 701(f)(3)(E)</ref>, inserted reference to amortization deduction, amortization adjustments, and to section 191 in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s405/c/4">Pub. L. 95–600, § 405(c)(4)</ref>, substituted “relating to rollover of gain on sale of principal residence” for “relating to sale or exchange of residence”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s404/c/7">Pub. L. 95–600, § 404(c)(7)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to a one-time exclusion and principal residence and substituted “55” for “65”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s202/a">Pub. L. 94–455, § 202(a)</ref>, in revising text generally, made the following changes:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Added par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Redesignated as pars. (2) and (3) existing pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Made the following changes in par. (2): inserted in heading “, and before <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>”; designated introductory text as subpar. “(A) In general”; inserted therein “and the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) exceeds the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(i), then”; redesignated as cl. (i) existing subpar. (A); substituted therein “attributable to periods after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, and before <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>” for “(as defined in subsection (b)(1) or (4) attributable to periods after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>”; substituted cl. (ii) and concluding text for subpar. (B) and concluding text which read:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) the excess of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the amount realized (in the case of a sale, exchange, or involuntary conversion), or the fair market value of such property (in the case of any other disposition), over</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the adjusted basis of such property,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be treated as gain from the sale or exchange of property which is neither a capital asset nor property described in section 1231. Such gain shall be recognized notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle.”; redesignated as subpar. (B) existing subpar. (C); substituted therein introductory “subparagraph (A)” for “paragraph (1)”; and deleted from cl. (ii) “constructed, reconstructed, or acquired by the taxpayer before <date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>,” after “section 1250 property” and “is” before “financed”, and substituted “1” for “one”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) Made the following changes in par. (3): substituted in subpar. (A) “determined under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) exceeds the sum of the amounts determined under paragraphs (1)(A)(i) and (2)(A)(i)” for “determined under paragraph (1)(B) exceeds the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)”; and substituted subpar. (A)(ii) and concluding text for par. (2)(A)(ii), and concluding text which read:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the excess of the amount determined under paragraph (1)(B) over the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A),</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall also be treated as gain from the sale or exchange of property which is neither a capital asset nor property described in section 1231. Such gain shall be recognized notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1951(c)(2)(C), 2122(b)(4), 2124(a)(3)(D), inserted “(as in effect before its repeal by the Tax Reform Act of 1976)” after “section 168” and reference to sections 190 and 191.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/31/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(31)(A)</ref>, substituted reference to section “1033(a)(2)(A)” for “1033(a)(3)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/31/B">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(31)(B)</ref>, substituted reference to section “1033(a)(2)” for “1033(a)(3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1901(b)(31)(B), (E), 1906(b)(13)(A), substituted reference to sections “1033(a)(2)” and “1033(b)” for “1033(a)(3)” and “1033(c)”, respectively, and struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5), (8)(F)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s202/b">Pub. L. 94–455, § 202(b)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/3/K">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(3)(K)</ref>, substituted “ordinary income” for “gain from the sale or exchange of property which is neither a capital asset nor property described in section 1231”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s202/c/1">Pub. L. 94–455, § 202(c)(1)</ref>, substituted introductory text “the sum of a series of amounts determined for the periods set forth in subsection (a), with the amount for any such period being determined by multiplying” for “the sum of—(A) the amount (if any) determined by multiplying”; substituted subpar. (A) as combined text for prior subpars. (A)(i) and (B)(i) reading “(i) the amount which bears the same ratio to the lower of the amounts specified in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) for the section 1250 property as the additional depreciation for such element attributable to periods after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, bears to the sum of the additional depreciation for all elements attributable to periods after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, by” and “(i) the amount which bears the same ratio to the lower of the amounts specified in subsection (a)(2)(A)(i) or (ii) for the section 1250 property as the additional depreciation for such element attributable to periods before <date date="1970-01-01">January 1, 1970</date>, bears to the sum of the additional depreciation for all elements attributable to periods before <date date="1970-01-01">January 1, 1970</date>, by”; and substituted subpar. (B) as combined text for prior subpars. (A)(ii) and (B)(ii), inserting therein “for such period” after “for such element”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/3/K">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(3)(K)</ref>, substituted “ordinary income” for “gain from the sale or exchange of property which is neither a capital asset nor property described in section 1231”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s202/c/2">Pub. L. 94–455, § 202(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “shall be determined in a manner similar to that provided by subsection (f)(2).” for “shall be the amount determined by multiplying—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the amount which bears the same ratio to the lower of the additional depreciation or the gain recognized for the section 1250 property disposed of as the additional depreciation for such element bears to the sum of the additional depreciation for all elements disposed of, by</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the applicable percentage for such element.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, determinations with respect to any element shall be made as if it were a separate property.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a)(1)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/93/625">Pub. L. 93–625</ref> substituted “<date date="1976-01-01">January 1, 1976</date>” for “<date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/94/81/s2/b">Pub. L. 94–81, § 2(b)</ref>, inserted reference to par. (9) in par. (3), and added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/92/178">Pub. L. 92–178</ref> inserted reference to section 188.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s521/b">Pub. L. 91–172, § 521(b)</ref>, modified the recapture rules pertaining to residential housing by allowing a 1 percent per month reduction in the amount to be recaptured as ordinary income after the property has been held for 100 full months, with other real property remaining subject to full recapture, applied the existing recapture rules where the sale of property was subject to a binding contract in existence prior to <date date="1969-07-25">July 25, 1969</date>, provided that changes in the recapture rules are not to apply in federally assisted projects (such as programs under section 221(d)(3) or 236 of the National Housing Act) or to other publicly assisted housing programs under which the return to the investor is limited on a comparable basis, thereby rendering these projects subject to a recapture of the depreciation in full if the sale occurs in the first 12 months and for a phaseout of the recapture of the excess of accelerated over straight-line depreciation after 20 months, the recapture being reduced at the rate of 1 percent per month until 120 months after which no recapture applies, with such recapture rules to continue to apply only with respect to such property constructed, reconstructed, or acquired before <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>, and applied new recapture rules to depreciation attributable to periods after <date date="1969-12-31">Dec. 31, 1969</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s512/c">Pub. L. 91–172, § 512(c)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s704/b/5">Pub. L. 91–172, § 704(b)(5)</ref>, inserted reference to sections 169 and 185.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, §§ 521(e)(1), 910(b)(1), substituted “subsection (a)” for “subsection (a)(1)” wherever it appears and added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s910/b/2">Pub. L. 91–172, § 910(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s521/e/2/A">Pub. L. 91–172, § 521(e)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a)” for “subsection (a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s521/e/2/B">Pub. L. 91–172, § 521(e)(2)(B)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (A) and (B) as cls. (i) and (ii), respectively, of subpar. (A) and, in cls. (i) and (ii) as so redesignated, inserted reference to depreciation attributable to periods after <date date="1969-12-31">Dec. 31, 1969</date>, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s910/b/3">Pub. L. 91–172, § 910(b)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (g) and redesignated former subsecs. (g) and (h) as (h) and (i), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id44cd282f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2830-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/109/135">Pub. L. 109–135</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of the Energy Policy Act of 2005, <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, to which they relate, but amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s402/a/7">section 402(a)(7) of Pub. L. 109–135</ref> not applicable with respect to any transaction ordered in compliance with the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s79">15 U.S.C. 79</ref> et seq.) before its repeal, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s402/m">section 402(m) of Pub. L. 109–135</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2005 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s23">section 23 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="2005-12-31">Dec. 31, 2005</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1331/d">section 1331(d) of Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s179D">section 179D of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2831-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> applicable to sales and exchanges after <date date="1997-05-06">May 6, 1997</date>, with certain exceptions, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s312/d">section 312(d) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s121">section 121 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2832-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> effective, except as otherwise expressly provided, as if included in the provision of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1702/i">section 1702(i) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2833-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1995 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/7">Pub. L. 104–7</ref> applicable to sales and exchanges on or after <date date="1995-01-17">January 17, 1995</date>, and to sales and exchanges before such date if FCC tax certificate with respect to such sale or exchange was issued on or after such date, but not applicable with respect to certain binding contracts, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/7/s2/d">section 2(d) of Pub. L. 104–7</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of Repeal note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1071">section 1071 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2834-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 11812(b)(11), (12) of <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, but not applicable to any property to which <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref> does not apply by reason of subsec. (f)(5) of section 168, and not applicable to rehabilitation expenditures described in <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s252/f/5">section 252(f)(5) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11812/c">section 11812(c) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s42">section 42 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2835-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7831/g">section 7831(g) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2836-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2837-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to that portion of the basis of any property which is attributable to expenditures paid or incurred after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s242/c">section 242(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of Repeal note under former <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s185">section 185 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2838-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s715">section 715 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2839-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/448">Pub. L. 97–448</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if it had been included in the provision of the Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981, <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s109">section 109 of Pub. L. 97–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd283a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s204/e">section 204(e) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1980-12-31">Dec. 31, 1980</date>, in taxable years ending after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s209/a">section 209(a) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s212/d/2/F">section 212(d)(2)(F) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to expenditures incurred after <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s212/e">section 212(e) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46">section 46 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd283b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1979-12-31">Dec. 31, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/s251/b">section 251(b) of Pub. L. 96–223</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s193">section 193 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/222">Pub. L. 96–222</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if it had been included in the provisions of the Revenue Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/222/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 96–222</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s32">section 32 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd283c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s404/c/7">section 404(c)(7) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref> applicable to sales or exchanges after <date date="1978-07-26">July 26, 1978</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s404/d/1">section 404(d)(1) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s121">section 121 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s405/c/4">section 405(c)(4) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref> applicable to sales and exchanges of residences after <date date="1978-07-26">July 26, 1978</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s405/d">section 405(d) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1038">section 1038 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 701(f)(3)(C), (E) of <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref> effective as if included within the amendment of subsec. (b)(3) and (4) by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2124">section 2124 of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s701/f/8">section 701(f)(8) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 1978 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s167">section 167 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd283d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tII/s202/d">Pub. L. 94–455, title II, § 202(d)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1530">90 Stat. 1530</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“The amendments made by this section (other than subsection (b)) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s167">section 167 of this title</ref>] shall apply for taxable years ending after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>. The amendment made by subsection (b) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to proceedings (and to operations of law) referred to in section 1250(d)(10) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] which begin after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1901(b)(3)(K), (31)(A), (B), (E) of <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/d">section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1951/c/2/C">section 1951(c)(2)(C) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1951/d">section 1951(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2122/b/4">section 2122(b)(4) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, and before <date date="1983-01-01">Jan. 1, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2122/c">section 2122(c) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/167">Pub. L. 96–167</ref>, 9(c), <date date="1979-12-29">Dec. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1278">93 Stat. 1278</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s190">section 190 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2124/a/3/D">section 2124(a)(3)(D) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable with respect to additions to capital accounts made after <date date="1976-06-14">June 14, 1976</date> and before <date date="1981-06-15">June 15, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2124/a/4">section 2124(a)(4) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s642">section 642 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd283e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/81/s2/c">Pub. L. 94–81, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/418">89 Stat. 418</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/81/s2/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2) the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1245">section 1245 of this title</ref>] shall apply to dispositions after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Election for past transactions.—</inline></heading><content>In the case of any disposition occurring before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>], the amendments made by this section shall apply only if the organization acquiring the property elects (in the manner provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate) within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act to have such amendments apply with respect to such property.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/625">Pub. L. 93–625</ref> applicable with respect to property placed in service after <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/625/s5/d">section 5(d) of Pub. L. 93–625</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s167">section 167 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd283f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1971 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/178">Pub. L. 92–178</ref> applicable to taxable years ending after <date date="1971-12-31">Dec. 31, 1971</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/178/s303/d">section 303(d) of Pub. L. 92–178</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s642">section 642 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44cd2840-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 521(b), (c), (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years ending after <date date="1969-07-24">July 24, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s521/g">section 521(g) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s167">section 167 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s704/b/5">section 704(b)(5) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref> applicable to taxable years ending after <date date="1968-12-31">Dec. 31, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s704/c">section 704(c) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s169">section 169 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tIX/s910/d">Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, § 910(d)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/722">83 Stat. 722</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“The amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1039">section 1039 of this title</ref> and amending this section] shall apply to approved dispositions of qualified housing projects (within the meaning of section 1039 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] as added by subsection (a)) after <date date="1969-10-09">October 9, 1969</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id44cd2841-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s231/c">Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 231(c)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/105">78 Stat. 105</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s231/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting this section and amending sections 170, 301, 312, 341, 453, 751, and the analysis preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1231">section 1231 of this title</ref>] shall apply to dispositions after <date date="1963-12-31">December 31, 1963</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id44cd2842-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11821/b">section 11821(b) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s45K">section 45K of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
