<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id44ec493a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359"><num value="1359">§ 1359.</num><heading> Disposition of qualifying vessels</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44ec493b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any qualifying vessel operator sells or disposes of any qualifying vessel in an otherwise taxable transaction, at the election of such operator, no gain shall be recognized if any replacement qualifying vessel is acquired during the period specified in subsection (b), except to the extent that the amount realized upon such sale or disposition exceeds the cost of the replacement qualifying vessel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44ec493c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Period within which property must be replaced</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The period referred to in subsection (a) shall be the period beginning one year prior to the disposition of the qualifying vessel and ending—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44ec493d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 3 years after the close of the first taxable year in which the gain is realized, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44ec493e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> subject to such terms and conditions as may be specified by the Secretary, on such later date as the Secretary may designate on application by the taxpayer.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such application shall be made at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44ec493f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of section to noncorporate operators</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “qualifying vessel operator” includes any person who would be a qualifying vessel operator were such person a corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44ec4940-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for assessment of deficiency attributable to gain</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a qualifying vessel operator has made the election provided in subsection (a), then—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44ec4941-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the statutory period for the assessment of any deficiency, for any taxable year in which any part of the gain is realized, attributable to such gain shall not expire prior to the expiration of 3 years from the date the Secretary is notified by such operator (in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe) of the replacement qualifying vessel or of an intention not to replace, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44ec4942-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such deficiency may be assessed before the expiration of such 3-year period notwithstanding the provisions of section 6212(c) or the provisions of any other law or rule of law which would otherwise prevent such assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44ec4943-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1359/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis of replacement qualifying vessel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any replacement qualifying vessel purchased by the qualifying vessel operator which resulted in the nonrecognition of any part of the gain realized as the result of a sale or other disposition of a qualifying vessel, the basis shall be the cost of the replacement qualifying vessel decreased in the amount of the gain not so recognized; and if the property purchased consists of more than one piece of property, the basis determined under this sentence shall be allocated to the purchased properties in proportion to their respective costs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id44ec4944-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tII/s248/a">Pub. L. 108–357, title II, § 248(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1456">118 Stat. 1456</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id44ec4945-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id44ec4946-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id44ec4947-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s248/c">section 248(c) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2004 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s56">section 56 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
