<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id44f830be-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382"><num value="1382">§ 1382.</num><heading> Taxable income of cooperatives</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830bf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Gross income</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (b), the gross income of any organization to which this part applies shall be determined without any adjustment (as a reduction in gross receipts, an increase in cost of goods sold, or otherwise) by reason of any allocation or distribution to a patron out of the net earnings of such organization or by reason of any amount paid to a patron as a per-unit retain allocation (as defined in section 1388(f)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830c0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Patronage dividends and per-unit retain allocations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining the taxable income of an organization to which this part applies, there shall not be taken into account amounts paid during the payment period for the taxable year—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830c1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> as patronage dividends (as defined in section 1388(a)), to the extent paid in money, qualified written notices of allocation (as defined in section 1388(c)), or other property (except nonqualified written notices of allocation (as defined in section 1388(d))) with respect to patronage occurring during such taxable year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830c2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in money or other property (except written notices of allocation) in redemption of a nonqualified written notice of allocation which was paid as a patronage dividend during the payment period for the taxable year during which the patronage occurred;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830c3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> as per-unit retain allocations (as defined in section 1388(f)), to the extent paid in money, qualified per-unit retain certificates (as defined in section 1388(h)), or other property (except nonqualified per-unit retain certificates, as defined in section 1388(i)) with respect to marketing occurring during such taxable year; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830c4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in money or other property (except per-unit retain certificates) in redemption of a nonqualified per-unit retain certificate which was paid as a per-unit retain allocation during the payment period for the taxable year during which the marketing occurred.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this title, any amount not taken into account under the preceding sentence shall, in the case of an amount described in paragraph (1) or (2), be treated in the same manner as an item of gross income and as a deduction therefrom, and in the case of an amount described in paragraph (3) or (4), be treated as a deduction in arriving at gross income.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830c5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Deduction for nonpatronage distributions, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining the taxable income of an organization described in section 1381(a)(1), there shall be allowed as a deduction (in addition to other deductions allowable under this chapter)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830c6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> amounts paid during the taxable year as dividends on its capital stock; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830c7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> amounts paid during the payment period for the taxable year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44f830c8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in money, qualified written notices of allocation, or other property (except nonqualified written notices of allocation) on a patronage basis to patrons with respect to its earnings during such taxable year which are derived from business done for the United States or any of its agencies or from sources other than patronage, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44f830c9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in money or other property (except written notices of allocation) in redemption of a nonqualified written notice of allocation which was paid, during the payment period for the taxable year during which the earnings were derived, on a patronage basis to a patron with respect to earnings derived from business or sources described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830ca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment period for each taxable year</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (b) and (c)(2), the payment period for any taxable year is the period beginning with the first day of such taxable year and ending with the fifteenth day of the ninth month following the close of such year. For purposes of subsections (b)(1) and (c)(2)(A), a qualified check issued during the payment period shall be treated as an amount paid in money during such period if endorsed and cashed on or before the 90th day after the close of such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830cb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Products marketed under pooling arrangements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (b), in the case of a pooling arrangement for the marketing of products—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830cc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the patronage shall (to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary) be treated as patronage occurring during the taxable year in which the pool closes, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44f830cd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the marketing of products shall be treated as occurring during any of the taxable years in which the pool is open.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830ce-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of earnings received after patronage occurred</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any portion of the earnings from business done with or for patrons is includible in the organization’s gross income for a taxable year after the taxable year during which the patronage occurred, then for purposes of applying paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) to such portion the patronage shall, to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be considered to have occurred during the taxable year of the organization during which such earnings are includible in gross income.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830cf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of completed crop pool method of accounting</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830d0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An organization described in section 1381(a) which is engaged in pooling arrangements for the marketing of products may compute its taxable income with respect to any pool opened prior to <date date="1978-03-01">March 1, 1978</date>, under the completed crop pool method of accounting if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44f830d1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the organization has computed its taxable income under such method for the 10 taxable years ending with its first taxable year beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">December 31, 1976</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44f830d2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> with respect to the pool, the organization has entered into an agreement with the United States or any of its agencies which includes provisions to the effect that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44f830d3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the United States or such agency shall provide a loan to the organization with the products comprising the pool serving as collateral for such loan,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44f830d4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the organization shall use an amount equal to the proceeds of such loan to make price support advances to eligible producers (as determined by the United States or such agency), to defray costs of handling, processing, and storing such products, or to pay all or part of any administrative costs associated with the price support program,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44f830d5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an amount equal to the net proceeds (as determined under such agreement) from the sale or exchange of the products in the pool shall be used to repay such loan until such loan is repaid in full (or all the products in the pool are disposed of), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44f830d6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the net gains (as determined under such agreement) from the sale or exchange of such products shall be distributed to eligible producers, except to the extent that the United States or such agency permits otherwise.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44f830d7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1382/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Completed crop pool method of accounting defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “completed crop pool method of accounting” means a method of accounting under which gain or loss is computed separately for each crop year pool in the year in which the last of the products in the pool are disposed of.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id44fa79c8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s17/a">Pub. L. 87–834, § 17(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1046">76 Stat. 1046</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tII/s211/a/1">Pub. L. 89–809, title II, § 211(a)(1)</ref>–(4), <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1580">80 Stat. 1580</ref>, 1581; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tIX/s911/a">Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, § 911(a)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/722">83 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/345/s3">Pub. L. 95–345, § 3</ref>, <date date="1978-08-15">Aug. 15, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/483">92 Stat. 483</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id44fa79c9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id44fa79ca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id44fa79cb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/345">Pub. L. 95–345</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> expanded the category of per-unit retain allocations that may not be taken into account in determining the taxable income of an organization, by including per-unit retain allocations paid for in money or other property (except nonqualified per-unit retain certificates as defined in section 1388(i) of this section).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s211/a/1">Pub. L. 89–809, § 211(a)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to amounts paid to patrons as a per-unit retain allocation as defined in section 1388(f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s211/a/2">Pub. L. 89–809, § 211(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “and per-unit retain allocations” in heading, added pars. (3) and (4), and, in text following par. (4), inserted provisions making existing text applicable only to amounts described in pars. (1) and (2) and inserted text covering the treatment of amounts described in pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s211/a/3">Pub. L. 89–809, § 211(a)(3)</ref>, inserted provision that the marketing of products shall be treated as occurring during any of the taxable years in which the pool is open.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s211/a/4">Pub. L. 89–809, § 211(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b)” for “subsection (b)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id44fa79cc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa79cd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tIX/s911/c">Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, § 911(c)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/722">83 Stat. 722</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/172/tIX/s911/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1388">section 1388 of this title</ref>] shall apply to per-unit retain allocations made after <date date="1969-10-09">October 9, 1969</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa79ce-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tII/s211/e">Pub. L. 89–809, title II, § 211(e)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1584">80 Stat. 1584</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/89/809/tII/s211/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The amendments made by subsections (a), (b), and (c) [amending this section and sections 1383, 1385, and 1388 of this title] shall apply to per-unit retain allocations made during taxable years of an organization described in section 1381(a) (relating to organizations to which part I of subchapter T of chapter 1 applies) beginning after <date date="1966-04-30">April 30, 1966</date>, with respect to products delivered during such years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The amendments made by subsection (d) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6044">section 6044 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to calendar years after 1966.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id44fa79cf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable, except as otherwise provided, to taxable years of organizations described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1381/a">section 1381(a) of this title</ref> beginning after <date date="1962-12-31">Dec. 31, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s17/c">section 17(c) of Pub. L. 87–834</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1381">section 1381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
