<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id44fa7a05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388"><num value="1388">§ 1388.</num><heading> Definitions; special rules</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Patronage dividend</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “patronage dividend” means an amount paid to a patron by an organization to which part I of this subchapter applies—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44fa7a07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> on the basis of quantity or value of business done with or for such patron,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44fa7a08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> under an obligation of such organization to pay such amount, which obligation existed before the organization received the amount so paid, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44fa7a09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> which is determined by reference to the net earnings of the organization from business done with or for its patrons.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such term does not include any amount paid to a patron to the extent that (A) such amount is out of earnings other than from business done with or for patrons, or (B) such amount is out of earnings from business done with or for other patrons to whom no amounts are paid, or to whom smaller amounts are paid, with respect to substantially identical transactions. For purposes of paragraph (3), net earnings shall not be reduced by amounts paid during the year as dividends on capital stock or other proprietary capital interests of the organization to the extent that the articles of incorporation or bylaws of such organization or other contract with patrons provide that such dividends are in addition to amounts otherwise payable to patrons which are derived from business done with or for patrons during the taxable year.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Written notice of allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “written notice of allocation” means any capital stock, revolving fund certificate, retain certificate, certificate of indebtedness, letter of advice, or other written notice, which discloses to the recipient the stated dollar amount allocated to him by the organization and the portion thereof, if any, which constitutes a patronage dividend.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified written notice of allocation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “qualified written notice of allocation” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a0d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a written notice of allocation which may be redeemed in cash at its stated dollar amount at any time within a period beginning on the date such written notice of allocation is paid and ending not earlier than 90 days from such date, but only if the distributee receives written notice of the right of redemption at the time he receives such written notice of allocation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a0e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a written notice of allocation which the distributee has consented, in the manner provided in paragraph (2), to take into account at its stated dollar amount as provided in section 1385(a).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such term does not include any written notice of allocation which is paid as part of a patronage dividend or as part of a payment described in section 1382(c)(2)(A), unless 20 percent or more of the amount of such patronage dividend, or such payment, is paid in money or by qualified check.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a0f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Manner of obtaining consent</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A distributee shall consent to take a written notice of allocation into account as provided in paragraph (1)(B) only by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a10-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> making such consent in writing,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a11-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> obtaining or retaining membership in the organization after—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a12-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such organization has adopted (after <date date="1962-10-16">October 16, 1962</date>) a bylaw providing that membership in the organization constitutes such consent, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a13-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> he has received a written notification and copy of such bylaw, or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a14-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if neither subparagraph (A) nor (B) applies, endorsing and cashing a qualified check, paid as a part of the patronage dividend or payment of which such written notice of allocation is also a part, on or before the 90th day after the close of the payment period for the taxable year of the organization for which such patronage dividend or payment is paid.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a15-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Period for which consent is effective</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a16-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a17-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a consent described in paragraph (2) (A) shall be a consent with respect to all patronage of the distributee with the organization occurring (determined with the application of section 1382(e)) during the taxable year of the organization during which such consent is made and all subsequent taxable years of the organization; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a18-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a consent described in paragraph (2) (B) shall be a consent with respect to all patronage of the distributee with the organization occurring (determined without the application of section 1382(e)) after he received the notification and copy described in paragraph (2)(B)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a19-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Revocation, etc.</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a1a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any consent described in paragraph (2)(A) may be revoked (in writing) by the distributee at any time. Any such revocation shall be effective with respect to patronage occurring on or after the first day of the first taxable year of the organization beginning after the revocation is filed with such organization; except that in the case of a pooling arrangement described in section 1382(e), a revocation made by a distributee shall not be effective as to any pool with respect to which the distributee has been a patron before such revocation.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a1b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any consent described in paragraph (2)(B) shall not be effective with respect to any patronage occurring (determined without the application of section 1382(e)) after the distributee ceases to be a member of the organization or after the bylaws of the organization cease to contain the provision described in paragraph (2)(B)(i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a1c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified check</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “qualified check” means only a check (or other instrument which is redeemable in money) which is paid as a part of a patronage dividend, or as a part of a payment described in section 1382(c)(2)(A), to a distributee who has not given consent as provided in paragraph (2)(A) or (B) with respect to such patronage dividend or payment, and on which there is clearly imprinted a statement that the endorsement and cashing of the check (or other instrument) constitutes the consent of the payee to include in his gross income, as provided in the Federal income tax laws, the stated dollar amount of the written notice of allocation which is a part of the patronage dividend or payment of which such qualified check is also a part. Such term does not include any check (or other instrument) which is paid as part of a patronage dividend or payment which does not include a written notice of allocation (other than a written notice of allocation described in paragraph (1)(A)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a1d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonqualified written notice of allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “nonqualified written notice of allocation” means a written notice of allocation which is not described in subsection (c) or a qualified check which is not cashed on or before the 90th day after the close of the payment period for the taxable year for which the distribution of which it is a part is paid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a1e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of amount paid or received</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, in determining amounts paid or received—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44fa7a1f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> property (other than a written notice of allocation or a per-unit retain certificate) shall be taken into account at its fair market value, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44fa7a20-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a qualified written notice of allocation or qualified per-unit retain certificate shall be taken into account at its stated dollar amount.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a21-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Per-unit retain allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “per-unit retain allocation” means any allocation, by an organization to which part I of this subchapter applies, to a patron with respect to products marketed for him, the amount of which is fixed without reference to the net earnings of the organization pursuant to an agreement between the organization and the patron.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a22-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Per-unit retain certificate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “per-unit retain certificate” means any written notice which discloses to the recipient the stated dollar amount of a per-unit retain allocation to him by the organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a23-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified per-unit retain certificate</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a24-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “qualified per-unit retain certificate” means any per-unit retain certificate which the distributee has agreed, in the manner provided in paragraph (2), to take into account at its stated dollar amount as provided in section 1385(a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a25-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Manner of obtaining agreement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A distributee shall agree to take a per-unit retain certificate into account as provided in paragraph (1) only by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a26-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> making such agreement in writing, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a27-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> obtaining or retaining membership in the organization after—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a28-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such organization has adopted (after <date date="1966-11-13">November 13, 1966</date>) a bylaw providing that membership in the organization constitutes such agreement, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a29-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> he has received a written notification and copy of such bylaw.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a2a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Period for which agreement is effective</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a2b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a2c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an agreement described in paragraph (2)(A) shall be an agreement with respect to all products delivered by the distributee to the organization during the taxable year of the organization during which such agreement is made and all subsequent taxable years of the organization; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a2d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an agreement described in paragraph (2)(B) shall be an agreement with respect to all products delivered by the distributee to the organization after he received the notification and copy described in paragraph (2)(B)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a2e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Revocation, etc.</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a2f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any agreement described in paragraph (2)(A) may be revoked (in writing) by the distributee at any time. Any such revocation shall be effective with respect to products delivered by the distributee on or after the first day of the first taxable year of the organization beginning after the revocation is filed with the organization; except that in the case of a pooling arrangement described in section 1382(e) a revocation made by a distributee shall not be effective as to any products which were delivered to the organization by the distributee before such revocation.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a30-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/h/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any agreement described in paragraph (2)(B) shall not be effective with respect to any products delivered after the distributee ceases to be a member of the organization or after the bylaws of the organization cease to contain the provision described in paragraph (2)(B)(i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a31-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonqualified per-unit retain certificate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “nonqualified per-unit retain certificate” means a per-unit retain certificate which is not described in subsection (h).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a32-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for the netting of gains and losses by cooperatives</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, in the case of any organization to which part I of this subchapter applies—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a33-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Optional netting of patronage gains and losses permitted</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The net earnings of such organization may, at its option, be determined by offsetting patronage losses (including any patronage loss carried to such year) which are attributable to 1 or more allocation units (whether such units are functional, divisional, departmental, geographic, or otherwise) against patronage earnings of 1 or more other such allocation units.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a34-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain netting permitted after section 381 transactions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If such an organization acquires the assets of another such organization in a transaction described in section 381(a), the acquiring organization may, in computing its net earnings for taxable years ending after the date of acquisition, offset losses of 1 or more allocation units of the acquiring or acquired organization against earnings of the acquired or acquiring organization, respectively, but only to the extent—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a35-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such earnings are properly allocable to periods after the date of acquisition, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44fa7a36-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such earnings could have been offset by such losses if such earnings and losses had been derived from allocation units of the same organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a37-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice requirements</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a38-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of any organization which exercises its option under paragraph (1) for any taxable year, such organization shall, on or before the 15th day of the 9th month following the close of such taxable year, provide to its patrons a written notice which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a39-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> states that the organization has offset earnings and losses from 1 or more of its allocation units and that such offset may have affected the amount which is being distributed to its patrons,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a3a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> states generally the identity of the offsetting allocation units, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a3b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> states briefly what rights, if any, its patrons may have to additional financial information of such organization under terms of its charter, articles of incorporation, or bylaws, or under any provision of law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a3c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain information need not be provided</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An organization may exclude from the information required to be provided under clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) any detailed or specific data regarding earnings or losses of such units which such organization determines would disclose commercially sensitive information which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a3d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> could result in a competitive disadvantage to such organization, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a3e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> could create a competitive advantage to the benefit of a competitor of such organization.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a3f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to provide sufficient notice</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that an organization failed to provide sufficient notice under this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a40-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Secretary shall notify such organization, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44fa7a41-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such organization shall, upon receipt of such notification, provide to its patrons a revised notice meeting the requirements of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">Any such failure shall not affect the treatment of the organization under any provision of this subchapter or section 521.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a42-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/j/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Patronage earnings or losses defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the terms “patronage earnings” and “patronage losses” means <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002180">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002180"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “mean”.</note> earnings and losses, respectively, which are derived from business done with or for patrons of the organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44fa7a43-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s1388/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperative marketing includes value-added processing involving animals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of section 521 and this subchapter, the marketing of the products of members or other producers shall include the feeding of such products to cattle, hogs, fish, chickens, or other animals and the sale of the resulting animals or animal products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id44fa7a44-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s17/a">Pub. L. 87–834, § 17(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1049">76 Stat. 1049</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tII/s211/c">Pub. L. 89–809, title II, § 211(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1582">80 Stat. 1582</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tIX/s911/b">Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, § 911(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/722">83 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1901/a/153">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1901(a)(153)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1789">90 Stat. 1789</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tIII/s316/b/3">Pub. L. 95–600, title III, § 316(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2830">92 Stat. 2830</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXIII/s13210/a">Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13210(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/323">100 Stat. 323</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11813/b/24">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11813(b)(24)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-555">104 Stat. 1388–555</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tIII">Pub. L. 108–357, title III</ref>, §§ 312(a), 316(a), <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1467">118 Stat. 1467</ref>, 1469.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id44fa7a45-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id44fa7a46-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id44fa7a47-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s312/a">Pub. L. 108–357, § 312(a)</ref>, inserted at end of concluding provisions “For purposes of paragraph (3), net earnings shall not be reduced by amounts paid during the year as dividends on capital stock or other proprietary capital interests of the organization to the extent that the articles of incorporation or bylaws of such organization or other contract with patrons provide that such dividends are in addition to amounts otherwise payable to patrons which are derived from business done with or for patrons during the taxable year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s316/a">Pub. L. 108–357, § 316(a)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> struck out subsec. (k) which cross-referenced section 46(h) for provisions relating to apportionment of investment credit between cooperative organizations and their patrons.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (j), (k). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> added subsec. (j) and redesignated former subsec. (j) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (c)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901</ref> (a)(153)(A), substituted “<date date="1962-10-16">October 16, 1962</date>” for “the date of the enactment of the Revenue Act of 1962”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/153/B">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(153)(B)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1966-11-13">November 13, 1966</date>” for “the date of the enactment of this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> struck out reference to allocations made by organizations other than by payment of money or other property except per-unit retain certificates.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s211/c/1">Pub. L. 89–809, § 211(c)(1)</ref>, inserted references to per-unit retain certificates.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s211/c/2">Pub. L. 89–809, § 211(c)(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (f) to (i).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id44fa7a48-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa7a49-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tIII/s312/b">Pub. L. 108–357, title III, § 312(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1467">118 Stat. 1467</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/357/tIII/s312/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to distributions in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s316/a">section 316(a) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s316/c">section 316(c) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa7a4a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1990-12-31">Dec. 31, 1990</date>, but not applicable to any transition property (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s49/e">section 49(e) of this title</ref>), any property with respect to which qualified progress expenditures were previously taken into account under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46/d">section 46(d) of this title</ref>, and any property described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46/b/2/C">section 46(b)(2)(C) of this title</ref>, as such sections were in effect on <date date="1990-11-04">Nov. 4, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11813/c">section 11813(c) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s45K">section 45K of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa7a4b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXIII/s13210/c">Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13210(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/324">100 Stat. 324</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/272/tXIII/s13210/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1962-12-31">December 31, 1962</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of section 1388(j)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 [now 1986] (as added by subsection (a)) shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No inference</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>] shall be construed to infer that a change in law is intended as to whether any patronage earnings may or not be offset by nonpatronage losses, and any determination of such issue shall be made as if such amendments had not been enacted.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa7a4c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref> applicable to taxable years ending after <date date="1978-10-31">October 31, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s316/c">section 316(c) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46">section 46 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa7a4d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> applicable to per-unit retain allocations made after <date date="1969-10-09">Oct. 9, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s911/c">section 911(c) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1382">section 1382 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44fa7a4e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref> applicable to per-unit retain allocations made during taxable years of an organization described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1381/a">section 1381(a) of this title</ref> (relating to organizations to which part I of subchapter T of chapter 1 applies) beginning after <date date="1966-04-30">Apr. 30, 1966</date>, with respect to products delivered during such years, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s211/e/1">section 211(e)(1) of Pub. L. 89–809</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1382">section 1382 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id44fa7a4f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable, except as otherwise provided, to taxable years of organizations described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1381/a">section 1381(a) of this title</ref> beginning after <date date="1962-12-31">Dec. 31, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s17/c">section 17(c) of Pub. L. 87–834</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1381">section 1381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id44fa7a50-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11821/b">section 11821(b) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s45K">section 45K of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id44fa7a51-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Per-Unit Retain Certificates Covered by Written Agreements Between <date date="1965-10-14">Oct. 14, 1965</date>, and <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>: Transition Treatment of By-Law Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tII/s211/f">Pub. L. 89–809, title II, § 211(f)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1584">80 Stat. 1584</ref>, provided that a written agreement between a patron and a cooperative association which met certain qualifications and was entered into after <date date="1965-10-14">Oct. 14, 1965</date> and before <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, and which was in effect on <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, was to be treated for purposes of subsec. (h) of this section as if entered into after <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
