<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id45447bfc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523"><num value="2523">§ 2523.</num><heading> Gift to spouse</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447bfd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Allowance of deduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where a donor transfers during the calendar year by gift an interest in property to a donee who at the time of the gift is the donor’s spouse, there shall be allowed as a deduction in computing taxable gifts for the calendar year an amount with respect to such interest equal to its value.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447bfe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Life estate or other terminable interest</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where, on the lapse of time, on the occurrence of an event or contingency, or on the failure of an event or contingency to occur, such interest transferred to the spouse will terminate or fail, no deduction shall be allowed with respect to such interest—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id45447bff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if the donor retains in himself, or transfers or has transferred (for less than an adequate and full consideration in money or money’s worth) to any person other than such donee spouse (or the estate of such spouse), an interest in such property, and if by reason of such retention or transfer the donor (or his heirs or assigns) or such person (or his heirs or assigns) may possess or enjoy any part of such property after such termination or failure of the interest transferred to the donee spouse; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id45447c00-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the donor immediately after the transfer to the donee spouse has a power to appoint an interest in such property which he can exercise (either alone or in conjunction with any person) in such manner that the appointee may possess or enjoy any part of such property after such termination or failure of the interest transferred to the donee spouse. For purposes of this paragraph, the donor shall be considered as having immediately after the transfer to the donee spouse such power to appoint even though such power cannot be exercised until after the lapse of time, upon the occurrence of an event or contingency, or on the failure of an event or contingency to occur.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">An exercise or release at any time by the donor, either alone or in conjunction with any person, of a power to appoint an interest in property, even though not otherwise a transfer, shall, for purposes of paragraph (1), be considered as a transfer by him. Except as provided in subsection (e), where at the time of the transfer it is impossible to ascertain the particular person or persons who may receive from the donor an interest in property so transferred by him, such interest shall, for purposes of paragraph (1), be considered as transferred to a person other than the donee spouse.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c01-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest in unidentified assets</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where the assets out of which, or the proceeds of which, the interest transferred to the donee spouse may be satisfied include a particular asset or assets with respect to which no deduction would be allowed if such asset or assets were transferred from the donor to such spouse, then the value of the interest transferred to such spouse shall, for purposes of subsection (a), be reduced by the aggregate value of such particular assets.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c02-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Joint interests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the interest is transferred to the donee spouse as sole joint tenant with the donor or as tenant by the entirety, the interest of the donor in the property which exists solely by reason of the possibility that the donor may survive the donee spouse, or that there may occur a severance of the tenancy, shall not be considered for purposes of subsection (b) as an interest retained by the donor in himself.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c03-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Life estate with power of appointment in donee spouse</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where the donor transfers an interest in property, if by such transfer his spouse is entitled for life to all of the income from the entire interest, or all the income from a specific portion thereof, payable annually or at more frequent intervals, with power in the donee spouse to appoint the entire interest, or such specific portion (exercisable in favor of such donee spouse, or of the estate of such donee spouse, or in favor of either, whether or not in each case the power is exercisable in favor of others), and with no power in any other person to appoint any part of such interest, or such portion, to any person other than the donee spouse—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id45447c04-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the interest, or such portion, so transferred shall, for purposes of subsection (a) be considered as transferred to the donee spouse, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id45447c05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> no part of the interest, or such portion, so transferred shall, for purposes of subsection (b)(1), be considered as retained in the donor or transferred to any person other than the donee spouse.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection shall apply only if, by such transfer, such power in the donee spouse to appoint the interest, or such portion, whether exercisable by will or during life, is exercisable by such spouse alone and in all events. For purposes of this subsection, the term “specific portion” only includes a portion determined on a fractional or percentage basis.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Election with respect to life estate for donee spouse</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of qualified terminable interest property—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for purposes of subsection (a), such property shall be treated as transferred to the donee spouse, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for purposes of subsection (b)(1), no part of such property shall be considered as retained in the donor or transferred to any person other than the donee spouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified terminable interest property</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified terminable interest property” means any property—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which is transferred by the donor spouse,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in which the donee spouse has a qualifying income interest for life, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c0d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to which an election under this subsection applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c0e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain rules made applicable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, rules similar to the rules of clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv) of section 2056(b)(7)(B) shall apply and the rules of section 2056(b)(10) shall apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c0f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Election</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c10-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Time and manner</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An election under this subsection with respect to any property shall be made on or before the date prescribed by section 6075(b) for filing a gift tax return with respect to the transfer (determined without regard to section 6019(2)) and shall be made in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c11-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Election irrevocable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An election under this subsection, once made, shall be irrevocable.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c12-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of interest retained by donor spouse</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c13-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of any qualified terminable interest property—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id45447c14-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such property shall not be includible in the gross estate of the donor spouse, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id45447c15-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any subsequent transfer by the donor spouse of an interest in such property shall not be treated as a transfer for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c16-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Subparagraph (A) not to apply after transfer by donee spouse</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to any property after the donee spouse is treated as having transferred such property under section 2519, or such property is includible in the donee spouse’s gross estate under section 2044.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c17-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of joint and survivor annuities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a joint and survivor annuity where only the donor spouse and donee spouse have the right to receive payments before the death of the last spouse to die—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c18-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the donee spouse’s interest shall be treated as a qualifying income interest for life,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c19-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the donor spouse shall be treated as having made an election under this subsection with respect to such annuity unless the donor spouse otherwise elects on or before the date specified in paragraph (4)(A),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c1a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> paragraph (5) and section 2519 shall not apply to the donor spouse’s interest in the annuity, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45447c1b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/f/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> if the donee spouse dies before the donor spouse, no amount shall be includible in the gross estate of the donee spouse under section 2044 with respect to such annuity.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">An election under subparagraph (B), once made, shall be irrevocable.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c1c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for charitable remainder trusts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c1d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, after the transfer, the donee spouse is the only beneficiary who is not a charitable beneficiary (other than the donor) of a qualified charitable remainder trust, subsection (b) shall not apply to the interest in such trust which is transferred to the donee spouse.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c1e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “charitable beneficiary” and “qualified charitable remainder trust” have the meanings given to such terms by section 2056(b)(8)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c1f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Denial of double deduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section or any other provision of this chapter shall allow the value of any interest in property to be deducted under this chapter more than once with respect to the same donor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45447c20-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Disallowance of marital deduction where spouse not citizen</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the spouse of the donor is not a citizen of the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id45447c21-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> no deduction shall be allowed under this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id45447c22-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> section 2503(b) shall be applied with respect to gifts which are made by the donor to such spouse and with respect to which a deduction would be allowable under this section but for paragraph (1) by substituting “$100,000” for “$10,000”, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id45447c23-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s2523/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the principles of sections 2515 and 2515A (as such sections were in effect before their repeal by the Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981) shall apply, except that the provisions of such section 2515 providing for an election shall not apply.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection shall not apply to any transfer resulting from the acquisition of rights under a joint and survivor annuity described in subsection (f)(6).</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id45447c24-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/412">68A Stat. 412</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/614/tI/s102/c/3">Pub. L. 91–614, title I, § 102(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1841">84 Stat. 1841</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1902/a/12/E">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1902(a)(12)(E)</ref>, title XX, § 2002(b), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1806">90 Stat. 1806</ref>, 1854; <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tIV/s403/b/1">Pub. L. 97–34, title IV, § 403(b)(1)</ref>, (2), (d)(2), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/301">95 Stat. 301</ref>, 303; <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/tI/s104/a/2/B">Pub. L. 97–448, title I, § 104(a)(2)(B)</ref>, (4)–(6), <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2380">96 Stat. 2380</ref>, 2381; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1879/n/1">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1879(n)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2910">100 Stat. 2910</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tV/s5033/b">Pub. L. 100–647, title V, § 5033(b)</ref>, title VI, § 6152(b), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3672">102 Stat. 3672</ref>, 3725; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7815/d/1/A">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7815(d)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2415">103 Stat. 2415</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11702/g/1">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11702(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-515">104 Stat. 1388–515</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXIX/s1941/b">Pub. L. 102–486, title XIX, § 1941(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3036">106 Stat. 3036</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXVI/s1604/g/4">Pub. L. 105–34, title XVI, § 1604(g)(4)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1099">111 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/a/205">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(205)</ref>, (206), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1194">132 Stat. 1194</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id45447c25-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id45447c26-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Inflation Adjusted Items for Certain Years</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For inflation adjustment of certain items in this section, see Revenue Procedures listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id45447c27-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id45447c28-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 2515 and 2515A, referred to in subsec. (i)(3), were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tIV/s403/c/3/B">Pub. L. 97–34, title IV, § 403(c)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/302">95 Stat. 302</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id45447c29-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/205">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(205)</ref>, substituted “beneficiary who is not a charitable beneficiary” for “noncharitable beneficiary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/206">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(206)</ref>, substituted “term ‘charitable beneficiary’ ” for “term ‘noncharitable beneficiary’ ”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> substituted “qualified charitable remainder trust” for “qualified remainder trust”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s1941/b/1">Pub. L. 102–486, § 1941(b)(1)</ref>, in closing provisions, inserted at end “For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘specific portion’ only includes a portion determined on a fractional or percentage basis.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s1941/b/2">Pub. L. 102–486, § 1941(b)(2)</ref>, inserted before period at end “and the rules of section 2056(b)(10) shall apply”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> inserted at end “This subsection shall not apply to any transfer resulting from the acquisition of rights under a joint and survivor annuity described in subsection (f)(6).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7815/d/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7815(d)(2)</ref>, struck out “who is a citizen or resident” after “Where a donor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7815/d/1/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7815(d)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “which are made by the donor to such spouse and with respect to which a deduction would be allowable under this section but for paragraph (1)” for “made by the donor to such spouse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (f)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s6152/b">Pub. L. 100–647, § 6152(b)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s5033/b">Pub. L. 100–647, § 5033(b)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (f)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “An election under this subsection with respect to any property shall be made on or before the first April 15th after the calendar year in which the interest was transferred and shall be made in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s104/a/6">Pub. L. 97–448, § 104(a)(6)</ref>, substituted “rules similar to the rules of clauses (ii)” for “the rules of clauses (ii)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s104/a/4">Pub. L. 97–448, § 104(a)(4)</ref>, divided existing provisions into subpars. (A) and (B), in subpar. (A) as so designated substituted “shall be made on or before the first April 15th after the calendar year in which the interest was transferred and shall be made in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe” for “shall be made on the return of the tax imposed by section 2501 for the calendar year in which the interest was transferred”, and in subpar. (B) as so designated substituted “An election under this subsection” for “Such an election”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s104/a/5">Pub. L. 97–448, § 104(a)(5)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s104/a/2/B">Pub. L. 97–448, § 104(a)(2)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s403/b/1">Pub. L. 97–34, § 403(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “(1) In general” designation for existing text and struck out par. (2) which declared that the aggregate of the allowed deductions for any calendar quarter should not exceed the sum of $100,000 reduced, but not below zero, by the aggregate of the allowed deductions for preceding calendar quarters beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, plus 50 percent of the lesser of the amount of the allowed deductions for such calendar quarter, determined without regard to par. (2), or the amount, if any, by which the aggregate determined under cl. (i) of par. (2) for the calendar quarter and for each preceding calendar quarter beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, exceeds $200,000.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s403/b/2">Pub. L. 97–34, § 403(b)(2)</ref>, (d)(2), substituted provision relating to election with respect to life estate for donee spouse for provision relating to community property.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s403/d/2">Pub. L. 97–34, § 403(d)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), struck out “one-half of” after “interest equal to”, and added par. (2) relating to limitations on aggregate amount of deductions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1902/a/12/E">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1902(a)(12)(E)</ref>, struck out “Territory” after “any State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/614">Pub. L. 91–614</ref> substituted “quarter” for “year” in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4546c51a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c51b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> applicable to gifts made after <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/s1941/c/2">section 1941(c)(2) of Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2056">section 2056 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c51c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Technical and Miscellaneous Revenue Act of 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11702/j">section 11702(j) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s59">section 59 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c51d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7815/d/1/B">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7815(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2415">103 Stat. 2415</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7815/d/1/B">“The amendment made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to gifts made after <date date="1989-06-29">June 29, 1989</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7815/d/2">section 7815(d)(2) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Technical and Miscellaneous Revenue Act of 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7817">section 7817 of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c51e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tV/s5033/d/2">Pub. L. 100–647, title V, § 5033(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3673">102 Stat. 3673</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/647/tV/s5033/d/2">“The amendments made by subsection (b) [amending this section] shall apply to gifts on or after <date date="1988-07-14">July 14, 1988</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s6152/b">section 6152(b) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> applicable to transfers after <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, and, in the case of any estate or gift tax return filed before <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, such amendment inapplicable to the extent it would be inconsistent with the treatment of the annuity on such return unless executor or donor otherwise elects before the day 2 years after <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, the time for making such an election not to expire before such date, see section 6152(c), of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2056">section 2056 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c51f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1879/n/2">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1879(n)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2910">100 Stat. 2910</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1879/n/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to transfers made after <date date="1985-12-31">December 31, 1985</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c520-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/448">Pub. L. 97–448</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if it had been included in the provision of the Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981, <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s109">section 109 of Pub. L. 97–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c521-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to gifts made after <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s403/e/2">section 403(e)(2) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2056">section 2056 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c522-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXX/s2002/d/2">Pub. L. 94–455, title XX, § 2002(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1856">90 Stat. 1856</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/455/tXX/s2002/d/2">“The amendment made by subsection (b) [amending this section] shall apply to gifts made after <date date="1976-12-31">December 31, 1976</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4546c523-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/614">Pub. L. 91–614</ref> applicable with respect to gifts made after <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/614/s102/e">section 102(e) of Pub. L. 91–614</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2501">section 2501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4546c524-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s5033">Section 5033 of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> to Estates of, or Gifts by, Noncitizen and Nonresident Individuals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that in the case of the estate of, or gift by, an individual who was not a citizen or resident of the United States but was a resident of a foreign country with which the United States has a tax treaty with respect to estate, inheritance, or gift taxes, the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s5033">section 5033 of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> shall not apply to the extent such amendments would be inconsistent with the provisions of such treaty relating to estate, inheritance, or gift tax marital deductions, but that in the case of the estate of an individual dying before the date 3 years after <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, or a gift by an individual before the date 3 years after <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, the requirement of the preceding provision that the individual not be a citizen or resident of the United States shall not apply, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7815/d/14">section 7815(d)(14) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2056">section 2056 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4546c525-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1800–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4546c526-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Rule for Certain Transfers in October 1984</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1879/n/3">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1879(n)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2910">100 Stat. 2910</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1879/n/3">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“An election under section 2523(f) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 [now 1986] with respect to an interest in property which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> was transferred during October 1984, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> was transferred pursuant to a trust instrument stating that the grantor’s intention was that the property of the trust would constitute qualified terminable interest property as to which a Federal gift tax marital deduction would be allowed upon the grantor’s election,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be made on the return of tax imposed by section 2501 of such Code for the calendar year 1984 which is filed on or before the due date of such return or, if a timely return is not filed, on the first such return filed after the due date of such return and before <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
