<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id42afed97-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312"><num value="312">§ 312.</num><heading> Effect on earnings and profits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afed98-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, on the distribution of property by a corporation with respect to its stock, the earnings and profits of the corporation (to the extent thereof) shall be decreased by the sum of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afed99-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the amount of money,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afed9a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the principal amount of the obligations of such corporation (or, in the case of obligations having original issue discount, the aggregate issue price of such obligations), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afed9b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the adjusted basis of the other property, so distributed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afed9c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Distributions of appreciated property</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On the distribution by a corporation, with respect to its stock, of any property (other than an obligation of such corporation) the fair market value of which exceeds the adjusted basis thereof—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afed9d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the earnings and profits of the corporation shall be increased by the amount of such excess, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afed9e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> subsection (a)(3) shall be applied by substituting “fair market value” for “adjusted basis”.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this subsection and subsection (a), the adjusted basis of any property is its adjusted basis as determined for purposes of computing earnings and profits.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afed9f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments for liabilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In making the adjustments to the earnings and profits of a corporation under subsection (a) or (b), proper adjustment shall be made for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afeda0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the amount of any liability to which the property distributed is subject, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afeda1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the amount of any liability of the corporation assumed by a shareholder in connection with the distribution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeda2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain distributions of stock and securities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeda3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The distribution to a distributee by or on behalf of a corporation of its stock or securities, of stock or securities in another corporation, or of property, in a distribution to which this title applies, shall not be considered a distribution of the earnings and profits of any corporation—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afeda4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if no gain to such distributee from the receipt of such stock or securities, or property, was recognized under this title, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afeda5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the distribution was not subject to tax in the hands of such distributee by reason of section 305(a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeda6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Stock or securities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “stock or securities” includes rights to acquire stock or securities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeda7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/e"><num value="e" class="bold">[(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s61/a/2/B">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 61(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/581">98 Stat. 581</ref>]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeda8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on earnings and profits of gain or loss and of receipt of tax-free distributions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeda9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on earnings and profits of gain or loss</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The gain or loss realized from the sale or other disposition (after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>) of property by a corporation—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afedaa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for the purpose of the computation of the earnings and profits of the corporation, shall (except as provided in subparagraph (B)) be determined by using as the adjusted basis the adjusted basis (under the law applicable to the year in which the sale or other disposition was made) for determining gain, except that no regard shall be had to the value of the property as of <date date="1913-03-01">March 1, 1913</date>; but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afedab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for purposes of the computation of the earnings and profits of the corporation for any period beginning after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>, shall be determined by using as the adjusted basis the adjusted basis (under the law applicable to the year in which the sale or other disposition was made) for determining gain.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Gain or loss so realized shall increase or decrease the earnings and profits to, but not beyond, the extent to which such a realized gain or loss was recognized in computing taxable income under the law applicable to the year in which such sale or disposition was made. Where, in determining the adjusted basis used in computing such realized gain or loss, the adjustment to the basis differs from the adjustment proper for the purpose of determining earnings and profits, then the latter adjustment shall be used in determining the increase or decrease above provided. For purposes of this subsection, a loss with respect to which a deduction is disallowed under section 1091 (relating to wash sales of stock or securities), or the corresponding provision of prior law, shall not be deemed to be recognized.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedac-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on earnings and profits of receipt of tax-free distributions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Where a corporation receives (after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>) a distribution from a second corporation which (under the law applicable to the year in which the distribution was made) was not a taxable dividend to the shareholders of the second corporation, the amount of such distribution shall not increase the earnings and profits of the first corporation in the following cases:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afedad-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> no such increase shall be made in respect of the part of such distribution which (under such law) is directly applied in reduction of the basis of the stock in respect of which the distribution was made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afedae-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> no such increase shall be made if (under such law) the distribution causes the basis of the stock in respect of which the distribution was made to be allocated between such stock and the property received (or such basis would, but for section 307(b), be so allocated).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedaf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Earnings and profits—increase in value accrued before <date date="1913-03-01">March 1, 1913</date></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afedb0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If any increase or decrease in the earnings and profits for any period beginning after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>, with respect to any matter would be different had the adjusted basis of the property involved been determined without regard to its <date date="1913-03-01">March 1, 1913</date>, value, then, except as provided in paragraph (2), an increase (properly reflecting such difference) shall be made in that part of the earnings and profits consisting of increase in value of property accrued before <date date="1913-03-01">March 1, 1913</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afedb1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the application of subsection (f) to a sale or other disposition after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>, results in a loss which is to be applied in decrease of earnings and profits for any period beginning after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>, then, notwithstanding subsection (f) and in lieu of the rule provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the amount of such loss so to be applied shall be reduced by the amount, if any, by which the adjusted basis of the property used in determining the loss exceeds the adjusted basis computed without regard to the value of the property on <date date="1913-03-01">March 1, 1913</date>, and if such amount so applied in reduction of the decrease exceeds such loss, the excess over such loss shall increase that part of the earnings and profits consisting of increase in value of property accrued before <date date="1913-03-01">March 1, 1913</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedb2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation in certain corporate separations and reorganizations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedb3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Section 355</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a distribution or exchange to which section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) applies, proper allocation with respect to the earnings and profits of the distributing corporation and the controlled corporation (or corporations) shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedb4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Section 368(a)(1)(C) or (D)</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a reorganization described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of section 368(a)(1), proper allocation with respect to the earnings and profits of the acquired corporation shall, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be made between the acquiring corporation and the acquired corporation (or any corporation which had control of the acquired corporation before the reorganization).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedb5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution of proceeds of loan insured by the United States</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a corporation distributes property with respect to its stock and if, at the time of distribution—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afedb6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> there is outstanding a loan to such corporation which was made, guaranteed, or insured by the United States (or by any agency or instrumentality thereof), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42afedb7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the amount of such loan so outstanding exceeds the adjusted basis of the property constituting security for such loan,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the earnings and profits of the corporation shall be increased by the amount of such excess, and (immediately after the distribution) shall be decreased by the amount of such excess. For purposes of paragraph (2), the adjusted basis of the property at the time of distribution shall be determined without regard to any adjustment under section 1016(a)(2) (relating to adjustment for depreciation, etc.). For purposes of this subsection, a commitment to make, guarantee, or insure a loan shall be treated as the making, guaranteeing, or insuring of a loan.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedb8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/j"><num value="j" class="bold">[(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tIV/s413/c/4">Pub. L. 108–357, title IV, § 413(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1507">118 Stat. 1507</ref>]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedb9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of depreciation on earnings and profits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedba-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of computing the earnings and profits of a corporation for any taxable year beginning after <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, the allowance for depreciation (and amortization, if any) shall be deemed to be the amount which would be allowable for such year if the straight line method of depreciation had been used for each taxable year beginning after <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedbb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If for any taxable year a method of depreciation was used by the taxpayer which the Secretary has determined results in a reasonable allowance under section 167(a) and which is the unit-of-production method or other method not expressed in a term of years, then the adjustment to earnings and profits for depreciation for such year shall be determined under the method so used (in lieu of the straight line method).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedbc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for tangible property</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedbd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in the case of tangible property to which section 168 applies, the adjustment to earnings and profits for depreciation for any taxable year shall be determined under the alternative depreciation system (within the meaning of section 168(g)(2)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedbe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of amounts deductible under section 179, 179B, 179C, 179D, or 179E</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedbf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/3/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of computing the earnings and profits of a corporation, except as provided in clause (ii), any amount deductible under section 179, 179B, 179C, 179D, or 179E shall be allowed as a deduction ratably over the period of 5 taxable years (beginning with the taxable year for which such amount is deductible under section 179, 179B, 179C, 179D, or 179E, as the case may be).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/3/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of a corporation that is a real estate investment trust, any amount deductible under section 179D shall be allowed in the year in which the property giving rise to such deduction is placed in service (or, in the case of energy efficient building retrofit property, the year in which the qualifying final certification is made).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain foreign corporations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of paragraph (1) shall not apply in computing the earnings and profits of a foreign corporation for any taxable year for which less than 20 percent of the gross income from all sources of such corporation is derived from sources within the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/k/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis adjustment not taken into account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In computing the earnings and profits of a corporation for any taxable year, the allowance for depreciation (and amortization, if any) shall be computed without regard to any basis adjustment under section 50(c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Discharge of indebtedness income</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/l/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Does not increase earnings and profits if applied to reduce basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The earnings and profits of a corporation shall not include income from the discharge of indebtedness to the extent of the amount applied to reduce basis under section 1017.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/l/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction of deficit in earnings and profits in certain cases</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afedc6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the interest of any shareholder of a corporation is terminated or extinguished in a title 11 or similar case (within the meaning of section 368(a)(3)(A)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afedc7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> there is a deficit in the earnings and profits of the corporation,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">then such deficit shall be reduced by an amount equal to the paid-in capital which is allocable to the interest of the shareholder which is so terminated or extinguished.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> No adjustment for interest paid on certain registration-required obligations not in registered form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The earnings and profits of any corporation shall not be decreased by any interest with respect to which a deduction is not or would not be allowable by reason of section 163(f), unless at the time of issuance the issuer is a foreign corporation that is not a controlled foreign corporation (within the meaning of section 957) and the issuance did not have as a purpose the avoidance of section 163(f) of this subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002099">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002099"><num>1</num> Subsec. (m) was enacted without a period at the end.</note></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedc9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments to earnings and profits to more accurately reflect economic gain and loss</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of computing the earnings and profits of a corporation, the following adjustments shall be made:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction period carrying charges</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedcb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of any amount paid or incurred for construction period carrying charges—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedcc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> no deduction shall be allowed with respect to such amount, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedcd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the basis of the property with respect to which such charges are allocable shall be increased by such amount.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedce-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction period carrying charges defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “construction period carrying charges” means all—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedcf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> interest paid or accrued on indebtedness incurred or continued to acquire, construct, or carry property,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedd0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> property taxes, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedd1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> similar carrying charges,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">to the extent such interest, taxes, or charges are attributable to the construction period for such property and would be allowable as a deduction in determining taxable income under this chapter for the taxable year in which paid or incurred.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedd2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “construction period” has the meaning given the term production period under section 263A(f)(4)(B).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002100">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002100"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedd3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Intangible drilling costs and mineral exploration and development costs</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedd4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Intangible drilling costs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount allowable as a deduction under section 263(c) in determining taxable income (other than costs incurred in connection with a nonproductive well)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedd5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall be capitalized, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedd6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall be allowed as a deduction ratably over the 60-month period beginning with the month in which such amount was paid or incurred.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedd7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Mineral exploration and development costs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount allowable as a deduction under section 616(a) or 617 in determining taxable income—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedd8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall be capitalized, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afedd9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> shall be allowed as a deduction ratably over the 120-month period beginning with the later of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id42afedda-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the month in which production from the deposit begins, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id42afeddb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the month in which such amount was paid or incurred.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeddc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain amortization provisions not to apply</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Sections 173 and 248 shall not apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeddd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> LIFO inventory adjustments</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedde-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Earnings and profits shall be increased or decreased by the amount of any increase or decrease in the LIFO recapture amount as of the close of each taxable year; except that any decrease below the LIFO recapture amount as of the close of the taxable year preceding the 1st taxable year to which this paragraph applies to the taxpayer shall be taken into account only to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afeddf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> LIFO recapture amount</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “LIFO recapture amount” means the amount (if any) by which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afede0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the inventory amount of the inventory assets under the first-in, first-out method authorized by section 471, exceeds</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42afede1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the inventory amount of such assets under the LIFO method.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42afede2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id42afede3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> LIFO method</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “LIFO method” means the method authorized by section 472 (relating to last-in, first-out inventories).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id42afede4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Inventory assets</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “inventory assets” means stock in trade of the corporation, or other property of a kind which would properly be included in the inventory of the corporation if on hand at the close of the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id42afede5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Inventory amount</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The inventory amount of assets under the first-in, first-out method authorized by section 471 shall be determined—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id42afede6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> if the corporation uses the retail method of valuing inventories under section 472, by using such method, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id42afede7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/4/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if subclause (I) does not apply, by using cost or market, whichever is lower.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afede8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Installment sales</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any installment sale, earnings and profits shall be computed as if the corporation did not use the installment method.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afede9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Completed contract method of accounting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a taxpayer who uses the completed contract method of accounting, earnings and profits shall be computed as if such taxpayer used the percentage of completion method of accounting.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Redemptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a corporation distributes amounts in a redemption to which section 302(a) or 303 applies, the part of such distribution which is properly chargeable to earnings and profits shall be an amount which is not in excess of the ratable share of the earnings and profits of such corporation accumulated after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>, attributable to the stock so redeemed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedeb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain foreign corporations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a foreign corporation described in subsection (k)(4)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afedec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> paragraphs (4) and (6) shall apply only in the case of taxable years beginning after <date date="1985-12-31">December 31, 1985</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42afeded-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/n/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> paragraph (5) shall apply only in the case of taxable years beginning after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42afedee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s312/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of original issue discount and issue price for purposes of subsection (a)(2)</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)(2), the terms “original issue discount” and “issue price” have the same respective meanings as when used in subpart A of part V of subchapter P of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id42afedef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/95">68A Stat. 95</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/403/s3/a">Pub. L. 87–403, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-02-02">Feb. 2, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/6">76 Stat. 6</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref>, §§ 13(f)(3), 14(b)(1), <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1035">76 Stat. 1035</ref>, 1040; <ref href="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s231/b/3">Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 231(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/105">78 Stat. 105</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/484/s1/b/1">Pub. L. 88–484, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-22">Aug. 22, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/597">78 Stat. 597</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/570/s1/b/3">Pub. L. 89–570, § 1(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-12">Sept. 12, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/762">80 Stat. 762</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tII/s211/b/3">Pub. L. 91–172, title II, § 211(b)(3)</ref>, title IV, § 442(a), title IX, § 905(b)(2), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/570">83 Stat. 570</ref>, 628, 714; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tII/s205/c/1/D">Pub. L. 94–455, title II, § 205(c)(1)(D)</ref>, title XIX, §§ 1901(a)(43), (b)(32)(B)(i), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1535">90 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1771, 1800, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/95/628/s3/c">Pub. L. 95–628, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3627">92 Stat. 3627</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/589/s5/f">Pub. L. 96–589, § 5(f)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3406">94 Stat. 3406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tII/s206/a">Pub. L. 97–34, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/224">95 Stat. 224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tII">Pub. L. 97–248, title II</ref>, §§ 205(a)(3), 222(e)(3), title III, § 310(b)(3), <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/429">96 Stat. 429</ref>, 480, 597; <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/tIII/s306/a/6/B">Pub. L. 97–448, title III, § 306(a)(6)(B)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2402">96 Stat. 2402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 61(a)–(c)(1), 63(b), 111(e)(5), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/579-581">98 Stat. 579–581</ref>, 583, 633; <ref href="/us/pl/99/121/tI/s103/b/1/C">Pub. L. 99–121, title I, § 103(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="1985-10-11">Oct. 11, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/509">99 Stat. 509</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tII">Pub. L. 99–514, title II</ref>, §§ 201(b), (d)(6), 241(b)(1), title VI, § 631(e)(1), title VIII, § 803(b)(3), title XVIII, §§ 1804(f)(1)(A)–(E), 1809(a)(2)(C)(ii), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2137">100 Stat. 2137</ref>, 2141, 2181, 2273, 2355, 2804, 2805, 2819; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI">Pub. L. 100–647, title I</ref>, §§ 1002(a)(3), 1018(d)(4), (u)(4), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3353">102 Stat. 3353</ref>, 3578, 3590; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII</ref>, §§ 7611(f)(5)(A), 7811(m)(2), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2373">103 Stat. 2373</ref>, 2412; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, §§ 11812(b)(5), 11813(b)(14), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-535">104 Stat. 1388–535</ref>, 1388–555; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXVI/s1604/a/2">Pub. L. 105–34, title XVI, § 1604(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1097">111 Stat. 1097</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tIII/s338/b/3">Pub. L. 108–357, title III, § 338(b)(3)</ref>, title IV, § 413(c)(4), (5), <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1481">118 Stat. 1481</ref>, 1507; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXIII">Pub. L. 109–58, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1323(b)(3), 1331(b)(5), <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/1015">119 Stat. 1015</ref>, 1024; <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dA/tIV/s404/b/2">Pub. L. 109–432, div. A, title IV, § 404(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2956">120 Stat. 2956</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tII/s221/a/34/F">Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(34)(F)</ref>, (49), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/4042">128 Stat. 4042</ref>, 4045; <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/tI/s13303/b">Pub. L. 117–169, title I, § 13303(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-16">Aug. 16, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1951">136 Stat. 1951</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id42afedf0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id42afedf1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id42afedf2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 263A(f)(4)(B), referred to in subsec. (n)(1)(C), was redesignated section 263A(f)(5)(B) by <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13801/a/1">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2169">131 Stat. 2169</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id42afedf3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (k)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169">Pub. L. 117–169</ref> designated existing provisions as cl. (i), inserted heading, substituted “For purposes of computing the earnings and profits of a corporation, except as provided in clause (ii)” for “For purposes of computing the earnings and profits of a corporation”, and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (d)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/49">Pub. L. 113–295, § 221(a)(49)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “In the case of a distribution of stock or securities, or property, to which section 115(h) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 (or the corresponding provision of prior law) applied, the effect on earnings and profits of such distribution shall be determined under such section 115(h), or the corresponding provision of prior law, as the case may be.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/34/F">Pub. L. 113–295, § 221(a)(34)(F)</ref>, struck out “179A,” after “section 179,” in heading and in two places in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (k)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432">Pub. L. 109–432</ref> substituted “179D, or 179E” for “or 179D” in heading and two places in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (k)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1331/b/5">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1331(b)(5)</ref>, substituted “179, 179A, 179B, 179C, or 179D” for “179, 179A, 179B, or 179C” in heading and two places in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1323/b/3">Pub. L. 109–58, § 1323(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “179, 179A, 179B, or 179C” for “179 179A, or 179B” in heading and two places in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s413/c/4">Pub. L. 108–357, § 413(c)(4)</ref>, struck out subsec. (j) which related to earnings and profits of foreign investment companies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s338/b/3">Pub. L. 108–357, § 338(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “179A, or 179B” for “or 179A” in heading and two places in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s413/c/5">Pub. L. 108–357, § 413(c)(5)</ref>, struck out “, a foreign investment company (within the meaning of section 1246(b)), or a foreign personal holding company (within the meaning of section 552)” before “and the issuance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (k)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, in heading substituted “179 or 179A” for “179” and in text substituted “section 179 or 179A shall” for “section 179 shall” and “section 179 or 179A, as the case may be)” for “section 179)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (k)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11812/b/5">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11812(b)(5)</ref>, substituted heading for one which read: “Exceptions” and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “If for any taxable year beginning after <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, a method of depreciation was used by the taxpayer which the Secretary has determined results in a reasonable allowance under section 167(a), and which is not—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) a declining balance method,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the sum of the years-digit method, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) any other method allowable solely by reason of the application of subsection (b)(4) or (j)(1)(C) of section 167,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the adjustment to earnings and profits for depreciation for such year shall be determined under the method so used (in lieu of under the straight line method).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11813/b/14">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11813(b)(14)</ref>, substituted “section 50(c)” for “section 48(q)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7811/m/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7811(m)(2)</ref>, made clarifying amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/d/4">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(d)(4)</ref>, see 1988 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(2)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7611/f/5/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7611(f)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “in which such amount was paid or incurred” for “in which the production from the well begins”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/d/4">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(d)(4)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7811/m/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7811(m)(2)</ref>, substituted “of any property (other than an obligation of such corporation)” for “of any property” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1002/a/3">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1002(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)” for “paragraphs (1) and (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/u/4">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(u)(4)</ref>, made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s803/b/3/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 803(b)(3)(A)</ref>. See 1986 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1804/f/1/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1804(f)(1)(A)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally, substituting provisions relating to distributions of appreciated property for provisions relating to distribution of certain inventory assets.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1804/f/1/B">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1804(f)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), struck out “, etc.” after “liabilities” in heading and struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “any gain recognized to the corporation on the distribution.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s201/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 201(b)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally, substituting provisions relating to tangible property to which section 168 applies and amounts deductible under section 179 for provisions relating to recovery property within the meaning of section 168, amounts deductible under section 179, and flexibility if a different recovery percentage is elected under section 168 based on a longer recovery period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1809/a/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1809(a)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, in subpar. (A), struck out “and rules similar to the rules under the next to the last sentence of section 168(b)(2)(A) and section 168(b)(2)(B) shall apply” after “low-income housing)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s201/d/6">Pub. L. 99–514, § 201(d)(6)</ref>, struck out last sentence “In determining the earnings and profits of such corporation in the case of recovery property (within the meaning of section 168), the rules of section 168(f)(2) shall apply.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s803/b/3/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 803(b)(3)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/u/4">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(u)(4)</ref>, struck out “(determined without regard to section 189)” after “incurred”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s803/b/3/B">Pub. L. 99–514, § 803(b)(3)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (C) and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “The term ‘construction period’ has the meaning given such term by section 189(e)(2) (determined without regard to any real property limitation).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s241/b/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 241(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “, 177,” after “sections 173”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s631/e/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 631(e)(1)</ref>, amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (4) read as follows: “Earnings and profits shall be increased or decreased by the amount of any increase or decrease in the LIFO recapture amount (determined under section 336(b)(3)) as of the close of each taxable year; except that any decrease below the LIFO recapture amount as of the close of the taxable year preceding the first taxable year to which this paragraph applies to the taxpayer shall be taken into account only to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1804/f/1/D">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1804(f)(1)(D)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (4). Former par. (4), relating to certain untaxed appreciation of distributed property, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(5) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1804/f/1/D">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1804(f)(1)(D)</ref>, redesignated pars. (6) to (8) as (5) to (7), respectively. Former par. (5) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1804/f/1/D">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1804(f)(1)(D)</ref>, (E), redesignated par. (9) as (8) and substituted provisions of subpars. (A) and (B) for “paragraphs (5), (6), and (7) shall apply only in the case of taxable years beginning after <date date="1985-12-31">December 31, 1985</date>.” Former par. (8) redesignated (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (k)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/121">Pub. L. 99–121</ref> substituted “19-year real property” for “18-year real property” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s61/c/1/A">Pub. L. 98–369, § 61(c)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “(or, in the case of obligations having original issue discount, the aggregate issue price of such obligations)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s61/a/2/B">Pub. L. 98–369, § 61(a)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which provided: “In the case of amounts distributed in a redemption to which section 302(a) or 303 applies, the part of such distribution which is properly chargeable to capital account shall not be treated as a distribution of earnings and profits.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s63/b">Pub. L. 98–369, § 63(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (h) generally, designating existing provisions as par. (1) and adding par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s61/a/2/A">Pub. L. 98–369, § 61(a)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which provided: “If a foreign investment company (as defined in section 1246) distributes amounts in a redemption to which section 302(a) or 303 applies, the part of such distribution which is properly chargeable to earnings and profits shall be an amount which is not in excess of the ratable share of the earnings and profits of the company accumulated after <date date="1913-02-28">February 28, 1913</date>, attributable to the stock so redeemed.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s111/e/5">Pub. L. 98–369, § 111(e)(5)</ref>, substituted “18-year real property and low-income housing” for “15-year real property” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s61/b">Pub. L. 98–369, § 61(b)</ref>, substituted “40 years” for “35 years” in table item relating to 15-year real property. Directory language that table be amended by substituting “40 years” for “35 years” in item relating to 15-year real property and 20-year real property, was executed by making the substitution in item relating to 15-year real property. The table contained no item relating to 20-year real property.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s61/a/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 61(a)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s61/c/1/B">Pub. L. 98–369, § 61(c)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448">Pub. L. 97–448</ref> substituted “Redemptions” for “Partial liquidations and redemptions” in heading, and in text struck out “in partial liquidation or” after “distributes amounts”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s222/e/3">Pub. L. 97–248, § 222(e)(3)</ref>, struck out “partial liquidations and” in heading, and in text struck out “in partial liquidation (whether before, on, or after <date date="1954-06-22">June 22, 1954</date>) or” after “amounts distributed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s205/a/3">Pub. L. 97–248, § 205(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s310/b/3">Pub. L. 97–248, § 310(b)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (k)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref> added par. (3), redesignated former par. (3) as (4) substituted “The provisions of paragraphs (1) and (3)” for “The provisions of paragraph (1)”, and inserted provision that the rules of section 168(f)(2) shall apply in determining the earnings and profits of the corporation in the case of recovery property (within the meaning of section 168).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/96/589">Pub. L. 96–589</ref> added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/628">Pub. L. 95–628</ref> substituted “gain recognized to the corporation on the distribution” for “gain to the corporation recognized under subsection (b), (c), or (d) of section 311, under section 341(f), or under section 617(d)(1), 1245(a), 1250(a), 1251(c), 1252(a), or 1254(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s205/c/1/D">Pub. L. 94–455, § 205(c)(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “1252(a), or 1254(a)” for “or 1252(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/43/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(43)(A)</ref>, substituted “this title” for “this Code” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1901(a)(43)(B), 1906(b)(13)(A), redesignated subsec. (i) as (h) and struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”. Former subsec. (h), which related to earnings and profits of personal service corporations, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/43/B">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(43)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated subsec. (j) as (i), and, among other changes, substituted “paragraph (2)” for “subparagraph (B) of the preceding sentence” and “of this subsection” for “of this paragraph”, and struck out provisions relating to the effective date of this subsec. Former subsec. (i) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1901(a)(43)(D), (b)(32)(B)(i), 1906(b)(13)(A), redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (j), struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” in par. (1) and in par. (3) provision relating to the effective date of such paragraph. Former subsec. (j) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1901(b)(32)(B)(i), 1906(b)(13)(A), redesignated subsec. (m) as (k) and struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” in par. (2). Former subsec. (k), relating to special adjustment on disposition of antitrust stock received as a dividend, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/32/B/i">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(32)(B)(i)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/32/B/i">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(32)(B)(i)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (m) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, §§ 211(b)(3), 905(b)(2), substituted “1250(a), 1251(c), or 1252(a)”, for “or 1250(a)” and inserted reference to section 311(d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s442/a">Pub. L. 91–172, § 442(a)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/89/570">Pub. L. 89–570</ref> inserted reference to section 617(d)(1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/88/484">Pub. L. 88–484</ref> authorized adjustment for amount of gain recognized under section 341(f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/88/272">Pub. L. 88–272</ref> inserted reference to section 1250(a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s13/f/3">Pub. L. 87–834, § 13(f)(3)</ref>, included any gain recognized under section 1245(a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/87/403">Pub. L. 87–403</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s14/b/1">Pub. L. 87–834, § 14(b)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id42b25ef4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25ef5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2022 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/169">Pub. L. 117–169</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="2022-12-31">Dec. 31, 2022</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s13303/d/1">section 13303(d)(1) of Pub. L. 117–169</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s179D">section 179D of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25ef6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/295">Pub. L. 113–295</ref> effective <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, subject to a savings provision, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/b">section 221(b) of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25ef7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/432">Pub. L. 109–432</ref> applicable to costs paid or incurred after <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s404/c">section 404(c) of Pub. L. 109–432</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s179E">section 179E of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25ef8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1323/b/3">section 1323(b)(3) of Pub. L. 109–58</ref> applicable to properties placed in service after <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1323/c">section 1323(c) of Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s179C">section 179C of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1331/b/5">section 1331(b)(5) of Pub. L. 109–58</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="2005-12-31">Dec. 31, 2005</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/s1331/d">section 1331(d) of Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s179D">section 179D of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25ef9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s338/b/3">section 338(b)(3) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref> applicable to expenses paid or incurred after <date date="2002-12-31">Dec. 31, 2002</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s338/c">section 338(c) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s179B">section 179B of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 413(c)(4), (5) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/357">Pub. L. 108–357</ref> applicable to taxable years of foreign corporations beginning after <date date="2004-12-31">Dec. 31, 2004</date>, and to taxable years of United States shareholders with or within which such taxable years of foreign corporations end, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s413/d/1">section 413(d)(1) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2004 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25efa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> effective as if included in the amendments made by section 1913 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1604/a/4">section 1604(a)(4) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s263">section 263 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25efb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11812/b/5">section 11812(b)(5) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, but not applicable to any property to which <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref> does not apply by reason of subsec. (f)(5) of section 168, and not applicable to rehabilitation expenditures described in <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s252/f/5">section 252(f)(5) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11812/c">section 11812(c) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s42">section 42 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11813/b/14">section 11813(b)(14) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1990-12-31">Dec. 31, 1990</date>, but not applicable to any transition property (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s49/e">section 49(e) of this title</ref>), any property with respect to which qualified progress expenditures were previously taken into account under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46/d">section 46(d) of this title</ref>, and any property described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46/b/2/C">section 46(b)(2)(C) of this title</ref>, as such sections were in effect on <date date="1990-11-04">Nov. 4, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11813/c">section 11813(c) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s45K">section 45K of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25efc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7611/f/5/A">section 7611(f)(5)(A) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref> applicable to costs paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after <date date="1989-12-31">Dec. 31, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7611/g/2">section 7611(g)(2) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s56">section 56 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7811/m/2">section 7811(m)(2) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Technical and Miscellaneous Revenue Act of 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7817">section 7817 of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25efd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25efe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">If any interest costs incurred after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, are attributable to costs incurred before <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s803/b/3">section 803(b)(3) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> is applicable to such interest costs only to the extent such interest costs are attributable to costs which were required to be capitalized under section 263 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 and which would have been taken into account in applying section 189 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (as in effect before its repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s803">section 803 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>) or, if applicable, section 266 of such Code, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7831/d/2">section 7831(d)(2) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s263A">section 263A of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 201(b), (d)(6) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, with exceptions, see sections 203 and 204 of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 201(b), (d)(6) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> not applicable to any property placed in service before <date date="1994-01-01">Jan. 1, 1994</date>, if such property placed in service as part of specified rehabilitations, and not applicable to certain additional rehabilitations, see section 251(d)(2), (3) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46">section 46 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s241/b/1">section 241(b)(1) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to expenditures paid or incurred after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s241/c">section 241(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of Repeal note under former <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s177">section 177 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s631/e/1">section 631(e)(1) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to any distribution in complete liquidation, and any sale or exchange, made by a corporation after <date date="1986-07-31">July 31, 1986</date>, unless such corporation is completely liquidated before <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, any transaction described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s338">section 338 of this title</ref> for which the acquisition date occurs after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, and any distribution, not in complete liquidation, made after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, with exceptions and special and transitional rules, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s633">section 633 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s336">section 336 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s803/b/3">section 803(b)(3) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to costs incurred after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s803/d">section 803(d) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s263A">section 263A of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1804(f)(1)(A)–(E) and 1809(a)(2)(C)(ii) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provisions of the Tax Reform Act of 1984, <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1881">section 1881 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s48">section 48 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1804/f/3">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1804(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2805">100 Stat. 2805</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1804/f/3">“Paragraph (7) of section 312(n) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 [now 1986] (as redesignated by paragraph (1)(D) of this subsection), and the amendments made by section 61(a)(2) of the Tax Reform Act of 1984 [amending this section], shall apply to distributions in taxable years beginning after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25eff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/121">Pub. L. 99–121</ref> applicable with respect to property placed in service by the taxpayer after <date date="1985-05-08">May 8, 1985</date>, with specified exceptions, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/121/s105/b">section 105(b) of Pub. L. 99–121</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f00-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s61/e/1">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 61(e)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/582">98 Stat. 582</ref>, 583, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustments to earnings and profits.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 312</inline>(n).—</heading><content>The provisions of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 312(n) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] (as added by subsection (a)) shall apply to amounts paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Paragraph (4) of section 312</inline>(n).—</heading><content>The provisions of paragraph (4) of section 312(n) of such Code (as so added) shall apply to distributions after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>; except that such provisions shall not apply to any distribution to which the amendments made by section 54(a) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s311">section 311 of this title</ref>] do not apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">LIFO inventory</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of paragraph (5) of section 312(n) of such Code (as so added) shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Installment sales</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of paragraph (6) of section 312(n) of such Code (as so added) shall apply to sales after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Completed contract method</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of paragraph (7) of section 312(n) of such Code (as so added) shall apply to contracts entered into after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subsection</inline> (b).—</heading><content>The amendments made by subsection (b) [amending this section] shall apply to property placed in service in taxable years beginning after <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subsection</inline> (c).—</heading><content>The amendments made by subsection (c) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1275">section 1275 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to distributions declared after <date date="1984-03-15">March 15, 1984</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s61/a/2">section 61(a)(2) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to distributions in taxable years beginning after <date date="1984-09-30">Sept. 30, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1804/f/3">section 1804(f)(3) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1986 Amendment note above.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1804/f/1/F">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1804(f)(1)(F)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2805">100 Stat. 2805</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1804/f/1/F">“Any reference in subsection (e) of section 61 of the Tax Reform Act of 1984 [set out above] to a paragraph of section 312(n) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 [now 1986] shall be treated as a reference to such paragraph as in effect before its redesignation by subparagraph (D) [see 1986 Amendment note above].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s63/c">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 63(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/584">98 Stat. 584</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s63/c">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s368">section 368 of this title</ref>] shall apply to transactions pursuant to plans adopted after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s111/e/5">section 111(e)(5) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable with respect to property placed in service by the taxpayer after <date date="1984-03-15">Mar. 15, 1984</date>, subject to certain exceptions, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s111/g">section 111(g) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f01-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/448">Pub. L. 97–448</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s311/d">section 311(d) of Pub. L. 97–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f02-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s205/a/3">section 205(a)(3) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to periods after <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, under rules similar to the rules of <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s48/m">section 48(m) of this title</ref>, with certain qualifications, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s205/c/1">section 205(c)(1) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s196">section 196 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s222/e/3">section 222(e)(3) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to distributions after <date date="1982-08-31">Aug. 31, 1982</date>, with exceptions for certain partial liquidations, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s222/f">section 222(f) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s302">section 302 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s310/b/3">section 310(b)(3) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to obligations issued after <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, with exceptions for certain warrants, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s310/d">section 310(d) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s103">section 103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f03-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1980-12-31">Dec. 31, 1980</date>, in taxable years ending after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s209/a">section 209(a) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f04-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/589">Pub. L. 96–589</ref> applicable to transactions which occur after <date date="1980-12-31">Dec. 31, 1980</date>, other than transactions which occur in proceedings in bankruptcy cases or similar judicial proceedings or in proceedings under Title 11, Bankruptcy, commencing on or before <date date="1980-12-31">Dec. 31, 1980</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/589/s7">section 7 of Pub. L. 96–589</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s108">section 108 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/628">Pub. L. 95–628</ref> applicable to distributions made after <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/628/s3/d">section 3(d) of Pub. L. 95–628</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s205/c/1/D">section 205(c)(1)(D) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years ending after <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s205/e">section 205(e) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1254">section 1254 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/43">section 1901(a)(43) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/d">section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/32">section 1901(b)(32) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/d">section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s211/b/3">section 211(b)(3) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s211/c">section 211(c) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 905(b)(2) <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> effective with respect to distributions made after <date date="1969-11-30">Nov. 30, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s905/c">section 905(c) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s311">section 311 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/570">Pub. L. 89–570</ref> applicable to taxable years ending after <date date="1966-09-12">Sept. 12, 1966</date>, but only in respect of expenditures paid or incurred after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/570/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 89–570</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s617">section 617 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/484">Pub. L. 88–484</ref> applicable with respect to transactions after <date date="1964-08-22">Aug. 22, 1964</date> in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/484/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 88–484</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/272">Pub. L. 88–272</ref> applicable to dispositions after <date date="1963-12-31">Dec. 31, 1963</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/272/s231/c">section 231(c) of Pub. L. 88–272</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1250">section 1250 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b25f0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s13/f/3">section 13(f)(3) of Pub. L. 87–834</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1962-12-31">Dec. 31, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s13/g">section 13(g) of Pub. L. 87–834</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1245">section 1245 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s14/c">Pub. L. 87–834, § 14(c)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1041">76 Stat. 1041</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/87/834/s14/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting sections 1246 and 1247 of this title and amending this section and sections 751 and 1223 of this title] shall apply with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1962-12-31">December 31, 1962</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/87/403/s3/g">Pub. L. 87–403, § 3(g)</ref>, <date date="1962-02-02">Feb. 2, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/8">76 Stat. 8</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/87/403/s3/g">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 535, 543, 545, 556 and 561 of this title] shall apply only with respect to distributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1962-02-02">Feb. 2, 1962</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id42b25f0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11821/b">section 11821(b) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s45K">section 45K of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id42b25f0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1800–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
