<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4571cd76-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s3221"><num value="3221">§ 3221.</num><heading> Rate of tax</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4571cd77-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s3221/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Tier 1 tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to the applicable percentage of compensation paid during any calendar year by such employer for services rendered to such employer. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “applicable percentage” means the percentage equal to the sum of the rates of tax in effect under subsections (a) and (b) of section 3111 for the calendar year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4571cd78-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s3221/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Tier 2 tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to the percentage determined under section 3241 for any calendar year of the compensation paid during such calendar year by such employer for services rendered to such employer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4571cd79-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s3221/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For application of different contribution bases with respect to the taxes imposed by subsections (a) and (b), see section 3231(e)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4571cd7a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/433">68A Stat. 433</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1164">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1164</ref>, pt. II, § 206(a), <ref href="/us/stat/68/1040">68 Stat. 1040</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/28">Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, pt. II, § 201(d), <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/29">73 Stat. 29</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/133/tII/s202">Pub. L. 88–133, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1963-10-05">Oct. 5, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/221">77 Stat. 221</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/tI">Pub. L. 89–97, title I</ref>, §§ 105(b)(3), 111(c)(3), <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/335">79 Stat. 335</ref>, 342; <ref href="/us/pl/89/212">Pub. L. 89–212</ref>, §§ 4, 5(c), <date date="1965-09-29">Sept. 29, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/861">79 Stat. 861</ref>, 862; <ref href="/us/pl/89/699/tIII/s301/c">Pub. L. 89–699, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, (e), <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1078">80 Stat. 1078</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/700/tIII">Pub. L. 89–700, title III</ref>, §§ 301(iii), (v), (vi), 302, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1088">80 Stat. 1088</ref>, 1089; <ref href="/us/pl/91/215/s5/a">Pub. L. 91–215, § 5(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1970-03-17">Mar. 17, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/71">84 Stat. 71</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/69/tI/s102/d">Pub. L. 93–69, title I, § 102(d)</ref>–(f), <date date="1973-07-10">July 10, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/162">87 Stat. 162</ref>, 163; <ref href="/us/pl/93/445/tV/s501">Pub. L. 93–445, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1359">88 Stat. 1359</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/93/tII/s203">Pub. L. 94–93, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/466">89 Stat. 466</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1903(a)(9), 1906(b)(13)(G), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1808">90 Stat. 1808</ref>, 1835; <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tVII/s741/c">Pub. L. 97–34, title VII, § 741(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/347">95 Stat. 347</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/tII">Pub. L. 98–76, title II</ref>, §§ 211(b), 222, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/419">97 Stat. 419</ref>, 420; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9032/a">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9032(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-296">101 Stat. 1330–296</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5125/c">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5125(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-286">104 Stat. 1388–286</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/90/tII">Pub. L. 107–90, title II</ref>, §§ 203(b), 204(a), <date date="2001-12-21">Dec. 21, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/891">115 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/147/tI/s101/d/1">Pub. L. 111–147, title I, § 101(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/74">124 Stat. 74</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tII/s221/a/100/C">Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(100)(C)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/4052">128 Stat. 4052</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/b/36">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(36)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1204">132 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4571cd7b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4571cd7c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4571cd7d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which provided for a special rate for certain individuals hired in 2010.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295">Pub. L. 113–295</ref> amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) consisted of pars. (1) and (2) establishing the tier 2 tax and its applicable percentage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/147">Pub. L. 111–147</ref> added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/90/s204/a">Pub. L. 107–90, § 204(a)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to 16.10 percent of the compensation paid during any calendar year by such employer for services rendered to such employer.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/107/90/s203/b">Pub. L. 107–90, § 203(b)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c) and struck out former subsecs. (c) and (d) which provided, in subsec. (c), for imposition of excise tax on every employer, with respect to having individuals in his employ, for each man-hour for which compensation was paid by such employer for services rendered to him during any calendar quarter, and for credit against such tax of amount equivalent in each month to the aggregate amount of reductions in supplemental annuities accruing in such month to employees of such employer, and, in subsec. (d), that such tax would not apply to an employer with respect to employees covered by a supplemental pension plan which is established pursuant to an agreement reached through collective bargaining between the employer and employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> substituted “applicable” for “following” before “percentage of” and provision defining “applicable percentage” for provision specifying the tax rate to be 7.05 percent, 7.15 percent, 7.51 percent, and 7.65 percent in the case of compensation paid during 1985, 1986 or 1987, 1988 or 1989, or 1990 or thereafter, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to the following percentage of compensation paid during any calendar year by such employer for services rendered to such employer:</p>
<html:table class="Quoted" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c2,L0,tp0,p6,6/7,s10,19,tp0,p6,6/7,s10,19; " id="id4571cd7e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 145pt;" />
<html:col style="width:61pt ; max-width:61pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 145.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:left;"><html:b>“In the case of compensation paid during:</html:b></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:61.0pt ; max-width:61.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;"><html:b>The rate shall be:</html:b></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> 1985</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">13.75  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> 1986 or thereafter</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">14.75.”</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s222/a">Pub. L. 98–76, § 222(a)</ref>, in amending subsec. (a) generally, substituted provisions imposing an excise tax on employers, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to a percentage of compensation paid as set out in an accompanying table, for provisions which imposed an excise tax on employers, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to 12.75 percent of so much of the compensation paid in any calendar month by such employer for services rendered to him as was not in excess of an amount equal to one-twelfth of the current maximum annual taxable “wages” as defined in section 3121 for any month, with certain exceptions dealing with multiple employers.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s211/b">Pub. L. 98–76, § 211(b)</ref>, substituted “12.75 percent” for “11.75 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s222/a">Pub. L. 98–76, § 222(a)</ref>, in amending subsec. (b) generally, substituted provisions imposing a second tier excise tax on employers equal to a percentage of compensation paid as set out in an accompanying table, for provisions that the rate of tax imposed by former subsec. (a) would be increased by the rate of tax imposed with respect to wages by section 3111(a) plus the rate imposed by section 3111(b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s222/b">Pub. L. 98–76, § 222(b)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref> substituted in first sentence “11.75” for “9.5”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1903(a)(9)(A), 1906(b)(13)(G), struck out provisions relating to the <date date="1973-09-30">September 30, 1973</date> qualification on the applicability of provisions of this subsection, “of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954” after “as defined in section 3121” wherever appearing, and “of the Treasury” after “to the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1903/a/9/B">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1903(a)(9)(B)</ref>, struck out “, with respect to compensation paid for services rendered after <date date="1973-09-30">September 30, 1973</date>,” after “shall be increased”, “of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954” after “by section 3111(a)” and “of such Code” after “by section 3111(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1903(a)(9)(C), 1906(b)(13)(G), struck out “(1) at the rate of two cents for the period beginning <date date="1966-11-01">November 1, 1966</date>, and ending <date date="1970-03-31">March 31, 1970</date>, and (2) commencing <date date="1970-04-01">April 1, 1970</date>,” after “during any calendar quarter,” , “commencing with the quarter beginning <date date="1970-04-01">April 1, 1970</date>” after “required for each calendar quarter”, “of the Treasury” after “representatives, and the Secretary” and “of the Treasury” after “shall certify to the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/93">Pub. L. 94–93</ref> substituted “compensation paid in any calendar month by such employer” for “compensation paid by such employer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/445/s501/a">Pub. L. 93–445, § 501(a)</ref>, struck out “for appropriation to the Railroad Retirement Supplemental Account provided for in section 15(b) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937” after “commencing <date date="1970-04-01">April 1, 1970</date>, at such rate as will make available”, substituted “at the level provided under section 3(j) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 as in effect on <date date="1974-12-31">December 31, 1974</date>” for “under section 3(j) of such Act”, and inserted “or section 2(h)(2) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974” after “section 3(j)(2) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/445/s501/b">Pub. L. 93–445, § 501(b)</ref>, substituted “section 2(b) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974” for “section 3(j) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937” and “section 2(b) of such Act” for “section 3(j) of such Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/69/s102/d">Pub. L. 93–69, § 102(d)</ref>, (e), substituted new tax rate provisions on employers for services rendered after <date date="1973-09-30">Sept. 30, 1973</date>, for former provisions which prescribed 6¼, 6½, 7, 7¼, and 7½ percent on income for services rendered after <date date="1965-09-30">Sept. 30, 1965</date>; <date date="1965-12-31">Dec. 31, 1965</date>; <date date="1966-12-31">Dec. 31, 1966</date>; <date date="1967-12-31">Dec. 31, 1967</date>; and <date date="1968-12-31">Dec. 31, 1968</date>, respectively, as is, with respect to any employee for any calendar month, not in excess of (i) $450, or (ii) an amount equal to one-twelfth of the current maximum annual taxable “wages” as defined in section 3121 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, whichever is greater, for any month after <date date="1965-09-30">Sept. 30, 1965</date>, and, in first sentence, substituted “1973” for “1965” wherever appearing, struck out “(i) $450, or (ii)” before “an amount equal to” in two places, and struck out “, whichever is greater,” after “Internal Revenue Code of 1954” in two places, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/69/s102/f">Pub. L. 93–69, § 102(f)</ref>, substituted “1973” for “1965” and “by the rate of tax imposed with respect to wages by section 3111(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 plus the rate imposed by section 3111(b) of such Code”, for “by a number of percentage points (including fractional points) equal at any given time to the number of percentage points (including fractional points) by which the rate of the tax imposed with respect to wages by section 3111(a) plus the rate imposed by section 3111(b) at such time exceeds 2¾ percent (the rate provided by paragraph (2) of section 3111 as amended by the Social Security Amendments of 1956)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/215/s5/a">Pub. L. 91–215, § 5(a)</ref>, provided a variable standard of taxation on employers for services rendered them during any calendar quarter at the existing 2 cent rate for each man-hour of services for the period from <date date="1966-11-01">Nov. 1, 1966</date> to <date date="1970-03-31">Mar. 31, 1970</date>, and thereafter at such rates as will permit supplemental annuity payments under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s228c/j">section 228c(j) of this title</ref>, and authorized the Railroad Retirement Board to make the necessary determination of rates, and made it its duty to publish notice of such determinations in the Federal Register.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/215/s5/b/1">Pub. L. 91–215, § 5(b)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/700">Pub. L. 89–700</ref>, §§ 301(iii), (v), 302, substituted “after <date date="1965-09-30">September 30, 1965</date>” for “after the month in which this provision was amended in 1959” in six places, and “(i) $450, or (ii) an amount equal to one-twelfth of the current maximum annual taxable ‘wages’ as defined in section 3121 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, whichever is greater, for any month after <date date="1965-09-30">September 30, 1965</date>” for “400 for any calendar month before the calendar month next following the month in which this provision was amended in 1963, or $450 for any calendar month after the month in which this provision was so amended and before the calendar month next following the calendar month in which this provision was amended in 1965, or (i) $450, or (ii) an amount equal to one-twelfth of the current maximum annual taxable ‘wages’ as defined in section 3121 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, whichever is greater, for any month after the month in which this provision was so amended” in four places, and inserted sentence providing that where compensation for services rendered in a month is paid by two or more employers, one of the employers may, by notice to the Secretary, and by agreement with the other employer, elect for the tax imposed by section 3201 and this section to apply to all of the compensation paid by such employer for such month as does not exceed the maximum amount of compensation in respect to which taxes are imposed by section 3201 and this section; and in such a case the liability of the other employer shall be limited to the difference, if any, between the compensation paid by the electing employer and the maximum amount of compensation to which section 3201 and this section apply.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/699/s301/c">Pub. L. 89–699, § 301(c)</ref>, substituted “7 percent” for “6¾ percent” in subd. (3), “7¼ percent” for “7 percent” in subd. (4), and “7½ percent” for “7¼ percent” in subd. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/700/s301/vi">Pub. L. 89–700, § 301(vi)</ref>, substituted “after <date date="1965-09-30">September 30, 1965</date>” for “after <date date="1964-12-31">December 31, 1964</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/89/699">Pub. L. 89–699</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/212">Pub. L. 89–212</ref> substituted pars. (1) to (5) for former pars. (1) and (2) which imposed an excise tax equal to 6¾ percent of so much of the compensation paid by such employer for services rendered to him after the month in which this provision was amended in 1959, and before <date date="1962-01-01">Jan. 1, 1962</date>, and 7¼ percent of so much of the compensation paid by such employer for services rendered to him after <date date="1961-12-31">Dec. 31, 1961</date>, and inserted “and before the calendar month next following the calendar month in which this provision was amended in 1965, or (i) $450, or (ii) an amount equal to one-twelfth of the current maximum annual taxable ‘wages’ as defined in section 3121, whichever is greater, for any month after the month in which this provision was so amended” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/97">Pub. L. 89–97</ref> substituted “the rate of the tax imposed with respect to wages by section 3111(a) at such time exceeds 2¾ percent (the rate provided by paragraph (2) of section 3111 as amended by the Social Security Amendments of 1956)” for “the rate of the tax imposed with respect to wages by section 3111 at such time exceeds the rate provided by paragraph (2) of such section 3111 as amended by the Social Security Amendments of 1956” and inserted “plus the rate imposed by section 3111(b)” after “section 3111(a)”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/88/133">Pub. L. 88–133</ref> limited the existing taxable compensation base of $400 to any calendar month before Nov. 1963 and increased such base to $450 for any calendar month after Oct. 1963.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/86/28/s201/d/1">Pub. L. 86–28, § 201(d)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), (B), designated former provisions of section as subsec. (a), increased the tax from 6¼ percent of the compensation not in excess of $350 for any calendar month to 6¾ percent of the compensation not in excess of $400 for any calendar month for services rendered before <date date="1962-01-01">Jan. 1, 1962</date>, and to 7¼ percent for services rendered after <date date="1961-12-31">Dec. 31, 1961</date>, and substituted “after the month in which this provision was amended in 1959” for “after 1954” and for “after <date date="1954-12-31">December 31, 1954</date>” in six places, “not more than $400” for “not more than $350”, and “less than $400” for “less than $350”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/86/28/s201/d/2/C">Pub. L. 86–28, § 201(d)(2)(C)</ref>, added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, substituted “$350” for “$300” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4571cd7f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4571cd80-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/295">Pub. L. 113–295</ref> effective <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, subject to a savings provision, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/b">section 221(b) of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4571cd81-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/147">Pub. L. 111–147</ref> applicable to compensation paid after <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/147/s101/e">section 101(e) of Pub. L. 111–147</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s51">section 51 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4571cd82-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/90/s203/b">section 203(b) of Pub. L. 107–90</ref> applicable to calendar years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">Dec. 31, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/90/s203/c">section 203(c) of Pub. L. 107–90</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3211">section 3211 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/90/s204/a">section 204(a) of Pub. L. 107–90</ref> applicable to calendar years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">Dec. 31, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/90/s204/f">section 204(f) of Pub. L. 107–90</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s24">section 24 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45741673-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9032/b">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9032(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-296">101 Stat. 1330–296</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9032/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to compensation paid after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45741674-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s211/b">section 211(b) of Pub. L. 98–76</ref> applicable to compensation paid for services rendered after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, and before <date date="1985-01-01">Jan. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s212">section 212 of Pub. L. 98–76</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s222">section 222 of Pub. L. 98–76</ref> applicable to remuneration paid after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s227/a">section 227(a) of Pub. L. 98–76</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45741675-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to compensation paid for services rendered after <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s741/e">section 741(e) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45741676-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1903/a/9">section 1903(a)(9) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable with respect to compensation paid for services rendered after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1903/d">section 1903(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45741677-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/93">Pub. L. 94–93</ref> applicable for taxable years ending on or after <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, and for taxable years ending before <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, as to which the period for assessment and collection of tax or the filing of a claim for credit or refund has not expired on <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/93/s207">section 207 of Pub. L. 94–93</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45741678-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/445/tVI/s604">Pub. L. 93–445, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1361">88 Stat. 1361</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/445/tVI/s604">“The amendments made by the provisions of title V of this Act [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6413">section 6413 of this title</ref>] shall become effective on <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, and shall apply only with respect to compensation paid for services rendered on or after that date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45741679-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1973 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/69">Pub. L. 93–69</ref> effective <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, and applicable only with respect to compensation paid for services rendered on or after <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>; and applicable to railway labor organization covered by a private supplemental pension plan as of <date date="1973-10-01">Oct. 1, 1973</date>, and subject to a moratorium, agreed to on or before <date date="1973-03-08">Mar. 8, 1973</date>, for changes in pay rates, on the earlier of (1) date of expiration of such moratorium, or (2) date as of which the railway labor organization through collective bargaining agreement makes amendment applicable, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/69/s109/b">section 109(b) of Pub. L. 93–69</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4574167a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/699">Pub. L. 89–699</ref> effective with respect to man-hours, beginning with first month following <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, for which compensation is paid, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/699/s301/f">section 301(f) of Pub. L. 89–699</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3211">section 3211 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4574167b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1965 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/212/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 89–212</ref> effective only with respect to calendar months after the month in which <ref href="/us/pl/89/212">Pub. L. 89–212</ref> is enacted [September 1965], and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/212/s5/c">section 5(c) of Pub. L. 89–212</ref> effective only with respect to compensation paid for services rendered after <date date="1965-09-30">Sept. 30, 1965</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/212/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 89–212</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s105/b/3">section 105(b)(3) of Pub. L. 89–97</ref> effective with respect to compensation paid for services rendered after <date date="1965-12-31">Dec. 31, 1965</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s105/b/4">section 105(b)(4) of Pub. L. 89–97</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s111/c/3">section 111(c)(3) of Pub. L. 89–97</ref> applicable to calendar year 1966 or to any subsequent calendar year but only if by October 1 immediately preceding such calendar year the Railroad Retirement Tax Act provides for a maximum amount of monthly compensation taxable under such Act during all months of such calendar year equal to one-twelfth of maximum wages which Federal Insurance Contributions Act provides may be counted for such calendar year, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s111/e">section 111(e) of Pub. L. 89–97</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i–1">section 1395i–1 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4574167c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1959 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/86/28">Pub. L. 86–28</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, first day of calendar month next following May 1959, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/28/s202">section 202 of Pub. L. 86–28</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4574167d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1954 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, effective as if enacted as a part of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954], see section 407 of act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id4574167e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/e">section 401(e) of Pub. L. 115–141</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s23">section 23 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4574167f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Penalties and Interest Not Assessed for Failure To Make Timely Payment During Period <date date="1982-01-01">January 1, 1982</date>, to <date date="1982-06-30">June 30, 1982</date>, of Taxes Attributable to Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/97/123">Pub. L. 97–123</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provision that no penalties or interest shall be assessed on account of any failure to make timely payment of taxes imposed by subsec. (b) of this section with respect to payments made for the period <date date="1982-01-01">Jan. 1, 1982</date>, and ending <date date="1982-06-30">June 30, 1982</date>, to the extent that such taxes are attributable to <ref href="/us/pl/97/123/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 97–123</ref> or the amendments made by that section, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/123/s3/f">section 3(f) of Pub. L. 97–123</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id45741680-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Payroll Credits for Emergency Sick or Family Leave and Special Rule for 2020</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For allowance of credit against tax imposed by subsec. (a) of this section for certain sick leave wages paid by an employer applicable during part of 2020, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/127/s7001">section 7001 of Pub. L. 116–127</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3111">section 3111 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For allowance of credit againt tax imposed by subsec. (a) of this section for certain family leave wages paid by an employer applicable during part of 2020, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/127/s7003">section 7003 of Pub. L. 116–127</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3111">section 3111 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provision that sick leave and family leave wages paid out by reason of certain provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/116/127">Pub. L. 116–127</ref> not to be considered compensation for purposes of subsec. (a) of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/127/s7005">section 7005 of Pub. L. 116–127</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3111">section 3111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id45741681-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Excise Taxes on Employers; Employees Covered by Certain Supplemental Pension Plans</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/215/s5/b/2">Pub. L. 91–215, § 5(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-03-17">Mar. 17, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/71">84 Stat. 71</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/215/s5/b/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to (A) supplemental annuities paid on or after <date date="1970-04-01">April 1, 1970</date>, and (B) man-hours with respect to which compensation is paid for services rendered to such employer on or after such day.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
