<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id42b4a964-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332"><num value="332">§ 332.</num><heading> Complete liquidations of subsidiaries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a965-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No gain or loss shall be recognized on the receipt by a corporation of property distributed in complete liquidation of another corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a966-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Liquidations to which section applies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, a distribution shall be considered to be in complete liquidation only if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42b4a967-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the corporation receiving such property was, on the date of the adoption of the plan of liquidation, and has continued to be at all times until the receipt of the property, the owner of stock (in such other corporation) meeting the requirements of section 1504(a)(2); and either</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42b4a968-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the distribution is by such other corporation in complete cancellation or redemption of all its stock, and the transfer of all the property occurs within the taxable year; in such case the adoption by the shareholders of the resolution under which is authorized the distribution of all the assets of such corporation in complete cancellation or redemption of all its stock shall be considered an adoption of a plan of liquidation, even though no time for the completion of the transfer of the property is specified in such resolution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id42b4a969-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> such distribution is one of a series of distributions by such other corporation in complete cancellation or redemption of all its stock in accordance with a plan of liquidation under which the transfer of all the property under the liquidation is to be completed within 3 years from the close of the taxable year during which is made the first of the series of distributions under the plan, except that if such transfer is not completed within such period, or if the taxpayer does not continue qualified under paragraph (1) until the completion of such transfer, no distribution under the plan shall be considered a distribution in complete liquidation.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If such transfer of all the property does not occur within the taxable year, the Secretary may require of the taxpayer such bond, or waiver of the statute of limitations on assessment and collection, or both, as he may deem necessary to insure, if the transfer of the property is not completed within such 3-year period, or if the taxpayer does not continue qualified under paragraph (1) until the completion of such transfer, the assessment and collection of all income taxes then imposed by law for such taxable year or subsequent taxable years, to the extent attributable to property so received. A distribution otherwise constituting a distribution in complete liquidation within the meaning of this subsection shall not be considered as not constituting such a distribution merely because it does not constitute a distribution or liquidation within the meaning of the corporate law under which the distribution is made; and for purposes of this subsection a transfer of property of such other corporation to the taxpayer shall not be considered as not constituting a distribution (or one of a series of distributions) in complete cancellation or redemption of all the stock of such other corporation, merely because the carrying out of the plan involves (A) the transfer under the plan to the taxpayer by such other corporation of property, not attributable to shares owned by the taxpayer, on an exchange described in section 361, and (B) the complete cancellation or redemption under the plan, as a result of exchanges described in section 354, of the shares not owned by the taxpayer.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a96a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Deductible liquidating distributions of regulated investment companies and real estate investment trusts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a corporation receives a distribution from a regulated investment company or a real estate investment trust which is considered under subsection (b) as being in complete liquidation of such company or trust, then, notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, such corporation shall recognize and treat as a dividend from such company or trust an amount equal to the deduction for dividends paid allowable to such company or trust by reason of such distribution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a96b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Recognition of gain on liquidation of certain holding companies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a96c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any distribution to a foreign corporation in complete liquidation of an applicable holding company—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42b4a96d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> subsection (a) and section 331 shall not apply to such distribution, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id42b4a96e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such distribution shall be treated as a distribution of property to which section 301 applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a96f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable holding company</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a970-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “applicable holding company” means any domestic corporation—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42b4a971-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> which is a common parent of an affiliated group,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42b4a972-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> stock of which is directly owned by the distributee foreign corporation,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42b4a973-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> substantially all of the assets of which consist of stock in other members of such affiliated group, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id42b4a974-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> which has not been in existence at all times during the 5 years immediately preceding the date of the liquidation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a975-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Affiliated group</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, the term “affiliated group” has the meaning given such term by section 1504(a) (without regard to paragraph (2) of section 1504(b)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a976-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with subpart F</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the distributee of a distribution described in paragraph (1) is a controlled foreign corporation (as defined in section 957), then notwithstanding paragraph (1) or subsection (a), such distribution shall be treated as a distribution to which section 331 applies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id42b4a977-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s332/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide such regulations as appropriate to prevent the abuse of this subsection, including regulations which provide, for the purposes of clause (iv) of paragraph (2)(A), that a corporation is not in existence for any period unless it is engaged in the active conduct of a trade or business or owns a significant ownership interest in another corporation so engaged.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id42b4a978-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/102">68A Stat. 102</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tVI/s631/e/2">Pub. L. 99–514, title VI, § 631(e)(2)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1804(e)(6)(A), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2273">100 Stat. 2273</ref>, 2803; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tIII/s3001/a">Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title III, § 3001(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-904">112 Stat. 2681–904</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s893/a">Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 893(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1646">118 Stat. 1646</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s412/v">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 412(v)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2638">119 Stat. 2638</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/d/1/D/xvii/III">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(d)(1)(D)(xvii)(III)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1208">132 Stat. 1208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id42b4a979-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id42b4a97a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id42b4a97b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> substituted “paragraph (2)” for “paragraphs (2) and (4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135">Pub. L. 109–135</ref> substituted “distribution of property to which section 301 applies” for “distribution to which section 301 applies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357">Pub. L. 108–357</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s3001/b/1">Pub. L. 105–277, § 3001(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “this section” for “subsection (a)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s3001/a">Pub. L. 105–277, § 3001(a)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1804/e/6/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1804(e)(6)(A)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “the corporation receiving such property was, on the date of the adoption of the plan of liquidation, and has continued to be at all times until the receipt of the property, the owner of stock (in such other corporation) possessing at least 80 percent of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote and the owner of at least 80 percent of the total number of shares of all other classes of stock (except nonvoting stock which is limited and preferred as to dividends); and either”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s631/e/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 631(e)(2)</ref>, struck out subsec. (c) containing special rule for indebtedness of subsidiary to parent in relation to complete liquidations of subsidiaries.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id42b4a97c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b4a97d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s893/b">Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 893(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1647">118 Stat. 1647</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s893/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to distributions in complete liquidation occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b4a97e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tIII/s3001/c">Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title III, § 3001(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-904">112 Stat. 2681–904</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tIII/s3001/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s334">section 334 of this title</ref>] shall apply to distributions after <date date="1998-05-21">May 21, 1998</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id42b4a97f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s631/e/2">section 631(e)(2) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to any distribution in complete liquidation, and any sale or exchange, made by a corporation after <date date="1986-07-31">July 31, 1986</date>, unless such corporation is completely liquidated before <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, any transaction described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s338">section 338 of this title</ref> for which the acquisition date occurs after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, and any distribution, not in complete liquidation, made after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, with exceptions and special and transitional rules, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s633">section 633 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s336">section 336 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1804/e/6/B">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1804(e)(6)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2803">100 Stat. 2803</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1804/e/6/B">
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in clause (iii), the amendment made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to plans of complete liquidation adopted after <date date="1985-03-28">March 28, 1985</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain distributions made after <date date="1984-12-31">december 31, 1984</date></inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in clause (iii), the amendment made by subparagraph (A) shall also apply with respect to plans of complete liquidations adopted on or before <date date="1985-03-28">March 28, 1985</date>, pursuant to which any distribution is made in a taxable year beginning after <date date="1984-12-31">December 31, 1984</date> (<date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>, in the case of an affiliated group to which an election under section 60(b)(7) of the Tax Reform Act of 1984 [<ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1504">section 1504 of this title</ref>] applies), but only if the liquidating corporation and any corporation which receives a distribution in complete liquidation of such corporation are members of an affiliated group of corporations filing a consolidated return for the taxable year which includes the date of the distribution.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transitional rule for affiliated groups</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to plans of complete liquidation if the liquidating corporation is a member of an affiliated group of corporations under section 60(b) (2), (5), (6), or (8) of the Tax Reform Act of 1984 [<ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1504">section 1504 of this title</ref>], for all taxable years which include the date of any distribution pursuant to such plan.”</content>
</clause>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id42b4a980-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/e">section 401(e) of Pub. L. 115–141</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s23">section 23 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id42b4a981-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1800–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
