<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4305d5a9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404"><num value="404">§ 404.</num><heading> Deduction for contributions of an employer to an employees’ trust or annuity plan and compensation under a deferred-payment plan</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5aa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If contributions are paid by an employer to or under a stock bonus, pension, profit-sharing, or annuity plan, or if compensation is paid or accrued on account of any employee under a plan deferring the receipt of such compensation, such contributions or compensation shall not be deductible under this chapter; but, if they would otherwise be deductible, they shall be deductible under this section, subject, however, to the following limitations as to the amounts deductible in any year:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5ab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Pension trusts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5ac-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the taxable year when paid, if the contributions are paid into a pension trust (other than a trust to which paragraph (3) applies), and if such taxable year ends within or with a taxable year of the trust for which the trust is exempt under section 501(a), in the case of a defined benefit plan other than a multiemployer plan, in an amount determined under subsection (<i>o</i>), and in the case of any other plan in an amount determined as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5ad-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standard provided by section 412(a) for plan years ending within or with such taxable year (or for any prior plan year), if such amount is greater than the amount determined under clause (ii) or (iii) (whichever is applicable with respect to the plan),</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5ae-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount necessary to provide with respect to all of the employees under the trust the remaining unfunded cost of their past and current service credits distributed as a level amount, or a level percentage of compensation, over the remaining future service of each such employee, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, but if such remaining unfunded cost with respect to any 3 individuals is more than 50 percent of such remaining unfunded cost, the amount of such unfunded cost attributable to such individuals shall be distributed over a period of at least 5 taxable years,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5af-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an amount equal to the normal cost of the plan, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, plus, if past service or other supplementary pension or annuity credits are provided by the plan, an amount necessary to amortize the unfunded costs attributable to such credits in equal annual payments (until fully amortized) over 10 years, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">In determining the amount deductible in such year under the foregoing limitations the funding method and the actuarial assumptions used shall be those used for such year under section 431, and the maximum amount deductible for such year shall be an amount equal to the full funding limitation for such year determined under section 431.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5b0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule in case of certain amendments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a multiemployer plan which the Secretary of Labor finds to be collectively bargained which makes an election under this subparagraph (in such manner and at such time as may be provided under regulations prescribed by the Secretary), if the full funding limitation determined under section 431(c)(6) for such year is zero, if as a result of any plan amendment applying to such plan year, the amount determined under section 431(c)(6)(A)(ii) exceeds the amount determined under section 431(c)(6)(A)(i), and if the funding method and the actuarial assumptions used are those used for such year under section 431, the maximum amount deductible in such year under the limitations of this paragraph shall be an amount equal to the lesser of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5b1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the full funding limitation for such year determined by applying section 431(c)(6) but increasing the amount referred to in subparagraph (A) thereof by the decrease in the present value of all unamortized liabilities resulting from such amendment, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5b2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the normal cost under the plan reduced by the amount necessary to amortize in equal annual installments over 10 years (until fully amortized) the decrease described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">In the case of any election under this subparagraph, the amount deductible under the limitations of this paragraph with respect to any of the plan years following the plan year for which such election was made shall be determined as provided under such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary to carry out the purposes of this subparagraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5b3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain collectively-bargained plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a plan which the Secretary of Labor finds to be collectively bargained, established or maintained by an employer doing business in not less than 40 States and engaged in the trade or business of furnishing or selling services described in section 168(i)(10)(C), with respect to which the rates have been established or approved by a State or political subdivision thereof, by any agency or instrumentality of the United States, or by a public service or public utility commission or other similar body of any State or political subdivision thereof, and in the case of any employer which is a member of a controlled group with such employer, subparagraph (B) shall be applied by substituting for the words “plan amendment” the words “plan amendment or increase in benefits payable under title II of the Social Security Act”. For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term “controlled group” has the meaning provided by section 1563(a), determined without regard to section 1563(a)(4) and (e)(3)(C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5b4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount determined on basis of unfunded current liability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a defined benefit plan which is a multiemployer plan, except as provided in regulations, the maximum amount deductible under the limitations of this paragraph shall not be less than the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5b5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 140 percent of the current liability of the plan determined under section 431(c)(6)(D), over</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5b6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the value of the plan’s assets determined under section 431(c)(2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5b7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/1/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Carryover</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount paid in a taxable year in excess of the amount deductible in such year under the foregoing limitations shall be deductible in the succeeding taxable years in order of time to the extent of the difference between the amount paid and deductible in each such succeeding year and the maximum amount deductible for such year under the foregoing limitations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5b8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Employees’ annuities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the taxable year when paid, in an amount determined in accordance with paragraph (1), if the contributions are paid toward the purchase of retirement annuities, or retirement annuities and medical benefits as described in section 401(h), and such purchase is part of a plan which meets the requirements of section 401(a)(3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), (9), (11), (12), (13), (14), (15), (16), (17),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002111">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002111"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> (19), (20), (22), (26), (27), (31), and (37) and, if applicable, the requirements of section 401(a)(10) and of section 401(d), and if refunds of premiums, if any, are applied within the current taxable year or next succeeding taxable year toward the purchase of such retirement annuities, or such retirement annuities and medical benefits.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5b9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Stock bonus and profit-sharing trusts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5ba-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Limits on deductible contributions</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5bb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the taxable year when paid, if the contributions are paid into a stock bonus or profit-sharing trust, and if such taxable year ends within or with a taxable year of the trust with respect to which the trust is exempt under section 501(a), in an amount not in excess of the greater of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4305d5bc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> 25 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to the beneficiaries under the stock bonus or profit-sharing plan, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4305d5bd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the amount such employer is required to contribute to such trust under section 401(k)(11) for such year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5be-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Carryover of excess contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Any amount paid into the trust in any taxable year in excess of the limitation of clause (i) (or the corresponding provision of prior law) shall be deductible in the succeeding taxable years in order of time, but the amount so deductible under this clause in any 1 such succeeding taxable year together with the amount allowable under clause (i) shall not exceed the amount described in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i), whichever is greater, with respect to such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5bf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain retirement plans excluded</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “stock bonus or profit-sharing trust” shall not include any trust designed to provide benefits upon retirement and covering a period of years, if under the plan the amounts to be contributed by the employer can be determined actuarially as provided in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> 2 or more trusts treated as 1 trust</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the contributions are made to 2 or more stock bonus or profit-sharing trusts, such trusts shall be considered a single trust for purposes of applying the limitations in this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/A/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Defined contribution plans subject to the funding standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Except as provided by the Secretary, a defined contribution plan which is subject to the funding standards of section 412 shall be treated in the same manner as a stock bonus or profit-sharing plan for purposes of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Profit-sharing plan of affiliated group</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a profit-sharing plan, or a stock bonus plan in which contributions are determined with reference to profits, of a group of corporations which is an affiliated group within the meaning of section 1504, if any member of such affiliated group is prevented from making a contribution which it would otherwise have made under the plan, by reason of having no current or accumulated earnings or profits or because such earnings or profits are less than the contributions which it would otherwise have made, then so much of the contribution which such member was so prevented from making may be made, for the benefit of the employees of such member, by the other members of the group, to the extent of current or accumulated earnings or profits, except that such contribution by each such other member shall be limited, where the group does not file a consolidated return, to that proportion of its total current and accumulated earnings or profits remaining after adjustment for its contribution deductible without regard to this subparagraph which the total prevented contribution bears to the total current and accumulated earnings or profits of all the members of the group remaining after adjustment for all contributions deductible without regard to this subparagraph. Contributions made under the preceding sentence shall be deductible under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph by the employer making such contribution, and, for the purpose of determining amounts which may be carried forward and deducted under the second sentence of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph in succeeding taxable years, shall be deemed to have been made by the employer on behalf of whose employees such contributions were made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Trusts created or organized outside the United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing trust would qualify for exemption under section 501(a) except for the fact that it is a trust created or organized outside the United States, contributions to such a trust by an employer which is a resident, or corporation, or other entity of the United States, shall be deductible under the preceding paragraphs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Other plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the plan is not one included in paragraph (1), (2), or (3), in the taxable year in which an amount attributable to the contribution is includible in the gross income of employees participating in the plan, but, in the case of a plan in which more than one employee participates only if separate accounts are maintained for each employee. For purposes of this section, any vacation pay which is treated as deferred compensation shall be deductible for the taxable year of the employer in which paid to the employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Time when contributions deemed made</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), a taxpayer shall be deemed to have made a payment on the last day of the preceding taxable year if the payment is on account of such taxable year and is made not later than the time prescribed by law for filing the return for such taxable year (including extensions thereof).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on deductions where combination of defined contribution plan and defined benefit plan</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5c7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If amounts are deductible under the foregoing paragraphs of this subsection (other than paragraph (5)) in connection with 1 or more defined contribution plans and 1 or more defined benefit plans or in connection with trusts or plans described in 2 or more of such paragraphs, the total amount deductible in a taxable year under such plans shall not exceed the greater of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5c8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 25 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to the beneficiaries under such plans, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4305d5c9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount of contributions made to or under the defined benefit plans to the extent such contributions do not exceed the amount of employer contributions necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standard provided by section 412 with respect to any such defined benefit plans for the plan year which ends with or within such taxable year (or for any prior plan year).</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">A defined contribution plan which is a pension plan shall not be treated as failing to provide definitely determinable benefits merely by limiting employer contributions to amounts deductible under this section. In the case of a defined benefit plan which is a single employer plan, the amount necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standard provided by section 412 shall not be less than the excess (if any) of the plan’s funding target (as defined in section 430(d)(1)) over the value of the plan’s assets (as determined under section 430(g)(3)).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5ca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Carryover of contributions in excess of the deductible limit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount paid under the plans in any taxable year in excess of the limitation of subparagraph (A) shall be deductible in the succeeding taxable years in order of time, but the amount so deductible under this subparagraph in any 1 such succeeding taxable year together with the amount allowable under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed 25 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during such taxable year to the beneficiaries under the plans.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5cb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Paragraph not to apply in certain cases</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5cc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Beneficiary test</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">This paragraph shall not have the effect of reducing the amount otherwise deductible under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), if no employee is a beneficiary under more than 1 trust or under a trust and an annuity plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5cd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Elective deferrals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If, in connection with 1 or more defined contribution plans and 1 or more defined benefit plans, no amounts (other than elective deferrals (as defined in section 402(g)(3))) are contributed to any of the defined contribution plans for the taxable year, then subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to any of such defined contribution plans and defined benefit plans.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5ce-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of employer contributions to 1 or more defined contribution plans—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4305d5cf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> if such contributions do not exceed 6 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to the beneficiaries under such plans, this paragraph shall not apply to such contributions or to employer contributions to the defined benefit plans to which this paragraph would otherwise apply by reason of contributions to the defined contribution plans, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4305d5d0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if such contributions exceed 6 percent of such compensation, this paragraph shall be applied by only taking into account such contributions to the extent of such excess.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> For purposes of this clause, amounts carried over from preceding taxable years under subparagraph (B) shall be treated as employer contributions to 1 or more defined contributions plans to the extent attributable to employer contributions to such plans in such preceding taxable years.</continuation>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5d1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Guaranteed plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In applying this paragraph, any single-employer plan covered under section 4021 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 shall not be taken into account.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5d2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/C/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Multiemployer plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In applying this paragraph, any multiemployer plan shall not be taken into account.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5d3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Insurance contract plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, a plan described in section 412(e)(3) shall be treated as a defined benefit plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5d4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Self-employed individuals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a plan included in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) which provides contributions or benefits for employees some or all of whom are employees within the meaning of section 401(c)(1), for purposes of this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5d5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “employee” includes an individual who is an employee within the meaning of section 401(c)(1), and the employer of such individual is the person treated as his employer under section 401(c)(4);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5d6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “earned income” has the meaning assigned to it by section 401(c)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5d7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the contributions to such plan on behalf of an individual who is an employee within the meaning of section 401(c)(1) shall be considered to satisfy the conditions of section 162 or 212 to the extent that such contributions do not exceed the earned income of such individual (determined without regard to the deductions allowed by this section) derived from the trade or business with respect to which such plan is established, and to the extent that such contributions are not allocable (determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary) to the purchase of life, accident, health, or other insurance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5d8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/8/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any reference to compensation shall, in the case of an individual who is an employee within the meaning of section 401(c)(1), be considered to be a reference to the earned income of such individual derived from the trade or business with respect to which the plan is established.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5d9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain contributions to employee stock ownership plans</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5da-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/9/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Principal payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (3) and (7), if contributions are paid into a trust which forms a part of an employee stock ownership plan (as described in section 4975(e)(7)), and such contributions are, on or before the time prescribed in paragraph (6), applied by the plan to the repayment of the principal of a loan incurred for the purpose of acquiring qualifying employer securities (as described in section 4975(e)(8)), such contributions shall be deductible under this paragraph for the taxable year determined under paragraph (6). The amount deductible under this paragraph shall not, however, exceed 25 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to the employees under such employee stock ownership plan. Any amount paid into such trust in any taxable year in excess of the amount deductible under this paragraph shall be deductible in the succeeding taxable years in order of time to the extent of the difference between the amount paid and deductible in each such succeeding year and the maximum amount deductible for such year under the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5db-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/9/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (3) and (7), if contributions are made to an employee stock ownership plan (described in subparagraph (A)) and such contributions are applied by the plan to the repayment of interest on a loan incurred for the purpose of acquiring qualifying employer securities (as described in subparagraph (A)), such contributions shall be deductible for the taxable year with respect to which such contributions are made as determined under paragraph (6).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5dc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/9/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> S corporations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">This paragraph shall not apply to an S corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5dd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/9/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified gratuitous transfers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A qualified gratuitous transfer (as defined in section 664(g)(1)) shall have no effect on the amount or amounts otherwise deductible under paragraph (3) or (7) or under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5de-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributions by certain ministers to retirement income accounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of contributions made by a minister described in section 414(e)(5) to a retirement income account described in section 403(b)(9) and not by a person other than such minister, such contributions—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5df-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall be treated as made to a trust which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) and which is part of a plan which is described in section 401(a), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5e0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall be deductible under this subsection to the extent such contributions do not exceed the limit on elective deferrals under section 402(g) or the limit on annual additions under section 415.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, all plans in which the minister is a participant shall be treated as one plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5e1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations relating to deferred compensation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of determining under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5e2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> whether compensation of an employee is deferred compensation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5e3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> when deferred compensation is paid,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">no amount shall be treated as received by the employee, or paid, until it is actually received by the employee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5e4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/a/12"><num value="12" class="bold">(12)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraphs (3), (7), (8), and (9) and subsection (h)(1)(C), the term “compensation” shall include amounts treated as “participant’s compensation” under subparagraph (C) or (D) of section 415(c)(3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5e5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Method of contributions, etc., having the effect of a plan; certain deferred benefits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5e6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Method of contributions, etc., having the effect of a plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5e7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> there is no plan, but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4305d5e8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> there is a method or arrangement of employer contributions or compensation which has the effect of a stock bonus, pension, profit-sharing, or annuity plan, or other plan deferring the receipt of compensation (including a plan described in paragraph (2)),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">subsection (a) shall apply as if there were such a plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5e9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Plans providing certain deferred benefits</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5ea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this section, any plan providing for deferred benefits (other than compensation) for employees, their spouses, or their dependents shall be treated as a plan deferring the receipt of compensation. In the case of such a plan, for purposes of this section, the determination of when an amount is includible in gross income shall be made without regard to any provisions of this chapter excluding such benefits from gross income.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5eb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any benefit provided through a welfare benefit fund (as defined in section 419(e)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4305d5ec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain negotiated plans</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If contributions are paid by an employer—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4305d5ed-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> under a plan under which such contributions are held in trust for the purpose of paying (either from principal or income or both) for the benefit of employees and their families and dependents at least medical or hospital care, or pensions on retirement or death of employees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43081fde-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such plan was established prior to <date date="1954-01-01">January 1, 1954</date>, as a result of an agreement between employee representatives and the Government of the United States during a period of Government operation, under seizure powers, of a major part of the productive facilities of the industry in which such employer is engaged,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">such contributions shall not be deductible under this section nor be made nondeductible by this section, but the deductibility thereof shall be governed solely by section 162 (relating to trade or business expenses). For purposes of this chapter and subtitle B, in the case of any individual who before <date date="1974-07-01">July 1, 1974</date>, was a participant in a plan described in the preceding sentence—</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43081fdf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/c/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such individual, if he is or was an employee within the meaning of section 401(c)(1), shall be treated (with respect to service covered by the plan) as being an employee other than an employee within the meaning of section 401(c)(1) and as being an employee of a participating employer under the plan,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43081fe0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/c/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> earnings derived from service covered by the plan shall be treated as not being earned income within the meaning of section 401(c)(2), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43081fe1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/c/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> such individual shall be treated as an employee of a participating employer under the plan with respect to service before <date date="1975-07-01">July 1, 1975</date>, covered by the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Section 277 (relating to deductions incurred by certain membership organizations in transactions with members) does not apply to any trust described in this subsection. The first and third sentences of this subsection shall have no application with respect to amounts contributed to a trust on or after any date on which such trust is qualified for exemption from tax under section 501(a).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fe2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Deductibility of payments of deferred compensation, etc., to independent contractors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a plan would be described in so much of subsection (a) as precedes paragraph (1) thereof (as modified by subsection (b)) but for the fact that there is no employer-employee relationship, the contributions or compensation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43081fe3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall not be deductible by the payor thereof under this chapter, but</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43081fe4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall (if they would be deductible under this chapter but for paragraph (1)) be deductible under this subsection for the taxable year in which an amount attributable to the contribution or compensation is includible in the gross income of the persons participating in the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fe5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributions allocable to life insurance protection for self-employed individuals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a self-employed individual described in section 401(c)(1), contributions which are allocable (determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) to the purchase of life, accident, health, or other insurance shall not be taken into account under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fe6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/f"><num value="f" class="bold">[(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tVII/s713/b/3">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 713(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/957">98 Stat. 957</ref>]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fe7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain employer liability payments considered as contributions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fe8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, any amount paid by an employer under section 4041(b), 4062, 4063, or 4064, or part 1 of subtitle E of title IV of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 shall be treated as a contribution to which this section applies by such employer to or under a stock bonus, pension, profit-sharing, or annuity plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fe9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Controlled group deductions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a payment described in paragraph (1) made by an entity which is liable because it is a member of a commonly controlled group of corporations, trades, or businesses, within the meaning of subsection (b) or (c) of section 414, the fact that the entity did not directly employ participants of the plan with respect to which the liability payment was made shall not affect the deductibility of a payment which otherwise satisfies the conditions of section 162 (relating to trade or business expenses) or section 212 (relating to expenses for the production of income).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing of deduction of contributions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43081feb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, any payment described in paragraph (1) shall (subject to the last sentence of subsection (a)(1)(A)) be deductible under this section when paid.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributions under standard terminations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply (and subsection (a)(1)(A) shall apply) to any payments described in paragraph (1) which are paid to terminate a plan under section 4041(b) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to the extent such payments result in the assets of the plan being in excess of the total amount of benefits under such plan which are guaranteed by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation under section 4022 of such Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fed-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributions to certain trusts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any payment described in paragraph (1) which is made under section 4062(c) of such Act and such payment shall be deductible at such time as may be prescribed in regulations which are based on principles similar to the principles of subsection (a)(1)(A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> References to Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, any reference to a section of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 shall be treated as a reference to such section as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Retirement Protection Act of 1994.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for simplified employee pensions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ff0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Employer contributions to a simplified employee pension shall be treated as if they are made to a plan subject to the requirements of this section. Employer contributions to a simplified employee pension are subject to the following limitations:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43081ff1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Contributions made for a year are deductible—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43081ff2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of a simplified employee pension maintained on a calendar year basis, for the taxable year with or within which the calendar year ends, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43081ff3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of a simplified employee pension which is maintained on the basis of the taxable year of the employer, for such taxable year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43081ff4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Contributions shall be treated for purposes of this subsection as if they were made for a taxable year if such contributions are made on account of such taxable year and are made not later than the time prescribed by law for filing the return for such taxable year (including extensions thereof).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43081ff5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The amount deductible in a taxable year for a simplified employee pension shall not exceed 25 percent of the compensation paid to the employees during the calendar year ending with or within the taxable year (or during the taxable year in the case of a taxable year described in subparagraph (A)(ii)). The excess of the amount contributed over the amount deductible for a taxable year shall be deductible in the succeeding taxable years in order of time, subject to the 25 percent limit of the preceding sentence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ff6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on certain trusts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For any taxable year for which the employer has a deduction under paragraph (1), the otherwise applicable limitations in subsection (a)(3)(A) shall be reduced by the amount of the allowable deductions under paragraph (1) with respect to participants in the trust subject to subsection (a)(3)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ff7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with subsection (a)(7)</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (a)(7), a simplified employee pension shall be treated as if it were a separate stock bonus or profit-sharing trust.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ff8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/i"><num value="i" class="bold">[(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXI/s1171/b/6">Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1171(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2513">100 Stat. 2513</ref>]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ff9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules relating to application with section 415</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ffa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> No deduction in excess of section 415 limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In computing the amount of any deduction allowable under paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), (7), or (9) of subsection (a) for any year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43081ffb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a defined benefit plan, there shall not be taken into account any benefits for any year in excess of any limitation on such benefits under section 415 for such year, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43081ffc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a defined contribution plan, the amount of any contributions otherwise taken into account shall be reduced by any annual additions in excess of the limitation under section 415 for such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ffd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> No advance funding of cost-of-living adjustments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of clause (i), (ii) or (iii) of subsection (a)(1)(A), and in computing the full funding limitation, there shall not be taken into account any adjustments under section 415(d)(1) for any year before the year for which such adjustment first takes effect.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43081ffe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Deduction for dividends paid on certain employer securities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43081fff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a C corporation, there shall be allowed as a deduction for a taxable year the amount of any applicable dividend paid in cash by such corporation with respect to applicable employer securities. Such deduction shall be in addition to the deductions allowed under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082000-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable dividend</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082001-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “applicable dividend” means any dividend which, in accordance with the plan provisions—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43082002-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is paid in cash to the participants in the plan or their beneficiaries,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43082003-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is paid to the plan and is distributed in cash to participants in the plan or their beneficiaries not later than 90 days after the close of the plan year in which paid,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43082004-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> is, at the election of such participants or their beneficiaries—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43082005-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/A/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> payable as provided in clause (i) or (ii), or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43082006-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/A/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> paid to the plan and reinvested in qualifying employer securities, or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43082007-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> is used to make payments on a loan described in subsection (a)(9) the proceeds of which were used to acquire the employer securities (whether or not allocated to participants) with respect to which the dividend is paid.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082008-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on certain dividends</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A dividend described in subparagraph (A)(iv) which is paid with respect to any employer security which is allocated to a participant shall not be treated as an applicable dividend unless the plan provides that employer securities with a fair market value of not less than the amount of such dividend are allocated to such participant for the year which (but for subparagraph (A)) such dividend would have been allocated to such participant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082009-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable employer securities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “applicable employer securities” means, with respect to any dividend, employer securities which are held on the record date for such dividend by an employee stock ownership plan which is maintained by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4308200a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the corporation paying such dividend, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4308200b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any other corporation which is a member of a controlled group of corporations (within the meaning of section 409(<i>l</i>)(4)) which includes such corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4308200c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for deduction</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4308200d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The deduction under paragraph (1) shall be allowable in the taxable year of the corporation in which the dividend is paid or distributed to a participant or his beneficiary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4308200e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reinvestment dividends</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), an applicable dividend reinvested pursuant to clause (iii)(II) of paragraph (2)(A) shall be treated as paid in the taxable year of the corporation in which such dividend is reinvested in qualifying employer securities or in which the election under clause (iii) of paragraph (2)(A) is made, whichever is later.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4308200f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Repayment of loans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of an applicable dividend described in clause (iv) of paragraph (2)(A), the deduction under paragraph (1) shall be allowable in the taxable year of the corporation in which such dividend is used to repay the loan described in such clause.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082010-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Other rules</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082011-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Disallowance of deduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may disallow the deduction under paragraph (1) for any dividend if the Secretary determines that such dividend constitutes, in substance, an avoidance or evasion of taxation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082012-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan qualification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A plan shall not be treated as violating the requirements of section 401, 409, or 4975(e)(7), or as engaging in a prohibited transaction for purposes of section 4975(d)(3), merely by reason of any payment or distribution described in paragraph (2)(A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082013-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082014-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Employer securities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “employer securities” has the meaning given such term by section 409(<i>l</i>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082015-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Employee stock ownership plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “employee stock ownership plan” has the meaning given such term by section 4975(e)(7). Such term includes a tax credit employee stock ownership plan (as defined in section 409).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082016-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/k/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Full vesting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In accordance with section 411, an applicable dividend described in clause (iii)(II) of paragraph (2)(A) shall be subject to the requirements of section 411(a)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43082017-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on amount of annual compensation taken into account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of applying the limitations of this section, the amount of annual compensation of each employee taken into account under the plan for any year shall not exceed $200,000. The Secretary shall adjust the $200,000 amount at the same time, and by the same amount, as any adjustment under section 401(a)(17)(B). For purposes of clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subsection (a)(1)(A), and in computing the full funding limitation, any adjustment under the preceding sentence shall not be taken into account for any year before the year for which such adjustment first takes effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43082018-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for simple retirement accounts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082019-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/m/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Employer contributions to a simple retirement account shall be treated as if they are made to a plan subject to the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4308201a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/m/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4308201b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/m/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Deduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Contributions described in paragraph (1) shall be deductible in the taxable year of the employer with or within which the calendar year for which the contributions were made ends.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4308201c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/m/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributions after end of year</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, contributions shall be treated as made for a taxable year if they are made on account of the taxable year and are made not later than the time prescribed by law for filing the return for the taxable year (including extensions thereof).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4308201d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Elective deferrals not taken into account for purposes of deduction limits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Elective deferrals (as defined in section 402(g)(3)) shall not be subject to any limitation contained in paragraph (3), (7), or (9) of subsection (a) or paragraph (1)(C) of subsection (h) and such elective deferrals shall not be taken into account in applying any such limitation to any other contributions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4308201e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Deduction limit for single-employer plans</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(A)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4308201f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a defined benefit plan to which subsection (a)(1)(A) applies (other than a multiemployer plan), the amount determined under this subsection for any taxable year shall be equal to the greater of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43082020-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the sum of the amounts determined under paragraph (2) with respect to each plan year ending with or within the taxable year, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43082021-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the sum of the minimum required contributions under section 430 for such plan years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082022-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of amount</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082023-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount determined under this paragraph for any plan year shall be equal to the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43082024-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43082025-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the funding target for the plan year,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43082026-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the target normal cost for the plan year, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43082027-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the cushion amount for the plan year, over</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43082028-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the value (determined under section 430(g)(3)) of the assets of the plan which are held by the plan as of the valuation date for the plan year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082029-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain employers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If section 430(i) does not apply to a plan for a plan year, the amount determined under subparagraph (A)(i) for the plan year shall in no event be less than the sum of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4308202a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the funding target for the plan year (determined as if section 430(i) applied to the plan), plus</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4308202b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the target normal cost for the plan year (as so determined).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4308202c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Cushion amount</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (2)(A)(i)(III)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4308202d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The cushion amount for any plan year is the sum of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4308202e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 50 percent of the funding target for the plan year, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4308202f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the amount by which the funding target for the plan year would increase if the plan were to take into account—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43082030-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> increases in compensation which are expected to occur in succeeding plan years, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43082031-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if the plan does not base benefits for service to date on compensation, increases in benefits which are expected to occur in succeeding plan years (determined on the basis of the average annual increase in benefits over the 6 immediately preceding plan years).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082032-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43082033-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In making the computation under subparagraph (A)(ii), the plan’s actuary shall assume that the limitations under subsection (<i>l</i>) and section 415(b) shall apply.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43082034-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/3/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Expected increases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of a plan year during which a plan is covered under section 4021 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, the plan’s actuary may, notwithstanding subsection (<i>l</i>), take into account increases in the limitations which are expected to occur in succeeding plan years.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082035-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for plans with 100 or fewer participants</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082036-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of determining the amount under paragraph (3) for any plan year, in the case of a plan which has 100 or fewer participants for the plan year, the liability of the plan attributable to benefit increases for highly compensated employees (as defined in section 414(q)) resulting from a plan amendment which is made or becomes effective, whichever is later, within the last 2 years shall not be taken into account in determining the target liability.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43082037-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule for determining number of participants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of determining the number of plan participants, all defined benefit plans maintained by the same employer (or any member of such employer’s controlled group (within the meaning of section 412(d)(3)) shall be treated as one plan, but only participants of such member or employer shall be taken into account.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082038-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for terminating plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a plan which, subject to section 4041 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, terminates during the plan year, the amount determined under paragraph (2) shall in no event be less than the amount required to make the plan sufficient for benefit liabilities (within the meaning of section 4041(d) of such Act).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43082039-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Actuarial assumptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any computation under this subsection for any plan year shall use the same actuarial assumptions which are used for the plan year under section 430 (determined by not taking into account any adjustment under clause (iv) of subsection (h)(2)(C) thereof).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4308203a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any term used in this subsection which is also used in section 430 shall have the same meaning given such term by section 430.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4308203b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s404/o/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> CSEC plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Solely for purposes of this subsection, a CSEC plan shall be treated as though section 430 applied to such plan and the minimum required contribution for any plan year shall be the amount described in section 412(a)(2)(D).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4308203c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/138">68A Stat. 138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/tI/s24">Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 24</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1623">72 Stat. 1623</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/792/s3">Pub. L. 87–792, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-10-10">Oct. 10, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/819">76 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/863/s2/b">Pub. L. 87–863, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1141">76 Stat. 1141</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tII/s204/a">Pub. L. 89–809, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, (b)(2), (3), <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1577">80 Stat. 1577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tIII/s321/b/3">Pub. L. 91–172, title III, § 321(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/591">83 Stat. 591</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tII">Pub. L. 93–406, title II</ref>, §§ 1013(c), 1016(a)(3), 2001(a), (g)(2)(E), (F), 2004(b), (c)(1), 2007(a), (b), title IV, § 4401(a), formerly § 4081(a), <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/921">88 Stat. 921</ref>, 929, 952, 957, 986, 993, 994, 1033, renumbered § 4401(a), <ref href="/us/pl/96/364/tI/s108/a">Pub. L. 96–364, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1267">94 Stat. 1267</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/267/s1/c/3">Pub. L. 94–267, § 1(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-04-15">Apr. 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/367">90 Stat. 367</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXV/s1502/a/2">Pub. L. 94–455, title XV, § 1502(a)(2)</ref>, title XIX, §§ 1901(a)(59), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1737">90 Stat. 1737</ref>, 1774, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tI">Pub. L. 95–600, title I</ref>, §§ 133(a), (b), 141(f)(9), 152(f), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2783">92 Stat. 2783</ref>, 2795, 2799; <ref href="/us/pl/96/222/tI/s101/a/10/E">Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 101(a)(10)(E)</ref>, (J)(ii), <date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/202">94 Stat. 202</ref>, 204; <ref href="/us/pl/96/364/tII/s205">Pub. L. 96–364, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1287">94 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tIII">Pub. L. 97–34, title III</ref>, §§ 312(a), 331(b), 333(a), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/283">95 Stat. 283</ref>, 293, 296; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tII">Pub. L. 97–248, title II</ref>, §§ 235(f), 237(e)(2), 238(a), 253(b), <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/507">96 Stat. 507</ref>, 512, 533; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV/s474/r/14">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 474(r)(14)</ref>, title V, §§ 512(a), 542(a), title VII, § 713(b)(3), (d)(4)(A), (5), (6), (9), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/842">98 Stat. 842</ref>, 862, 890, 957, 958; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXI/s11011/c/1">Pub. L. 99–272, title XI, § 11011(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/257">100 Stat. 257</ref>, 258; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXI">Pub. L. 99–514, title XI</ref>, §§ 1106(d)(2), 1108(c), 1112(d)(2), 1131(a), (b), 1136(b), 1171(b)(6), 1173(a), title XVIII, §§ 1848(c), 1851(b)(2)(A)–(C)(ii), 1854(b)(2)–(5), 1875(c)(7), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2424">100 Stat. 2424</ref>, 2433, 2445, 2476, 2477, 2486, 2513, 2515, 2857, 2863, 2878, 2895; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9307/c">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9307(c)</ref>, (d), title X, § 10201(b)(2), (3), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-357">101 Stat. 1330–357</ref>, 1330–387; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI">Pub. L. 100–647, title I</ref>, §§ 1011(d)(1), (4), (f)(6), 1011A(e)(4), 1011B(h)(3), (6), 1018(t)(4)(A), (5), title II, § 2005(b), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3459">102 Stat. 3459</ref>, 3463, 3478, 3491, 3492, 3588, 3589, 3610; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII</ref>, §§ 7302(a), 7841(b)(1), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2351">103 Stat. 2351</ref>, 2428; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11812/b/7">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11812(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-535">104 Stat. 1388–535</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/tV/s522/a/2">Pub. L. 102–318, title V, § 522(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-03">July 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/314">106 Stat. 314</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/tXIII/s13212/c/1">Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13212(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/472">107 Stat. 472</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tVII/s751/a/11">Pub. L. 103–465, title VII, § 751(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/5022">108 Stat. 5022</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI">Pub. L. 104–188, title I</ref>, §§ 1316(d)(1), (2), 1421(b)(2), 1431(b)(3), 1461(b), 1704(q)(1), (t)(76), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1786">110 Stat. 1786</ref>, 1795, 1803, 1823, 1887, 1891; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXV/s1530/c/2">Pub. L. 105–34, title XV, § 1530(c)(2)</ref>, title XVI, § 1601(d)(2)(C), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1078">111 Stat. 1078</ref>, 1088; <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tVI/s6015/d">Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6015(d)</ref>, title VII, § 7001(a), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/821">112 Stat. 821</ref>, 827; <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/tVI">Pub. L. 107–16, title VI</ref>, §§ 611(c)(1), 614(a), 616(a)–(b)(2)(A), 632(a)(3)(B), 652(a), 662(a), (b), <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/97">115 Stat. 97</ref>, 102, 103, 114, 129, 142; <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 107–147, title IV, § 411</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), (2), (4), (s), (w), <date date="2002-03-09">Mar. 9, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/47">116 Stat. 47</ref>, 51, 52; <ref href="/us/pl/108/218/tI/s101/b/5">Pub. L. 108–218, title I, § 101(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="2004-04-10">Apr. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/598">118 Stat. 598</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tVIII">Pub. L. 109–280, title VIII</ref>, §§ 801(a)–(c)(3), (d), 802(a), 803(a), (b), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/992-996">120 Stat. 992–996</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/245/tI/s104/c/1">Pub. L. 110–245, title I, § 104(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-17">June 17, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1627">122 Stat. 1627</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/tI/s108/a">Pub. L. 110–458, title I, § 108(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/5108">122 Stat. 5108</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dD/tII/s40211/a/2/A">Pub. L. 112–141, div. D, title II, § 40211(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/847">126 Stat. 847</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/97/tII/s202/c/6">Pub. L. 113–97, title II, § 202(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2014-04-07">Apr. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1136">128 Stat. 1136</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4308203d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id4308203e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Inflation Adjusted Items for Certain Years</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For inflation adjustment of certain items in this section, see Internal Revenue Notices listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4308203f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id43082040-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(C), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Title II of the Social Security Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 401 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 401(a)(17), referred to in subsec. (a)(2), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tII/s237/b">Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 237(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/511">96 Stat. 511</ref>. A new section 401(a)(17) was added by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXI/s1106/d/1">Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1106(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2423">100 Stat. 2423</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (a)(3)(A)(v)(II), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, which was approved <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(D)(iv), (7)(C)(iv), (g)(1), (3)(B), (C), (4), and (<i>o</i>)(3)(B)(ii), (5), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/829">88 Stat. 829</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 18 (§ 1001 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. Part 1 of subtitle E of title IV of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 is classified generally to part 1 (§ 1381 et seq.) of subtitle E of subchapter III of chapter 18 of Title 29. Sections 4021, 4022, 4041, 4062, 4063, and 4064 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 are classified to sections 1321, 1322, 1341, 1362, 1363, and 1364, respectively, of Title 29. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Retirement Protection Act of 1994, referred to in subsec. (g)(4), is the date of enactment of subtitle F (§§ 750–781) of title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, which was approved <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id43082041-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/113/97">Pub. L. 113–97</ref> added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/112/141">Pub. L. 112–141</ref> inserted “(determined by not taking into account any adjustment under clause (iv) of subsection (h)(2)(C) thereof)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(1)(D)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s108/b">Pub. L. 110–458, § 108(b)</ref>, substituted “431(c)(6)(D)” for “431(c)(6)(C)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/245">Pub. L. 110–245</ref> substituted “(31), and (37)” for “and (31)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s108/a/2">Pub. L. 110–458, § 108(a)(2)</ref>, in concluding provisions, substituted “the excess (if any) of the plan’s funding target (as defined in section 430(d)(1)) over the value of the plan’s assets (as determined under section 430(g)(3))” for “the plan’s funding shortfall determined under section 430” in last sentence and struck out second sentence which read as follows: “For purposes of clause (ii), if paragraph (1)(D) applies to a defined benefit plan for any plan year, the amount necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standard provided by section 412 with respect to such plan for such plan year shall not be less than the unfunded current liability of such plan under section 412(<i>l</i>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s108/c">Pub. L. 110–458, § 108(c)</ref>, amended cl. (iii) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In the case of employer contributions to 1 or more defined contribution plans, this paragraph shall only apply to the extent that such contributions exceed 6 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to the beneficiaries under such plans. For purposes of this clause, amounts carried over from preceding taxable years under subparagraph (B) shall be treated as employer contributions to 1 or more defined contributions to the extent attributable to employer contributions to such plans in such preceding taxable years.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(2)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s108/a/1/A">Pub. L. 110–458, § 108(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “430(g)(3)” for “430(g)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s108/a/1/B">Pub. L. 110–458, § 108(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “412(d)(3)” for “412(f)(4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/a/1">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, (c)(1), inserted “in the case of a defined benefit plan other than a multiemployer plan, in an amount determined under subsection (<i>o</i>), and in the case of any other plan” after “section 501(a),” in introductory provisions and substituted “431” for “412” in two places in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/c/2">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(c)(2)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “In the case of a multiemployer plan” for “In the case of a plan”, “431(c)(6)” for “412(c)(7)”, “431(c)(6)(A)(ii)” for “412(c)(7)(B)”, “431(c)(6)(A)(i)” for “412(c)(7)(A)”, and “431” for “412”, and, in cl. (i), substituted “431(c)(6)” for “412(c)(7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s802/a">Pub. L. 109–280, § 802(a)</ref>, amended heading and text of subpar. (D) generally, substituting provisions relating to maximum amount deductible in the case of a defined benefit plan which is a multiemployer plan for provisions relating to maximum amount deductible in the case of any defined benefit plan and stating rule for plans with 100 or less participants, rule for determining number of participants, and rule for terminating plans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(D)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/d/1">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “section 412(<i>l</i>)(8)(A), except that section 412(<i>l</i>)(8)(A) shall be applied for purposes of this clause by substituting ‘150 percent (140 percent in the case of a multiemployer plan) of current liability’ for ‘the current liability’ in clause (i).” for “section 412(<i>l</i>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/d/2">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(d)(2)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subpar. (F). Text read as follows: “An employer may elect to disregard subsections (b)(5)(B)(ii)(II) and (<i>l</i>)(7)(C)(i)(IV) of section 412 solely for purposes of determining the interest rate used in calculating the maximum amount of the deduction allowable under this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/c/3/A">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(c)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted at end “In the case of a defined benefit plan which is a single employer plan, the amount necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standard provided by section 412 shall not be less than the plan’s funding shortfall determined under section 430.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s803/a">Pub. L. 109–280, § 803(a)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(C)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/b">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(b)</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(C)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s803/b">Pub. L. 109–280, § 803(b)</ref>, added cl. (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/c/3/B">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(c)(3)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D) and struck out heading and text of former subpar. (D). Former text read as follows: “For purposes of this paragraph, any plan described in section 412(i) shall be treated as a defined benefit plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s801/a/2">Pub. L. 109–280, § 801(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/108/218">Pub. L. 108–218</ref> added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1)(D)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411/s">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411(s)</ref>, substituted “Special rule for terminating plans” for “Plans maintained by professional service employers” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411</ref>(<i>l</i>)(4), reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “This paragraph shall not have the effect of reducing the amount otherwise deductible under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), if no employee is a beneficiary under more than 1 trust or under a trust and an annuity plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), substituted “(9) and subsection (h)(1)(C),” for “(9),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411/w/1/A">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411(w)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “during the taxable year” after “such corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411/w/1/B">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411(w)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “(A)(iv)” for “(A)(iii)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411/w/1/C">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411(w)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), substituted “clause (iv)” for “clause (iii)” in subpar. (B), added a new subpar. (B), and redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411/w/2">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411(w)(2)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411">Pub. L. 107–147, § 411</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2), substituted “subsection (a) or paragraph (1)(C) of subsection (h)” for “subsection (a),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s616/a/2/B/i">Pub. L. 107–16, § 616(a)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “(other than a trust to which paragraph (3) applies)” after “pension trust” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s652/a">Pub. L. 107–16, § 652(a)</ref>, reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In the case of any defined benefit plan (other than a multiemployer plan) which has more than 100 participants for the plan year, except as provided in regulations, the maximum amount deductible under the limitations of this paragraph shall not be less than the unfunded current liability determined under section 412(<i>l</i>). For purposes of determining whether a plan has more than 100 participants, all defined benefit plans maintained by the same employer (or any member of such employer’s controlled group (within the meaning of section 412(<i>l</i>)(8)(C))) shall be treated as 1 plan, but only employees of such member or employer shall be taken into account.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(i)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s616/a/1/A">Pub. L. 107–16, § 616(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “25 percent” for “15 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s616/a/2/A">Pub. L. 107–16, § 616(a)(2)(A)</ref>, amended cl. (v) generally, substituting present provisions for provisions which directed that the limitation of cl. (i) for any taxable year would be increased by the unused pre-87 limitation carryforwards and defined “unused pre-87 limitation carryforwards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s616/b/2/A">Pub. L. 107–16, § 616(b)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out at end “The term ‘compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to all employees’ shall include any amount with respect to which an election under section 415(c)(3)(C) is in effect, but only to the extent that any contribution with respect to such amount is nonforfeitable.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s632/a/3/B">Pub. L. 107–16, § 632(a)(3)(B)</ref>, struck out “, the exclusion allowance under section 403(b)(2),” after “deferrals under section 402(g)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s616/b/1">Pub. L. 107–16, § 616(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s616/a/1/B">Pub. L. 107–16, § 616(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “25 percent” for “15 percent” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s616/a/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 107–16, § 616(a)(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, (iii), substituted “certain trusts” for “stock bonus and profit-sharing trust” in heading and “trust subject to subsection (a)(3)(A)” for “stock bonus or profit-sharing trust” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2)(A)(iii), (iv). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s662/a">Pub. L. 107–16, § 662(a)</ref>, added cl. (iii) and redesignated former cl. (iii) as (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s662/b">Pub. L. 107–16, § 662(b)</ref>, inserted “avoidance or” before “evasion”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s611/c/1">Pub. L. 107–16, § 611(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “$200,000” for “$150,000” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s614/a">Pub. L. 107–16, § 614(a)</ref>, added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(9)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s6015/d">Pub. L. 105–206, § 6015(d)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (C), relating to qualified gratuitous transfers, as (D) and inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s7001/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 7001(a)</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1601/d/2/C/i">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1601(d)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “not in excess of the greater of—” and subcls. (I) and (II) for “not in excess of 15 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to the beneficiaries under the stock bonus or profit-sharing plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1601/d/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1601(d)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, substituted “the amount described in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i), whichever is greater, with respect to such taxable year.” for “15 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during such taxable year to the beneficiaries under the plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1530/c/2">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1530(c)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C) relating to qualified gratuitous transfers.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1704/t/76">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1704(t)(76)</ref>, struck out “(18),” after “(17),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1316/d/1">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1316(d)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (C) relating to S corporations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1461/b">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1461(b)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1704/q/1">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1704(q)(1)</ref>, substituted “(9)” for “(10)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1316/d/2">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1316(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “a C corporation” for “a corporation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1431/b/3">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1431(b)(3)</ref>, struck out at end “In determining the compensation of an employee, the rules of section 414(q)(6) shall apply, except that in applying such rules, the term ‘family’ shall include only the spouse of the employee and any lineal descendants of the employee who have not attained age 19 before the close of the year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1421/b/2">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1421(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (g)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> substituted “the Retirement Protection Act of 1994” for “the Single-Employer Pension Plan Amendments Act of 1986”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref> substituted “$150,000” for “$200,000” in first sentence and “The Secretary shall adjust the $150,000 amount at the same time, and by the same amount, as any adjustment under section 401(a)(17)(B).” for “The Secretary shall adjust the $200,000 amount at the same time and in the same manner as under section 415(d).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/318">Pub. L. 102–318</ref> substituted “(27), and (31)” for “and (27)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> substituted “section 168(i)(10)(C)” for “section 167(<i>l</i>)(3)(A)(iii)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7841/b/1">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7841(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “4041(b),” after “under section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7302/a">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7302(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (k) generally, substituting “Deduction for dividends paid on certain employer securities” for “Dividends paid deductions” in heading and pars. (1) to (6) for former pars. (1) and (2) and concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s2005/b/3">Pub. L. 100–647, § 2005(b)(3)</ref>, struck out “(without regard to any reduction by the credit balance in the funding standard account)” after “under section 412(<i>l</i>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s2005/b/1">Pub. L. 100–647, § 2005(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “For purposes of determining whether a plan has more than 100 participants” for “For purposes of this subparagraph”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s2005/b/2">Pub. L. 100–647, § 2005(b)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “For purposes of clause (ii), if paragraph (1)(D) applies to a defined benefit plan for any plan year, the amount necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standard provided by section 412 with respect to such plan for such plan year shall not be less than the unfunded current liability of such plan under section 412(<i>l</i>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011A/e/4/A">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011A(e)(4)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “foregoing paragraphs” for “foregoing provisions” and inserted “or in connection with trusts or plans described in 2 or more of such paragraphs” after “defined benefit plans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/t/5">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(t)(5)</ref>, made technical correction to <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1875/c/7/B">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1875(c)(7)(B)</ref>, see 1986 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011/f/6">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011(f)(6)</ref>, inserted “(or during the taxable year in the case of a taxable year described in subparagraph (A)(ii))” after “within the taxable year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011A/e/4/B">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011A(e)(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “Coordination with subsection (a)(7)” for “Effect on limit on deductions” in heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “For any taxable year for which the employer has a deduction under paragraph (1), the otherwise applicable 25 percent limitations in subsection (a)(7) shall be reduced by the amount of the allowable deductions under paragraph (1) with respect to participants in the stock bonus or profit-sharing trust.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011B/h/3/A">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011B(h)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “(whether or not allocated to participants)” after “to employer securities” in par. (2)(C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011B/h/6">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011B(h)(6)</ref>, substituted “or as engaging in a prohibited transaction for purposes of section 4975(d)(3) merely by reason of any distribution or payment” for “merely by reason of any distribution” in third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/t/4/A">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(t)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “evasion of taxation” for “avoidance of taxation” in fourth sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011B/h/3/B">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011B(h)(3)(B)</ref>, inserted at end “Paragraph (2)(C) shall not apply to dividends from employer securities which are allocated to any participant unless the plan provides that employer securities with a fair market value not less than the amount of such dividends are allocated to such participant for the year which (but for paragraph (2)(C)) such dividends would have been allocated to such participant.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011/d/4">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011(d)(4)</ref>, inserted at end “In determining the compensation of an employee, the rules of section 414(q)(6) shall apply, except that in applying such rules, the term ‘family’ shall include only the spouse of the employee and any lineal descendants of the employee who have not attained age 19 before the close of the year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011/d/1">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011(d)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “For purposes of clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subsection (a)(1)(A), and in computing the full funding limitation, any adjustment under the preceding sentence shall not be taken into account for any year before the year for which such adjustment first takes effect.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(1)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s9307/d">Pub. L. 100–203, § 9307(d)</ref>, inserted “the unfunded costs attributable to” after “to amortize”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(D), (E). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s9307/c">Pub. L. 100–203, § 9307(c)</ref>, added subpar. (D) and redesignated former subpar. (D) as (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10201/b/3">Pub. L. 100–203, § 10201(b)(3)</ref>, inserted at end “For purposes of this section, any vacation pay which is treated as deferred compensation shall be deductible for the taxable year of the employer in which paid to the employee.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10201/b/2">Pub. L. 100–203, § 10201(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Exception” for “Exception for certain benefits” in heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) any benefit provided through a welfare benefit fund (as defined in section 419(e)), or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) any benefit with respect to which an election under section 463 applies.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1851/b/2/C/i">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1851(b)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “this chapter; but, if they would otherwise be deductible” for “section 162 (relating to trade or business expenses) or section 212 (relating to expenses for the production of income); but, if they satisfy the conditions of either of such sections”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1136/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1136(b)</ref>, substituted “(26), and (27)” for “and (26)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1112/d/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1112(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “(22), and (26)” for “and (22)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1131/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1131(a)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally, revising and restating as cls. (i) to (v) provisions formerly contained in single paragraph.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1131/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1131(b)</ref>, amended par. (7) generally, revising and restating as subpars. (A) to (C) provisions formerly contained in single paragraph, and adding subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1875/c/7/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1875(c)(7)(A)</ref>, inserted “(determined without regard to the deductions allowed by this section)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1875/c/7/B">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1875(c)(7)(B)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/t/5">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(t)(5)</ref>, struck out “(determined without regard to the deductions allowed by this section)” after “earned income of such individual”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1848/c">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1848(c)</ref>, substituted “the deduction allowed by this section” for “the deductions allowed by this section and section 405(c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1851/b/2/B/i">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1851(b)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “certain” for “unfunded” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1851/b/2/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1851(b)(2)(A)</ref>, (B)(ii), substituted “certain” for “unfunded” in heading, and in subpar. (B)(ii), substituted “any benefit” for “to any benefit”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1851/b/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1851(b)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, substituted “under this chapter” for “under section 162 or 212” in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s11011/c/1">Pub. L. 99–272, § 11011(c)(1)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to the amendment, par. (3), coordination with subsection (a), read as follows: “Any payment described in paragraph (1) shall (subject to the last sentence of subsection (a)(1)(A)) be deductible under this section when paid.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s11011/c/2">Pub. L. 99–272, § 11011(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1108/c">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1108(c)</ref>, amended subpars. (A) and (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpars. (A) and (B) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) Contributions made for a calendar year are deductible for the taxable year with which or within which the calendar year ends.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) Contributions made within 3½ months after the close of a calendar year are treated as if they were made on the last day of such calendar year if they are made on account of such calendar year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1171/b/6">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1171(b)(6)</ref>, struck out subsec. (i) relating to the deductibility of unused portions of employee stock ownership credit.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1854/b/2/B">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1854(b)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out “during the taxable year” after “cash by such corporation” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1854/b/4">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1854(b)(4)</ref>, inserted “The Secretary may disallow the deduction under this subsection for any dividend if the Secretary determines that such dividend constitutes, in substance, an avoidance of taxation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1854/b/3">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1854(b)(3)</ref>, inserted “A plan to which this subsection applies shall not be treated as violating the requirements of section 401, 409, or 4975(e)(7) merely by reason of any distribution described in paragraph (2).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1854/b/2/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1854(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “Any deduction under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) shall be allowed in the taxable year of the corporation in which the dividend is paid or distributed to the participant under paragraph (2).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1173/a/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1173(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “Any deduction under paragraph (2)(C) shall be allowable in the taxable year of the corporation in which the dividend is used to repay the loan described in such paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1854/b/5">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1854(b)(5)</ref>, inserted “or their beneficiaries”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1173/a/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1173(a)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1106/d/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1106(d)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(8)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s713/d/6">Pub. L. 98–369, § 713(d)(6)</ref>, inserted “(determined without regard to the deductions allowed by this section and section 405(c))”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9), (10). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s713/d/4/A">Pub. L. 98–369, § 713(d)(4)(A)</ref>, struck out par. (9) relating to plans benefiting self-employed individuals and redesignated par. (10) as (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s512/a">Pub. L. 98–369, § 512(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally, inserting heading, redesignating former heading as par. (1) heading, designating existing provisions as par. (1), and in par. (1) as so designated, inserted “(including a plan described in paragraph (2))” after “compensation” and adding par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s713/d/9">Pub. L. 98–369, § 713(d)(9)</ref>, substituted “under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a)” for “under this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s713/b/3">Pub. L. 98–369, § 713(b)(3)</ref>, repealed subsec. (f) which related to certain loan repayments considered as contributions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s713/d/5">Pub. L. 98–369, § 713(d)(5)</ref>, repealed par. (4) which related to effect on self-employed individuals or shareholder-employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s474/r/14">Pub. L. 98–369, § 474(r)(14)</ref>, in par. (1), substituted “If any portion of the employee stock ownership credit determined under section 41 for any taxable year has not, after the application of section 38(c), been allowed under section 38 for any taxable year, such portion shall be allowed as a deduction (without regard to any limitations provided under this section) for the last taxable year to which such portion could have been allowed as a credit under section 39” for “There shall be allowed as a deduction (without regard to any limitations provided under this section) for the last taxable year to which an unused employee stock ownership credit carryover (within the meaning of section 44G(b)(2)(A)) may be carried, an amount equal to the portion of such unused credit carryover which expires at the close of such taxable year”, and in par. (2), substituted references to section 41 and 41(c)(3) for references to section 44G and 44G(c)(3), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s542/a">Pub. L. 98–369, § 542(a)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s237/e/2">Pub. L. 97–248, § 237(e)(2)</ref>, substituted “(8), (9)” for “(8)”, and “401(a)(10) and of section 401(d)” for “401(a)(9), (10), (17), and (18) and of section 401(d) (other than paragraph (1))”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s253/b">Pub. L. 97–248, § 253(b)</ref>, inserted provision that “compensation otherwise paid or accrued during the taxable year to all employees” shall include any amount with respect to which an election under section 415(c)(3)(C) is in effect, but only to the extent that any contribution with respect to such amount is nonforfeitable.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s238/a">Pub. L. 97–248, § 238(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally, substituting provisions relating to contributions allocable to life insurance protection for self-employed individuals, for provisions relating to general requirements, contributions made under more than one plan, contributions allocable to insurance protection, and limitations of not lower than $750 or 100 percent of earned income with respect to special limitations for self-employed individuals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s235/f">Pub. L. 97–248, § 235(f)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s333/a">Pub. L. 97–34, § 333(a)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s312/a">Pub. L. 97–34, § 312(a)</ref>, substituted in pars. (1) and (2)(A) “$15,000” for “$7,500”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s331/b">Pub. L. 97–34, § 331(b)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/364">Pub. L. 96–364</ref> redesignated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted applicability to part 1 of subtitle E of title IV of Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/222">Pub. L. 96–222</ref> inserted “or shareholder employees” after “individuals” in heading, and in par. (4) “or described in section 1379(b)(1)” after “of subsection (e)” and “or a shareholder-employee (as defined in section 1379(d))” after “section 401(c)(1)” and substituted in pars. (2) to (4) “paragraph (1)” for “subparagraph (1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s141/f/9">Pub. L. 95–600, § 141(f)(9)</ref>, substituted “(20), and (22)” for “and (20)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s133/b">Pub. L. 95–600, § 133(b)</ref>, substituted “other plan” for “similar plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s133/a">Pub. L. 95–600, § 133(a)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s152/f">Pub. L. 95–600, § 152(f)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(1)(B), (8)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/267">Pub. L. 94–267</ref> substituted “(19), and (20)” for “and (19)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/59">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(59)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which related to the taxability of the beneficiary under certain forfeitable contracts purchased by exempt organizations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(B), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1502/a/2">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1502(a)(2)</ref>, inserted provisions following subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1013/c/1">Pub. L. 93–406, § 1013(c)(1)</ref>, expanded subpars. (A), (B), and (C) to accommodate the increased minimum funding standards required by section 412.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, §§ 1016(a)(3), 2001(g)(2)(E), 2004(c)(1), inserted references to the requirements of section 401(a)(11), (12), (13), (14), (15), (16), (17), (18), and (19), and, if applicable, the requirements of section 401(a)(17) and (18).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2004/b">Pub. L. 93–406, § 2004(b)</ref>, inserted “, but the amount so deductible under this sentence in any one succeeding taxable year together with the amount so deductible under the first sentence of this subparagraph shall not exceed 25 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during such taxable year to the beneficiaries under the plan” after “If in any taxable year there is paid into the trust, or a similar trust then in effect, amounts less than the amounts deductible under the preceding sentence, the excess, or if no amount is paid, the amounts deductible, shall be carried forward and be deductible when paid in the succeeding taxable years in order of time, but the amount so deductible under this sentence in any such succeeding taxable year shall not exceed 15 percent of the compensation otherwise paid or accrued during such succeeding taxable year to the beneficiaries under the plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1013/c/2">Pub. L. 93–406, § 1013(c)(2)</ref>, substituted provisions covering only taxpayers operating on the accrual basis for provisions covering the time when contributions shall be deemed made.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1013/c/3">Pub. L. 93–406, § 1013(c)(3)</ref>, inserted reference to the amount of contributions made to or under the trusts or plans to the extent such contributions do not exceed the amount of employer contributions necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standards provided by section 412 for the plan year which ends with or within such taxable year (or for any prior plan year) and substituted “25 percent” for “30 percent” in provision covering amounts paid into trusts or under an annuity plan in any taxable year in excess of the amount allowable with respect to such year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2001/g/2/F">Pub. L. 93–406, § 2001(g)(2)(F)</ref>, substituted “the second sentence of paragraph (3)” for “paragraph (1)(D), the second and third sentences of paragraph (3), and the second sentence of paragraph (7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2008/a">Pub. L. 93–406, § 2008(a)</ref>, (b), substituted “or pensions” for “and pensions” in par. (1), substituted “The first and third sentences of this subsection” for “This subsection” in provisions covering amounts contributed to a trust on or after any date on which such trust is qualified for exemption from tax under section 501(a), inserted provisions setting out specified treatment to be accorded individuals who before <date date="1974-07-01">July 1, 1974</date>, were participants in plans described in the subsections, and inserted provision that section 277 (relating to deductions incurred by certain membership organizations in transactions with members) does not apply to any trust described in the subsection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2001/a/1">Pub. L. 93–406, § 2001(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “subject to paragraphs (2) and (4), not exceed $7,500, or 15 percent” for “subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), not exceed $2,500, or 10 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2001/a/2">Pub. L. 93–406, § 2001(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “shall (subject to paragraph (4)) not exceed $7,500, or 15 percent” for “shall not exceed $2,500 or 10 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2001/a/3">Pub. L. 93–406, § 2001(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s4081/a">Pub. L. 93–406, § 4081(a)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> substituted “If the plan is not one included in paragraph (1), (2), or (3), in the taxable year in which an amount attributable to the contribution is includible in the gross income of employees participating in the plan, but, in the case of a plan in which more than one employee participates only if separate accounts are maintained for each employee” for “In the taxable year when paid, if the plan is not one included in paragraph (1), (2), or (3), if the employees’ rights to or derived from such employer’s contribution or such compensation are nonforfeitable at the time the contribution or compensation is paid”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s204/a">Pub. L. 89–809, § 204(a)</ref>, repealed par. (10) which provided for a special limitation on the amount allowed as a deduction for self-employed individuals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s204/b/2">Pub. L. 89–809, § 204(b)(2)</ref>, (3), struck out references to par. (10) of subsec. (a) wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/87/863">Pub. L. 87–863</ref> inserted “, or retirement annuities and medical benefits as described in section 401(h),” after “purchase of retirement annuities”, and “, or such retirement annuities and medical benefits” after “such retirement annuities.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/87/792/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 87–792, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “(5), (6), (7), and (8), and, if applicable, the requirements of section 401(a)(9) and (10) and of section 401(d) (other than paragraph (1)),” for “(5), and (6),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8) to (10). <ref href="/us/pl/87/792/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 87–792, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, added pars. (8) to (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/87/792/s3/b">Pub. L. 87–792, § 3(b)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/85/866">Pub. L. 85–866</ref> substituted “income); but, if” for “income) but if” preceding par. (1).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id430a9142-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9143-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/97">Pub. L. 113–97</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="2013-12-31">Dec. 31, 2013</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/97/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 113–97</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9144-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/141/dD/tII/s40211/c">Pub. L. 112–141, div. D, title II, § 40211(c)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/850">126 Stat. 850</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/141/dD/tII/s40211/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section [amending this section, sections 417, 420 and 430 of this title, and sections 1021, 1055, 1083, 1306, and 1310 of Title 29, Labor, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1021">section 1021 of Title 29</ref>] shall apply with respect to plan years beginning after <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rules with respect to elections.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjusted funding target attainment percentage</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A plan sponsor may elect not to have the amendments made by this section apply to any plan year beginning before <date date="2013-01-01">January 1, 2013</date>, either (as specified in the election)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> for all purposes for which such amendments apply, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> solely for purposes of determining the adjusted funding target attainment percentage under sections 436 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and 206(g) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1056/g">29 U.S.C. 1056(g)</ref>] for such plan year.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">A plan shall not be treated as failing to meet the requirements of sections 204(g) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1054/g">29 U.S.C. 1054(g)</ref>] and 411(d)(6) of such Code solely by reason of an election under this paragraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Opt out of existing elections</inline>.—</heading><content>If, on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>], an election is in effect with respect to any plan under sections 303(h)((2)(D)(ii) [sic] of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1083/h/2/D/ii">29 U.S.C. 1083(h)(2)(D)(ii)</ref>] and 430(h)((2)(D)(ii) [sic] of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, then, notwithstanding the last sentence of each such section, the plan sponsor may revoke such election without the consent of the Secretary of the Treasury. The plan sponsor may make such revocation at any time before the date which is 1 year after such date of enactment and such revocation shall be effective for the 1st plan year to which the amendments made by this section apply and all subsequent plan years. Nothing in this subparagraph shall preclude a plan sponsor from making a subsequent election in accordance with such sections.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9145-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/458">Pub. L. 110–458</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref> to which the amendment relates, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/458/s112">section 112 of Pub. L. 110–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/245">Pub. L. 110–245</ref> applicable with respect to deaths and disabilities occurring on or after <date date="2007-01-01">Jan. 1, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/245/s104/d/1">section 104(d)(1) of Pub. L. 110–245</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9146-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tVIII/s801/e">Pub. L. 109–280, title VIII, § 801(e)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/995">120 Stat. 995</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/280/tVIII/s801/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s404A">section 404A of this title</ref>] shall apply to years beginning after <date date="2007-12-31">December 31, 2007</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rules</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by subsection (d) [amending this section] shall apply to years beginning after <date date="2005-12-31">December 31, 2005</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tVIII/s802/b">Pub. L. 109–280, title VIII, § 802(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/996">120 Stat. 996</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/280/tVIII/s802/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to years beginning after <date date="2007-12-31">December 31, 2007</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tVIII/s803/d">Pub. L. 109–280, title VIII, § 803(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/996">120 Stat. 996</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/280/tVIII/s803/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4972">section 4972 of this title</ref>] shall apply to contributions for taxable years beginning after <date date="2005-12-31">December 31, 2005</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9147-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/218/tI/s101/d">Pub. L. 108–218, title I, § 101(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-04-10">Apr. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/599">118 Stat. 599</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/218/tI/s101/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the amendments made by this section [amending this section, sections 412 and 415 of this title, and sections 1082 and 1306 of Title 29, Labor] shall apply to plan years beginning after <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lookback rules</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of applying subsections (d)(9)(B)(ii) and (e)(1) of section 302 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1082/d/9/B/ii">29 U.S.C. 1082(d)(9)(B)(ii)</ref>, (e)(1)] and subsections (<i>l</i>)(9)(B)(ii) and (m)(1) of [former] section 412 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to plan years beginning after <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>, the amendments made by this section may be applied as if such amendments had been in effect for all prior plan years. The Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe simplified assumptions which may be used in applying the amendments made by this section to such prior plan years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition rule for section 415 limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of any participant or beneficiary receiving a distribution after <date date="2003-12-31">December 31, 2003</date>[,] and before <date date="2005-01-01">January 1, 2005</date>, the amount payable under any form of benefit subject to section 417(e)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and subject to adjustment under section 415(b)(2)(B) of such Code shall not, solely by reason of the amendment made by subsection (b)(4) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s415">section 415 of this title</ref>], be less than the amount that would have been so payable had the amount payable been determined using the applicable interest rate in effect as of the last day of the last plan year beginning before <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9148-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/147">Pub. L. 107–147</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001, <ref href="/us/pl/107/16">Pub. L. 107–16</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/147/s411/x">section 411(x) of Pub. L. 107–147</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s25B">section 25B of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9149-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s611/c/1">section 611(c)(1) of Pub. L. 107–16</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">Dec. 31, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s611/i/1">section 611(i)(1) of Pub. L. 107–16</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s415">section 415 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s614/b">Pub. L. 107–16, title VI, § 614(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/102">115 Stat. 102</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s614/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s616/c">Pub. L. 107–16, title VI, § 616(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/103">115 Stat. 103</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s616/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4972">section 4972 of this title</ref>] shall apply to years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s632/a/3/B">section 632(a)(3)(B) of Pub. L. 107–16</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">Dec. 31, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/16/s632/a/4">section 632(a)(4) of Pub. L. 107–16</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s652/c">Pub. L. 107–16, title VI, § 652(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/130">115 Stat. 130</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s652/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4972">section 4972 of this title</ref>] shall apply to plan years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s662/c">Pub. L. 107–16, title VI, § 662(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/142">115 Stat. 142</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s662/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2001-12-31">December 31, 2001</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a914a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s6015/d">section 6015(d) of Pub. L. 105–206</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provisions of the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997, <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s6024">section 6024 of Pub. L. 105–206</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tVII/s7001/b">Pub. L. 105–206, title VII, § 7001(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/827">112 Stat. 827</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/206/tVII/s7001/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Change in method of accounting</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of any taxpayer required by the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] to change its method of accounting for its first taxable year ending after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>]—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> such change shall be treated as initiated by the taxpayer,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such change shall be treated as made with the consent of the Secretary of the Treasury; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the net amount of the adjustments required to be taken into account by the taxpayer under section 481 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be taken into account ratably over the 3-taxable year period beginning with such first taxable year.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a914b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1530/c/2">section 1530(c)(2) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref> applicable to transfers made by trusts to, or for the use of, an employee stock ownership plan after <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1530/d">section 1530(d) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1601/d/2/C">section 1601(d)(2)(C) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of the Small Business Job Protection Act of 1996, <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, to which it relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1601/j">section 1601(j) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s23">section 23 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a914c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1316(d)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1997-12-31">Dec. 31, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1316/f">section 1316(f) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s170">section 170 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1421/b/2">section 1421(b)(2) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1996-12-31">Dec. 31, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1421/e">section 1421(e) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1431/b/3">section 1431(b)(3) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="1996-12-31">Dec. 31, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1431/d/2">section 1431(d)(2) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s414">section 414 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1461/c">Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1461(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1824">110 Stat. 1824</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1461/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1414">section 1414 of this title</ref>] shall apply to years beginning after <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1704/q/2">Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1704(q)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1887">110 Stat. 1887</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1704/q/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall take effect as if included in the amendments made by section 713(d)(4)(A) of the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 [<ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a914d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref> applicable, except as otherwise provided, to benefits accruing in plan years beginning after <date date="1993-12-31">Dec. 31, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s13212/d">section 13212(d) of Pub. L. 103–66</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a914e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/318">Pub. L. 102–318</ref> applicable, except as otherwise provided, to distributions after <date date="1992-12-31">Dec. 31, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/s522/d">section 522(d) of Pub. L. 102–318</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a914f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable to property placed in service after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, but not applicable to any property to which <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s168">section 168 of this title</ref> does not apply by reason of subsec. (f)(5) of section 168, and not applicable to rehabilitation expenditures described in <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s252/f/5">section 252(f)(5) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11812/c">section 11812(c) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s42">section 42 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9150-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7302/b">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7302(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2352">103 Stat. 2352</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7302/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to employer securities acquired after <date date="1989-08-04">August 4, 1989</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Securities acquired with certain loans</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amendment made by this section shall not apply to employer securities acquired after <date date="1989-08-04">August 4, 1989</date>, which are acquired—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> with the proceeds of any loan which was made pursuant to a binding written commitment in effect on <date date="1989-08-04">August 4, 1989</date>, and at all times thereafter before such loan is made, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> pursuant to a written binding contract (or tender offer registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission) in effect on <date date="1989-08-04">August 4, 1989</date>, and at all times thereafter before such securities are acquired.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7841/b/2">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7841(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2428">103 Stat. 2428</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7841/b/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to payments made after <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9151-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1011(d)(1), (4), (f)(6), 1011A(e)(4), 1011B(h)(3), (6), and 1018(t)(4)(A), (5) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tII/s2005/e">Pub. L. 100–647, title II, § 2005(e)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3612">102 Stat. 3612</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7812/d">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7812(d)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2412">103 Stat. 2412</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7812/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 412, 414, and 4972 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1082">section 1082 of Title 29</ref>, Labor] shall take effect as if included in the amendments made by the provisions of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987 [<ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>] to which it relates, except that the amendment made by subsection (a)(1) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4972">section 4972 of this title</ref>] shall take effect as if included in the amendment made by section 1131(c) of the Tax Reform Act of 1986 [<ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430a9152-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9307/f">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9307(f)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-359">101 Stat. 1330–359</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7881/d/3">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7881(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2439">103 Stat. 2439</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7881/d/3">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s412">section 412 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1082">section 1082 of Title 29</ref>, Labor] shall apply to years beginning after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amortization of gains and losses</inline>.—</heading><content>Sections 412(b)(2)(B)(iv) and 412(b)(3)(B)(ii) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and sections 302(b)(2)(B)(iv) and 302(b)(3)(B)(ii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1082/b/2/B/iv">29 U.S.C. 1082(b)(2)(B)(iv)</ref>, (3)(B)(ii)] (as amended by paragraphs (1)(A) and (2)(A) of subsection (a)) shall apply to gains and losses established in years beginning after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>. For purposes of the preceding sentence, any gain or loss determined by a valuation occurring as of <date date="1988-01-01">January 1, 1988</date>, shall be treated as established in years beginning before 1988, or at the election of the employer, shall be amortized in accordance with Internal Revenue Service Notice 89–52.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tX/s10201/c/1">Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10201(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-388">101 Stat. 1330–388</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/203/tX/s10201/c/1">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 419 and 461 of this title, and repealing sections 81 and 463 of this title] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d0253-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1106/d/2">section 1106(d)(2) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to benefits accruing in years beginning after <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1106/i/5">section 1106(i)(5) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s415">section 415 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1108/c">section 1108(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1108/h">section 1108(h) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s219">section 219 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1112/d/2">section 1112(d)(2) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to plan years beginning after <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, with special rule regarding collective bargaining agreements ratified before <date date="1986-03-01">Mar. 1, 1986</date>, and with provision for waiver of excise tax on reversions, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1112/e">section 1112(e) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXI/s1131/d">Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1131(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2478">100 Stat. 2478</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1011A/e/3">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1011A(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3478">102 Stat. 3478</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1011A/e/3">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4972">section 4972 of this title</ref> and amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rules for collective bargaining agreements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of a plan maintained pursuant to 1 or more collective bargaining agreements between employee representatives and 1 or more employers ratified before <date date="1986-03-01">March 1, 1986</date>, the amendments made by this section shall not apply to contributions pursuant to any such agreement for taxable years beginning before the earlier of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> <date date="1989-01-01">January 1, 1989</date>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the date on which the last of such collective bargaining agreements terminates (determined without regard to any extension thereof after <date date="1986-02-28">February 28, 1986</date>).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1171/b/6">section 1171(b)(6) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to compensation paid or accrued after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, but this <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s404/i">section 404(i) of this title</ref> to continue to apply with respect to credits under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s41">section 41 of this title</ref> attributable to compensation paid or accrued before <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date> (or under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s38">section 38 of this title</ref> with respect to qualified investment before <date date="1983-01-01">Jan. 1, 1983</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1171/c">section 1171(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXI/s1173/c/1">Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1173(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2516">100 Stat. 2516</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXI/s1173/c/1">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to dividends paid in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1848(c), 1851(b)(2)(A)–(C)(ii), and 1854(b)(3)–(5) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provisions of the Tax Reform Act of 1984, <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1881">section 1881 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s48">section 48 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1854/b/2">section 1854(b)(2) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> not applicable to dividends paid before <date date="1986-01-01">Jan. 1, 1986</date>, if the taxpayer treated such dividends in a manner inconsistent with such amendment on a return filed with the Secretary before <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1854/b/6">section 1854(b)(6) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1875/c/7/B">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1875(c)(7)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2895">100 Stat. 2895</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXI/s11011/c/3">Pub. L. 99–272, title XI, § 11011(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/258">100 Stat. 258</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/272/tXI/s11011/c/3">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall apply to payments made after <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d0254-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s474/r/14">section 474(r)(14) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, and to carrybacks from such years, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s475/a">section 475(a) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s21">section 21 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tV/s512/c">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title V, § 512(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/863">98 Stat. 863</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tV/s512/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s162">section 162 of this title</ref>] shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>] in taxable years ending after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for certain extended vacation pay plans</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of any extended vacation pay plan maintained pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> between employee representatives and 1 or more employers, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in effect on <date date="1984-06-22">June 22, 1984</date>,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the amendments made by this section shall not apply before the date on which such collective bargaining agreement terminates (determined without regard to any extension thereof agreed to after <date date="1984-06-22">June 22, 1984</date>). For purposes of the preceding sentence, any plan amendment made pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement relating to the plan which amends the plan solely to conform to any requirement added by this section shall not be treated as a termination of such collective bargaining agreement.”</continuation>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tV/s542/d">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title V, § 542(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/891">98 Stat. 891</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tV/s542/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 116 and 3405 of this title] shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s713">section 713 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s715">section 715 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d0255-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tII/s253/c">Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 253(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/533">96 Stat. 533</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/248/tII/s253/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s415">section 415 of this title</ref>] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1981-12-31">December 31, 1981</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s235/f">section 235(f) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, in the case of any plan which is not in existence on <date date="1982-07-01">July 1, 1982</date>, applicable to years ending after <date date="1982-07-01">July 1, 1982</date>, and in the case of any plan which is in existence on <date date="1982-07-01">July 1, 1982</date>, applicable to years beginning after <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s235/g/1">section 235(g)(1) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s415">section 415 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 237 and 238 of <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s241">section 241 of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s416">section 416 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d0256-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s312/a">section 312(a) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to plans which include employees within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401/c/1">section 401(c)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s312/f/1">section 312(f)(1) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tIII/s331/f/2">Pub. L. 97–34, title III, § 331(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/295">95 Stat. 295</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/34/tIII/s331/f/2">“The amendments made by subsections (b) and (c) [amending this section and sections 56, 409A, and 6699 of this title] shall apply to taxable years ending after <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d0257-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/364">Pub. L. 96–364</ref> effective <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/364/s210/a">section 210(a) of Pub. L. 96–364</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s194A">section 194A of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/222">Pub. L. 96–222</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if it had been included in the provisions of the Revenue Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/222/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 96–222</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s32">section 32 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d0258-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tI/s133/c">Pub. L. 95–600, title I, § 133(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2783">92 Stat. 2783</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/222/tI/s101/a/5">Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 101(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/196">94 Stat. 196</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to deductions for taxable years beginning after <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for certain title insurance companies.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><content>In the case of a qualified title insurance company plan, the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to deductions for taxable years beginning after <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified title insurance company plan.—</inline></heading><chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term ‘qualified title insurance company plan’ means a plan of a qualified title insurance company—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> which defers the payment of amounts credited by such company to separate accounts for members of such company in consideration of their issuance of policies of title insurance, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> under which no part of such amounts is payable to or withdrawable by the members until after the period for the adverse possession of real property under applicable State law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified title insurance company.—</inline></heading><chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (B), the term ‘qualified title insurance company’ means an unincorporated title insurance company organized as a business trust—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> which is engaged in the business of providing title insurance coverage on interests in and liens upon real property obtained by clients of the members of such company, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> which is subject to tax under section 831 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954].”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s141/f/9">section 141(f)(9) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref> effective with respect to qualified investment for taxable years beginning after <date date="1978-12-31">Dec. 31, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s141/g/1">section 141(g)(1) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s409">section 409 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s152/f">section 152(f) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1978-12-31">Dec. 31, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s152/h">section 152(h) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s408">section 408 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d0259-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1502/a/2">section 1502(a)(2) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1502/b">section 1502(b) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s415">section 415 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/59">section 1901(a)(59) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/d">section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/267">Pub. L. 94–267</ref> applicable with respect to payments made to an employee on or after <date date="1974-07-04">July 4, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/267/s1/e">section 1(e) of Pub. L. 94–267</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d025a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1013(c) and 1016(a)(3) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> applicable, except as otherwise provided in section 1017(c) through (i) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, for plan years beginning after <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, but, in the case of plans in existence on <date date="1974-01-01">Jan. 1, 1974</date>, amendment by sections 1013(c) and 1016(a)(3) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> applicable for plan years beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1017">section 1017 of Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Transitional Rules note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s410">section 410 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tII/s2001/i/1">Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 2001(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/957">88 Stat. 957</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/406/tII/s2001/i/1">“The amendments made by subsections (a) [amending this section] and (b) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1379">section 1379 of this title</ref>] apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1973-12-31">December 31, 1973</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 2001(g)(2)(E), (F) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> applicable to distributions made in taxable years beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2001/i/5">section 2001(i)(5) of Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s72">section 72 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tII/s2008/c">Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 2008(c)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/994">88 Stat. 994</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/406/tII/s2008/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years ending on or after <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 2004(b), (c)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s2004/d">section 2004(d) of Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Transition Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s415">section 415 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s4081/a">section 4081(a) of Pub. L. 93–406</ref> effective on <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, with exceptions specified in section 1461(b), (c) of Title 29, Labor, see <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1461/a">section 1461(a) of Title 29</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d025b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> applicable with respect to contributions made and premiums paid after <date date="1969-08-01">Aug. 1, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s321/d">section 321(d) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s83">section 83 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d025c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1967-12-31">Dec. 31, 1967</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s204/d">section 204(d) of Pub. L. 89–809</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d025d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/863">Pub. L. 87–863</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/863/s2/c">section 2(c) of Pub. L. 87–863</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/792">Pub. L. 87–792</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1962-12-31">Dec. 31, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/792/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 87–792</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s22">section 22 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id430d025e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/866">Pub. L. 85–866</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1953-12-31">Dec. 31, 1953</date>, and ending after <date date="1954-08-16">Aug. 16, 1954</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/s1/c/1">section 1(c)(1) of Pub. L. 85–866</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s165">section 165 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d025f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate to issue before <date date="1988-02-01">Feb. 1, 1988</date>, final regulations to carry out amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1112">section 1112 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1141">section 1141 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id430d0260-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11821/b">section 11821(b) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s45K">section 45K of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d0261-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Clarification of Treatment of Contributions to Multiemployer Plan</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s658">Pub. L. 107–16, title VI, § 658</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/137">115 Stat. 137</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/16/tVI/s658">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Not Considered Method of Accounting</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of section 446 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, a determination under section 404(a)(6) of such Code regarding the taxable year with respect to which a contribution to a multiemployer pension plan is deemed made shall not be treated as a method of accounting of the taxpayer. No deduction shall be allowed for any taxable year for any contribution to a multiemployer pension plan with respect to which a deduction was previously allowed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Treasury shall promulgate such regulations as necessary to clarify that a taxpayer shall not be allowed an aggregate amount of deductions for contributions to a multiemployer pension plan which exceeds the amount of such contributions made or deemed made under section 404(a)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to such plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a), and any regulations promulgated under subsection (b), shall be effective for years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d0262-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1998</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle D [§§ 1401–1465] of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> require an amendment to any plan or annuity contract, such amendment shall not be required to be made before the first day of the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1998-01-01">Jan. 1, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1465">section 1465 of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d0263-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1994</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle B [§§ 521–523] of title V of <ref href="/us/pl/102/318">Pub. L. 102–318</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1994-01-01">Jan. 1, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/s523">section 523 of Pub. L. 102–318</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d0264-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1800–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d0265-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination of Repeals of Certain Sections</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tVII/s713/d/8">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 713(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/958">98 Stat. 958</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“Sections 404(e) and 1379(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982 [<date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>]) shall not apply to any plan to which section 401(j) of such Code applies (or would apply but for its repeal).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d0266-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deductibility of Payments to Plan by Corporation Operating Public Transportation System Acquired by State</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/364/tIV/s408">Pub. L. 96–364, title IV, § 408</ref>, <date date="1980-09-26">Sept. 26, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1307">94 Stat. 1307</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> For purposes of subsection (g) of section 404 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] (relating to certain employer liability payments considered as contributions), as amended by section 205 of this Act, any payment made to a plan covering employees of a corporation operating a public transportation system shall be treated as a payment described in paragraph (1) of such subsection if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> such payment is made to fund accrued benefits under the plan in conjunction with an acquisition by a State (or agency or instrumentality thereof) of the stock or assets of such corporation, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> such acquisition is pursuant to a State public transportation law enacted after <date date="1979-06-30">June 30, 1979</date>, and before <date date="1980-01-01">January 1, 1980</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The provisions of this section shall apply to payments made after <date date="1980-06-29">June 29, 1980</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id430d0267-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Year of Deduction for Certain Employer Contributions for Severance Payments Required by Foreign Law</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tII/s1022/j">Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1022(j)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/942">88 Stat. 942</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“Effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1973-12-31">December 31, 1973</date>, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an employer is engaged in a trade or business in a foreign country,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> such employer is required by the laws of that country to make payments, based on periods of service, to its employees or their beneficiaries after the employees’ retirement, death, or other separation from the service, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> such employer establishes a trust (whether organized within or outside the United States) for the purpose of funding the payments required by such law,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then, in determining for purposes of paragraph (5) of section 404(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] the taxable year in which any contribution to or under the plan is includible in the gross income of the nonresident alien employees of such employer, such paragraph (5) shall be treated as not requiring that separate accounts be maintained for such nonresident alien employees.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
