<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id45c9ff16-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253"><num value="4253">§ 4253.</num><heading> Exemptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff17-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain coin-operated service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Service paid for by inserting coins in coin-operated telephones available to the public shall not be subject to the tax imposed by section 4251 with respect to local telephone service, or with respect to toll telephone service if the charge for such toll telephone service is less than 25 cents; except that where such coin-operated telephone service is furnished for a guaranteed amount, the amounts paid under such guarantee plus any fixed monthly or other periodic charge shall be subject to the tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff18-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> News services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251, except with respect to local telephone service, on any payment received from any person for services used in the collection of news for the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or radio broadcasting, or in the dissemination of news through the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or by means of radio broadcasting, if the charge for such service is billed in writing to such person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff19-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> International, etc., organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for services furnished to an international organization, or to the American National Red Cross.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff1a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Servicemen in combat zone</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for any toll telephone service which originates within a combat zone, as defined in section 112, from a member of the Armed Forces of the United States performing service in such combat zone, as determined under such section, provided a certificate, setting forth such facts as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, is furnished to the person receiving such payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff1b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Items otherwise taxed</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Only one payment of tax under section 4251 shall be required with respect to the tax on any service, notwithstanding the lines or stations of one or more persons are used in furnishing such service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff1c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Common carriers and communications companies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on the amount paid for any toll telephone service described in section 4252(b)(2) to the extent that the amount so paid is for use by a common carrier, telephone or telegraph company, or radio broadcasting station or network in the conduct of its business as such.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff1d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Installation charges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on so much of any amount paid for the installation of any instrument, wire, pole, switchboard, apparatus, or equipment as is properly attributable to such installation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff1e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonprofit hospitals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a nonprofit hospital for services furnished to such organization. For purposes of this subsection, the term “nonprofit hospital” means a hospital referred to in section 170(b)(1)(A)(iii) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff1f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> State and local governmental exemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 upon any payment received for services or facilities furnished to the government of any State, or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45c9ff20-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption for nonprofit educational organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a nonprofit educational organization for services or facilities furnished to such organization. For purposes of this subsection, the term “nonprofit educational organization” means an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a). The term also includes a school operated as an activity of an organization described in section 501(c)(3) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a), if such school normally maintains a regular faculty and curriculum and normally has a regularly enrolled body of pupils or students in attendance at the place where its educational activities are regularly carried on.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45cc7021-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption for qualified blood collector organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under regulations provided by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a qualified blood collector organization (as defined in section 7701(a)(49)) for services or facilities furnished to such organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id45cc7022-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing of exemption certificates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45cc7023-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/l/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order to claim an exemption under subsection (c), (h), (i), (j), or (k), a person shall provide to the provider of communications services a statement (in such form and manner as the Secretary may provide) certifying that such person is entitled to such exemption.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id45cc7024-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/l/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration of certificate</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any statement provided under paragraph (1) shall remain in effect until—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45cc7025-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the provider of communications services has actual knowledge that the information provided in such statement is false, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id45cc7026-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s4253/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such provider is notified by the Secretary that the provider of the statement is no longer entitled to an exemption described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If any information provided in such statement is no longer accurate, the person providing such statement shall inform the provider of communications services within 30 days of any change of information.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id45cc7027-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/504">68A Stat. 504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/tI/s133/a">Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1290">72 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/344/s4/a">Pub. L. 86–344, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-21">Sept. 21, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/619">73 Stat. 619</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/508/s4/b">Pub. L. 87–508, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/115">76 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/44/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/146">79 Stat. 146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/368/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 89–368, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-15">Mar. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/66">80 Stat. 66</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tI/s101/j/27">Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(j)(27)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/529">83 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1904(a)(6), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1811">90 Stat. 1811</ref>, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11217/c/1">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11217(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-438">104 Stat. 1388–438</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tXII/s1207/c">Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1207(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1070">120 Stat. 1070</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id45cc7028-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id45cc7029-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id45cc702a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1207/c">Section 1207(c) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, which directed the amendment of section 4253 without specifying the act to be amended, was executed to this section, which is section 4253 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See 2006 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, relating to the tax on communications, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/90/364/tI/s105/b/3">Pub. L. 90–364, title I, § 105(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-06-28">June 28, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/266">82 Stat. 266</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tVII/s702/b/3">Pub. L. 91–172, title VII, § 702(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/660">83 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/614/tII/s201/b/3">Pub. L. 91–614, title II, § 201(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1843">84 Stat. 1843</ref>, effective with respect to amounts paid pursuant to bills first rendered on or after <date date="1982-01-01">Jan. 1, 1982</date>. In the case of communications services rendered before <date date="1981-11-01">Nov. 1, 1981</date>, for which a bill has not been rendered before <date date="1982-01-01">Jan. 1, 1982</date>, a bill shall be treated as having been first rendered on <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>. Repeal of this subchapter was not executed in view of the amendments to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4251">section 4251 of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/96/499">Pub. L. 96–499</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, extending the date in (and finally eliminating) provisions which had reduced the tax to zero after a specified date.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id45cc702b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1207/c/1">Pub. L. 109–280, § 1207(c)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (k). Former subsec. (k) redesignated (<i>l</i>). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1207/c/1">Pub. L. 109–280, § 1207(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (k) as (<i>l</i>). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1207/c/2">Pub. L. 109–280, § 1207(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “(j), or (k)” for “or (j)”. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1904/a/6">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1904(a)(6)</ref>, added subsecs. (i) and (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> substituted “section 170(b)(1)(A)(iii)” for “section 503(b)(5)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/89/368">Pub. L. 89–368</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> substituted “with respect to local telephone service, or with respect to toll telephone service if the charge for such toll telephone service is less than 25 cents”, for “with respect to general telephone service, or with respect to toll telephone service or telegraph service if the charge for such toll telephone service or telegraph service is less than 25 cents”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> substituted “local telephone service” for “general telephone service” and “such service” for “such services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> substituted “International, etc., organizations” for “Certain organizations” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> reenacted subsec. (d) without change.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> substituted “any service” for “toll telephone service, telegraph service, or teletypewriter exchange service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> substituted amounts paid for any toll telephone service for amounts paid for wire mileage service, wire and equipment service, and use of any telephone or radiotelephone line or channel which constitutes general telephone service if such line or channel connects stations between any two of which there would otherwise be a toll charge.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> reenacted subsec. (g) without change.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> struck out subsecs. (h) to (j), which related to terminal facilities in case of wire mileage service and to certain interior and private communications services.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/87/508">Pub. L. 87–508</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/86/344">Pub. L. 86–344</ref> substituted “Common carriers and communications companies” for “Special wire service in company business” in heading, incorporated existing provisions in opening and closing statements and par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted “general telephone service, or with respect to toll telephone service or telegraph service if the charge for such toll telephone service or telegraph service is less than 25 cents” for “local telephone service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted “general telephone service, on any payment received from any person for services used” for “local telephone service, upon any payment received from any person for services or facilities utilized”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted “on any payment received for services furnished to an international organization, or to the American National Red Cross” for “upon any payment received for services or facilities furnished to an international organization, or any organization created by act of Congress to act in matters of relief under the treaty of Geneva of <date date="1864-08-22">August 22, 1864</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted “on any payment received for any toll telephone service” for “with respect to long distance telephone service upon any payment received for any telephone or radio telephone message”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted “toll telephone service, telegraph service, or teletypewriter exchange service” for “long distance telephone service or telegraph service” and “in furnishing such service” for “in the transmission of such dispatch, message or conversation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted “any wire mileage service or wire and equipment service as is used in the conduct” for “the service described in sections 4252(d) and (e) as is utilized in the conduct”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> added subsecs. (g) to (i).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id45cc702c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc702d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref> effective <date date="2007-01-01">Jan. 1, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1207/g/1">section 1207(g)(1) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4041">section 4041 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc702e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11217/c/2">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11217(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-438">104 Stat. 1388–438</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11217/c/2">
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to any claim for exemption made after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration of existing certificates</inline>.—</heading><content>Any annual certificate of exemption effective on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>] shall remain effective until the end of the annual period.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc702f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1904/a/6">section 1904(a)(6) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective on first day of first month which begins more than 90 days after <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1904/d">section 1904(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4041">section 4041 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc7030-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> effective <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s101/k/1">section 101(k)(1) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4940">section 4940 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc7031-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/368">Pub. L. 89–368</ref> applicable to amounts paid pursuant to bills first rendered on or after <date date="1966-04-01">April 1, 1966</date>, for services rendered on or after such date and to amounts paid pursuant to bills rendered on or after such date for services which were rendered before such date and for which no previous bill was rendered except with respect to such services as were rendered more than two months before such date and, as to services rendered more than 2 months before such date, direction that the provisions of subchapter B of chapter 33 of the Code in effect at the time such services were rendered, be applied, subject to the provision of section 701(b)(2) of the Excise Tax Reduction Act of 1965.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc7032-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1965 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/44">Pub. L. 89–44</ref> applicable to amounts paid pursuant to bills rendered on or after <date date="1966-01-01">January 1, 1966</date>, for services rendered on or after such date, but, in the case of amounts paid pursuant to bills rendered after <date date="1966-01-01">January 1, 1966</date>, for services rendered before such date for which no previous bill had been rendered, applicable except with respect to such services as were rendered more than two months before such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/44/s701/b/2/A">section 701(b)(2)(A) of Pub. L. 89–44</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4251">section 4251 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc7033-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/508">Pub. L. 87–508</ref> applicable with respect to services furnished on or after <date date="1963-01-01">Jan. 1, 1963</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/508/s4/c">section 4(c) of Pub. L. 87–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4252">section 4252 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc7034-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1959 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/86/344/s4/b">Pub. L. 86–344, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-21">Sept. 21, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/619">73 Stat. 619</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to amounts paid on or after <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>, for services rendered on or after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall not apply with respect to amounts paid pursuant to bills rendered before <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>. In the case of amounts paid pursuant to bills rendered on or after such date for services for which no bill was rendered before such date, such amendment shall apply except with respect to such services as were rendered more than 2 months before such date. In the case of services rendered more than 2 months before such date, the provisions of subchapter B of chapter 33 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] in effect at the time such services were rendered shall apply to the amounts paid for such services.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id45cc7035-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/s133/b">section 133(b) of Pub. L. 85–859</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4251">section 4251 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
