<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id436533d4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431"><num value="431">§ 431.</num><heading> Minimum funding standards for multiemployer plans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id436533d5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of section 412, the accumulated funding deficiency of a multiemployer plan for any plan year is the amount, determined as of the end of the plan year, equal to the excess (if any) of the total charges to the funding standard account of the plan for all plan years (beginning with the first plan year for which this part applies to the plan) over the total credits to such account for such years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id436533d6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding standard account</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533d7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Account required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each multiemployer plan to which this part applies shall establish and maintain a funding standard account. Such account shall be credited and charged solely as provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533d8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges to account</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For a plan year, the funding standard account shall be charged with the sum of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533d9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the normal cost of the plan for the plan year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533da-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the amounts necessary to amortize in equal annual installments (until fully amortized)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533db-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of a plan which comes into existence on or after <date date="2008-01-01">January 1, 2008</date>, the unfunded past service liability under the plan on the first day of the first plan year to which this section applies, over a period of 15 plan years,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533dc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> separately, with respect to each plan year, the net increase (if any) in unfunded past service liability under the plan arising from plan amendments adopted in such year, over a period of 15 plan years,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533dd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> separately, with respect to each plan year, the net experience loss (if any) under the plan, over a period of 15 plan years, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533de-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> separately, with respect to each plan year, the net loss (if any) resulting from changes in actuarial assumptions used under the plan, over a period of 15 plan years,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533df-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the amount necessary to amortize each waived funding deficiency (within the meaning of section 412(c)(3)) for each prior plan year in equal annual installments (until fully amortized) over a period of 15 plan years,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533e0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the amount necessary to amortize in equal annual installments (until fully amortized) over a period of 5 plan years any amount credited to the funding standard account under section 412(b)(3)(D) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Pension Protection Act of 2006), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533e1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the amount necessary to amortize in equal annual installments (until fully amortized) over a period of 20 years the contributions which would be required to be made under the plan but for the provisions of section 412(c)(7)(A)(i)(I) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Pension Protection Act of 2006).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533e2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Credits to account</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For a plan year, the funding standard account shall be credited with the sum of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533e3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount considered contributed by the employer to or under the plan for the plan year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533e4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the amount necessary to amortize in equal annual installments (until fully amortized)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533e5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> separately, with respect to each plan year, the net decrease (if any) in unfunded past service liability under the plan arising from plan amendments adopted in such year, over a period of 15 plan years,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533e6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> separately, with respect to each plan year, the net experience gain (if any) under the plan, over a period of 15 plan years, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533e7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> separately, with respect to each plan year, the net gain (if any) resulting from changes in actuarial assumptions used under the plan, over a period of 15 plan years,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533e8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the amount of the waived funding deficiency (within the meaning of section 412(c)(3)) for the plan year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533e9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> in the case of a plan year for which the accumulated funding deficiency is determined under the funding standard account if such plan year follows a plan year for which such deficiency was determined under the alternative minimum funding standard under section 412(g) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Pension Protection Act of 2006), the excess (if any) of any debit balance in the funding standard account (determined without regard to this subparagraph) over any debit balance in the alternative minimum funding standard account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533ea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for amounts first amortized in plan years before 2008</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any amount amortized under section 412(b) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Pension Protection Act of 2006) over any period beginning with a plan year beginning before 2008 in lieu of the amortization described in paragraphs (2)(B) and (3)(B), such amount shall continue to be amortized under such section as so in effect.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533eb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Combining and offsetting amounts to be amortized</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, amounts required to be amortized under paragraph (2) or paragraph (3), as the case may be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533ec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may be combined into one amount under such paragraph to be amortized over a period determined on the basis of the remaining amortization period for all items entering into such combined amount, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id436533ed-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may be offset against amounts required to be amortized under the other such paragraph, with the resulting amount to be amortized over a period determined on the basis of the remaining amortization periods for all items entering into whichever of the two amounts being offset is the greater.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533ee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The funding standard account (and items therein) shall be charged or credited (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury) with interest at the appropriate rate consistent with the rate or rates of interest used under the plan to determine costs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533ef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules relating to charges and credits to funding standard account</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this part—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawal liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount received by a multiemployer plan in payment of all or part of an employer’s withdrawal liability under part 1 of subtitle E of title IV of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 shall be considered an amount contributed by the employer to or under the plan. The Secretary may prescribe by regulation additional charges and credits to a multiemployer plan’s funding standard account to the extent necessary to prevent withdrawal liability payments from being unduly reflected as advance funding for plan liabilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments when a multiemployer plan leaves reorganization</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a multiemployer plan is not in reorganization in the plan year but was in reorganization in the immediately preceding plan year, any balance in the funding standard account at the close of such immediately preceding plan year—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533f2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall be eliminated by an offsetting credit or charge (as the case may be), but</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id436533f3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall be taken into account in subsequent plan years by being amortized in equal annual installments (until fully amortized) over 30 plan years.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent of any accumulated funding deficiency under section 4243(a) of such Act as of the end of the last plan year that the plan was in reorganization.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan payments to supplemental program or withdrawal liability payment fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount paid by a plan during a plan year to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation pursuant to section 4222 of such Act or to a fund exempt under section 501(c)(22) pursuant to section 4223 of such Act shall reduce the amount of contributions considered received by the plan for the plan year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim withdrawal liability payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount paid by an employer pending a final determination of the employer’s withdrawal liability under part 1 of subtitle E of title IV of such Act and subsequently refunded to the employer by the plan shall be charged to the funding standard account in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Election for deferral of charge for portion of net experience loss</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If an election is in effect under section 412(b)(7)(F) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Pension Protection Act of 2006) for any plan year, the funding standard account shall be charged in the plan year to which the portion of the net experience loss deferred by such election was deferred with the amount so deferred (and paragraph (2)(B)(iii) shall not apply to the amount so charged).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any amount of any financial assistance from the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to any plan, and any repayment of such amount, shall be taken into account under this section and section 412 in such manner as is determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/7/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Short-term benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">To the extent that any plan amendment increases the unfunded past service liability under the plan by reason of an increase in benefits which are not payable as a life annuity but are payable under the terms of the plan for a period that does not exceed 14 years from the effective date of the amendment, paragraph (2)(B)(ii) shall be applied separately with respect to such increase in unfunded past service liability by substituting the number of years of the period during which such benefits are payable for “15”.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id436533f9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Special relief rules</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id436533fa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Amortization of net investment losses</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id436533fb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A multiemployer plan with respect to which the solvency test under subparagraph (C) is met may treat the portion of any experience loss or gain attributable to net investment losses incurred in either or both of the first two plan years ending after <date date="2008-08-31">August 31, 2008</date>, as an item separate from other experience losses, to be amortized in equal annual installments (until fully amortized) over the period—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id436533fc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> beginning with the plan year in which such portion is first recognized in the actuarial value of assets, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id436533fd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> ending with the last plan year in the 30-plan year period beginning with the plan year in which such net investment loss was incurred.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677dee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with extensions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If this subparagraph applies for any plan year—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677def-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> no extension of the amortization period under clause (i) shall be allowed under subsection (d), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677df0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if an extension was granted under subsection (d) for any plan year before the election to have this subparagraph apply to the plan year, such extension shall not result in such amortization period exceeding 30 years.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677df1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Net investment losses</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677df2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Net investment losses shall be determined in the manner prescribed by the Secretary on the basis of the difference between actual and expected returns (including any difference attributable to any criminally fraudulent investment arrangement).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677df3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/A/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Criminally fraudulent investment arrangements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The determination as to whether an arrangement is a criminally fraudulent investment arrangement shall be made under rules substantially similar to the rules prescribed by the Secretary for purposes of section 165.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677df4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Expanded smoothing period</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677df5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A multiemployer plan with respect to which the solvency test under subparagraph (C) is met may change its asset valuation method in a manner which—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677df6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> spreads the difference between expected and actual returns for either or both of the first 2 plan years ending after <date date="2008-08-31">August 31, 2008</date>, over a period of not more than 10 years,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677df7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> provides that for either or both of the first 2 plan years beginning after <date date="2008-08-31">August 31, 2008</date>, the value of plan assets at any time shall not be less than 80 percent or greater than 130 percent of the fair market value of such assets at such time, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677df8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> makes both changes described in subclauses (I) and (II) to such method.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677df9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Asset valuation methods</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If this subparagraph applies for any plan year—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677dfa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the Secretary shall not treat the asset valuation method of the plan as unreasonable solely because of the changes in such method described in clause (i), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677dfb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> such changes shall be deemed approved by the Secretary under section 302(d)(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and section 412(d)(1).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677dfc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Amortization of reduction in unfunded accrued liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If this subparagraph and subparagraph (A) both apply for any plan year, the plan shall treat any reduction in unfunded accrued liability resulting from the application of this subparagraph as a separate experience amortization base, to be amortized in equal annual installments (until fully amortized) over a period of 30 plan years rather than the period such liability would otherwise be amortized over.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677dfd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Solvency test</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The solvency test under this paragraph is met only if the plan actuary certifies that the plan is projected to have sufficient assets to timely pay expected benefits and anticipated expenditures over the amortization period, taking into account the changes in the funding standard account under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677dfe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on benefit increases</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If subparagraph (A) or (B) apply to a multiemployer plan for any plan year, then, in addition to any other applicable restrictions on benefit increases, a plan amendment increasing benefits may not go into effect during either of the 2 plan years immediately following such plan year unless—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677dff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the plan actuary certifies that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e00-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any such increase is paid for out of additional contributions not allocated to the plan immediately before the application of this paragraph to the plan, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e01-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the plan’s funded percentage and projected credit balances for such 2 plan years are reasonably expected to be at least as high as such percentage and balances would have been if the benefit increase had not been adopted, or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e02-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amendment is required as a condition of qualification under part I of subchapter D or to comply with other applicable law.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e03-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A plan sponsor of a plan to which this paragraph applies shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e04-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> give notice of such application to participants and beneficiaries of the plan, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> inform the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation of such application in such form and manner as the Director of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation may prescribe.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Relief for 2020 and 2021</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A multiemployer plan with respect to which the solvency test under subparagraph (C) is met as of <date date="2020-02-29">February 29, 2020</date>, may elect to apply this paragraph (without regard to whether such plan previously elected the application of this paragraph)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> by substituting “<date date="2020-02-29">February 29, 2020</date>” for “<date date="2008-08-31">August 31, 2008</date>” each place it appears in subparagraphs (A)(i), (B)(i)(I), and (B)(i)(II),</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> by inserting “and other losses related to the virus SARS–CoV–2 or coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID–19) (including experience losses related to reductions in contributions, reductions in employment, and deviations from anticipated retirement rates, as determined by the plan sponsor)” after “net investment losses” in subparagraph (A)(i), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/b/8/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> by substituting “this subparagraph or subparagraph (A)” for “this subparagraph and subparagraph (A) both” in subparagraph (B)(iii).</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The preceding sentence shall not apply to a plan to which special financial assistance is granted under section 4262 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974. For purposes of the application of this subparagraph, the Secretary shall rely on the plan sponsor’s calculations of plan losses unless such calculations are clearly erroneous.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional rules</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations to be made under funding method</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this part, normal costs, accrued liability, past service liabilities, and experience gains and losses shall be determined under the funding method used to determine costs under the plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Valuation of assets</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e0d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this part, the value of the plan’s assets shall be determined on the basis of any reasonable actuarial method of valuation which takes into account fair market value and which is permitted under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e0e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Election with respect to bonds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The value of a bond or other evidence of indebtedness which is not in default as to principal or interest may, at the election of the plan administrator, be determined on an amortized basis running from initial cost at purchase to par value at maturity or earliest call date. Any election under this subparagraph shall be made at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations provide, shall apply to all such evidences of indebtedness, and may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e0f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Actuarial assumptions must be reasonable</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, all costs, liabilities, rates of interest, and other factors under the plan shall be determined on the basis of actuarial assumptions and methods—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43677e10-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> each of which is reasonable (taking into account the experience of the plan and reasonable expectations), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43677e11-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which, in combination, offer the actuary’s best estimate of anticipated experience under the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e12-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain changes as experience gain or loss</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43677e13-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a change in benefits under the Social Security Act or in other retirement benefits created under Federal or State law, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43677e14-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a change in the definition of the term “wages” under section 3121, or a change in the amount of such wages taken into account under regulations prescribed for purposes of section 401(a)(5),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">results in an increase or decrease in accrued liability under a plan, such increase or decrease shall be treated as an experience loss or gain.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e15-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Full funding</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, as of the close of a plan year, a plan would (without regard to this paragraph) have an accumulated funding deficiency in excess of the full funding limitation—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43677e16-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the funding standard account shall be credited with the amount of such excess, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43677e17-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all amounts described in subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) of subsection (b)(2) and subparagraph (B) of subsection (b)(3) which are required to be amortized shall be considered fully amortized for purposes of such subparagraphs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e18-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Full-funding limitation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e19-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of paragraph (5), the term “full-funding limitation” means the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e1a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the accrued liability (including normal cost) under the plan (determined under the entry age normal funding method if such accrued liability cannot be directly calculated under the funding method used for the plan), over</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e1b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the lesser of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e1c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the fair market value of the plan’s assets, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e1d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the value of such assets determined under paragraph (2).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e1e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum amount</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e1f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In no event shall the full-funding limitation determined under subparagraph (A) be less than the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e20-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> 90 percent of the current liability of the plan (including the expected increase in current liability due to benefits accruing during the plan year), over</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e21-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the value of the plan’s assets determined under paragraph (2).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e22-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Assets</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), assets shall not be reduced by any credit balance in the funding standard account.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e23-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Full funding limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, unless otherwise provided by the plan, the accrued liability under a multiemployer plan shall not include benefits which are not nonforfeitable under the plan after the termination of the plan (taking into consideration section 411(d)(3)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e24-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Current liability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e25-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “current liability” means all liabilities to employees and their beneficiaries under the plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e26-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of unpredictable contingent event benefits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), any benefit contingent on an event other than—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e27-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> age, service, compensation, death, or disability, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e28-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an event which is reasonably and reliably predictable (as determined by the Secretary),</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">shall not be taken into account until the event on which the benefit is contingent occurs.</continuation>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e29-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest rate used</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The rate of interest used to determine current liability under this paragraph shall be the rate of interest determined under subparagraph (E).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e2a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Mortality tables</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e2b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/iv/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Commissioners’ standard table</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In the case of plan years beginning before the first plan year to which the first tables prescribed under subclause (II) apply, the mortality table used in determining current liability under this paragraph shall be the table prescribed by the Secretary which is based on the prevailing commissioners’ standard table (described in section 807(d)(5)(A)) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002119"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> used to determine reserves for group annuity contracts issued on <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e2c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/iv/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Secretary may by regulation prescribe for plan years beginning after <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, mortality tables to be used in determining current liability under this subsection. Such tables shall be based upon the actual experience of pension plans and projected trends in such experience. In prescribing such tables, the Secretary shall take into account results of available independent studies of mortality of individuals covered by pension plans.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e2d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Separate mortality tables for the disabled</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding clause (iv)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e2e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/v/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Secretary shall establish mortality tables which may be used (in lieu of the tables under clause (iv)) to determine current liability under this subsection for individuals who are entitled to benefits under the plan on account of disability. The Secretary shall establish separate tables for individuals whose disabilities occur in plan years beginning before <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, and for individuals whose disabilities occur in plan years beginning on or after such date.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e2f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/v/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for disabilities occurring after 1994</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In the case of disabilities occurring in plan years beginning after <date date="1994-12-31">December 31, 1994</date>, the tables under subclause (I) shall apply only with respect to individuals described in such subclause who are disabled within the meaning of title II of the Social Security Act and the regulations thereunder.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e30-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/D/vi"><num value="vi" class="bold">(vi)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodic review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall periodically (at least every 5 years) review any tables in effect under this subparagraph and shall, to the extent such Secretary determines necessary, by regulation update the tables to reflect the actual experience of pension plans and projected trends in such experience.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e31-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Required change of interest rate</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of determining a plan’s current liability for purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e32-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If any rate of interest used under the plan under subsection (b)(6) to determine cost is not within the permissible range, the plan shall establish a new rate of interest within the permissible range.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e33-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Permissible range</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e34-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Except as provided in subclause (II), the term “permissible range” means a rate of interest which is not more than 5 percent above, and not more than 10 percent below, the weighted average of the rates of interest on 30-year Treasury securities during the 4-year period ending on the last day before the beginning of the plan year.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e35-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">If the Secretary finds that the lowest rate of interest permissible under subclause (I) is unreasonably high, the Secretary may prescribe a lower rate of interest, except that such rate may not be less than 80 percent of the average rate determined under such subclause.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e36-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Assumptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding paragraph (3)(A), the interest rate used under the plan shall be—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e37-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> determined without taking into account the experience of the plan and reasonable expectations, but</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e38-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/6/E/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> consistent with the assumptions which reflect the purchase rates which would be used by insurance companies to satisfy the liabilities under the plan.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e39-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual valuation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e3a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this section, a determination of experience gains and losses and a valuation of the plan’s liability shall be made not less frequently than once every year, except that such determination shall be made more frequently to the extent required in particular cases under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e3b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Valuation date</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e3c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/7/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Current year</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), the valuation referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be made as of a date within the plan year to which the valuation refers or within one month prior to the beginning of such year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e3d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/7/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of prior year valuation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The valuation referred to in subparagraph (A) may be made as of a date within the plan year prior to the year to which the valuation refers if, as of such date, the value of the assets of the plan are not less than 100 percent of the plan’s current liability (as defined in paragraph (6)(D) without regard to clause (iv) thereof).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e3e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/7/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Information under clause (ii) shall, in accordance with regulations, be actuarially adjusted to reflect significant differences in participants.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e3f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/7/B/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A change in funding method to use a prior year valuation, as provided in clause (ii), may not be made unless as of the valuation date within the prior plan year, the value of the assets of the plan are not less than 125 percent of the plan’s current liability (as defined in paragraph (6)(D) without regard to clause (iv) thereof).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e40-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Time when certain contributions deemed made</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, any contributions for a plan year made by an employer after the last day of such plan year, but not later than two and one-half months after such day, shall be deemed to have been made on such last day. For purposes of this subparagraph, such two and one-half month period may be extended for not more than six months under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e41-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension of amortization periods for multiemployer plans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e42-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Automatic extension upon application by certain plans</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e43-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the plan sponsor of a multiemployer plan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e44-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> submits to the Secretary an application for an extension of the period of years required to amortize any unfunded liability described in any clause of subsection (b)(2)(B) or described in subsection (b)(4), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e45-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> includes with the application a certification by the plan’s actuary described in subparagraph (B),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall extend the amortization period for the period of time (not in excess of 5 years) specified in the application. Such extension shall be in addition to any extension under paragraph (2).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e46-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A certification with respect to a multiemployer plan is described in this subparagraph if the plan’s actuary certifies that, based on reasonable assumptions—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e47-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> absent the extension under subparagraph (A), the plan would have an accumulated funding deficiency in the current plan year or any of the 9 succeeding plan years,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e48-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the plan sponsor has adopted a plan to improve the plan’s funding status,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e49-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the plan is projected to have sufficient assets to timely pay expected benefits and anticipated expenditures over the amortization period as extended, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e4a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the notice required under paragraph (3)(A) has been provided.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e4b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative extension</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e4c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the plan sponsor of a multiemployer plan submits to the Secretary an application for an extension of the period of years required to amortize any unfunded liability described in any clause of subsection (b)(2)(B) or described in subsection (b)(4), the Secretary may extend the amortization period for a period of time (not in excess of 10 years reduced by the number of years of any extension under paragraph (1) with respect to such unfunded liability) if the Secretary makes the determination described in subparagraph (B). Such extension shall be in addition to any extension under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e4d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may grant an extension under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e4e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such extension would carry out the purposes of the Pension Protection Act of 2006 and would provide adequate protection for participants under the plan and their beneficiaries, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43677e4f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the failure to permit such extension would—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e50-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> result in a substantial risk to the voluntary continuation of the plan, or a substantial curtailment of pension benefit levels or employee compensation, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id43677e51-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> be adverse to the interests of plan participants in the aggregate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e52-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Action by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall act upon any application for an extension under this paragraph within 180 days of the submission of such application. If the Secretary rejects the application for an extension under this paragraph, the Secretary shall provide notice to the plan detailing the specific reasons for the rejection, including references to the criteria set forth above.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e53-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Advance notice</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e54-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall, before granting an extension under this subsection, require each applicant to provide evidence satisfactory to such Secretary that the applicant has provided notice of the filing of the application for such extension to each affected party (as defined in section 4001(a)(21) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974) with respect to the affected plan. Such notice shall include a description of the extent to which the plan is funded for benefits which are guaranteed under title IV of such Act and for benefit liabilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43677e55-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s431/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of relevant information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall consider any relevant information provided by a person to whom notice was given under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id43677e56-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tII/s211/a">Pub. L. 109–280, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/890">120 Stat. 890</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/192/tII/s211/a/2">Pub. L. 111–192, title II, § 211(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-06-25">June 25, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1304">124 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dO/tI">Pub. L. 113–235, div. O, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b)(2), 108(b)(3)(A), <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2774">128 Stat. 2774</ref>, 2788; <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tI/s171/a">Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title I, § 171(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/4023">128 Stat. 4023</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/a/101">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(101)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1189">132 Stat. 1189</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/2/tIX/s9703/a/2">Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9703(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/189">135 Stat. 189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id43677e57-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id43677e58-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id43677e59-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, referred to in subsecs. (b)(7)(A) to (D), (8)(B)(ii)(II), (F) and (d)(3)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/829">88 Stat. 829</ref>. Title IV of the Act is classified principally to subchapter III (§ 1301 et seq.) of chapter 18 of Title 29, Labor. Part 1 of subtitle E of title IV of the Act is classified generally to part 1 (§ 1381 et seq.) of subtitle E of subchapter III of chapter 18 of Title 29. Sections 302, 4001, 4222, 4223, 4243, and 4262 of the Act are classified to sections 1082, 1301, 1402, 1403, 1423, and 1432, respectively, of Title 29. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Pension Protection Act of 2006, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(D), (E), (3)(D), (4), (7)(E), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, which was approved <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(4)(A), (6)(D)(v)(II), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 7 (§ 301 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 401 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 807(d)(5), referred to in subsec. (c)(6)(D)(iv)(I), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13517/a/2/A">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13517(a)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2144">131 Stat. 2144</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Pension Protection Act of 2006, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(B)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/780">120 Stat. 780</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2006 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of Title 29</ref>, Labor, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id43677e5a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(8)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/117/2">Pub. L. 117–2</ref> added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> substituted “the Pension Protection Act of 2006” for “this Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s108/b/3/A">Pub. L. 113–235, § 108(b)(3)(A)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) related to accumulated funding deficiency of multiemployer plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295">Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, which directed amendment of subpar. (C) by substituting “<date date="2015-12-31">December 31, 2015</date>” for “<date date="2014-12-31">December 31, 2014</date>”, could not be executed because of previous repeal of subpar. (C) by <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s101/b/2">Pub. L. 113–235, § 101(b)(2)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s101/b/2">Pub. L. 113–235, § 101(b)(2)</ref>, struck out subpar. (C). Text read as follows: “The preceding provisions of this paragraph shall not apply with respect to any application submitted after <date date="2014-12-31">December 31, 2014</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/192">Pub. L. 111–192</ref> added par. (8).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id43677e5b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43677e5c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/2/tIX/s9703/b">Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9703(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/189">135 Stat. 189</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/2/tIX/s9703/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1084">section 1084 of Title 29</ref>, Labor] shall take effect as of the first day of the first plan year ending on or after <date date="2020-02-29">February 29, 2020</date>, except that any election a plan makes pursuant to this section that affects the plan’s funding standard account for the first plan year beginning after <date date="2020-02-29">February 29, 2020</date>, shall be disregarded for purposes of applying the provisions of section 305 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1085">29 U.S.C. 1085</ref>] and section 432 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to such plan year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restrictions on benefit increases</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the restrictions on plan amendments increasing benefits in sections 304(b)(8)(D) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1084/b/8/D">29 U.S.C. 1084(b)(8)(D)</ref>] and 431(b)(8)(D) of such Code, as applied by the amendments made by this section, shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43677e5d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tI/s171/c">Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title I, § 171(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/4023">128 Stat. 4023</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tI/s171/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1084">section 1084 of Title 29</ref>, Labor] shall apply to applications submitted under section 431(d)(1)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and section 304(d)(1)(C) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1084/d/1/C">29 U.S.C. 1084(d)(1)(C)</ref>] after <date date="2014-12-31">December 31, 2014</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s108/b/3/A">section 108(b)(3)(A) of Pub. L. 113–235</ref> applicable with respect to plan years beginning after <date date="2014-12-31">Dec. 31, 2014</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dO/s108/c">section 108(c) of div. O of Pub. L. 113–235</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of Repeal note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s418">section 418 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43677e5e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/192/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 111–192, title II, § 211(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-06-25">June 25, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1306">124 Stat. 1306</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/192/tII/s211/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1084">section 1084 of Title 29</ref>, Labor] shall take effect as of the first day of the first plan year ending after <date date="2008-08-31">August 31, 2008</date>, except that any election a plan makes pursuant to this section that affects the plan’s funding standard account for the first plan year beginning after <date date="2008-08-31">August 31, 2008</date>, shall be disregarded for purposes of applying the provisions of section 305 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1085">29 U.S.C. 1085</ref>] and section 432 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to such plan year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restrictions on benefit increases</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the restrictions on plan amendments increasing benefits in sections 304(b)(8)(D) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1084/b/8/D">29 U.S.C. 1084(b)(8)(D)</ref>] and 431(b)(8)(D) of such Code, as added by this section, shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-06-25">June 25, 2010</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id43677e5f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tII/s211/b">Pub. L. 109–280, title II, § 211(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/898">120 Stat. 898</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/280/tII/s211/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section [enacting this section] shall apply to plan years beginning after 2007.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for certain amortization extensions</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary of the Treasury grants an extension under section 304 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1084">29 U.S.C. 1084</ref>] and section 412(e) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to any application filed with the Secretary of the Treasury on or before <date date="2005-06-30">June 30, 2005</date>, the extension (and any modification thereof) shall be applied and administered under the rules of such sections as in effect before the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>], including the use of the rate of interest determined under section 6621(b) of such Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id43677e60-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Rule for Certain Benefits Funded Under an Agreement Approved by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For applicability of this section to a multiemployer plan that is a party to an agreement that was approved by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation prior to <date date="2005-06-30">June 30, 2005</date>, and that increases benefits and provides for certain withdrawal liability rules, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s206">section 206 of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s412">section 412 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
