<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id461b059c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006"><num value="5006">§ 5006.</num><heading> Determination of tax</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id461b059d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id461b059e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the tax on distilled spirits shall be determined when the spirits are withdrawn from bond. Such tax shall be determined by such means as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe, and with the use of such devices and apparatus (including but not limited to tanks and pipelines) as the Secretary may require. The tax on distilled spirits withdrawn from the bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant shall be determined upon completion of the gauge for determination of tax and before withdrawal from bonded premises, under such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id461b059f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Distilled spirits not accounted for</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary finds that the distiller has not accounted for all the distilled spirits produced by him, he shall, from all the evidence he can obtain, determine what quantity of distilled spirits was actually produced by such distiller, and an assessment shall be made for the difference between the quantity reported and the quantity shown to have been actually produced at the rate of tax imposed by law for every proof gallon.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Taxable loss</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> On original quantity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Where there is evidence satisfactory to the Secretary that there has been any loss of distilled spirits from any cask or other package deposited on bonded premises, other than a loss which by reason of section 5008(a) is not taxable, the Secretary may require the withdrawal from bonded premises of such distilled spirits, and direct the officer designated by him to collect the tax accrued on the original quantity of distilled spirits entered for deposit on bonded premises in such cask or package; except that, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, when the extent of any loss from causes other than theft or unauthorized voluntary destruction can be established by the proprietor to the satisfaction of the Secretary an allowance of the tax on the loss so established may be credited against the tax on the original quantity. If such tax is not paid on demand it shall be assessed and collected as other taxes are assessed and collected.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative method</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Where there is evidence satisfactory to the Secretary that there has been access, other than is authorized by law, to the contents of casks or packages stored on bonded premises, and the extent of such access is such as to evidence a lack of due diligence or a failure to employ necessary and effective controls on the part of the proprietor, the Secretary (in lieu of requiring the casks or packages to which such access has been had to be withdrawn and tax paid on the original quantity of distilled spirits entered for deposit on bonded premises in such casks or packages as provided in paragraph (1)) may assess an amount equal to the tax on 5 proof gallons of distilled spirits at the prevailing rate on each of the total number of such casks or packages as determined by him.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of subsection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of this subsection shall apply to distilled spirits which are filled into casks or packages, as authorized by law, after entry and deposit on bonded premises, whether by recasking, filling from storage tanks, consolidation of packages, or otherwise; and the quantity filled into such casks or packages shall be deemed to be the original quantity for the purpose of this subsection, in the case of loss from such casks or packages.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Distilled spirits not bonded</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The tax on any distilled spirits, removed from the place where they were distilled and (except as otherwise provided by law) not deposited in storage on bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant, shall, at any time within the period of limitation provided in section 6501, when knowledge of such fact is obtained by the Secretary, be assessed on the distiller of such distilled spirits (or other person liable for the tax) and payment of such tax immediately demanded and, on the neglect or refusal of payment, the Secretary shall proceed to collect the same by distraint. This paragraph shall not exclude any other remedy or proceeding provided by law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Production at other than qualified plants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided by law, the tax on any distilled spirits produced in the United States at any place other than a qualified distilled spirits plant shall be due and payable immediately upon production.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Unlawfully imported distilled spirits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Distilled spirits smuggled or brought into the United States unlawfully shall, for purposes of this chapter, be held to be imported into the United States, and the internal revenue tax shall be due and payable at the time of such importation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id461b05a8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5006/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions relating to removal of distilled spirits from bonded premises on determination of tax, see section 5213.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id461b05a9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/tII/s201">Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1320">72 Stat. 1320</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/tVIII">Pub. L. 96–39, title VIII</ref>, §§ 804(a), 807(a)(4), <date date="1979-07-26">July 26, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/274">93 Stat. 274</ref>, 280.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id461b05aa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id461b05ab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id461b05ac-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 5006, acts <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/599">68A Stat. 599</ref>; <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/tII/s206/a">Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1431">72 Stat. 1431</ref>, consisted of provisions similar to those comprising this section, prior to the general revision of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those comprising subsecs. (a)(2)(A), (3) of this section were contained in prior sections 5007(e)(1) and 5232(a), <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/600">68A Stat. 600</ref>, 643, prior to the general revision of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id461b05ad-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/s804/a">Pub. L. 96–39, § 804(a)</ref>, struck out “internal revenue” after “provided in this section, the” and “storage, gauging, and bottling” after “but not limited to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/s804/a">Pub. L. 96–39, § 804(a)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (2). Former par. (2), relating to distilled spirits entered for storage, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/s807/a/4/A">Pub. L. 96–39, § 807(a)(4)(A)</ref>, (B), substituted “on bonded premises” for “in storage in internal revenue bond” in two places and “; except” for “, notwithstanding that the time specified in any bond given for the withdrawal of the spirits entered in storage in such cask or package has not expired, except”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/s807/a/4/B">Pub. L. 96–39, § 807(a)(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “on bonded premises” for “in storage in internal revenue bond”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsecs. (a) to (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id461b05ae-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id461b05af-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/39">Pub. L. 96–39</ref> effective <date date="1980-01-01">Jan. 1, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/39/s810">section 810 of Pub. L. 96–39</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5001">section 5001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id461b05b0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of 1972 Amendments to Prior Sections</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/859/tII/s206/f">Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 206(f)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1431">72 Stat. 1431</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 5005, 5232, 5242, and 5243 of this title] shall apply with respect to:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> distilled spirits which on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>] are in internal revenue bonded warehouses or are in transit to or between such warehouses, and in respect of which the 8-year bonding period has not expired before the date of enactment of this Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> distilled spirits which after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>] are entered for deposit in an internal revenue bonded warehouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> If the 8 years from the date of original entry of any distilled spirits for deposit in internal revenue bonded warehouses expires at any time during the 10-day period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>], the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to such spirits if (and only if) before the close of such 10-day period there is filed with the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate either—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a consent of surety which changes (for periods on and after the date of the enactment of this Act) the condition based on the withdrawal of spirits from the internal revenue bonded warehouse within 8 years from the date of original entry for deposit to a condition based on the withdrawal of spirits from the internal revenue bonded warehouse within 20 years from the date of original entry for deposit, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a bond which applies to periods on and after the date of the enactment of this Act and which satisfies the requirements of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954], as amended by this section, and is conditioned on the withdrawal of spirits from the internal revenue bonded warehouse within 20 years from the date of original entry for deposit.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
