<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4637b55d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373"><num value="5373">§ 5373.</num><heading> Wine spirits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4637b55e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The wine spirits authorized to be used in wine production shall be brandy or wine spirits produced in a distilled spirits plant (with or without the use of water to facilitate extraction and distillation) exclusively from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4637b55f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> fresh or dried fruit, or their residues,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4637b560-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the wine or wine residues, therefrom, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4637b561-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> special natural wine under such conditions as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that where, in the production of natural wine or special natural wine, sugar has been used, the wine or the residuum thereof may not be used if the unfermented sugars therein have been refermented. Such wine spirits shall not be reduced with water from distillation proof, nor be distilled, unless regulations otherwise provide, at less than 140 degrees of proof (except that commercial brandy aged in wood for a period of not less than 2 years, and barreled at not less than 100 degrees of proof, shall be deemed wine spirits for the purpose of this subsection).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4637b562-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Withdrawal of wine spirits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4637b563-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The proprietor of any bonded wine cellar may withdraw and receive wine spirits without payment of tax from the bonded premises of any distilled spirits plant, or from any bonded wine cellar as provided in paragraph (2), for use in the production of natural wine, for addition to concentrated or unconcentrated juice for use in wine production, or for such other uses as may be authorized in this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4637b564-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Wine spirits so withdrawn, and not used in wine production or as otherwise authorized in this subchapter, may, as provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be transferred to the bonded premises of any distilled spirits plant or bonded wine cellar, or may be taxpaid and removed as provided by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4637b565-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> On such use, transfer, or taxpayment, the Secretary shall credit the proprietor with the amount of wine spirits so used or transferred or taxpaid and, in addition, with such portion of wine spirits so withdrawn as may have been lost either in transit or on the bonded wine cellar premises, to the extent allowable under section 5008(a). Where the proprietor has used wine spirits in actual wine production but in violation of the requirements of this subchapter, the Secretary shall also extend such credit to the wine spirits so used if the proprietor satisfactorily shows that such wine spirits were not knowingly used in violation of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id4637b566-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Suitable samples of brandy or wine spirits may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be withdrawn free of tax from the bonded premises of any distilled spirits plant, bonded wine cellar, or authorized experimental premises, for analysis or testing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4637b567-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5373/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Distillates containing aldehydes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When the Secretary deems such removal and use will not jeopardize the revenue nor unduly increase administrative supervision, distillates containing aldehydes may, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, be removed without payment of tax from the bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant to an adjacent bonded wine cellar and used therein in fermentation of wine to be used as distilling material at the distilled spirits plant from which such unfinished distilled spirits were removed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4637b568-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/tII/s201">Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1382">72 Stat. 1382</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/619/s1">Pub. L. 90–619, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1236">82 Stat. 1236</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4637b569-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4637b56a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id4637b56b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 5373, <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/667">68A Stat. 667</ref>, consisted of provisions similar to those comprising this section, prior to the general revision of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4637b56c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/619">Pub. L. 90–619</ref> inserted special natural wine, under conditions prescribed by regulations, as one of the materials from which wine spirits may be produced and extended to special natural wines the existing prohibition on the use of natural wine whose sugars have been refermented.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4637b56d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4637b56e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/90/619/s6">Pub. L. 90–619, § 6</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1237">82 Stat. 1237</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/90/619/s6">“The amendments made by this Act [amending this section and sections 5382 to 5387 of this title] shall take effect on the first day of the first month which begins 90 days or more after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
