<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id43d2ea61-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547"><num value="547">§ 547.</num><heading> Deduction for deficiency dividends</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43d2ea62-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a determination (as defined in subsection (c)) with respect to a taxpayer establishes liability for personal holding company tax imposed by section 541 (or by a corresponding provision of a prior income tax law) for any taxable year, a deduction shall be allowed to the taxpayer for the amount of deficiency dividends (as defined in subsection (d)) for the purpose of determining the personal holding company tax for such year, but not for the purpose of determining interest, additional amounts, or assessable penalties computed with respect to such personal holding company tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43d2ea63-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules for application of section</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43d2ea64-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Allowance of deduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The deficiency dividend deduction shall be allowed as of the date the claim for the deficiency dividend deduction is filed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43d2ea65-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit or refund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the allowance of a deficiency dividend deduction results in an overpayment of personal holding company tax for any taxable year, credit or refund with respect to such overpayment shall be made as if on the date of the determination 2 years remained before the expiration of the period of limitation on the filing of claim for refund for the taxable year to which the overpayment relates. No interest shall be allowed on a credit or refund arising from the application of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43d2ea66-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “determination” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43d2ea67-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a decision by the Tax Court or a judgment, decree, or other order by any court of competent jurisdiction, which has become final;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43d2ea68-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a closing agreement made under section 7121; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43d2ea69-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, an agreement signed by the Secretary and by, or on behalf of, the taxpayer relating to the liability of such taxpayer for personal holding company tax.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43d5345a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Deficiency dividends</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43d5345b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “deficiency dividends” means the amount of the dividends paid by the corporation on or after the date of the determination and before filing claim under subsection (e), which would have been includible in the computation of the deduction for dividends paid under section 561 for the taxable year with respect to which the liability for personal holding company tax exists, if distributed during such taxable year. No dividends shall be considered as deficiency dividends for purposes of subsection (a) unless distributed within 90 days after the determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43d5345c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect on dividends paid deduction</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43d5345d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> For taxable year in which paid</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Deficiency dividends paid in any taxable year (to the extent of the portion thereof taken into account under subsection (a) in determining personal holding company tax) shall not be included in the amount of dividends paid for such year for purposes of computing the dividends paid deduction for such year and succeeding years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43d5345e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> For prior taxable year</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Deficiency dividends paid in any taxable year (to the extent of the portion thereof taken into account under subsection (a) in determining personal holding company tax) shall not be allowed for purposes of section 563(b) in the computation of the dividends paid deduction for the taxable year preceding the taxable year in which paid.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43d5345f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Claim required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No deficiency dividend deduction shall be allowed under subsection (a) unless (under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) claim therefor is filed within 120 days after the determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43d53460-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of statute of limitations and stay of collection</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43d53461-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of running of statute</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the corporation files a claim, as provided in subsection (e), the running of the statute of limitations provided in section 6501 on the making of assessments, and the bringing of distraint or a proceeding in court for collection, in respect of the deficiency and all interest, additional amounts, or assessable penalties, shall be suspended for a period of 2 years after the date of the determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43d53462-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Stay of collection</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by section 541 established by a determination under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43d53463-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the collection of the deficiency and all interest, additional amounts, and assessable penalties shall, except in cases of jeopardy, be stayed until the expiration of 120 days after the date of the determination, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43d53464-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if claim for deficiency dividend deduction is filed under subsection (e), the collection of such part of the deficiency as is not reduced by the deduction for deficiency dividends provided in subsection (a) shall be stayed until the date the claim is disallowed (in whole or in part) and if disallowed in part collection shall be made only with respect to the part disallowed.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">No distraint or proceeding in court shall be begun for the collection of an amount the collection of which is stayed under subparagraph (A) or (B) during the period for which the collection of such amount is stayed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43d53465-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s547/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Deduction denied in case of fraud, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No deficiency dividend deduction shall be allowed under subsection (a) if the determination contains a finding that any part of the deficiency is due to fraud with intent to evade tax, or to wilful failure to file an income tax return within the time prescribed by law or prescribed by the Secretary in pursuance of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id43d53466-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/191">68A Stat. 191</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1901(a)(78), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1777">90 Stat. 1777</ref>, 1834.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id43d53467-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id43d53468-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id43d53469-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsecs. (c)(3), (e), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/78">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(78)</ref>, struck out subsec. (h) relating to the effective date of provisions concerning deduction of deficiency dividends.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id43d5346a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43d5346b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/78">section 1901(a)(78) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/d">section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
