<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id46412a9f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5607"><num value="5607">§ 5607.</num><heading> Penalty and forfeiture for unlawful use, recovery, or concealment of denatured distilled spirits, or articles</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id46412aa0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5607/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> uses denatured distilled spirits withdrawn free of tax under section 5214(a)(1) in the manufacture of any medicinal preparation or flavoring extract in violation of the provisions of section 5273(b)(1) or knowingly sells, or offers for sale, any such medicinal preparation or flavoring extract in violation of section 5273(b)(2); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id46412aa1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5607/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> knowingly withdraws any denatured distilled spirits free of tax under section 5214(a)(1) for beverage purposes; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id46412aa2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5607/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> knowingly sells any denatured distilled spirits withdrawn free of tax under section 5214(a)(1), or any articles containing such denatured distilled spirits, for beverage purposes; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id46412aa3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5607/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> recovers or attempts to recover by redistillation or by any other process or means (except as authorized in section 5223 or in section 5273(c)) any distilled spirits from any denatured distilled spirits withdrawn free of tax under section 5214(a)(1), or from any articles manufactured therefrom, or knowingly uses, sells, conceals, or otherwise disposes of distilled spirits so recovered or redistilled;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both, for each such offense; and all personal property used in connection with his business, together with the buildings and ground constituting the premises on which such unlawful acts are performed or permitted to be performed shall be forfeited to the United States.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id46412aa4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/tII/s201">Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1402">72 Stat. 1402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id46412aa5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id46412aa6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id46412aa7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 5607, <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/684">68A Stat. 684</ref>, related to penalty for distilling on prohibited premises, prior to the general revision of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref>. See sections 5505(i) and 5601(a)(6) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those comprising this section were contained in prior section 5647, <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/693">68A Stat. 693</ref>, prior to the general revision of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
