<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id464f8250-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761"><num value="5761">§ 5761.</num><heading> Civil penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id464f8251-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitting things required or doing things forbidden</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever willfully omits, neglects, or refuses to comply with any duty imposed upon him by this chapter, or to do, or cause to be done, any of the things required by this chapter, or does anything prohibited by this chapter, shall in addition to any other penalty provided in this title, be liable to a penalty of $1,000, to be recovered, with costs of suit, in a civil action, except where a penalty under subsection (b) or (c) or under section 6651 or 6653 or part II of subchapter A of chapter 68 may be collected from such person by assessment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id464f8252-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to pay tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever fails to pay any tax imposed by this chapter at the time prescribed by law or regulations, shall, in addition to any other penalty provided in this title, be liable to a penalty of 5 percent of the tax due but unpaid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id464f8253-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale of tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes for export</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (d) of section 5704—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id464f8254-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> every person who sells, relands, or receives within the jurisdiction of the United States any tobacco products or cigarette papers or tubes which have been labeled or shipped for exportation under this chapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id464f8255-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> every person who sells or receives such relanded tobacco products or cigarette papers or tubes, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id464f8256-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> every person who aids or abets in such selling, relanding, or receiving,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall, in addition to the tax and any other penalty provided in this title, be liable for a penalty equal to the greater of $1,000 or 5 times the amount of the tax imposed by this chapter. All tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes relanded within the jurisdiction of the United States shall be forfeited to the United States and destroyed. All vessels, vehicles, and aircraft used in such relanding or in removing such products, papers, and tubes from the place where relanded, shall be forfeited to the United States. This subsection and section 5754 shall not apply to any person who relands or receives tobacco products in the quantity allowed entry free of tax and duty under subchapter IV of chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States. No quantity of tobacco products other than the quantity referred to in the preceding sentence may be relanded or received as a personal use quantity.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id464f8257-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Personal use quantities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id464f8258-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No quantity of tobacco products other than the quantity referred to in paragraph (2) may be relanded or received as a personal use quantity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id464f8259-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for personal use quantity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subsection (c) and section 5754 shall not apply to any person who relands or receives tobacco products in the quantity allowed entry free of tax and duty under chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, and such person may voluntarily relinquish to the Secretary at the time of entry any excess of such quantity without incurring the penalty under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id464f825a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for delivery sales</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id464f825b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Paragraph (2) shall not apply to any tobacco product sold in connection with a delivery sale.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id464f825c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Delivery sale</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “delivery sale” means any sale of a tobacco product to a consumer if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id464f825d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the consumer submits the order for such sale by means of a telephone or other method of voice transmission, the mail, or the Internet or other online service, or the seller is otherwise not in the physical presence of the buyer when the request for purchase or order is made, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id464f825e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/d/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the tobacco product is delivered by use of a common carrier, private delivery service, or the mail, or the seller is not in the physical presence of the buyer when the buyer obtains personal possession of the tobacco product.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id464f825f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of section 6665</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The penalties imposed by subsections (b) and (c) shall be assessed, collected, and paid in the same manner as taxes, as provided in section 6665(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id464f8260-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s5761/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For penalty for failure to make deposits or for over­statement of deposits, see section 6656.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id464f8261-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/717">68A Stat. 717</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/tII/s202">Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1425">72 Stat. 1425</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tVII">Pub. L. 97–34, title VII</ref>, §§ 722(a)(3), 724(b)(5), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/342">95 Stat. 342</ref>, 345; <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/tI/s107/b">Pub. L. 97–448, title I, § 107(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2391">96 Stat. 2391</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tVII/s714/h/2">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 714(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/962">98 Stat. 962</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7721/c/4">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7721(c)(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2399">103 Stat. 2399</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIX/s9302/h/1/B">Pub. L. 105–33, title IX, § 9302(h)(1)(B)</ref>–(D), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/673">111 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/476/tIV">Pub. L. 106–476, title IV</ref>, §§ 4002(c), 4003(a), <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2177">114 Stat. 2177</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/7/tIII/s315/a/3">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 315(a)(3)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–644; <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dC/tIV/s401/f/1">Pub. L. 109–432, div. C, title IV, § 401(f)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3049">120 Stat. 3049</ref>, 3050.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id464f8262-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id464f8263-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id464f8264-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (d)(2), is not set out in the Code. See Publication of Harmonized Tariff Schedule note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">section 1202 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id464f8265-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/f/2/A">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(f)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out at end “This subsection and section 5754 shall not apply to any person who relands or receives tobacco products in the quantity allowed entry free of tax and duty under chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, and such person may voluntarily relinquish to the Secretary at the time of entry any excess of such quantity without incurring the penalty under this subsection. No quantity of tobacco products other than the quantity referred to in the preceding sentence may be relanded or received as a personal use quantity.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/f/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 401(f)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsecs. (d) and (e) as (e) and (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref> inserted at end “This subsection and section 5754 shall not apply to any person who relands or receives tobacco products in the quantity allowed entry free of tax and duty under chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, and such person may voluntarily relinquish to the Secretary at the time of entry any excess of such quantity without incurring the penalty under this subsection. No quantity of tobacco products other than the quantity referred to in the preceding sentence may be relanded or received as a personal use quantity.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/476/s4003/a">Pub. L. 106–476, § 4003(a)</ref>, inserted at end “This subsection and section 5754 shall not apply to any person who relands or receives tobacco products in the quantity allowed entry free of tax and duty under subchapter IV of chapter 98 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States. No quantity of tobacco products other than the quantity referred to in the preceding sentence may be relanded or received as a personal use quantity.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/476/s4002/c">Pub. L. 106–476, § 4002(c)</ref>, which directed amendment of the last sentence of subsec. (c) by substituting “the jurisdiction of the United States shall be forfeited to the United States and destroyed. All vessels, vehicles, and aircraft used in such relanding or in removing such products, papers, and tubes from the place where relanded, shall be forfeited to the United States.” for “the jurisdiction of the United States” and all that followed through the end period, was executed by making the substitution for “the jurisdiction of the United States, and all vessels, vehicles, and aircraft used in such relanding or in removing such products, papers, and tubes from the place where relanded, shall be forfeited to the United States.” in the second sentence of subsec. (c) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the intervening retroactive amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/106/476/s4003/a">Pub. L. 106–476, § 4003(a)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref>. See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s9302/h/1/C">Pub. L. 105–33, § 9302(h)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b) or (c)” for “subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s9302/h/1/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 9302(h)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s9302/h/1/D">Pub. L. 105–33, § 9302(h)(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “The penalties imposed by subsections (b) and (c)” for “The penalty imposed by subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s9302/h/1/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 9302(h)(1)(B)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s9302/h/1/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 9302(h)(1)(B)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7721/c/4">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7721(c)(4)</ref>, inserted “or part II of subchapter A of chapter 68” after “or 6653”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7721/c/5">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7721(c)(5)</ref>, substituted “6665” for “6662” in heading and “6665(a)” for “6662(a)” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> substituted “section 6662” for “section 6660” in heading and “section 6662(a)” for “section 6660(a)” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448">Pub. L. 97–448</ref> substituted “section 6660” for “section 6659” in heading, and substituted “section 6660(a)” for “section 6659(a)” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s724/b/5">Pub. L. 97–34, § 724(b)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (c). Former subsec. (c), which related to applicability of section 6656 to failure to make deposit of taxes imposed under subchapter A on the prescribed date and imposition of penalty, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, §§ 722(a)(3), 724(b)(5), added subsec. (d). Former subsec. (d), which related to applicability of section 6660 and penalties imposed by subsections (b) and (c) to be assessed, collected, and paid in the manner as taxes provided in section 6660(a), was struck out. See subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> struck out reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6652">section 6652 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted provisions relating to failure to pay tax for provisions which made persons willfully failing to pay a tax liable, in addition to any other penalty provided in this title, to a penalty of the amount of the tax evaded, or not paid.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> substituted provisions relating to failure to make deposit of taxes for provisions which authorized a penalty of 5 percent of the tax due but unpaid where a person failed to pay tax at the time prescribed, and required the penalties to be added to the tax and assessed and collected at the same time, in the same manner, and as a part of the tax.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> added subsec. (d). Similar provisions were formerly contained in subsec. (c) of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id464f8266-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f8267-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/432">Pub. L. 109–432</ref> applicable with respect to goods entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after the 15th day after <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s401/g">section 401(g) of Pub. L. 109–432</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1681">section 1681 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f8268-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref> effective as if included in section 9302 of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, see section 1(a)(7) [title III, § 315(b)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5702">section 5702 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/476/s4002">section 4002 of Pub. L. 106–476</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/476/s4002/d">section 4002(d) of Pub. L. 106–476</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5704">section 5704 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/476/tIV/s4003/b">Pub. L. 106–476, title IV, § 4003(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2178">114 Stat. 2178</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/476/tIV/s4003/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect as if included in section 9302 of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 [<ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f8269-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> applicable to articles removed, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5702/j">section 5702(j) of this title</ref>, after <date date="1999-12-31">Dec. 31, 1999</date>, with transition rule, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s9302/i">section 9302(i) of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5701">section 5701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f826a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> applicable to returns the due date for which (determined without regard to extensions) is after <date date="1989-12-31">Dec. 31, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7721/d">section 7721(d) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f826b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s715">section 715 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f826c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/448">Pub. L. 97–448</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if it had been included in the provision of the Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981, <ref href="/us/pl/97/34">Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/s109">section 109 of Pub. L. 97–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f826d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s722/a/3">section 722(a)(3) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to returns filed after <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s722/a/4">section 722(a)(4) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5684">section 5684 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s724/b/5">section 724(b)(5) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to returns filed after <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s724/c">section 724(c) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6656">section 6656 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id464f826e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/859">Pub. L. 85–859</ref> effective <date date="1958-09-03">Sept. 3, 1958</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/859/s210/a/1">section 210(a)(1) of Pub. L. 85–859</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5001">section 5001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
