<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id46735ec6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046"><num value="6046">§ 6046.</num><heading> Returns as to organization or reorganization of foreign corporations and as to acquisitions of their stock</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46735ec7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement of return</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46735ec8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A return complying with the requirements of subsection (b) shall be made by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46735ec9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> each United States citizen or resident who becomes an officer or director of a foreign corporation if a United States person (as defined in section 7701(a)(30)) meets the stock ownership requirements of paragraph (2) with respect to such corporation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46735eca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> each United States person—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46735ecb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> who acquires stock which, when added to any stock owned on the date of such acquisition, meets the stock ownership requirements of paragraph (2) with respect to a foreign corporation, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46735ecc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> who acquires stock which, without regard to stock owned on the date of such acquisition, meets the stock ownership requirements of paragraph (2) with respect to a foreign corporation,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46735ecd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> each person (not described in subparagraph (B)) who is treated as a United States shareholder under section 953(c) with respect to a foreign corporation, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46735ece-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> each person who becomes a United States person while meeting the stock ownership requirements of paragraph (2) with respect to stock of a foreign corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In the case of a foreign corporation with respect to which any person is treated as a United States shareholder under section 953(c), subparagraph (A) shall be treated as including a reference to each United States person who is an officer or director of such corporation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46735ecf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Stock ownership requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person meets the stock ownership requirements of this paragraph with respect to any corporation if such person owns 10 percent or more of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46735ed0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the total combined voting power of all classes of stock of such corporation entitled to vote, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46735ed1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the total value of the stock of such corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46735ed2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Form and contents of returns</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The returns required by subsection (a) shall be in such form and shall set forth, in respect of the foreign corporation, such information as the Secretary prescribes by forms or regulations as necessary for carrying out the provisions of the income tax laws, except that in the case of persons described only in subsection (a)(1)(A) the information required shall be limited to the names and addresses of persons described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46735ed3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Ownership of stock</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), stock owned directly or indirectly by a person (including, in the case of an individual, stock owned by members of his family) shall be taken into account. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the family of an individual shall be considered as including only his brothers and sisters (whether by the whole or half blood), spouse, ancestors, and lineal descendants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46735ed4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for filing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any return required by subsection (a) shall be filed on or before the 90th day after the day on which, under any provision of subsection (a), the United States citizen, resident, or person becomes liable to file such return (or on or before such later day as the Secretary may by forms or regulations prescribe).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4675a8c5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No information shall be required to be furnished under this section with respect to any foreign corporation unless such information was required to be furnished under regulations which have been in effect for at least 90 days before the date on which the United States citizen, resident, or person becomes liable to file a return required under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4675a8c6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6046/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions relating to penalties for violations of this section, sections 6679 and 7203.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4675a8c7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/747">68A Stat. 747</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/780/s7/a">Pub. L. 86–780, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-09-14">Sept. 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/1016">74 Stat. 1016</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s20/b">Pub. L. 87–834, § 20(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1061">76 Stat. 1061</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/a/4">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(4)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1824">90 Stat. 1824</ref>, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s341/a">Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/635">96 Stat. 635</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1012/i/19">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1012(i)(19)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3510">102 Stat. 3510</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1146/a">Pub. L. 105–34, title XI, § 1146(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/986">111 Stat. 986</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/172/s11/a/33">Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(33)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2487">121 Stat. 2487</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4675a8c8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4675a8c9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4675a8ca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/172">Pub. L. 110–172</ref> substituted “subsection (a)(1)(A)” for “subsection (a)(1)” and “subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a)(1)” for “paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “A return complying with the requirements of subsection (b) shall be made by—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) each United States citizen or resident who is on <date date="1963-01-01">January 1, 1963</date>, an officer or director of a foreign corporation, 5 percent or more in value of the stock of which is owned by a United States person (as defined in section 7701(a)(30)), or who becomes such an officer or director at any time after such date,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) each United States person who on <date date="1963-01-01">January 1, 1963</date>, owns 5 percent or more in value of the stock of a foreign corporation, or who, at any time after such date—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(A) acquires stock which, when added to any stock owned on <date date="1963-01-01">January 1, 1963</date>, has a value equal to 5 percent or more of the value of the stock of a foreign corporation, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(B) acquires an additional 5 percent or more in value of the stock of a foreign corporation,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) each person (not described in paragraph (2)) who, at any time after <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, is treated as a United States shareholder under section 953(c) with respect to a foreign corporation, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) each person who at any time after <date date="1963-01-01">January 1, 1963</date>, becomes a United States person while owning 5 percent or more in value of the stock of a foreign corporation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of a foreign corporation with respect to which any person is treated as a United States shareholder under section 953(c), paragraph (1) shall be treated as including a reference to each United States person who is an officer or director of such corporation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/i/19/C">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(i)(19)(C)</ref>, inserted sentence at end relating to foreign corporation with respect to which any person is treated as a United States shareholder under section 953(c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/i/19/A">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(i)(19)(A)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/i/19/B">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(i)(19)(B)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a)” for “subsection (a)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> inserted “(or on or before such later day as the Secretary may by forms or regulations prescribe)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/a/4">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(a)(4)</ref>, struck out provisions relating to the requirement for information to be furnished in the case of liability to file a return under subsec. (a) of this section arising on or after <date date="1963-01-01">Jan. 1, 1963</date>, and before <date date="1963-06-01">June 1, 1963</date>, under regulations in effect on or before <date date="1963-06-01">June 1, 1963</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> substituted “organization or reorganization of foreign corporations and as to acquisitions of their stock” for “creation or organization, or reorganization, of foreign corporations” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) <inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—On or before the 90th day after the creation or organization, or reorganization, of any foreign corporation—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) Each United States citizen or resident who was an officer or director of the corporation at any time within 60 days after the creation or organization, or reorganization thereof, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) Each United States shareholder of the corporation by or for whom, at any time within 60 days after the creation or organization or reorganization of the corporation, 5 percent or more in value of the stock of the corporation outstanding was owned directly or indirectly (including, in the case of an individual, stock owned by members of his family),</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall make a return in compliance with the provisions of subsection (b).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> inserted the exception providing that in the case of persons described only in subsec. (a)(1) the information required shall be limited to the names and addresses of persons described in subsec. (a)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> substituted provisions requiring, for purposes of subsec. (a), stock owned directly or indirectly by a person (including, in the case of an individual, stock owned by members of his family) to be taken into account for provisions which defined “United States shareholder”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> added subsecs. (d) and (e) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (f) and inserted a reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6679">section 6679 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/780">Pub. L. 86–780</ref> substituted “Returns as to creation or organization, or reorganization, of foreign corporations” for “Returns as to formation or reorganization of foreign corporations” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/86/780">Pub. L. 86–780</ref> substituted requirement that returns relating to the creation, organization, or reorganization of foreign corporations be made by every citizen or resident of the United States who was an officer or director of the corporation at any time within 60 days after its creation, organization, or reorganization, and by every United States shareholder of the corporation owning at least 5 percent of its outstanding stock at any time within such 60 days for requirement that every attorney, accountant, fiduciary, bank, trust company, financial institution, or other person, who advises as to the formation or reorganization of a foreign corporation, file a return in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/86/780">Pub. L. 86–780</ref> reenacted the substance of subsec. (b), struck out “to the full extent of the information within the possession or knowledge or under the control of the person required to make the return” before “such information”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/86/780">Pub. L. 86–780</ref> inserted the provisions defining United States shareholder and members of family and struck out provision relating to the making of a return by an attorney-at-law with respect to privileged communications.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4675a8cb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4675a8cc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1146/b">Pub. L. 105–34, title XI, § 1146(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/986">111 Stat. 986</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1146/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="1998-01-01">January 1, 1998</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4675a8cd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4675a8ce-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s341/c">Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 341(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/635">96 Stat. 635</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s341/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6048">section 6048 of this title</ref>] shall apply to returns filed after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4675a8cf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s20/e/2">Pub. L. 87–834, § 20(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1063">76 Stat. 1063</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/87/834/s20/e/2">“The amendments made by subsection (b) [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="1963-01-01">January 1, 1963</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4675a8d0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1960 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/86/780/s8">Pub. L. 86–780, § 8</ref>, <date date="1960-09-14">Sept. 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/1016">74 Stat. 1016</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/86/780/s8">“The amendments made by section 7 [amending this section] shall apply only with respect to foreign corporations created or organized, or reorganized, after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1960-09-14">Sept. 14, 1960</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
