<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id46b60ce2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205"><num value="6205">§ 6205.</num><heading> Special rules applicable to certain employment taxes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46b60ce3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment of tax</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46b60ce4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If less than the correct amount of tax imposed by section 3101, 3111, 3201, 3221, or 3402 is paid with respect to any payment of wages or compensation, proper adjustments, with respect to both the tax and the amount to be deducted, shall be made, without interest, in such manner and at such times as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46b60ce5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> United States as employer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received from the United States or a wholly-owned instrumentality thereof during any calendar year, each head of a Federal agency or instrumentality who makes a return pursuant to section 3122 and each agent, designated by the head of a Federal agency or instrumentality, who makes a return pursuant to such section shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46b60ce6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Guam or American Samoa as employer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received during any calendar year from the Government of Guam, the Government of American Samoa, a political subdivision of either, or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, the Governor of Guam, the Governor of American Samoa, and each agent designated by either who makes a return pursuant to section 3125 shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46b60ce7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> District of Columbia as employer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received during any calendar year from the District of Columbia or any instrumentality which is wholly owned thereby, the Mayor of the District of Columbia and each agent designated by him who makes a return pursuant to section 3125 shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46b60ce8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> States and political subdivisions as employer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received from a State or any political subdivision thereof (or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby) during any calendar year, each head of an agency or instrumentality, and each agent designated by either, who makes a return pursuant to section 3125 shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46b60ce9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6205/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Underpayments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If less than the correct amount of tax imposed by section 3101, 3111, 3201, 3221, or 3402 is paid or deducted with respect to any payment of wages or compensation and the underpayment cannot be adjusted under subsection (a) of this section, the amount of the underpayment shall be assessed and collected in such manner and at such times (subject to the statute of limitations properly applicable thereto) as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id46b60cea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/768">68A Stat. 768</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/778/tI/s103/r/1">Pub. L. 86–778, title I, § 103(r)(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/940">74 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/tIII/s317/d">Pub. L. 89–97, title III, § 317(d)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/389">79 Stat. 389</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/a/13">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(13)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1825">90 Stat. 1825</ref>, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXIII/s13205/a/2/D">Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13205(a)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/315">100 Stat. 315</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id46b60ceb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id46b60cec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id46b60ced-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/a/13">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(a)(13)</ref>, substituted “Mayor of the District of Columbia and each agent designated by him” for “Commissioners of the District of Columbia and each agent designated by them” after “owned thereby, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/89/97">Pub. L. 89–97</ref> added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/86/778">Pub. L. 86–778</ref> added par. (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id46b60cee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46b60cef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> applicable to services performed after <date date="1986-03-31">Mar. 31, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s13205/d/1">section 13205(d)(1) of Pub. L. 99–272</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3121">section 3121 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46b60cf0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective on first day of first month which begins more than 90 days after <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/d/1">section 1906(d)(1) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6013">section 6013 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46b60cf1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1965 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/97">Pub. L. 89–97</ref> applicable with respect to services performed after quarter ending <date date="1965-09-30">Sept. 30, 1965</date>, and after quarter in which Secretary of the Treasury receives a certification from Commissioners of District of Columbia expressing their desire to have insurance system established by sections 401 et seq. and 1395c et seq. of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, extended to officers and employees coming under provisions of such amendments, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s317/g">section 317(g) of Pub. L. 89–97</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s410">section 410 of Title 42</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46b60cf2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1960 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/86/778">Pub. L. 86–778</ref> applicable only with respect to (1) service in the employ of the Government of Guam or any political subdivision thereof, or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing wholly owned thereby, which is performed after 1960 and after the calendar quarter in which the Secretary of the Treasury receives a certification by the Governor of Guam that legislation has been enacted by the Government of Guam expressing its desire to have the insurance system established by title II of the Social Security Act, section 401 et seq. of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, extended to the officers and employees of such Government and such political subdivisions and instrumentalities, and (2) service in the employ of the Government of American Samoa or any political subdivision thereof or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing wholly owned thereby, which is performed after 1960 and after the calendar quarter in which the Secretary of the Treasury receives a certification by the Governor of American Samoa that the Government of American Samoa desires to have the insurance system established by title II of the Social Security Act, section 401 et seq. of Title 42, extended to the officers and employees of such Government and such political subdivisions and instrumentalities, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/778/s103/v/1">section 103(v)(1) of Pub. L. 86–778</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">section 402 of Title 42</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
