<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id46d50683-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402"><num value="6402">§ 6402.</num><heading> Authority to make credits or refunds</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d50684-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any overpayment, the Secretary, within the applicable period of limitations, may credit the amount of such overpayment, including any interest allowed thereon, against any liability in respect of an internal revenue tax on the part of the person who made the overpayment and shall, subject to subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f), refund any balance to such person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77785-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Credits against estimated tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to prescribe regulations providing for the crediting against the estimated income tax for any taxable year of the amount determined by the taxpayer or the Secretary to be an overpayment of the income tax for a preceding taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77786-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Offset of past-due support against overpayments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amount of any overpayment to be refunded to the person making the overpayment shall be reduced by the amount of any past-due support (as defined in section 464(c) of the Social Security Act) owed by that person of which the Secretary has been notified by a State in accordance with section 464 of such Act. The Secretary shall remit the amount by which the overpayment is so reduced to the State collecting such support and notify the person making the overpayment that so much of the overpayment as was necessary to satisfy his obligation for past-due support has been paid to the State. The Secretary shall apply a reduction under this subsection first to an amount certified by the State as past due support under section 464 of the Social Security Act before any other reductions allowed by law. This subsection shall be applied to an overpayment prior to its being credited to a person’s future liability for an internal revenue tax. For purposes of this subsection, any reference to a State shall include a reference to any Indian tribe or tribal organization receiving a grant under section 455(f) of the Social Security Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77787-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection of debts owed to Federal agencies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77788-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receiving notice from any Federal agency that a named person owes a past-due legally enforceable debt (other than past-due support subject to the provisions of subsection (c)) to such agency, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d77789-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reduce the amount of any overpayment payable to such person by the amount of such debt;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d7778a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> pay the amount by which such overpayment is reduced under subparagraph (A) to such agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d7778b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> notify the person making such overpayment that such overpayment has been reduced by an amount necessary to satisfy such debt.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d7778c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Priorities for offset</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any overpayment by a person shall be reduced pursuant to this subsection after such overpayment is reduced pursuant to subsection (c) with respect to past-due support collected pursuant to an assignment under section 408(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s608/a/3">42 U.S.C. 608(a)(3)</ref>) and before such overpayment is reduced pursuant to subsections (e) and (f) and before such overpayment is credited to the future liability for tax of such person pursuant to subsection (b). If the Secretary receives notice from a Federal agency or agencies of more than one debt subject to paragraph (1) that is owed by a person to such agency or agencies, any overpayment by such person shall be applied against such debts in the order in which such debts accrued.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d7778d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of OASDI overpayments</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id46d7778e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to an OASDI overpayment only if the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3720A/f">section 3720A(f) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, are met with respect to such overpayment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id46d7778f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice; protection of other persons filing joint return</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77790-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of a debt consisting of an OASDI overpayment, if the Secretary determines upon receipt of the notice referred to in paragraph (1) that the refund from which the reduction described in paragraph (1)(A) would be made is based upon a joint return, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id46d77791-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> notify each taxpayer filing such joint return that the reduction is being made from a refund based upon such return, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id46d77792-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> include in such notification a description of the procedures to be followed, in the case of a joint return, to protect the share of the refund which may be payable to another person.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77793-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments based on protections given to other taxpayers on joint return</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the other person filing a joint return with the person owing the OASDI overpayment takes appropriate action to secure his or her proper share of the refund subject to reduction under this subsection, the Secretary shall pay such share to such other person. The Secretary shall deduct the amount of such payment from amounts which are derived from subsequent reductions in refunds under this subsection and are payable to a trust fund referred to in subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77794-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposit of amount of reduction into appropriate trust fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In lieu of payment, pursuant to paragraph (1)(B), of the amount of any reduction under this subsection to the Commissioner of Social Security, the Secretary shall deposit such amount in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, whichever is certified to the Secretary as appropriate by the Commissioner of Social Security.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77795-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/d/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> OASDI overpayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “OASDI overpayment” means any overpayment of benefits made to an individual under title II of the Social Security Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77796-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection of past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d77797-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receiving notice from any State that a named person owes a past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligation to such State, the Secretary shall, under such conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d77798-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reduce the amount of any overpayment payable to such person by the amount of such State income tax obligation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d77799-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> pay the amount by which such overpayment is reduced under subparagraph (A) to such State and notify such State of such person’s name, taxpayer identification number, address, and the amount collected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d7779a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> notify the person making such overpayment that the overpayment has been reduced by an amount necessary to satisfy a past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If an offset is made pursuant to a joint return, the notice under subparagraph (B) shall include the names, taxpayer identification numbers, and addresses of each person filing such return.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d7779b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Offset permitted only against residents of State seeking offset</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall apply to an overpayment by any person for a taxable year only if the address shown on the Federal return for such taxable year of the overpayment is an address within the State seeking the offset.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d7779c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Priorities for offset</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any overpayment by a person shall be reduced pursuant to this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d7779d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> after such overpayment is reduced pursuant to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d7779e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subsection (a) with respect to any liability for any internal revenue tax on the part of the person who made the overpayment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d7779f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subsection (c) with respect to past-due support; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d777a0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> subsection (d) with respect to any past-due, legally enforceable debt owed to a Federal agency; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777a1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> before such overpayment is credited to the future liability for any Federal internal revenue tax of such person pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If the Secretary receives notice from one or more agencies of the State of more than one debt subject to paragraph (1) or subsection (f) that is owed by such person to such an agency, any overpayment by such person shall be applied against such debts in the order in which such debts accrued.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777a2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice; consideration of evidence</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No State may take action under this subsection until such State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777a3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> notifies by certified mail with return receipt the person owing the past-due State income tax liability that the State proposes to take action pursuant to this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777a4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> gives such person at least 60 days to present evidence that all or part of such liability is not past-due or not legally enforceable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777a5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> considers any evidence presented by such person and determines that an amount of such debt is past-due and legally enforceable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777a6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> satisfies such other conditions as the Secretary may prescribe to ensure that the determination made under subparagraph (C) is valid and that the State has made reasonable efforts to obtain payment of such State income tax obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777a7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligation” means a debt—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777a8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777a9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> which resulted from—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d777aa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/5/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a judgment rendered by a court of competent jurisdiction which has determined an amount of State income tax to be due; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d777ab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/5/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a determination after an administrative hearing which has determined an amount of State income tax to be due; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777ac-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> which is no longer subject to judicial review; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777ad-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which resulted from a State income tax which has been assessed but not collected, the time for redetermination of which has expired, and which has not been delinquent for more than 10 years.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “State income tax” includes any local income tax administered by the chief tax administration agency of the State.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777ae-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall issue regulations prescribing the time and manner in which States must submit notices of past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligations and the necessary information that must be contained in or accompany such notices. The regulations shall specify the types of State income taxes and the minimum amount of debt to which the reduction procedure established by paragraph (1) may be applied. The regulations may require States to pay a fee to reimburse the Secretary for the cost of applying such procedure. Any fee paid to the Secretary pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be used to reimburse appropriations which bore all or part of the cost of applying such procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777af-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/e/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Erroneous payment to State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any State receiving notice from the Secretary that an erroneous payment has been made to such State under paragraph (1) shall pay promptly to the Secretary, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, an amount equal to the amount of such erroneous payment (without regard to whether any other amounts payable to such State under such paragraph have been paid to such State).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777b0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection of unemployment compensation debts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777b1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receiving notice from any State that a named person owes a covered unemployment compensation debt to such State, the Secretary shall, under such conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777b2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reduce the amount of any overpayment payable to such person by the amount of such covered unemployment compensation debt;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777b3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> pay the amount by which such overpayment is reduced under subparagraph (A) to such State and notify such State of such person’s name, taxpayer identification number, address, and the amount collected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777b4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> notify the person making such overpayment that the overpayment has been reduced by an amount necessary to satisfy a covered unemployment compensation debt.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If an offset is made pursuant to a joint return, the notice under subparagraph (C) shall include information related to the rights of a spouse of a person subject to such an offset.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777b5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Priorities for offset</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any overpayment by a person shall be reduced pursuant to this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777b6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> after such overpayment is reduced pursuant to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d777b7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subsection (a) with respect to any liability for any internal revenue tax on the part of the person who made the overpayment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d777b8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subsection (c) with respect to past-due support; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id46d777b9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> subsection (d) with respect to any past-due, legally enforceable debt owed to a Federal agency; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777ba-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> before such overpayment is credited to the future liability for any Federal internal revenue tax of such person pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If the Secretary receives notice from a State or States of more than one debt subject to paragraph (1) or subsection (e) that is owed by a person to such State or States, any overpayment by such person shall be applied against such debts in the order in which such debts accrued.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777bb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice; consideration of evidence</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No State may take action under this subsection until such State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777bc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> notifies the person owing the covered unemployment compensation debt that the State proposes to take action pursuant to this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777bd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provides such person at least 60 days to present evidence that all or part of such liability is not legally enforceable or is not a covered unemployment compensation debt;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777be-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> considers any evidence presented by such person and determines that an amount of such debt is legally enforceable and is a covered unemployment compensation debt; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777bf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> satisfies such other conditions as the Secretary may prescribe to ensure that the determination made under subparagraph (C) is valid and that the State has made reasonable efforts to obtain payment of such covered unemployment compensation debt.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777c0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered unemployment compensation debt</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “covered unemployment compensation debt” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777c1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a past-due debt for erroneous payment of unemployment compensation due to fraud or the person’s failure to report earnings which has become final under the law of a State certified by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to section 3304 and which remains uncollected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777c2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> contributions due to the unemployment fund of a State for which the State has determined the person to be liable and which remain uncollected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777c3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any penalties and interest assessed on such debt.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777c4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777c5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may issue regulations prescribing the time and manner in which States must submit notices of covered unemployment compensation debt and the necessary information that must be contained in or accompany such notices. The regulations may specify the minimum amount of debt to which the reduction procedure established by paragraph (1) may be applied.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777c6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Fee payable to Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The regulations may require States to pay a fee to the Secretary, which may be deducted from amounts collected, to reimburse the Secretary for the cost of applying such procedure. Any fee paid to the Secretary pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be used to reimburse appropriations which bore all or part of the cost of applying such procedure.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777c7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of notices through Secretary of Labor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The regulations may include a requirement that States submit notices of covered unemployment compensation debt to the Secretary via the Secretary of Labor in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary of Labor. Such procedures may require States to pay a fee to the Secretary of Labor to reimburse the Secretary of Labor for the costs of applying this subsection. Any such fee shall be established in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury. Any fee paid to the Secretary of Labor may be deducted from amounts collected and shall be used to reimburse the appropriation account which bore all or part of the cost of applying this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777c8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Erroneous payment to State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any State receiving notice from the Secretary that an erroneous payment has been made to such State under paragraph (1) shall pay promptly to the Secretary, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, an amount equal to the amount of such erroneous payment (without regard to whether any other amounts payable to such State under such paragraph have been paid to such State).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777c9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of reductions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No court of the United States shall have jurisdiction to hear any action, whether legal or equitable, brought to restrain or review a reduction authorized by subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f). No such reduction shall be subject to review by the Secretary in an administrative proceeding. No action brought against the United States to recover the amount of any such reduction shall be considered to be a suit for refund of tax. This subsection does not preclude any legal, equitable, or administrative action against the Federal agency or State to which the amount of such reduction was paid or any such action against the Commissioner of Social Security which is otherwise available with respect to recoveries of overpayments of benefits under section 204 of the Social Security Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777ca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “Federal agency” means a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, and includes a Government corporation (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s103">section 103 of title 5</ref>, United States Code).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777cb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of payments to States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may provide that, for purposes of determining interest, the payment of any amount withheld under subsection (c), (e), or (f) to a State shall be treated as a payment to the person or persons making the overpayment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777cc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For procedures relating to agency notification of the Secretary, see <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3721">section 3721 of title 31</ref>, United States Code.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777cd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Refunds to certain fiduciaries of insolvent members of affiliated groups</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of an insolvent corporation which is a member of an affiliated group of corporations filing a consolidated return for any taxable year and which is subject to a statutory or court-appointed fiduciary, the Secretary may by regulation provide that any refund for such taxable year may be paid on behalf of such insolvent corporation to such fiduciary to the extent that the Secretary determines that the refund is attributable to losses or credits of such insolvent corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777ce-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Explanation of reason for refund disallowance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a disallowance of a claim for refund, the Secretary shall provide the taxpayer with an explanation for such disallowance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777cf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Earliest date for certain refunds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No credit or refund of an overpayment for a taxable year shall be made to a taxpayer before the 15th day of the second month following the close of such taxable year if a credit is allowed to such taxpayer under section 24 (by reason of subsection (d) thereof) or 32 for such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id46d777d0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Misdirected direct deposit refund</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than the date which is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Taxpayer First Act, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations to establish procedures to allow for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id46d777d1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/n/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> taxpayers to report instances in which a refund made by the Secretary by electronic funds transfer was not transferred to the account of the taxpayer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id46d777d2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/n/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> coordination with financial institutions for the purpose of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777d3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/n/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identifying the accounts to which transfers described in paragraph (1) were made; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id46d777d4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/n/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> recovery of the amounts so transferred; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id46d777d5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6402/n/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the refund to be delivered to the correct account of the taxpayer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id46d777d6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-06/ch736">Aug. 6, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/791">68A Stat. 791</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)</ref> (A), (K), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>, 1835; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXIII/s2331/c">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXIII, § 2331(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/861">95 Stat. 861</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2653/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2653(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1154">98 Stat. 1154</ref>, 1155; <ref href="/us/pl/98/378/s21/e">Pub. L. 98–378, § 21(e)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-16">Aug. 16, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1325">98 Stat. 1325</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tVI/s6276">Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6276</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3753">102 Stat. 3753</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5129/c">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5129(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-288">104 Stat. 1388–288</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s108/h/7">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(h)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1487">108 Stat. 1487</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tIII/s31001/u/2">Pub. L. 104–134, title III, § 31001(u)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-375">110 Stat. 1321–375</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tI/s110">Pub. L. 104–193, title I, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7), <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2173">110 Stat. 2173</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5514/a/1">Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5514(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/620">111 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIII">Pub. L. 105–206, title III</ref>, §§ 3505(a), 3711(a), (c), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/771">112 Stat. 771</ref>, 779, 781; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tVII/s7301/d">Pub. L. 109–171, title VII, § 7301(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/144">120 Stat. 144</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/a">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(a)</ref>, (d), <date date="2008-09-30">Sept. 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3570">122 Stat. 3570</ref>, 3573; <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/tVIII/s801/a">Pub. L. 111–291, title VIII, § 801(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-08">Dec. 8, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3157">124 Stat. 3157</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/312/tV/s503/a">Pub. L. 111–312, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-17">Dec. 17, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3308">124 Stat. 3308</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dQ/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/3076">129 Stat. 3076</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/a/285">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(285)</ref>–(287), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1198">132 Stat. 1198</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/25/tI/s1407">Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1407</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1001">133 Stat. 1001</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/258/tII/s202/a/2/F">Pub. L. 118–258, title II, § 202(a)(2)(F)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2972">138 Stat. 2972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id46d777d7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id46d777d8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id46d777d9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsecs. (c), (d)(3)(D), and (g), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 401 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Sections 204, 455, and 464 of the Act are classified to sections 404, 655, and 664, respectively, of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Taxpayer First Act, referred to in subsec. (n), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/25">Pub. L. 116–25</ref>, which was approved <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id46d777da-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/118/258">Pub. L. 118–258</ref> inserted at end “For purposes of this subsection, any reference to a State shall include a reference to any Indian tribe or tribal organization receiving a grant under section 455(f) of the Social Security Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/116/25">Pub. L. 116–25</ref> added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/285">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(285)</ref>, substituted “(f), refund” for “(f) refund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/286">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(286)</ref>, substituted “of such Act” for “of of such Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/287">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(287)</ref>, substituted “section 408(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s608/a/3">42 U.S.C. 608(a)(3)</ref>)” for “section 402(a)(26) of the Social Security Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref> added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/1">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “resulting from fraud” after “debts” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/2">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (3) and struck out former par. (3). Prior to amendment, text of par. (3) read as follows: “Paragraph (1) shall apply to an overpayment by any person for a taxable year only if the address shown on the Federal return for such taxable year of the overpayment is an address within the State seeking the offset.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/3/A">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(3)(A)</ref>, struck out “by certified mail with return receipt” after “notifies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/3/B">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “is not a covered unemployment compensation debt” for “due to fraud”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/312">Pub. L. 111–312</ref> substituted “is a covered unemployment compensation debt” for “is not a covered unemployment compensation debt”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/3/C">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “is not a covered unemployment compensation debt” for “due to fraud”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/2">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (4). Former par. (4) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/4/A">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(4)(A)</ref>, inserted “or the person’s failure to report earnings” after “due to fraud” and struck out “for not more than 10 years” after “remains uncollected”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/4/B">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(4)(B)</ref>, struck out “due to fraud” after “to be liable” and “for not more than 10 years” after “remain uncollected”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/291/s801/a/2">Pub. L. 111–291, § 801(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated pars. (5) to (7) as (4) to (6), respectively, and struck out par. (8). Prior to amendment, text of par. (8) read as follows: “This section shall not apply to refunds payable after the date which is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/d/1">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “(c), (d), (e), and (f)” for “(c), (d), and (e),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/d/2">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “and before such overpayment is reduced pursuant to subsections (e) and (f)” for “and before such overpayment is reduced pursuant to subsection (e)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/d/3">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(d)(3)</ref>, inserted “or subsection (f)” after “paragraph (1)” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/a">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(a)</ref>, added subsec. (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/a">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(a)</ref>, (d)(4), redesignated subsec. (f) as (g) and substituted “(c), (d), (e), or (f)” for “(c), (d), or (e)”. Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/a">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (h). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/a">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(a)</ref>, (d)(5), redesignated subsec. (h) as (i) and substituted “subsection (c), (e), or (f)” for “subsection (c) or (e)”. Former subsec. (i) redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/a">Pub. L. 110–328, § 3(a)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (i) to (k) as (j) to (<i>l</i>), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> substituted “of such Act.” for “the Social Security Act.” in first sentence and “The Secretary shall apply a reduction under this subsection first to an amount certified by the State as past due support under section 464 of the Social Security Act before any other reductions allowed by law.” for “A reduction under this subsection shall be applied first to satisfy any past-due support which has been assigned to the State under section 402(a)(26) or 471(a)(17) of the Social Security Act, and shall be applied to satisfy any other past-due support after any other reductions allowed by law (but before a credit against future liability for an internal revenue tax) have been made.” in third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/c/1">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “(c), (d), and (e)” for “(c) and (d)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/c/2">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “and before such overpayment is reduced pursuant to subsection (e) and before such overpayment” for “and before such overpayment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(a)</ref>, added subsec. (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(a)</ref>, (c)(3), redesignated subsec. (e) as (f) and substituted “(c), (d), or (e)” for “(c) or (d)” and “Federal agency or State” for “Federal agency”. Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(a)</ref>, (c)(4), redesignated subsec. (g) as (h) and substituted “subsection (c) or (e)” for “subsection (c)”. Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (i). Former subsec. (i) redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (j). Former subsec. (j) redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3505/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3505(a)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3711(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (j) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsecs. (a), (e) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s110">Pub. L. 104–193, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7). See 1996 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s110">Pub. L. 104–193, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7)(A), which directed substitution of “(c), (d), and (e)” for “(c) and (d)”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s110">Pub. L. 104–193, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7)(C), which directed amendment by adding subsec. (e), reading as follows: “<inline class="small-caps">Collection of Overpayments Under Title IV–A of the Social Security Act</inline>.—The amount of any overpayment to be refunded to the person making the overpayment shall be reduced (after reductions pursuant to subsections (c) and (d), but before a credit against future liability for an internal revenue tax) in accordance with section 405(e) of the Social Security Act (concerning recovery of overpayments to individuals under State plans approved under part A of title IV of such Act).”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s110">Pub. L. 104–193, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7)(B), which directed amendment by redesignating subsec. (e) as (f), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/134">Pub. L. 104–134</ref> amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (f) read as follows: “For purposes of this section, the term ‘Federal agency’ means a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States (other than an agency subject to <ref href="/us/act/1933-05-18/s9">section 9 of the Act of May 18, 1933</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/48/63">48 Stat. 63</ref>, chapter 32; <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s831h">16 U.S.C. 831h</ref>)), and includes a Government corporation (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s103">section 103 of title 5</ref>, United States Code).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s110">Pub. L. 104–193, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(7)(B), which directed amendment by redesignating subsecs. (f) to (i) as (g) to (j), respectively, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsecs. (d)(3)(C), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary of Health and Human Services” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s5129/c/1/A">Pub. L. 101–508, § 5129(c)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “any OASDI overpayment and” after “(other than”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s5129/c/1/B">Pub. L. 101–508, § 5129(c)(1)(B)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “For purposes of this subsection the term ‘OASDI overpayment’ means any overpayment of benefits made to an individual under title II of the Social Security Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s5129/c/2">Pub. L. 101–508, § 5129(c)(2)</ref>, inserted before period at end “or any such action against the Secretary of Health and Human Services which is otherwise available with respect to recoveries of overpayments of benefits under section 204 of the Social Security Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2653/b/2">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2653(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “subsections (c) and (d)” for “subsection (c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/378/s21/e/1">Pub. L. 98–378, § 21(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “collecting such support” for “to which such support has been assigned” and inserted provision that a reduction under this subsection shall be applied first to satisfy any past-due support which has been assigned to the State under section 402(a)(26) or 471(a)(17) of the Social Security Act, and shall be applied to satisfy any other past-due support after any other reductions allowed by law (but before a credit against future liability for an internal revenue tax) have been made.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2653/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2653(b)(1)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) to (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/378/s21/e/2">Pub. L. 98–378, § 21(e)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2653/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2653(b)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/378/s21/e/2">Pub. L. 98–378, § 21(e)(2)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (g) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2331/c/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2331(c)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to subsec. (c) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2331/c/2">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2331(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id46d777db-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777dc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref> applicable to credits or refunds made after <date date="2016-12-31">Dec. 31, 2016</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/s201/d">section 201(d) of Pub. L. 114–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6071">section 6071 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777dd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/312/tV/s503/b">Pub. L. 111–312, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-17">Dec. 17, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3308">124 Stat. 3308</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/312/tV/s503/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect as if included in section 801 of the Claims Resolution Act of 2010 [<ref href="/us/pl/111/291">Pub. L. 111–291</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/291/tVIII/s801/b">Pub. L. 111–291, title VIII, § 801(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-08">Dec. 8, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3157">124 Stat. 3157</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/291/tVIII/s801/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to refunds payable under section 6402 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-12-08">Dec. 8, 2010</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777de-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/328">Pub. L. 110–328</ref> applicable to refunds payable under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6402">section 6402 of this title</ref> on or after <date date="2008-09-30">Sept. 30, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/328/s3/e">section 3(e) of Pub. L. 110–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3304">section 3304 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777df-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171">Pub. L. 109–171</ref> effective <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, and applicable to payments under parts A and D of subchapter IV of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, for calendar quarters beginning on or after such date, subject to certain State options, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s7301/e">section 7301(e) of Pub. L. 109–171</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s608">section 608 of Title 42</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777e0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3505/b">Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3505(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/771">112 Stat. 771</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3505/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to disallowances after the 180th day after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711">section 3711 of Pub. L. 105–206</ref> applicable to refunds payable under this section after <date date="1999-12-31">Dec. 31, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3711/d">section 3711(d) of Pub. L. 105–206</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6103">section 6103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777e1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> effective as if included in section 110 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, at the time such section 110 became law, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5518/c">section 5518(c) of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s51">section 51 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777e2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> effective <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, with transition rules relating to State options to accelerate such date, rules relating to claims, actions, and proceedings commenced before such date, rules relating to closing out of accounts for terminated or substantially modified programs and continuance in office of Assistant Secretary for Family Support, and provisions relating to termination of entitlement under AFDC program, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s116">section 116 of Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, as amended, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s601">section 601 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777e3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777e4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5129/d">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5129(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-289">104 Stat. 1388–289</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5129/d">
<inline>“The amendments made by this section [amending this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3720A">section 3720A of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s404">section 404 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare]—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall take effect <date date="1991-01-01">January 1, 1991</date>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall not apply to refunds to which the amendments made by section 2653 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 (<ref href="/us/stat/98/1153">98 Stat. 1153</ref>) [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3720A">section 3720A of Title 31</ref> and amending this section and sections 6103 and 7213 of this title] do not apply.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777e5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/378">Pub. L. 98–378</ref> applicable with respect to refunds payable under this section after <date date="1985-12-31">Dec. 31, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/378/s21/g">section 21(g) of Pub. L. 98–378</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6103">section 6103 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2653/c">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2653(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1156">98 Stat. 1156</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9402/a">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9402(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-376">101 Stat. 1330–376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/tVII/s701/a">Pub. L. 100–485, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-13">Oct. 13, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2425">102 Stat. 2425</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/164/tIV/s401/a">Pub. L. 102–164, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-15">Nov. 15, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1061">105 Stat. 1061</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/164/tIV/s401/a">“The amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3720A">section 3720A of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and amending this section and sections 6103 and 7213 of this title] shall apply with respect to refunds payable under section 6402 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] after <date date="1985-12-31">December 31, 1985</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/102/164/tIV/s401/b">Pub. L. 102–164, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-11-15">Nov. 15, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1061">105 Stat. 1061</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/164/tIV/s401/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2653/c">section 2653(c) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out above] shall take effect on <date date="1991-10-01">October 1, 1991</date>.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id46d777e6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective, except as otherwise specifically provided, on <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2336">section 2336 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s651">section 651 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id46d9c1d7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Organ and Tissue Donation Information Included With Income Tax Refund Payments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tIII/s371">Pub. L. 104–191, title III, § 371</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2072">110 Stat. 2072</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/191/tIII/s371">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Treasury shall, to the extent practicable, include with the mailing of any payment of a refund of individual income tax made during the period beginning on <date date="1997-02-01">February 1, 1997</date>, and ending on <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, a copy of the document described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Text of Document</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and organizations promoting organ and tissue (including eye) donation, prepare a document suitable for inclusion with individual income tax refund payments which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> encourages organ and tissue donation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> includes a detachable organ and tissue donor card; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> urges recipients to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> sign the organ and tissue donor card;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> discuss organ and tissue donation with family members and tell family members about the recipient’s desire to be an organ and tissue donor if the occasion arises; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> encourage family members to request or authorize organ and tissue donation if the occasion arises.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id46d9c1d8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Clarification of Congressional Intent as to Scope of Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2653">Section 2653 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9402/b">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9402(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-376">101 Stat. 1330–376</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9402/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Nothing in the amendments made by section 2653 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3720A">section 3720A of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and amending this section and sections 6103 and 7213 of this title] shall be construed as exempting debts of corporations or any other category of persons from the application of such amendments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> It is the intent of the Congress that, to the extent practicable, the amendments made by section 2653 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 shall extend to all Federal agencies (as defined in the amendments made by such section).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall issue regulations to carry out the purposes of this subsection.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id46d9c1d9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study by General Accounting Office of Operation and Effectiveness of Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2653">Section 2653 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIX/s9402/c">Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9402(c)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-376">101 Stat. 1330–376</ref>, required the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, to conduct a study of the operation and effectiveness of amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2653">section 2653 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> on voluntary compliance with the income tax laws and, by <date date="1989-04-01">Apr. 1, 1989</date>, submit a report and recommendations to Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
