<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id470e3ed9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601"><num value="6601">§ 6601.</num><heading> Interest on underpayment, nonpayment, or extensions of time for payment, of tax</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3eda-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any amount of tax imposed by this title (whether required to be shown on a return, or to be paid by stamp or by some other method) is not paid on or before the last date prescribed for payment, interest on such amount at the underpayment rate established under section 6621 shall be paid for the period from such last date to the date paid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3edb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Last date prescribed for payment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the last date prescribed for payment of the tax shall be determined under chapter 62 with the application of the following rules:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3edc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Extensions of time disregarded</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The last date prescribed for payment shall be determined without regard to any extension of time for payment or any installment agreement entered into under section 6159.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3edd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Jeopardy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The last date prescribed for payment shall be determined without regard to any notice and demand for payment issued, by reason of jeopardy (as provided in chapter 70), prior to the last date otherwise prescribed for such payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ede-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Accumulated earnings tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of the tax imposed by section 531 for any taxable year, the last date prescribed for payment shall be deemed to be the due date (without regard to extensions) for the return of tax imposed by subtitle A for such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3edf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Last date for payment not otherwise prescribed</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of taxes payable by stamp and in all other cases in which the last date for payment is not otherwise prescribed, the last date for payment shall be deemed to be the date the liability for tax arises (and in no event shall be later than the date notice and demand for the tax is made by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of interest in certain income, estate, gift, and certain excise tax cases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a deficiency as defined in section 6211 (relating to income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes), if a waiver of restrictions under section 6213(d) on the assessment of such deficiency has been filed, and if notice and demand by the Secretary for payment of such deficiency is not made within 30 days after the filing of such waiver, interest shall not be imposed on such deficiency for the period beginning immediately after such 30th day and ending with the date of notice and demand and interest shall not be imposed during such period on any interest with respect to such deficiency for any prior period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Income tax reduced by carryback or adjustment for certain unused deductions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Net operating loss or capital loss carryback</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the amount of any tax imposed by subtitle A is reduced by reason of a carryback of a net operating loss or net capital loss, such reduction in tax shall not affect the computation of interest under this section for the period ending with the filing date for the taxable year in which the net operating loss or net capital loss arises.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreign tax credit carrybacks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If any credit allowed for any taxable year is increased by reason of a carryback of tax paid or accrued to foreign countries or possessions of the United States, such increase shall not affect the computation of interest under this section for the period ending with the filing date for the taxable year in which such taxes were in fact paid or accrued, or, with respect to any portion of such credit carryback from a taxable year attributable to a net operating loss carryback or a capital loss carryback from a subsequent taxable year, such increase shall not affect the computation of interest under this section for the period ending with the filing date for such subsequent taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain credit carrybacks</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If any credit allowed for any taxable year is increased by reason of a credit carryback, such increase shall not affect the computation of interest under this section for the period ending with the filing date for the taxable year in which the credit carryback arises, or, with respect to any portion of a credit carryback from a taxable year attributable to a net operating loss carryback, capital loss carryback, or other credit carryback from a subsequent taxable year, such increase shall not affect the computation of interest under this section for the period ending with the filing date for such subsequent taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit carryback defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “credit carryback” has the meaning given such term by section 6511(d)(4)(C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “filing date” has the meaning given to such term by section 6611(f)(4)(A).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable rules</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this title—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ee9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest treated as tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Interest prescribed under this section on any tax shall be paid upon notice and demand, and shall be assessed, collected, and paid in the same manner as taxes. Any reference to this title (except subchapter B of chapter 63, relating to deficiency procedures) to any tax imposed by this title shall be deemed also to refer to interest imposed by this section on such tax.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3eea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest on penalties, additional amounts, or additions to the tax</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3eeb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Interest shall be imposed under subsection (a) in respect of any assessable penalty, additional amount, or addition to the tax (other than an addition to tax imposed under section 6651(a)(1) or 6653 or under part II of subchapter A of chapter 68) only if such assessable penalty, additional amount, or addition to the tax is not paid within 21 calendar days from the date of notice and demand therefor (10 business days if the amount for which such notice and demand is made equals or exceeds $100,000), and in such case interest shall be imposed only for the period from the date of the notice and demand to the date of payment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3eec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest on certain additions to tax</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Interest shall be imposed under this section with respect to any addition to tax imposed by section 6651(a)(1) or 6653 or under part II of subchapter A of chapter 68 for the period which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id470e3eed-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> begins on the date on which the return of the tax with respect to which such addition to tax is imposed is required to be filed (including any extensions), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id470e3eee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> ends on the date of payment of such addition to tax.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3eef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments made within specified period after notice and demand</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If notice and demand is made for payment of any amount and if such amount is paid within 21 calendar days (10 business days if the amount for which such notice and demand is made equals or exceeds $100,000) after the date of such notice and demand, interest under this section on the amount so paid shall not be imposed for the period after the date of such notice and demand.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ef0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Satisfaction by credits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any portion of a tax is satisfied by credit of an overpayment, then no interest shall be imposed under this section on the portion of the tax so satisfied for any period during which, if the credit had not been made, interest would have been allowable with respect to such overpayment. The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent that section 6621(d) applies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ef1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on assessment and collection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Interest prescribed under this section on any tax may be assessed and collected at any time during the period within which the tax to which such interest relates may be collected.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ef2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception as to estimated tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any failure to pay any estimated tax required to be paid by section 6654 or 6655.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ef3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception as to Federal unemployment tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any failure to make a payment of tax imposed by section 3301 for a calendar quarter or other period within a taxable year required under authority of section 6157.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ef4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> 2-percent rate on certain portion of estate tax extended under section 6166</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ef5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the time for payment of an amount of tax imposed by chapter 11 is extended as provided in section 6166, then in lieu of the annual rate provided by subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3ef6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> interest on the 2-percent portion of such amount shall be paid at the rate of 2 percent, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3ef7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> interest on so much of such amount as exceeds the 2-percent portion shall be paid at a rate equal to 45 percent of the annual rate provided by subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this subsection, the amount of any deficiency which is prorated to installments payable under section 6166 shall be treated as an amount of tax payable in installments under such section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3ef8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> 2-percent portion</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “2-percent portion” means the lesser of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3ef9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3efa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of the tentative tax which would be determined under the rate schedule set forth in section 2001(c) if the amount with respect to which such tentative tax is to be computed were the sum of $1,000,000 and the applicable exclusion amount in effect under section 2010(c), reduced by</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3efb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the applicable credit amount in effect under section 2010(c), or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3efc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of the tax imposed by chapter 11 which is extended as provided in section 6166.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3efd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Inflation adjustment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of estates of decedents dying in a calendar year after 1998, the $1,000,000 amount contained in paragraph (2)(A) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3efe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> $1,000,000, multiplied by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id470e3eff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting “calendar year 1997” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If any amount as adjusted under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $10,000, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $10,000.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3f00-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/j/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the amount of tax imposed by chapter 11 which is extended as provided in section 6166 exceeds the 2-percent portion, any payment of a portion of such amount shall, for purposes of computing interest for periods after such payment, be treated as reducing the 2-percent portion by an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount of such payment as the amount of the 2-percent portion (determined without regard to this paragraph) bears to the amount of the tax which is extended as provided in section 6166.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id470e3f01-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6601/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> No interest on certain adjustments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions prohibiting interest on certain adjustments in tax, see section 6205(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id470e3f02-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/817">68A Stat. 817</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/tI">Pub. L. 85–866, title I</ref>, §§ 66(c), 83(a)(1), 84(a), title II, § 206(e), <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1658">72 Stat. 1658</ref>, 1663, 1664, 1685; <ref href="/us/pl/87/61/tII/s203/c/2">Pub. L. 87–61, title II, § 203(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-29">June 29, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/126">75 Stat. 126</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s2/e/3">Pub. L. 87–834, § 2(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/972">76 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/571/s3/d">Pub. L. 88–571, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1964-09-02">Sept. 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/858">78 Stat. 858</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/384/s1/f">Pub. L. 89–384, § 1(f)</ref>, <date date="1966-04-08">Apr. 8, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/104">80 Stat. 104</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/225/s2/e">Pub. L. 90–225, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="1967-12-27">Dec. 27, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/731">81 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/53/s2/e">Pub. L. 91–53, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="1969-08-07">Aug. 7, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/92">83 Stat. 92</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tI/s101/j/49">Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(j)(49)</ref>, title V, § 512(e)(3), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/531">83 Stat. 531</ref>, 641; <ref href="/us/pl/92/178/tVI/s601/d/3">Pub. L. 92–178, title VI, § 601(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/559">85 Stat. 559</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tII/s1016/a/17">Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/930">88 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/625/s7/a/2/A">Pub. L. 93–625, § 7(a)(2)(A)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2115">88 Stat. 2115</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/452/s3/c/3">Pub. L. 94–452, § 3(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-02">Oct. 2, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1514">90 Stat. 1514</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIII/s1307/d/2/H">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIII, § 1307(d)(2)(H)</ref>, title XVI, § 1605(b)(10), title XIX, §§ 1906(a)(34), (b)(13)(A), title XX, § 2004(b), title XXI, § 2107(g)(2)(C), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1728">90 Stat. 1728</ref>, 1755, 1829, 1834, 1867, 1904; <ref href="/us/pl/95/30/tII/s202/d/4/C">Pub. L. 95–30, title II, § 202(d)(4)(C)</ref>, <date date="1977-05-23">May 23, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/150">91 Stat. 150</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/628/s8/c/2">Pub. L. 95–628, § 8(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3632">92 Stat. 3632</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/tI/s101/f/7">Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(f)(7)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/253">94 Stat. 253</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII">Pub. L. 97–248, title III</ref>, §§ 344(b)(1), 346(c)(2), <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/635">96 Stat. 635</ref>, 637; <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/tII/s231/b/2/D">Pub. L. 98–76, title II, § 231(b)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/429">97 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s158/a">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 158(a)</ref>, title II, § 211(b)(26), title IV, § 412(b)(7), title VII, § 714(n)(1), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/696">98 Stat. 696</ref>, 757, 792, 963; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXIV/s1404/c/3">Pub. L. 99–514, title XIV, § 1404(c)(3)</ref>, title XV, §§ 1511(c)(11), 1512(a), 1564(a), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2714">100 Stat. 2714</ref>, 2745, 2746, 2762; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tX/s10301/b/5">Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10301(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-429">101 Stat. 1330–429</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI">Pub. L. 100–647, title I</ref>, §§ 1015(b)(2)(C), 1018(u)(42), title VI, § 6234(b)(1), title VII, § 7106(c)(5), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3569">102 Stat. 3569</ref>, 3592, 3736, 3774; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7721/c/8">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7721(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2400">103 Stat. 2400</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11801/c/20/B">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11801(c)(20)(B)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-528">104 Stat. 1388–528</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/168/tIII/s303/a">Pub. L. 104–168, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1458">110 Stat. 1458</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tV">Pub. L. 105–34, title V</ref>, §§ 501(e), 503(a), (c)(2), (3), title X, § 1055(a), title XII, § 1242(a), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/846">111 Stat. 846</ref>, 852, 853, 944, 1029; <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3301/b">Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3301(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/741">112 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s409/a/2">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 409(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2635">119 Stat. 2635</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tXI/s1101/f/9">Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(f)(9)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/638">129 Stat. 638</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s11002/d/1/JJ">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 11002(d)(1)(JJ)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2060">131 Stat. 2060</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/b/47">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(47)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1204">132 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id470e3f03-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id470e3f04-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Inflation Adjusted Items for Certain Years</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For inflation adjustment of certain items in this section, see Revenue Procedures listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id470e3f05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id470e3f06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(2) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> redesignated pars. (3) to (5) as (2) to (4), respectively, and struck out former par. (2) which related to dates prescribed for installment payments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (j)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97">Pub. L. 115–97</ref> substituted “for ‘calendar year 2016’ in subparagraph (A)(ii)” for “for ‘calendar year 1992’ in subparagraph (B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/74">Pub. L. 114–74</ref> struck out at end “In the case of a settlement under section 6224(c) which results in the conversion of partnership items to nonpartnership items pursuant to section 6231(b)(1)(C), the preceding sentence shall apply to a computational adjustment resulting from such settlement in the same manner as if such adjustment were a deficiency and such settlement were a waiver referred to in the preceding sentence.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135">Pub. L. 109–135</ref> substituted “6611(f)(4)(A)” for “6611(f)(3)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206">Pub. L. 105–206</ref> inserted at end “The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent that section 6621(d) applies.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1242/a">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1242(a)</ref>, inserted at end “In the case of a settlement under section 6224(c) which results in the conversion of partnership items to nonpartnership items pursuant to section 6231(b)(1)(C), the preceding sentence shall apply to a computational adjustment resulting from such settlement in the same manner as if such adjustment were a deficiency and such settlement were a waiver referred to in the preceding sentence.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1055/a">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1055(a)</ref>, added par. (2) and redesignated former pars. (2) and (3) as (3) and (4), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s503/c/3">Pub. L. 105–34, § 503(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “2-percent” for “4-percent” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s503/a">Pub. L. 105–34, § 503(a)</ref>, reenacted par. heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “If the time for payment of an amount of tax imposed by chapter 11 is extended as provided in section 6166, interest on the 4-percent portion of such amount shall (in lieu of the annual rate provided by subsection (a)) be paid at the rate of 4 percent. For purposes of this subsection, the amount of any deficiency which is prorated to installments payable under section 6166 shall be treated as an amount of tax payable in installments under such section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s503/a">Pub. L. 105–34, § 503(a)</ref>, amended heading and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘4-percent portion’ means the lesser of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) $345,800 reduced by the amount of the credit allowable under section 2010(a); or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the amount of the tax imposed by chapter 11 which is extended as provided in section 6166.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s501/e">Pub. L. 105–34, § 501(e)</ref>, added par. (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s503/c/2">Pub. L. 105–34, § 503(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “2-percent” for “4-percent” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s501/e">Pub. L. 105–34, § 501(e)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/168/s303/b/1">Pub. L. 104–168, § 303(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “21 calendar days from the date of notice and demand therefor (10 business days if the amount for which such notice and demand is made equals or exceeds $100,000)” for “10 days from the date of notice and demand therefor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/168/s303/a">Pub. L. 104–168, § 303(a)</ref>, substituted “specified period” for “10 days” in heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “If notice and demand is made for payment of any amount, and if such amount is paid within 10 days after the date of such notice and demand interest under this section on the amount so paid shall not be imposed for the period after the date of such notice and demand.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> struck out “or 6158(a)” after “6156(a)” in introductory provisions, struck out “or 6158(a), as the case may be” after “6156(a)” in subpar. (A), and struck out at end “For purposes of subparagraph (A), section 6158(a) shall be treated as providing that the date prescribed for payment of each installment shall not be later than the date prescribed for payment of the 1985 installment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> substituted “section 6651(a)(1) or 6653 or under part II of subchapter A of chapter 68” for “section 6651(a)(1), 6653, 6659, 6660, or 6661” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s6234/b/1">Pub. L. 100–647, § 6234(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “or any installment agreement entered into under section 6159” after “time for payment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/u/42">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(u)(42)</ref>, made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1404/c/3">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1404(c)(3)</ref>, see 1986 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1015/b/2/C">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1015(b)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “6653, 6659” for “6659”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s7106/c/5">Pub. L. 100–647, § 7106(c)(5)</ref>, struck out “or 3321” after “3301”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> substituted “section 6654 or 6655” for “section 6154 or 6654”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1511/c/11">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1511(c)(11)</ref>, substituted “the underpayment rate established under section 6621” for “an annual rate established under section 6621”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1404/c/3">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1404(c)(3)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/u/42">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(u)(42)</ref>, substituted “6156(a) or 6158(a)” for “6152(a), 6156(a), or 6158(a)” in introductory provisions and “6156(b) or 6158(a)” for “6152(b), 6156(b), or 6158(a)” in subpar. (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1512/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1512(a)</ref>, added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1564/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1564(a)</ref>, inserted “and interest shall not be imposed during such period on any interest with respect to such deficiency for any prior period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s714/n/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 714(n)(1)</ref>, made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s346/c/2/B">Pub. L. 97–248, § 346(c)(2)(B)</ref>. See 1982 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s211/b/26">Pub. L. 98–369, § 211(b)(26)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (3) and struck out former par. (3) which had provided that if the amount of any tax imposed by subtitle A was reduced by operation of section 815(d)(5) (relating to reduction of policyholders surplus account of life insurance companies for certain unused deductions), such reduction in tax would not affect the computation of interest under this section for the period ending with the last day of the last taxable year to which the loss described in section 815(d)(5)(A) was carried under section 812(b)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s158/a">Pub. L. 98–369, § 158(a)</ref>, in amending par. (2) generally, inserted “(other than an addition to tax imposed under section 6651(a)(1), 6659, 6660, or 6661)”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s412/b/7">Pub. L. 98–369, § 412(b)(7)</ref>, amended subsec. (h) generally, substituting “any estimated tax required to be paid by section 6154 or 6654” for “estimated tax required by section 6153 or section 6154”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/76">Pub. L. 98–76</ref> inserted “or 3321” after “3301”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s346/c/2/A">Pub. L. 97–248, § 346(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “the filing date for the taxable year” for “the last day of the taxable year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s346/c/2/B">Pub. L. 97–248, § 346(c)(2)(B)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s346/c/2/B">Pub. L. 98–369, § 346(c)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “the filing date for” for “the last day of” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s346/c/2/C">Pub. L. 97–248, § 346(c)(2)(C)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s344/b/1">Pub. L. 97–248, § 344(b)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (2) which had provided that no interest under this section was to be imposed on the interest provided by this section, and redesignated pars. (3) and (4) as (2) and (3), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> substituted “certain excise tax cases” for “chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 tax cases” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/628/s8/c/2/A">Pub. L. 95–628, § 8(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted in heading “Certain credit carrybacks” for “Investment credit carryback”, designated existing provision as subpar. (A), and in subpar. (A) as so designated, inserted heading “In general” and in text extended the application of the provision to credit carrybacks, previously limited to investment credit carrybacks, included other credit carrybacks, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/628/s8/c/2/B">Pub. L. 95–628, § 8(c)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out pars. (4) and (5) which provided for work incentive program credit carrybacks and new employee credit carrybacks, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/30">Pub. L. 95–30</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/452">Pub. L. 94–452</ref> substituted “, 6156(a), or 6158(a)” for “or 6156(a)” and “, 6156(b), or 6158(a)” for “or 6156(b)” and inserted requirement that for purposes of subparagraph (A), <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6158/a">section 6158(a) of this title</ref> shall be treated as providing that the date prescribed for payment of each installment shall not be later than the date prescribed for payment of the 1985 installment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1307(d)(2)(H), 1605(b)(10), substituted in heading “chapter 41, 42” for “chapter 42” and “43, or 44” for “or 43”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2107/g/2/C">Pub. L. 94–455, § 2107(g)(2)(C)</ref>, inserted “, an investment credit carryback,” after “net operating loss carryback”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/a/34">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(a)(34)</ref>, struck out “(or section 59 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j), (k). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2004/b">Pub. L. 94–455, § 2004(b)</ref>, added subsec. (j) and redesignated former subsec. (j) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/625/s7/a/2/A">Pub. L. 93–625, § 7(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “an annual rate established under section 6621” for “the rate of 6 percent per annum”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/93/625/s7/b/1">Pub. L. 93–625, § 7(b)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (b) relating to extensions of time for payment of estate tax, redesignated subsecs. (c) to (i) as (b) to (h), respectively, struck out subsec. (j) relating to extensions of time for payment of tax attributable to recoveries of foreign expropriation losses, and redesignated subsecs. (k) and (<i>l</i>) as (i) and (j), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> inserted reference to chapter 43 in heading, and substituted “certain excise” for “chapter 42” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/92/178">Pub. L. 92–178</ref> added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s101/j/49">Pub. L. 91–172, § 101(j)(49)</ref>, inserted reference to chapter 42 both in subsec. heading and in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s512/e/3/A">Pub. L. 91–172, § 512(e)(3)(A)</ref>, (B), substituted “loss or capital loss carryback” for “loss carryback” in heading, and “net operating loss or net capital loss” for “net operating loss” wherever it appears in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s512/e/3/C">Pub. L. 91–172, § 512(e)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “loss carryback or a capital loss carryback” for “loss carryback”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/91/53">Pub. L. 91–53</ref> added subsec. (k) and redesignated former subsec. (k) as (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/90/225">Pub. L. 90–225</ref> inserted “, or with respect to any portion of an investment credit carryback from a taxable year attributable to a net operating loss carryback from a subsequent taxable year, such increase shall not affect the computation of interest under this section for the period ending with the last day of such subsequent taxable year,” after “the investment credit carryback arises”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsecs. (j), (k). <ref href="/us/pl/89/384">Pub. L. 89–384</ref> added subsec. (j) and redesignated former subsec. (j) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/88/571">Pub. L. 88–571</ref> added par. (3) and inserted “or adjustment for certain unused deductions” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/87/61">Pub. L. 87–61</ref> substituted “6152(a) or 6156(a)” for “6152(a)” in introductory provisions, and “6152(b) or 6156(b), as the case may be” for “6152(b)” in subpar. (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/85/866">Pub. L. 85–866</ref>, §§ 66(c), 206(e), inserted reference to section 6166, and substituted “if the time for payment of an amount of such tax is postponed or extended as provided by section 6163” for “if postponement of the payment of an amount of such tax is permitted by section 6163(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/85/866">Pub. L. 85–866</ref>, §§ 83(a)(1), 84(a), added subsecs. (g) and (h) and redesignated former subsecs. (g) and (h) as (h) and (i), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id470e3f07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2017 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/97">Pub. L. 115–97</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="2017-12-31">Dec. 31, 2017</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s11002/e">section 11002(e) of Pub. L. 115–97</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/74">Pub. L. 114–74</ref> applicable to returns filed for partnership taxable years beginning after <date date="2017-12-31">Dec. 31, 2017</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/74/s1101/g">section 1101(g) of Pub. L. 114–74</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6221">section 6221 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/135">Pub. L. 109–135</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997, <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s409/d">section 409(d) of Pub. L. 109–135</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s961">section 961 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3301/c">Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3301(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/741">112 Stat. 741</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tIV/s4002/d">Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title IV, § 4002(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-906">112 Stat. 2681–906</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tIV/s4002/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided under paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6621">section 6621 of this title</ref>] shall apply to interest for periods beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to any applicable statute of limitation not having expired with regard to either a tax underpayment or a tax overpayment, the amendments made by this section shall apply to interest for periods beginning before the date of the enactment of this Act if the taxpayer—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> reasonably identifies and establishes periods of such tax overpayments and underpayments for which the zero rate applies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> not later than <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, requests the Secretary of the Treasury to apply section 6621(d) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by subsection (a), to such periods.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s501/e">section 501(e) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref> applicable to estates of decedents dying, and gifts made, after <date date="1997-12-31">Dec. 31, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s501/f">section 501(f) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 503(a), (c)(2), (3) of <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> applicable to estates of decedents dying after <date date="1997-12-31">Dec. 31, 1997</date>, with special rule in case of estate of any decedent dying before <date date="1998-01-01">Jan. 1, 1998</date>, with respect to which there is an election under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6166">section 6166 of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s503/d">section 503(d) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s163">section 163 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tX/s1055/c">Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1055(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/945">111 Stat. 945</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/34/tX/s1055/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6611">section 6611 of this title</ref>] shall apply to foreign tax credit carrybacks arising in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXII/s1242/b">Pub. L. 105–34, title XII, § 1242(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1029">111 Stat. 1029</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/34/tXII/s1242/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to adjustments with respect to partnership taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f0d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/168/tIII/s303/c">Pub. L. 104–168, title III, § 303(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1458">110 Stat. 1458</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/168/tIII/s303/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6651">section 6651 of this title</ref>] shall apply in the case of any notice and demand given after <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f0e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> applicable to returns the due date for which (determined without regard to extensions) is after <date date="1989-12-31">Dec. 31, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7721/d">section 7721(d) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s461">section 461 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f0f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1015/b/2/C">section 1015(b)(2)(C) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> applicable to returns the due date for which (determined without regard to extensions) is after <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1015/b/4">section 1015(b)(4) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6013">section 6013 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/u/42">section 1018(u)(42) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s6234/b/1">section 6234(b)(1) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> applicable to agreements entered into after <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s6234/c">section 6234(c) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6159">section 6159 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s7106/c/5">section 7106(c)(5) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> applicable to remuneration paid after <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s7106/d">section 7106(d) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3321">section 3321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f10-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1987-12-31">Dec. 31, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10301/c">section 10301(c) of Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s585">section 585 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id470e3f11-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1404/c/3">section 1404(c)(3) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1404/d">section 1404(d) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s643">section 643 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1511/c/11">section 1511(c)(11) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable for purposes of determining interest for periods after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1511/d">section 1511(d) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s47">section 47 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1512/b">Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1512(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2746">100 Stat. 2746</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1512/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to returns the due date for which (determined without regard to extensions) is after <date date="1985-12-31">December 31, 1985</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1564/b">Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1564(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2762">100 Stat. 2762</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1564/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to interest accruing after <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statute of limitations</inline>.—</heading><content>If refund or credit of any amount resulting from the application of the amendment made by subsection (a) is prevented at any time before the close of the date which is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>] by the operation of any law or rule of law (including res judicata), refund or credit of such amount (to the extent attributable to the application of the amendment made by subsection (a)) may, nevertheless, be made or allowed if claim therefore [sic] is filed before the close of such 1-year period.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b012-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s158/b">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 158(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/696">98 Stat. 696</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s158/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to interest accrued after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>], except with respect to additions to tax for which notice and demand is made before such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s211/b/26">section 211(b)(26) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s215">section 215 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s412/b/7">section 412(b)(7) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s414/a/1">section 414(a)(1) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6654">section 6654 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s714/n/1">section 714(n)(1) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s715">section 715 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b013-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/76">Pub. L. 98–76</ref> applicable to remuneration paid after <date date="1986-06-30">June 30, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/76/s231/d">section 231(d) of Pub. L. 98–76</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3321">section 3321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b014-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s344/b/1">section 344(b)(1) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to interest accruing after <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s344/c">section 344(c) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6622">section 6622 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s346/c/2">section 346(c)(2) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to interest accruing after the 30th day after <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s346/d/2">section 346(d)(2) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6611">section 6611 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b015-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> applicable to periods after <date date="1980-02-29">Feb. 29, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/s101/i">section 101(i) of Pub. L. 96–223</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6161">section 6161 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b016-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/628">Pub. L. 95–628</ref> applicable to carrybacks arising in taxable years beginning after <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/628/s8/d">section 8(d) of Pub. L. 95–628</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6511">section 6511 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b017-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/30">Pub. L. 95–30</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, and to credit carrybacks from such years, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/30/s202/e">section 202(e) of Pub. L. 95–30</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s51">section 51 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b018-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2004/b">section 2004(b) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable to estates of decedents dying after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s2004/g">section 2004(g) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6166">section 6166 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/452">Pub. L. 94–452</ref> effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/452/s3/e">section 3(e) of Pub. L. 94–452</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6151">section 6151 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b019-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/625">Pub. L. 93–625</ref> effective <date date="1975-07-01">July 1, 1975</date>, and applicable to amounts outstanding on such date or arising thereafter, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/625/s7/e">section 7(e) of Pub. L. 93–625</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6621">section 6621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b01a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> applicable, except as otherwise provided in section 1017(c) through (i) of <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, for plan years beginning after <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, but, in the case of plans in existence on <date date="1974-01-01">Jan. 1, 1974</date>, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> applicable for plan years beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1017">section 1017 of Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Transitional Rules note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s410">section 410 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b01b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1971 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/178">Pub. L. 92–178</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1971-12-31">Dec. 31, 1971</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/178/s601/f">section 601(f) of Pub. L. 92–178</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s381">section 381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b01c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s101/j/49">section 101(j)(49) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref> effective <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s101/k/1">section 101(k)(1) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4940">section 4940 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s512/e/3">section 512(e)(3) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref> applicable with respect to net capital losses sustained in taxable years beginning after <date date="1969-12-31">Dec. 31, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s512/g">section 512(g) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1969 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1212">section 1212 of this title</ref>. Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/53">Pub. L. 91–53</ref> applicable with respect to calendar years beginning after <date date="1969-12-31">Dec. 31, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/53/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 91–53</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6157">section 6157 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b01d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1967 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/225">Pub. L. 90–225</ref> applicable with respect to investment credit carrybacks attributable to net operating loss carrybacks from taxable years ending after <date date="1967-07-31">July 31, 1967</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/225/s2/g">section 2(g) of Pub. L. 90–225</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46">section 46 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b01e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/384">Pub. L. 89–384</ref> applicable with respect to amounts received after <date date="1964-12-31">December 31, 1964</date>, in respect of foreign expropriation losses (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1351/b">section 1351(b) of this title</ref>) sustained after <date date="1958-12-31">December 31, 1958</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/384/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 89–384</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1351">section 1351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b01f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/571">Pub. L. 88–571</ref> effective, with respect to amounts added to policyholders surplus accounts, for taxable years beginning after <date date="1958-12-31">Dec. 31, 1958</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/571/s3/f">section 3(f) of Pub. L. 88–571</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6501">section 6501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b020-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years ending after <date date="1961-12-31">Dec. 31, 1961</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s2/h">section 2(h) of Pub. L. 87–834</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46">section 46 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b021-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1961 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/61">Pub. L. 87–61</ref> effective <date date="1961-07-01">July 1, 1961</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/61/s208">section 208 of Pub. L. 87–61</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4041">section 4041 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4710b022-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 66(c) and 84(a) of <ref href="/us/pl/85/866">Pub. L. 85–866</ref> effective <date date="1954-08-17">Aug. 17, 1954</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/s1/c/2">section 1(c)(2) of Pub. L. 85–866</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s165">section 165 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/85/866/tI/s83/d">Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 83(d)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1664">72 Stat. 1664</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/866/tI/s83/d">“The amendments made by subsections (a) [amending this section and section 3794 of I.R.C. 1939], (b) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6611">section 6611 of this title</ref> and section 3771 of I.R.C. 1939], and (c) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6611">section 6611 of this title</ref>] shall apply only in respect of overpayments credited after <date date="1957-12-31">December 31, 1957</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/s206/e">section 206(e) of Pub. L. 85–866</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/s206/f">section 206(f) of Pub. L. 85–866</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6161">section 6161 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id4710b023-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/e">section 401(e) of Pub. L. 115–141</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s23">section 23 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11821/b">section 11821(b) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s45K">section 45K of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4710b024-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Administration of Penalties and Interest</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3801">Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3801</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/782">112 Stat. 782</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3801">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“The Joint Committee on Taxation and the Secretary of the Treasury shall each conduct a separate study—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> reviewing the administration and implementation by the Internal Revenue Service of the interest and penalty provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (including the penalty reform provisions of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1989 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, see Tables for classification]); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> making any legislative and administrative recommendations the Committee or the Secretary deems appropriate to simplify penalty or interest administration and reduce taxpayer burden.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such studies shall be submitted to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>].”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4710b025-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interest Not Payable on Underpayments Created or Increased by Tax Reform Act of 1976</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/30/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 95–30, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1977-05-23">May 23, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/152">91 Stat. 152</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“No interest shall be payable for any period before <date date="1977-04-16">April 16, 1977</date> (<date date="1977-03-16">March 16, 1977</date>, in the case of a corporation), on any underpayment of a tax imposed by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954], to the extent that such underpayment was created or increased by any provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1976 [<ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4710b026-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interest on Underpayment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tIX/s946/a">Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, § 946(a)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/729">83 Stat. 729</ref>, provided that in the case of any taxable year ending before <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, no interest on underpayment of taxes, to the extent that such underpayment was attributable to the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, was not to be assessed or collected for any period before the 90th day after <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id4710b027-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Interest Attributable to Net Operating Loss Carryback for Certain Taxable Years Ending in 1954</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/85/866/tI/s83/e">Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 83(e)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1664">72 Stat. 1664</ref>, provided that if by reason of the enactment of <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s172/b/1/A">section 172(b)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, a deficiency resulted for the first taxable year preceding a taxable year ending after <date date="1953-12-31">Dec. 31, 1953</date> but before <date date="1954-08-17">Aug. 17, 1954</date> and an overpayment resulted in the second preceding taxable year, then no interest was payable for any portion of such deficiency for any period during which there existed a corresponding overpayment to which interest was not payable.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
