<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id47156b11-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652"><num value="6652">§ 6652.</num><heading> Failure to file certain information returns, registration statements, etc.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b12-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Returns with respect to certain payments aggregating less than $10</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of each failure to file a statement of a payment to another person required under the authority of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47156b13-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> section 6042(a)(2) (relating to payments of dividends aggregating less than $10), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47156b14-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> section 6044(a)(2) (relating to payments of patronage dividends aggregating less than $10),</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid (upon notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing to so file the statement, $1 for each such statement not so filed, but the total amount imposed on the delinquent person for all such failures during the calendar year shall not exceed $1,000.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b15-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to report tips</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of failure by an employee to report to his employer on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor any amount of tips required to be so reported by section 6053(a) which are wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) or which are compensation (as defined in section 3231(e)), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be paid by the employee, in addition to the tax imposed by section 3101 or section 3201 (as the case may be) with respect to the amount of tips which he so failed to report, an amount equal to 50 percent of such tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b16-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Returns by exempt organizations and by certain trusts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b17-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual returns under section 6033(a)(1) or 6012(a)(6)</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b18-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalty on organization</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47156b19-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a failure to file a return required under section 6033(a)(1) (relating to returns by exempt organizations) or section 6012(a)(6) (relating to returns by political organizations) on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47156b1a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a failure to include any of the information required to be shown on a return filed under section 6033(a)(1) or section 6012(a)(6) or to show the correct information,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">there shall be paid by the exempt organization $20 for each day during which such failure continues. The maximum penalty under this subparagraph on failures with respect to any 1 return shall not exceed the lesser of $10,000 or 5 percent of the gross receipts of the organization for the year. In the case of an organization having gross receipts exceeding $1,000,000 for any year, with respect to the return required under section 6033(a)(1) or section 6012(a)(6) for such year, in applying the first sentence of this subparagraph, the amount of the penalty for each day during which a failure continues shall be $100 in lieu of the amount otherwise specified, and, in lieu of applying the second sentence of this subparagraph, the maximum penalty under this subparagraph shall not exceed $50,000.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b1b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Managers</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b1c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary may make a written demand on any organization subject to penalty under subparagraph (A) specifying therein a reasonable future date by which the return shall be filed (or the information furnished) for purposes of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b1d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with demand</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If any person fails to comply with any demand under clause (i) on or before the date specified in such demand, there shall be paid by the person failing to so comply $10 for each day after the expiration of the time specified in such demand during which such failure continues. The maximum penalty imposed under this subparagraph on all persons for failures with respect to any 1 return shall not exceed $5,000.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b1e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Public inspection of annual returns and reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a failure to comply with the requirements of section 6104(d) with respect to any annual return on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing) or report required under section 527(j), there shall be paid by the person failing to meet such requirements $20 for each day during which such failure continues. The maximum penalty imposed under this subparagraph on all persons for failures with respect to any 1 return or report shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b1f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Public inspection of applications for exemption and notice of status</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a failure to comply with the requirements of section 6104(d) with respect to any exempt status application materials (as defined in such section) or notice materials (as defined in such section) on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor, there shall be paid by the person failing to meet such requirements $20 for each day during which such failure continues.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b20-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/1/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> No penalty for certain annual notices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">This paragraph shall not apply with respect to any notice required under section 6033(i).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b21-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Returns under section 6034 or 6043(b)</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b22-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalty on organization or trust</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a failure to file a return required under section 6034 (relating to returns by certain trusts) or section 6043(b) (relating to terminations, etc., of exempt organizations), on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), there shall be paid by the exempt organization or trust failing so to file $10 for each day during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subparagraph on any organization or trust for failure to file any 1 return shall not exceed $5,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b23-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Managers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may make written demand on an organization or trust failing to file under subparagraph (A) specifying therein a reasonable future date by which such filing shall be made for purposes of this subparagraph. If such filing is not made on or before such date, there shall be paid by the person failing so to file $10 for each day after the expiration of the time specified in the written demand during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subparagraph on all persons for failure to file any 1 return shall not exceed $5,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b24-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Split-interest trusts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a trust which is required to file a return under section 6034(a), subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph shall not apply and paragraph (1) shall apply in the same manner as if such return were required under section 6033, except that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47156b25-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the 5 percent limitation in the second sentence of paragraph (1)(A) shall not apply,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47156b26-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of any trust with gross income in excess of $250,000, in applying the first sentence of paragraph (1)(A), the amount of the penalty for each day during which a failure continues shall be $100 in lieu of the amount otherwise specified, and in lieu of applying the second sentence of paragraph (1)(A), the maximum penalty under paragraph (1)(A) shall not exceed $50,000, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47156b27-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the third sentence of paragraph (1)(A) shall be disregarded.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">In addition to any penalty imposed on the trust pursuant to this subparagraph, if the person required to file such return knowingly fails to file the return, such penalty shall also be imposed on such person who shall be personally liable for such penalty.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b28-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure under section 6033(a)(2)</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b29-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalty on entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a failure to file a disclosure required under section 6033(a)(2), there shall be paid by the tax-exempt entity (the entity manager in the case of a tax-exempt entity described in paragraph (4), (5), (6), or (7) of section 4965(c)) $100 for each day during which such failure continues. The maximum penalty under this subparagraph on failures with respect to any 1 disclosure shall not exceed $50,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b2a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Written demand</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b2b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/3/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary may make a written demand on any entity or manager subject to penalty under subparagraph (A) specifying therein a reasonable future date by which the disclosure shall be filed for purposes of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b2c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to comply with demand</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If any entity or manager fails to comply with any demand under clause (i) on or before the date specified in such demand, there shall be paid by such entity or manager failing to so comply $100 for each day after the expiration of the time specified in such demand during which such failure continues. The maximum penalty imposed under this subparagraph on all entities and managers for failures with respect to any 1 disclosure shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b2d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any term used in this section which is also used in section 4965 shall have the meaning given such term under section 4965.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b2e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notices under section 506</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b2f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalty on organization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a failure to submit a notice required under section 506(a) (relating to organizations required to notify Secretary of intent to operate as 501(c)(4)) on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor, there shall be paid by the organization failing to so submit $20 for each day during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subparagraph on any organization for failure to submit any one notice shall not exceed $5,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b30-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Managers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may make written demand on an organization subject to penalty under subparagraph (A) specifying in such demand a reasonable future date by which the notice shall be submitted for purposes of this subparagraph. If such notice is not submitted on or before such date, there shall be paid by the person failing to so submit $20 for each day after the expiration of the time specified in the written demand during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subparagraph on all persons for failure to submit any one notice shall not exceed $5,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b31-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Reasonable cause exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No penalty shall be imposed under this subsection with respect to any failure if it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b32-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Other special rules</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b33-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment as tax</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any penalty imposed under this subsection shall be paid on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b34-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If more than 1 person is liable under this subsection for any penalty with respect to any failure, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable with respect to such failure.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b35-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Person</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, the term “person” means any officer, director, trustee, employee, or other individual who is under a duty to perform the act in respect of which the violation occurs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b36-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment for inflation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b37-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of any failure relating to a return required to be filed in a calendar year beginning after 2014, each of the dollar amounts under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) shall be increased by an amount equal to such dollar amount multiplied by the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year determined by substituting “calendar year 2013” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b38-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rounding</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If any amount adjusted under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47156b39-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is not less than $5,000 and is not a multiple of $500, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $500, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47156b3a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/c/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is not described in clause (i) and is not a multiple of $5, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $5.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b3b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual registration and other notification by pension plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b3c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any failure to file a registration statement required under section 6057(a) (relating to annual registration of certain plans) which includes all participants required to be included in such statement, on the date prescribed therefor (determined without regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause, there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing so to file, an amount equal to $10 for each participant with respect to whom there is a failure to file, multiplied by the number of days during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this paragraph on any person for any failure to file with respect to any plan year shall not exceed $50,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b3d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of change of status</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of failure to file a notification required under section 6057(b) (relating to notification of change of status) on the date prescribed therefor (determined without regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause, there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing so to file, $10 for each day during which such failure continues, but the total amounts imposed under this paragraph on any person for failure to file any notification shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b3e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Information required in connection with certain plans of deferred compensation, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of failure to file a return or statement required under section 6058 (relating to information required in connection with certain plans of deferred compensation), 6047 (relating to information relating to certain trusts and annuity and bond purchase plans), or 6039D (relating to returns and records with respect to certain fringe benefit plans) on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause, there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing so to file, $250 for each day during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subsection on any person for failure to file any return shall not exceed $150,000. This subsection shall not apply to any return or statement which is an information return described in section 6724(d)(1)(C)(ii) or a payee statement described in section 6724(d)(2)(AA).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b3f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Returns required under section 6039C</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b40-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of each failure to make a return required by section 6039C which contains the information required by such section on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, the amount determined under paragraph (2) shall be paid (upon notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing to make such return.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b41-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of penalty</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the amount determined under this paragraph with respect to any failure shall be $25 for each day during which such failure continues.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b42-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amount determined under paragraph (2) with respect to any person for failing to meet the requirements of section 6039C for any calendar year shall not exceed the lesser of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47156b43-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> $25,000, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47156b44-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 5 percent of the aggregate of the fair market value of the United States real property interests owned by such person at any time during such year.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of the preceding sentence, fair market value shall be determined as of the end of the calendar year (or, in the case of any property disposed of during the calendar year, as of the date of such disposition).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b45-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/g"><num value="g" class="bold">[(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tII/s221/a/39/B">Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(39)(B)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/4043">128 Stat. 4043</ref>]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b46-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to give notice to recipients of certain pension, etc., distributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of each failure to provide notice as required by section 3405(e)(10)(B), at the time prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such notice, an amount equal to $100 for each such failure, but the total amount imposed on such person for all such failures during any calendar year shall not exceed $50,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b47-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to give written explanation to recipients of certain qualifying rollover distributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of each failure to provide a written explanation as required by section 402(f), at the time prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such written explanation, an amount equal to $100 for each such failure, but the total amount imposed on such person for all such failures during any calendar year shall not exceed $50,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b48-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to file certification with respect to certain residential rental projects</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of each failure to provide a certification as required by section 142(d)(7) at the time prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such certification, an amount equal to $100 for each such failure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b49-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002318">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002318"><num>1</num> See 1993 Amendment note below.</note> Failure to make reports required under section 1202</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a failure to make a report required under section 1202(d)(1)(C) which contains the information required by such section on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing to make such report, an amount equal to $50 for each report with respect to which there was such a failure. In the case of any failure due to negligence or intentional disregard, the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting “$100” for “$50”. In the case of a report covering periods in 2 or more years, the penalty determined under preceding provisions of this subsection shall be multiplied by the number of such years. No penalty shall be imposed under this subsection on any failure which is shown to be due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47156b4a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to file return with respect to certain corporate transactions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any failure to make a return required under section 6043(c) containing the information required by such section on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause, there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing to file such return, an amount equal to $500 for each day during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subsection with respect to any return shall not exceed $100,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4717dc4b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Alcohol and tobacco taxes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For penalties for failure to file certain information returns with respect to alcohol and tobacco taxes, see, generally, subtitle E.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4717dc4c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to make reports required under sections 3511, 6053(c)(8), and 7705</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a failure to make a report required under section 3511, 6053(c)(8), or 7705 which contains the information required by such section on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing to make such report, an amount equal to $50 for each report with respect to which there was such a failure. In the case of any failure due to negligence or intentional disregard the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting “$100” for “$50”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4717dc4d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to provide notices with respect to qualified small employer health reimbursement arrangements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of each failure to provide a written notice as required by section 9831(d)(4), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such written notice, an amount equal to $50 per employee per incident of failure to provide such notice, but the total amount imposed on such person for all such failures during any calendar year shall not exceed $2,500.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4717dc4e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s6652/p"><num value="p" class="bold">(p)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to provide notice under section 83(i)</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of each failure to provide a notice as required by section 83(i)(6), at the time prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such notice, an amount equal to $100 for each such failure, but the total amount imposed on such person for all such failures during any calendar year shall not exceed $50,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4717dc4f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/821">68A Stat. 821</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/tI/s85">Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 85</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1664">72 Stat. 1664</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s19/d">Pub. L. 87–834, § 19(d)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1057">76 Stat. 1057</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s221/b/2">Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 221(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/74">78 Stat. 74</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/tIII/s313/e/2/B">Pub. L. 89–97, title III, § 313(e)(2)(B)</ref>, (3), <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/385">79 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/212/s2/e">Pub. L. 89–212, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-29">Sept. 29, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/859">79 Stat. 859</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tI/s101/d/4">Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/522">83 Stat. 522</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/tII/s1031/b/1/A">Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1031(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (B)(i), <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/945">88 Stat. 945</ref>, 946; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXII/s1207/e/3/B">Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1207(e)(3)(B)</ref>, (C), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1708">90 Stat. 1708</ref>, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/96/167/s7/b/1">Pub. L. 96–167, § 7(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1979-12-29">Dec. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1277">93 Stat. 1277</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/tI/s101/d/2/A">Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(d)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/251">94 Stat. 251</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/499/tXI/s1123/b">Pub. L. 96–499, title XI, § 1123(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2689">94 Stat. 2689</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/603/s1/d/2">Pub. L. 96–603, § 1(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-28">Dec. 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3504">94 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tIII/s311/f">Pub. L. 97–34, title III, § 311(f)</ref>, title VII, § 723(a)(1), (3), (4), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/281">95 Stat. 281</ref>, 343, 344; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII">Pub. L. 97–248, title III</ref>, §§ 309(b)(2), 315(a), (b), <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/595">96 Stat. 595</ref>, 605, 606; <ref href="/us/pl/97/448/tII/s201/i/2">Pub. L. 97–448, title II, § 201(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2395">96 Stat. 2395</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/67/tI/s105/b/1">Pub. L. 98–67, title I, § 105(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/380">97 Stat. 380</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 145(b)(1), (2), 146(b)(1), (2), 148(b)(1), (2), 149(b)(1), 155(b)(2)(A), title IV, § 491(d)(50), title V, § 531(b)(4)(B), title VII, § 714(j)(3), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/685">98 Stat. 685</ref>, 686, 688, 689, 693, 852, 882, 963; <ref href="/us/pl/98/397/tII/s207/b">Pub. L. 98–397, title II, § 207(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-23">Aug. 23, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1450">98 Stat. 1450</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/611/s1/d/2">Pub. L. 98–611, § 1(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-31">Oct. 31, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3177">98 Stat. 3177</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/612/s1/b/2">Pub. L. 98–612, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-31">Oct. 31, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3181">98 Stat. 3181</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXI/s1151/b">Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1151(b)</ref>, title XIII, § 1301(g), title XV, § 1501(d)(1)(A), title XVII, § 1702(b), title XVIII, §§ 1810(f)(9), 1811(c)(2), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2502">100 Stat. 2502</ref>, 2656, 2740, 2774, 2828, 2833; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tX">Pub. L. 100–203, title X</ref>, §§ 10502(d)(11), 10704(a), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-444">101 Stat. 1330–444</ref>, 1330–461; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI">Pub. L. 100–647, title I</ref>, §§ 1011B(a)(10), 1017(b), 1018(u)(36), title III, § 3021(a)(10), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3484">102 Stat. 3484</ref>, 3575, 3592, 3630; <ref href="/us/pl/101/140/tII/s203/a/1">Pub. L. 101–140, title II, § 203(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-08">Nov. 8, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/830">103 Stat. 830</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII</ref>, §§ 7208(b)(2), 7841(d)(5), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2338">103 Stat. 2338</ref>, 2428; <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/tV/s522/b/2/F">Pub. L. 102–318, title V, § 522(b)(2)(F)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-03">July 3, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/314">106 Stat. 314</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/tXIII/s13113/c">Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13113(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/429">107 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/168/tXIII">Pub. L. 104–168, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1314(a), (b), <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1480">110 Stat. 1480</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI">Pub. L. 104–188, title I</ref>, §§ 1455(c), (d)(2), 1704(s), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1818">110 Stat. 1818</ref>, 1887; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXII/s1281/a">Pub. L. 105–34, title XII, § 1281(a)</ref>, (b), title XVI, § 1602(d)(2)(B), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1037">111 Stat. 1037</ref>, 1094; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tI/s1004/b/2/B">Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title I, § 1004(b)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-890">112 Stat. 2681–890</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/230">Pub. L. 106–230</ref>, §§ 1(c), 2(c), 3(c), <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/479">114 Stat. 479</ref>, 482, 483; <ref href="/us/pl/109/222/tV/s516/c">Pub. L. 109–222, title V, § 516(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-05-17">May 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/371">120 Stat. 371</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/tXII">Pub. L. 109–280, title XII</ref>, §§ 1201(b)(2), 1223(d), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1065">120 Stat. 1065</ref>, 1091; <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tII/s221/a/39/B">Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(39)(B)</ref>, div. B, title II, §§ 206(c)(4), 208(b), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/4043">128 Stat. 4043</ref>, 4071, 4072; <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dQ/tIV/s405/c">Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title IV, § 405(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/3119">129 Stat. 3119</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dC/tXVIII/s18001/a/5">Pub. L. 114–255, div. C, title XVIII, § 18001(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1342">130 Stat. 1342</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI">Pub. L. 115–97, title I</ref>, §§ 11002(d)(1)(LL), 13603(e), <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2060">131 Stat. 2060</ref>, 2164; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/a/299/B">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(299)(B)</ref>, (300), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1198">132 Stat. 1198</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dO/tIV/s403/a">Pub. L. 116–94, div. O, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3180">133 Stat. 3180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4717dc50-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id4717dc51-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Inflation Adjusted Items for Certain Years</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For inflation adjustment of certain items in this section, see Revenue Procedures listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4717dc52-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id4717dc53-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1201(b)(2) and 1223(d) of <ref href="/us/pl/109/280">Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, which directed the amendment of section 6652 without specifying the act to be amended, were executed to this section, which is section 6652 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See 2006 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/140/s203/a/1">Pub. L. 101–140, § 203(a)(1)</ref>, amended this section to read as if the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151/b">section 1151(b) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> (enacting subsec. (<i>l</i>)) had not been enacted. Subsequent to enactment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, subsec. (<i>l</i>) was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref>. See 1989, 1988, and 1987 Amendment notes below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4717dc54-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s403/b/2">Pub. L. 116–94, § 403(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “$50,000” for “$5,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s403/b/1">Pub. L. 116–94, § 403(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “$10” for “$1”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s403/b/3">Pub. L. 116–94, § 403(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “$10,000” for “$1,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s403/b/1">Pub. L. 116–94, § 403(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “$10” for “$1”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s403/a">Pub. L. 116–94, § 403(a)</ref>, substituted “$250” for “$25” and “$150,000” for “$15,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s403/c">Pub. L. 116–94, § 403(c)</ref>, substituted “$100” for “$10” and “$50,000” for “$5,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (c)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/299/B">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(299)(B)</ref>, inserted “an amount equal to” after “increased by” and “for the calendar year” after “section 1(f)(3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/300">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(300)</ref>, substituted “section 6724(d)(2)(AA)” for “section 6724(d)(2)(Y)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (c)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s11002/d/1/LL">Pub. L. 115–97, § 11002(d)(1)(LL)</ref>, substituted “for ‘calendar year 2016’ in subparagraph (A)(ii)” for “for ‘calendar year 1992’ in subparagraph (B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (p). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13603/e">Pub. L. 115–97, § 13603(e)</ref>, added subsec. (p).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255">Pub. L. 114–255</ref> added subsec. (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (c)(4) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref> added par. (4) and redesignated former pars. (4) to (6) as (5) to (7), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s208/b/2/A">Pub. L. 113–295, § 208(b)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “in applying the first sentence of this subparagraph, the amount of the penalty for each day during which a failure continues shall be $100 in lieu of the amount otherwise specified, and” for “the first sentence of this subparagraph shall be applied by substituting ‘$100’ for ‘$20’ and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s208/b/2/B">Pub. L. 113–295, § 208(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “in applying the first sentence of paragraph (1)(A), the amount of the penalty for each day during which a failure continues shall be $100 in lieu of the amount otherwise specified, and in lieu of applying the second sentence of paragraph (1)(A), the maximum penalty under paragraph (1)(A) shall not exceed $50,000, and” for “the first sentence of paragraph (1)(A) shall be applied by substituting ‘$100’ for ‘$20’, and the second sentence thereof shall be applied by substituting ‘$50,000’ for ‘$10,000’, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s208/b/1">Pub. L. 113–295, § 208(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/39/B">Pub. L. 113–295, § 221(a)(39)(B)</ref>, struck out subsec. (g). Text read as follows: “In the case of failure to make a report required by section 219(f)(4) which contains the information required by such section on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing so to file, an amount equal to $25 for each participant with respect to whom there was a failure to file such information, multiplied by the number of years during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subsection on any person for failure to file shall not exceed $10,000. No penalty shall be imposed under this subsection on any failure which is shown to be due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s206/c/4">Pub. L. 113–295, § 206(c)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/222/s516/c/2">Pub. L. 109–222, § 516(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “6033(a)(1)” for “6033” wherever appearing in heading and text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1223/d">Pub. L. 109–280, § 1223(d)</ref>, added subpar. (E). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1201/b/2">Pub. L. 109–280, § 1201(b)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/222/s516/c/1">Pub. L. 109–222, § 516(c)(1)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former pars. (3) and (4) as (4) and (5), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s3/c/4">Pub. L. 106–230, § 3(c)(4)</ref>, inserted “or 6012(a)(6)” after “section 6033” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s3/c/3">Pub. L. 106–230, § 3(c)(3)</ref>, inserted “or section 6012(a)(6)” after “section 6033” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s3/c/1">Pub. L. 106–230, § 3(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “or section 6012(a)(6) (relating to returns by political organizations)” after “organizations)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s3/c/2">Pub. L. 106–230, § 3(c)(2)</ref>, inserted “or section 6012(a)(6)” after “section 6033”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s2/c">Pub. L. 106–230, § 2(c)</ref>, in heading inserted “and reports” after “returns” and in text inserted “or report required under section 527(j)” after “filing)” and “or report” after “1 return”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s1/c">Pub. L. 106–230, § 1(c)</ref>, in heading inserted “and notice of status” after “exemption” and in text inserted “or notice materials (as defined in such section)” after “section)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1004/b/2/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1004(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “section 6104(d) with respect to any annual return” for “subsection (d) or (e)(1) of section 6104 (relating to public inspection of annual returns)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1004/b/2/C">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1004(b)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “section 6104(d) with respect to any exempt status application materials (as defined in such section)” for “section 6104(e)(2) (relating to public inspection of applications for exemption)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1602/d/2/B">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1602(d)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “section 6724(d)(2)(Y)” for “section 6724(d)(2)(X)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1281/a">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1281(a)</ref>, inserted at end “No penalty shall be imposed under this subsection on any failure which is shown to be due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1281/b">Pub. L. 105–34, § 1281(b)</ref>, inserted at end “No penalty shall be imposed under this subsection on any failure which is shown to be due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/168">Pub. L. 104–168</ref> in concluding provisions, substituted “$20” for “$10” and “$10,000” for “$5,000” and inserted at end “In the case of an organization having gross receipts exceeding $1,000,000 for any year, with respect to the return required under section 6033 for such year, the first sentence of this subparagraph shall be applied by substituting ‘$100’ for ‘$20’ and, in lieu of applying the second sentence of this subparagraph, the maximum penalty under this subparagraph shall not exceed $50,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1704/s/1">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1704(s)(1)</ref>, substituted “$20” for “$10” and “$10,000” for “$5,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1704/s/2">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1704(s)(2)</ref>, substituted “$20” for “$10”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1455/d/2">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1455(d)(2)</ref>, inserted at end “This subsection shall not apply to any return or statement which is an information return described in section 6724(d)(1)(C)(ii) or a payee statement described in section 6724(d)(2)(X).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1455/c">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1455(c)</ref>, substituted “$100” and “$50,000” for “the $10” and “$5,000”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref>, which directed amendment of section by adding subsec. (k) before the last subsection, was executed by adding subsec. (k) after subsec. (j) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/102/318">Pub. L. 102–318</ref> substituted “3405(e)(10)(B)” for “3405(d)(10)(B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7841/d/5/B">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7841(d)(5)(B)</ref>, redesignated the subsec. (k), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, as (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7841/d/5/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7841(d)(5)(A)</ref>, redesignated the subsection relating to information with respect to includible employee benefits as (k), see Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/140">Pub. L. 101–140</ref> amended this section to read as if amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1151(b)</ref>, had not been enacted, see Codification note above and 1986 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7208/b/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7208(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>) and redesignated former subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7841/d/5/B">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7841(d)(5)(B)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (k), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, as (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7208/b/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 7208(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1017/b">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1017(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (j) as it existed prior to its repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10502/d/11">Pub. L. 100–203, § 10502(d)(11)</ref>, by inserting “(and the corresponding provision of section 4041(d)(1))” after “section 4041(a)(1)”, see 1987 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s3021/a/10">Pub. L. 100–647, § 3021(a)(10)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “the employer-provided benefit (within the meaning of section 89 without regard to subsection (g)(3) thereof) with respect to the employee to whom such failure relates.” See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1011B/a/10">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1011B(a)(10)</ref>, substituted “subsection (g)(3)(C)(i)” for “subsection (g)(3)”. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1018/u/36">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1018(u)(36)</ref>, substituted “or part II of subchapter B of this chapter” for “or section 6678”. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10704/a">Pub. L. 100–203, § 10704(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally, revising and restating as pars. (1) to (4) provisions of former pars. (1) to (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10502/d/11">Pub. L. 100–203, § 10502(d)(11)</ref>, struck out subsec. (j), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1702/b">section 1702(b) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, which related to failure to give written notice to certain sellers of diesel fuel.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10502/d/11">Pub. L. 100–203, § 10502(d)(11)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>), relating to information with respect to includible employee benefits, as (k), and directed the redesignation of a nonexistent subsec. (m) as (<i>l</i>). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/d/1/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1501(d)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b) as (a), substituted “Returns with respect to certain payments aggregating less than $10” for “Other returns” in heading, and struck out former subsec. (a) which provided penalties for failure to file returns relating to information at source, payments of dividends, etc. and certain transfers of stock.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1811/c/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1811(c)(2)</ref>, inserted “(other than by subsection (d) of such section)” in par. (3)(A)(ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/d/1/A/i">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1501(d)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (c) to (f) as (b) to (e), respectively. Former subsec. (b) redesignated (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/d/1/A/i">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1501(d)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1810/f/9/C">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1810(f)(9)(C)</ref>, struck out “etc.,” after “Returns” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1810/f/9/A">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1810(f)(9)(A)</ref>, in amending par. (1) generally, struck out “(A)” after “In the case of each failure”, and struck out “(B) to furnish a statement required by section 6039C(b)(3),” before “on the date required”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1810/f/9/B">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1810(f)(9)(B)</ref>, in amending par. (3) generally, designated former subpar. (B) of par. (3) as the entire paragraph, struck out former subpar. (A) setting a limitation of $25,000 with respect to each subsection for failure to meet the requirements of subsection (a) or (b) of section 6039C, struck out former subpar. (B) heading “For failure to meet requirements of section 6039C(c)” and in text substituted “requirements of section 6039C” for “requirements of subsection (c) of section 6039C” and inserted “(A)” before “$25,000” and “(B)” before “5 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/d/1/A/i">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1501(d)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (i) and (j) as (h) and (i), respectively. Former subsec. (h) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1702/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1702(b)</ref>, added subsec. (j) relating to failure to give written notice to certain sellers of diesel fuel, and redesignated former subsec. (j), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1301/g">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1301(g)</ref>, added subsec. (j) relating to failure to file certification with respect to certain residential projects.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/d/1/A/i">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1501(d)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (k), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, as (j). Former subsec. (j), relating to failure to give written explanation to recipients of certain qualifying rollover distributions, redesignated (i). Such subsec. (j), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, was subsequently redesignated as subsec. (k) by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1301/g">section 1301(g) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, and also by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1702/b">section 1702(b) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, both of which added a new subsec. (j), see above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/d/1/A/i">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1501(d)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (k), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, as (j). Subsequently, such subsec. (j) was redesignated as subsec. (k) by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1301/g">section 1301(g) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, and also by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1702/b">section 1702(b) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (<i>l</i>), (m). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1151(b)</ref>, directed the redesignation of a nonexistent subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (m), and added a new subsec. (<i>l</i>) relating to information with respect to includible employee benefits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s145/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 145(b)(1)</ref>, added cl. (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s146/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 146(b)(1)</ref>, added cl. (vi).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(vii). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s148/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 148(b)(1)</ref>, added cl. (vii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s149/b/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 149(b)(1)</ref>, added cl. (viii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(ix). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s155/b/2/A">Pub. L. 98–369, § 155(b)(2)(A)</ref>, added cl. (ix).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s148/b/2">Pub. L. 98–369, § 148(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “, 6050I, or 6050J” for “or 6050I”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s146/b/2">Pub. L. 98–369, § 146(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “, 6050H or 6050I” for “or section 6050H”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s145/b/2">Pub. L. 98–369, § 145(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “or section 6050H” after “section 6041A(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/611/s1/d/2">Pub. L. 98–611, § 1(d)(2)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/98/612/s1/b/2">Pub. L. 98–612, § 1(b)(2)</ref>, made identical amendments, substituting “6039D (relating to returns and records with respect to certain fringe benefit plans)” for “125(h) (relating to information with respect to cafeteria plans)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s531/b/4/B/i">Pub. L. 98–369, § 531(b)(4)(B)(i)</ref>, which directed the amendment of subsec. (f) by striking out “or 6047 (relating to information relating to certain trusts and annuity and bond purchase plans)” and inserting in lieu thereof “, 6047 (relating to information relating to certain trusts and annuity and bond purchase plans), or 125(h) (relating to information with respect to cafeteria plans)”, was executed by substituting the quoted phrase for “or 6047 (relating to information relating to certain trusts and annuity plans)”, as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s531/b/4/B/ii">Pub. L. 98–369, § 531(b)(4)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “; etc.” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s491/d/50">Pub. L. 98–369, § 491(d)(50)</ref>, struck out “and bond purchase” after “trusts and annuity”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s714/j/3">Pub. L. 98–369, § 714(j)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (i). Former subsec. (i), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/98/397/s207/b">Pub. L. 98–397, § 207(b)</ref>, added subsec. (j). Former subsec. (j), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s714/j/3">Pub. L. 98–369, § 714(j)(3)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (i), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, as (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/98/397/s207/b">Pub. L. 98–397, § 207(b)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (j), relating to alcohol and tobacco taxes, as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/67/s105/b/1/B">Pub. L. 98–67, § 105(b)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out cls. (ii), (iii), and (iv), redesignated cls. (v) and (vi) as (ii) and (iii), respectively, and in cl. (iii), as so redesignated, struck out “6042(e), 6044(f), 6049(e), or” before “6051(d)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/67/s105/b/1/A">Pub. L. 98–67, § 105(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (C), added par. (2), redesignated former par. (2) as (3), and in par. (3), as so redesignated, inserted references to paragraph (2) in provisions preceding subpar. (A) and in provisions of subpar. (A) preceding cl. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/448">Pub. L. 97–448</ref>, which directed that “or” be struck out at end of subpar. (F) of par. (1), “or” be inserted at end of par. (2), a new par. (3) be added, and that in provision following par. (3), “paragraph (2) or (3)” be substituted for “paragraph (2)”, was executed by striking out “or” at end of subpar. (A)(vi) of par. (1), inserting “or” at end of subpar. (B)(iv) of par. (1), redesignating par. (3) as subpar. (C) and adding such subpar. (C), to par. (1), and in provision following subpar. (C) substituting “subparagraph (B) or (C)” for “subparagraph (B)”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the intervening amendment of subsec. (a) by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s315/a">section 315(a) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref> which redesignated former par. (1) as subpar. (A), former subpars. (A) to (F) as cls. (i) to (vi), and former par. (2) as subpar. (B), and in provision following subpar. (B) as so redesignated, substituted “subparagraph (B)” for “paragraph (2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s315/a">Pub. L. 97–248, § 315(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) with a heading “In general”, redesignated former par. (1) as subpar. (A), in subpar. (A) as so redesignated struck out “aggregate” before “amount”, redesignated former subpars. (A) through (F) as cls. (i) through (vi), respectively, in cls. (ii) and (iii) as so redesignated struck out “aggregating $10 or more” after “dividends”, in cl. (iv) as so redesignated substituted “(a)” for “(a)(1)” and struck out “aggregating $10 or more” after “interest”, in cl. (vi) as so redesignated inserted “6042(e), 6044(f), 6049(e), or” before “6051(d)”, redesignated former par. (2) as subpar. (B), in subpar. (B) as so redesignated designated from “section 6052(a)” through the end of the parenthesis as cl. (iii) and struck out “with respect to group-term life insurance on the life of an employee” thereafter, added cls. (i), (ii), and (iv), in text after cl. (iv) substituted “subparagraph (A)” for “paragraph (1)”, “subparagraph (B)” for “paragraph (2)”, “$50 for each such failure” for “$10 for each such failure”, and “shall not exceed $50,000” for “shall not exceed $25,000”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s309/b/2">Pub. L. 97–248, § 309(b)(2)</ref>, struck out pars. (3) and (4) which referred to section 6049(a)(2) and section 6049(a)(3), respectively, as sources of authority for the requirement of filing a statement of payment to another person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s315/b">Pub. L. 97–248, § 315(b)</ref>, substituted “$25” and “$15,000” for “$10” and “$5,000”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s723/a/4">Pub. L. 97–34, § 723(a)(4)</ref>, inserted in heading “information at source,” before “payments of dividends”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s723/a/1">Pub. L. 97–34, § 723(a)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (A), (E), and (F), and redesignated former subpars. (A) to (C) as (B) to (D), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s723/a/3">Pub. L. 97–34, § 723(a)(3)</ref>, substituted provisions relating to failure to file required statement of payment to another person under authority of section 6042(a)(2), 6044(a)(2), or 6049(a)(2) or (3), and imposition of penalties with a maximum of $1,000 for all failures during the calendar year, for provisions relating to failure to file required statement of payment to another person under authority of section 6041, 6042(a)(2), 6044(a)(2), 6049(a)(2) or (3), 6050A(a) or (b), 6050C, 6051(d), or 6053(b), and imposition of penalties with a maximum of $1,000 for all failures during the calendar year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s311/f">Pub. L. 97–34, § 311(f)</ref>, added subsec. (h) and redesignated former subsec. (h) as (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> inserted reference to statement required by section 6050C (relating to information regarding windfall profit tax on crude oil).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/603">Pub. L. 96–603</ref> substituted in heading “returns” for “reports” and in text “failure to comply” for “failure to file a report required under section 6056 (relating to annual reports by private foundations) or to comply”, “failing to meet such requirements” for “failing so to file or meet the publicity requirement”, and “failure with respect” for “failure to file or comply with the requirements of section 6104(d) with regard”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/499">Pub. L. 96–499</ref> added subsec. (g) and redesignated former subsec. (g) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/167">Pub. L. 96–167</ref> inserted “or” after “$10 or more),” in par. (1), struck out par. (2) relating to failure to make a return required by section 6039(a) with respect to a transfer of stock or a transfer of legal title to stock, redesignated par. (3) as (2), and in closing provision substituted “return referred to in paragraph (2)” for “return referred to in paragraph (2) or (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, §§ 1207(e)(3)(B), (C), 1906(b)(13)(A), inserted “in the case of each failure to make a return required by section 6050A(a) (relating to reporting requirements of certain fishing boat operators),” after “income tax withheld),” and “or section 6050A(b) (relating to statements furnished by certain fishing boat operators),” after “respect to tips),” and struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1031/b/1/B/i">Pub. L. 93–406, § 1031(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “, registration statements, etc.” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1031/b/1/A">Pub. L. 93–406, § 1031(b)(1)(A)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) and (f) and redesignated former subsec. (e) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s313/e/2/B">Pub. L. 89–97, § 313(e)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “and in the case of each failure to furnish a statement required by section 6053(b) (relating to statements furnished by employers with respect to tips),” after “income tax withheld),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/89/212">Pub. L. 89–212</ref> inserted “or which are compensation (as defined in section 3231(e))” and “or section 3201 (as the case may be)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s313/e/3">Pub. L. 89–97, § 313(e)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s313/e/3">Pub. L. 89–97, § 313(e)(3)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/88/272">Pub. L. 88–272</ref> provided a penalty for failure to make a return required by section 6039(a) with respect to a transfer of stock or a transfer of legal title to stock, and by section 6052(a) with respect to group-term life insurance on the life of an employee.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> added subsec. (a). Former subsec. (a) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> redesignated former subsec. (a) as (b), and substituted “section 6042(a)(2) (relating to payments of dividends aggregating less than $10), section 6044(a)(2) (relating to payments of patronage dividends aggregating less than $10), section 6049(a)(2) (relating to payments of interest aggregating less than $10), section 6049(a)(3) (relating to other payments of interest by corporations), or section 6051(d) (relating to information returns with respect to income tax withheld)” for “section 6042(1) (relating to payments of corporate dividends), section 6044 (relating to patronage dividends), or section 6051(d) (relating to information returns with respect to income tax withheld)”. Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/85/866">Pub. L. 85–866</ref> substituted “section 6042(1)” for “section 6042” and “(upon notice and demand by the Secretary or his delegate and in the same manner as tax), by the person failing to so file the statement, $1 for each such statement not so filed” for “by the person failing to file the statement, upon notice and demand by the Secretary or his delegate and in the same manner as tax, $1 for each such statement not filed”, deleted “section 6045 (relating to returns of brokers)” after “patronage dividends)” and inserted “on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing)” after “income tax withheld),”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4717dc55-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc56-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2019 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dO/tIV/s403/d">Pub. L. 116–94, div. O, title IV, § 403(d)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3180">133 Stat. 3180</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/94/dO/tIV/s403/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to returns, statements, and notifications required to be filed, and notices required to be provided, after <date date="2019-12-31">December 31, 2019</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc57-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2017 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s11002/d/1/LL">section 11002(d)(1)(LL) of Pub. L. 115–97</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="2017-12-31">Dec. 31, 2017</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s11002/e">section 11002(e) of Pub. L. 115–97</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13603/e">section 13603(e) of Pub. L. 115–97</ref> applicable to failures to provide notice after <date date="2017-12-31">Dec. 31, 2017</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13603/f/2">section 13603(f)(2) of Pub. L. 115–97</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s83">section 83 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc58-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2016 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/255">Pub. L. 114–255</ref> applicable to notices with respect to years beginning after <date date="2016-12-31">Dec. 31, 2016</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s18001/a/7/D">section 18001(a)(7)(D) of Pub. L. 114–255</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s36B">section 36B of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc59-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/113">Pub. L. 114–113</ref> applicable to organizations which are described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/4">section 501(c)(4) of this title</ref> and organized after <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, and to certain then-existing organizations, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/s405/f">section 405(f) of Pub. L. 114–113</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s506">section 506 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc5a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/39/B">section 221(a)(39)(B) of Pub. L. 113–295</ref> effective <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, subject to a savings provision, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/s221/b">section 221(b) of div. A of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s206/c/4">section 206(c)(4) of Pub. L. 113–295</ref> applicable with respect to wages for services performed on or after January 1 of the first calendar year beginning more than 12 months after <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dB/s206/g/1">section 206(g)(1) of div. B of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3302">section 3302 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dB/s208/b">section 208(b) of div. B of Pub. L. 113–295</ref> applicable to returns required to be filed, and statements required to be furnished, after <date date="2014-12-31">Dec. 31, 2014</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dB/s208/h">section 208(h) of div. B of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6651">section 6651 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc5b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1201/b/2">section 1201(b)(2) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref> applicable to returns for taxable years beginning after <date date="2006-12-31">Dec. 31, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1201/c/2">section 1201(c)(2) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6034">section 6034 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1223/d">section 1223(d) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref> applicable to notices and returns with respect to annual periods beginning after 2006, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/280/s1223/f">section 1223(f) of Pub. L. 109–280</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6033">section 6033 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/222">Pub. L. 109–222</ref> applicable to disclosures the due date for which are after <date date="2006-05-17">May 17, 2006</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/222/s516/d/2">section 516(d)(2) of Pub. L. 109–222</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4965">section 4965 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc5c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s1/c">section 1(c) of Pub. L. 106–230</ref> effective <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s1/d">section 1(d) of Pub. L. 106–230</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s527">section 527 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s3/c">section 3(c) of Pub. L. 106–230</ref> applicable to returns for taxable years beginning after <date date="2000-06-30">June 30, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/230/s3/d">section 3(d) of Pub. L. 106–230</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6012">section 6012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc5d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> applicable to requests made after the later of <date date="1998-12-31">Dec. 31, 1998</date>, or the 60th day after the Secretary of the Treasury first issues the regulations referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6104/d/4">section 6104(d)(4) of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1004/b/3">section 1004(b)(3) of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6104">section 6104 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc5e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXII/s1281/e">Pub. L. 105–34, title XII, § 1281(e)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1037">111 Stat. 1037</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/34/tXII/s1281/e">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 6683 and 7519 of this title] shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1602/d/2/B">section 1602(d)(2)(B) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref> effective as if included in the provisions of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1602/i">section 1602(i) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s26">section 26 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4717dc5f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1455(c), (d)(2) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> applicable to returns, reports, and other statements the due date for which (determined without regard to extensions) is after <date date="1996-12-31">Dec. 31, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1455/e">section 1455(e) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s408">section 408 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/168/tXIII/s1314/c">Pub. L. 104–168, title XIII, § 1314(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1481">110 Stat. 1481</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/168/tXIII/s1314/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to returns for taxable years ending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2550-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref> applicable to stock issued after <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s13113/e">section 13113(e) of Pub. L. 103–66</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s53">section 53 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2551-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/318">Pub. L. 102–318</ref> applicable, except as otherwise provided, to distributions after <date date="1992-12-31">Dec. 31, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/s522/d">section 522(d) of Pub. L. 102–318</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2552-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7208/b/2">section 7208(b)(2) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref> applicable to transactions after <date date="1990-03-31">Mar. 31, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s7208/b/4">section 7208(b)(4) of Pub. L. 101–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6043">section 6043 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/140">Pub. L. 101–140</ref> effective as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151">section 1151 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/140/s203/c">section 203(c) of Pub. L. 101–140</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2553-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1011B(a)(10), 1017(b), 1018(u)(36) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s3021/a/10">section 3021(a)(10) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective as if included in the amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151">section 1151 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s3021/d/1">section 3021(d)(1) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s129">section 129 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2554-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10502/d/11">section 10502(d)(11) of Pub. L. 100–203</ref> applicable to sales after <date date="1988-03-31">Mar. 31, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10502/e">section 10502(e) of Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s40">section 40 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tX/s10704/d">Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10704(d)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-463">101 Stat. 1330–463</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/203/tX/s10704/d">
<inline>“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 6685 and 7207 of this title] shall apply—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to returns for years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> on and after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>] in the case of applications submitted to the Internal Revenue Service—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> after <date date="1987-07-15">July 15, 1987</date>, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> on or before <date date="1987-07-15">July 15, 1987</date>, if the organization has a copy of the application on <date date="1987-07-15">July 15, 1987</date>.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2555-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151/b">section 1151(b) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to years beginning after <date date="1988-12-31">Dec. 31, 1988</date>, with certain qualifications and exceptions, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151/k">section 1151(k) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1301/g">section 1301(g) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to bonds issued after <date date="1986-08-15">Aug. 15, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see sections 1311 to 1318 of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Transitional Rules note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s141">section 141 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/d/1/A">section 1501(d)(1)(A) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to returns the due date for which (determined without regard to extensions) is after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1501/e">section 1501(e) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6721">section 6721 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1702/b">section 1702(b) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to sales after first calendar quarter beginning more than 60 days after <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1702/c">section 1702(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4041">section 4041 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 1810(f)(9) and 1811(c)(2) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provisions of the Tax Reform Act of 1984, <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1881">section 1881 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s48">section 48 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2556-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/612">Pub. L. 98–612</ref> effective <date date="1985-01-01">Jan. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/612/s1/d/2">section 1(d)(2) of Pub. L. 98–612</ref>, <date date="1984-10-31">Oct. 31, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3181">98 Stat. 3181</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/611">Pub. L. 98–611</ref> effective <date date="1985-01-01">Jan. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/611/s1/g/2">section 1(g)(2) of Pub. L. 98–611</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s127">section 127 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/397">Pub. L. 98–397</ref> applicable to distributions after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/397/s302/c">section 302(c) of Pub. L. 98–397</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 145(b)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to amounts received after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s145/d">section 145(d) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6050H">section 6050H of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 146(b)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to amounts received after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s146/d">section 146(d) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6050I">section 6050I of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 148(b)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable with respect to acquisitions of property and abandonments of property after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s148/d">section 148(d) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6050J">section 6050J of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s149/b/1">section 149(b)(1) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable with respect to exchanges after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s149/d">section 149(d) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6050K">section 6050K of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s155/b/2/A">section 155(b)(2)(A) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to contributions made after <date date="1984-12-31">Dec. 31, 1984</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s155/d/1">section 155(d)(1) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6050L">section 6050L of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s491/d/50">section 491(d)(50) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to obligations issued after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s491/f/1">section 491(f)(1) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s62">section 62 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s531/b/4/B">section 531(b)(4)(B) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1985-01-01">Jan. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s531/h">section 531(h) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s132">section 132 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s714/j/3">section 714(j)(3) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s715">section 715 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2557-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/67">Pub. L. 98–67</ref> applicable with respect to payments made after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/67/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 98–67</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/97/448/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 97–448, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2397">96 Stat. 2397</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (b), any amendment made by this title [amending this section and sections 44D, 46, 48, 193, 613A, 4988, 4989, 4991–4997, 6015, 6154, 6654, 6655, and 6678 of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4996">section 4996 of this title</ref>, and amending a provision set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s44E">section 44E of this title</ref>] shall take effect as if it had been included in the provision of the Crude Oil Windfall Profit Tax Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref>] to which such amendment relates.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of independent producer</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by section 201(d)(1) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4992">section 4992 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on <date date="1983-01-01">January 1, 1983</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalty provision</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by section 201(i) [amending this section and sections 4997 and 6678 of this title] shall apply with respect to returns and statements the due dates for which (without regard to extensions) are after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amendments to section 613a.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The amendment made by section 202(d)(1) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s613A">section 613A of this title</ref>] shall apply to transfers in taxable years ending after <date date="1974-12-31">December 31, 1974</date>, but only for purposes of applying section 613A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] to periods after <date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The amendment made by section 202(d)(2) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s613A">section 613A of this title</ref>] shall apply to bulk sales after <date date="1982-09-18">September 18, 1982</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No withholding by reason of condensate provision</inline>.—</heading><content>No withholding of tax shall be required under section 4995 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by reason of the amendment made by section 201(h)(2)(A) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4996">section 4996 of this title</ref>] before the date on which regulations with respect to such amendment are published in the Federal Register.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2558-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s309/b/2">section 309(b)(2) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to amounts paid (or treated as paid) after <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s309/c">section 309(c) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6049">section 6049 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s315/d">Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 315(d)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/607">96 Stat. 607</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s315/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6678">section 6678 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to returns or statements the due date for the filing of which (without regard to extensions) is after <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2559-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s311/f">section 311(f) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1981-12-31">Dec. 31, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/s311/i/1">section 311(i)(1) of Pub. L. 97–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s219">section 219 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tVII/s723/c">Pub. L. 97–34, title VII, § 723(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/344">95 Stat. 344</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/34/tVII/s723/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 6041 and 6678 of this title] shall apply to returns and statements required to be furnished after <date date="1981-12-31">December 31, 1981</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a255a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/603">Pub. L. 96–603</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1980-12-31">Dec. 31, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/603/s1/f">section 1(f) of Pub. L. 96–603</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6033">section 6033 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/499">Pub. L. 96–499</ref>, applicable to 1980 and subsequent calendar years, with 1980 being treated as beginning on <date date="1980-06-19">June 19, 1980</date>, and ending on <date date="1980-12-31">Dec. 31, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/499/s1125/b">section 1125(b) of Pub. L. 96–499</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s897">section 897 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> applicable to periods after <date date="1980-02-29">Feb. 29, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/s101/i">section 101(i) of Pub. L. 96–223</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6161">section 6161 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a255b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/167/s7/c">Pub. L. 96–167, § 7(c)</ref>, <date date="1979-12-29">Dec. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1277">93 Stat. 1277</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/167/s7/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 6039 and 6678 of this title] shall apply with respect to calendar years beginning after 1979.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a255c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1207(e)(3)(B), (C) of <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable to calendar years beginning after <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1207/f/4">section 1207(f)(4) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3121">section 3121 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a255d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref> effective <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/406/s1034">section 1034 of Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6057">section 6057 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a255e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1969-12-31">Dec. 31, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s101/k/2/B">section 101(k)(2)(B) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4940">section 4940 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a255f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1965 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/212">Pub. L. 89–212</ref> effective only with respect to tips received after 1965, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/212/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 89–212</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/97">Pub. L. 89–97</ref> applicable only with respect to tips received by employees after 1965, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/s313/f">section 313(f) of Pub. L. 89–97</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6053">section 6053 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2560-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/272">Pub. L. 88–272</ref> applicable to group-term life insurance provided after <date date="1963-12-31">Dec. 31, 1963</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/272/s204/d">section 204(d) of Pub. L. 88–272</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/272">Pub. L. 88–272</ref> applicable to taxable years ending after <date date="1963-12-31">Dec. 31, 1963</date>, except for par. (2) of subsec. (a) which shall apply to stock transferred pursuant to options exercised on or after <date date="1964-01-01">Jan. 1, 1964</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/272/s221/e">section 221(e) of Pub. L. 88–272</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s421">section 421 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2561-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> applicable to payments of dividends and interest made on or after <date date="1963-01-01">Jan. 1, 1963</date>, and to payments of amounts described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6044/b">section 6044(b) of this title</ref> made on or after <date date="1963-01-01">Jan. 1, 1963</date>, with respect to patronage occurring on or after the first day of the first taxable year of the cooperative beginning on or after <date date="1963-01-01">Jan. 1, 1963</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s19/h">section 19(h) of Pub. L. 87–834</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6042">section 6042 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id471a2562-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/866">Pub. L. 85–866</ref> effective <date date="1954-08-17">Aug. 17, 1954</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/866/s1/c/2">section 1(c)(2) of Pub. L. 85–866</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s165">section 165 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id471a2563-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Nonenforcement of Amendment Made by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151">Section 1151 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> for Fiscal Year 1990</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">No monies appropriated by <ref href="/us/pl/101/136">Pub. L. 101–136</ref> to be used to implement or enforce <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1151">section 1151 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> or the amendments made by such section, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/136/s528">section 528 of Pub. L. 101–136</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s89">section 89 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id471a2564-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1998</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle D [§§ 1401–1465] of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/104/188">Pub. L. 104–188</ref> require an amendment to any plan or annuity contract, such amendment shall not be required to be made before the first day of the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1998-01-01">Jan. 1, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1465">section 1465 of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id471a2565-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1994</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle B [§§ 521–523] of title V of <ref href="/us/pl/102/318">Pub. L. 102–318</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1994-01-01">Jan. 1, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/318/s523">section 523 of Pub. L. 102–318</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id471a2566-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1800–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
