<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id43fb5a36-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704"><num value="704">§ 704.</num><heading> Partner’s distributive share</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a37-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of partnership agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A partner’s distributive share of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit shall, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, be determined by the partnership agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a38-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of distributive share</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A partner’s distributive share of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit (or item thereof) shall be determined in accordance with the partner’s interest in the partnership (determined by taking into account all facts and circumstances), if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43fb5a39-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the partnership agreement does not provide as to the partner’s distributive share of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit (or item thereof), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id43fb5a3a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the allocation to a partner under the agreement of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit (or item thereof) does not have substantial economic effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a3b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contributed property</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a3c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43fb5a3d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> income, gain, loss, and deduction with respect to property contributed to the partnership by a partner shall be shared among the partners so as to take account of the variation between the basis of the property to the partnership and its fair market value at the time of contribution,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43fb5a3e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> if any property so contributed is distributed (directly or indirectly) by the partnership (other than to the contributing partner) within 7 years of being contributed—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43fb5a3f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the contributing partner shall be treated as recognizing gain or loss (as the case may be) from the sale of such property in an amount equal to the gain or loss which would have been allocated to such partner under subparagraph (A) by reason of the variation described in subparagraph (A) if the property had been sold at its fair market value at the time of the distribution,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43fb5a40-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the character of such gain or loss shall be determined by reference to the character of the gain or loss which would have resulted if such property had been sold by the partnership to the distributee, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43fb5a41-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> appropriate adjustments shall be made to the adjusted basis of the contributing partner’s interest in the partnership and to the adjusted basis of the property distributed to reflect any gain or loss recognized under this subparagraph, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43fb5a42-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> if any property so contributed has a built-in loss—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43fb5a43-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such built-in loss shall be taken into account only in determining the amount of items allocated to the contributing partner, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43fb5a44-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> except as provided in regulations, in determining the amount of items allocated to other partners, the basis of the contributed property in the hands of the partnership shall be treated as being equal to its fair market value at the time of contribution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraph (C), the term “built-in loss” means the excess of the adjusted basis of the property (determined without regard to subparagraph (C)(ii)) over its fair market value at the time of contribution.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a45-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for distributions where gain or loss would not be recognized outside partnerships</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43fb5a46-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> property contributed by a partner (hereinafter referred to as the “contributing partner”) is distributed by the partnership to another partner, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id43fb5a47-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> other property of a like kind (within the meaning of section 1031) is distributed by the partnership to the contributing partner not later than the earlier of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43fb5a48-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the 180th day after the date of the distribution described in subparagraph (A), or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id43fb5a49-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the due date (determined with regard to extensions) for the contributing partner’s return of the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year in which the distribution described in subparagraph (A) occurs,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">then to the extent of the value of the property described in subparagraph (B), paragraph (1)(B) shall be applied as if the contributing partner had contributed to the partnership the property described in subparagraph (B).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a4a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Other rules</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules similar to the rules of paragraph (1) shall apply to contributions by a partner (using the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting) of accounts payable and other accrued but unpaid items. Any reference in paragraph (1) or (2) to the contributing partner shall be treated as including a reference to any successor of such partner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a4b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on allowance of losses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a4c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A partner’s distributive share of partnership loss (including capital loss) shall be allowed only to the extent of the adjusted basis of such partner’s interest in the partnership at the end of the partnership year in which such loss occurred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a4d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Carryover</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any excess of such loss over such basis shall be allowed as a deduction at the end of the partnership year in which such excess is repaid to the partnership.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a4e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43fb5a4f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In determining the amount of any loss under paragraph (1), there shall be taken into account the partner’s distributive share of amounts described in paragraphs (4) and (6) of section 702(a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id43fdca50-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a charitable contribution of property whose fair market value exceeds its adjusted basis, subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the extent of the partner’s distributive share of such excess.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43fdca51-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Partnership interests created by gift</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fdca52-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Distributive share of donee includible in gross income</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of any partnership interest created by gift, the distributive share of the donee under the partnership agreement shall be includible in his gross income, except to the extent that such share is determined without allowance of reasonable compensation for services rendered to the partnership by the donor, and except to the extent that the portion of such share attributable to donated capital is proportionately greater than the share of the donor attributable to the donor’s capital. The distributive share of a partner in the earnings of the partnership shall not be diminished because of absence due to military service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id43fdca53-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchase of interest by member of family</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, an interest purchased by one member of a family from another shall be considered to be created by gift from the seller, and the fair market value of the purchased interest shall be considered to be donated capital. The “family” of any individual shall include only his spouse, ancestors, and lineal descendants, and any trusts for the primary benefit of such persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id43fdca54-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s704/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2 fontsize7">For rules in the case of the sale, exchange, liquidation, or reduction of a partner’s interest, see section 706(c)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id43fdca55-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/240">68A Stat. 240</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tII/s213/c/2">Pub. L. 94–455, title II, § 213(c)(2)</ref>, (3)(A), (d), (e), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1548">90 Stat. 1548</ref>, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tII/s201/b/1">Pub. L. 95–600, title II, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2816">92 Stat. 2816</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s71/a">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 71(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/589">98 Stat. 589</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7642/a">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7642(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2379">103 Stat. 2379</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXIX/s1937/b/1">Pub. L. 102–486, title XIX, § 1937(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3033">106 Stat. 3033</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tX/s1063/a">Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1063(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/947">111 Stat. 947</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s833/a">Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 833(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1589">118 Stat. 1589</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tXI/s1102/b">Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1102(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/639">129 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13503/a">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13503(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2141">131 Stat. 2141</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id43fdca56-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id43fdca57-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id43fdca58-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97">Pub. L. 115–97</ref> designated first and second sentences of existing provisions as pars. (1) and (2), respectively, inserted headings, and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/114/74">Pub. L. 114–74</ref> substituted “Partnership interests created by gift” for “Family partnerships” in heading, redesignated pars. (2) and (3) as (1) and (2), respectively, substituted “this subsection” for “this section” in par. (2), and struck out former par. (1). Prior to amendment, text of par. (1) read as follows: “A person shall be recognized as a partner for purposes of this subtitle if he owns a capital interest in a partnership in which capital is a material income-producing factor, whether or not such interest was derived by purchase or gift from any other person.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357">Pub. L. 108–357</ref> added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> substituted “7 years” for “5 years” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> substituted “is distributed (directly or indirectly)” for “is distributed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, income, gain, loss, and deduction with respect to property contributed to the partnership by a partner shall be shared among partners so as to take account of the variation between the basis of the property to the partnership and its fair market value at the time of contribution. Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules similar to the rules of the preceding sentence shall apply to contributions by a partner (using the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting) of accounts payable and other accrued but unpaid items.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally, substituting provisions directing that, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, income, gain, loss, and deduction with respect to property contributed to the partnership by a partner be shared among partners so as to take account of the variation between the basis of the property to the partnership and its fair market value at the time of contribution, and that similar rules apply to contributions by a partner (using the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting) of accounts payable and other accrued but unpaid items for provisions which had directed that, if the partnership agreement so provided, depreciation, depletion, or gain or loss with respect to property contributed to the partnership by a partner would under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be shared among the partners so as to take account of the variation between the basis of the property to the partnership and its fair market value at the time of contribution, and struck out provisions which had directed that in determining a partner’s distributive share of items described in section 702(a), depreciation, depletion, or gain or loss with respect to property contributed to the partnership by a partner would, except to the extent otherwise provided, be allocated among the partners in the same manner as if such property had been purchased by the partnership and that if the partnership agreement did not provide otherwise, depreciation, depletion, or gain or loss with respect to undivided interests in property contributed to a partnership would be determined as though such undivided interests had not been contributed to the partnership.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref> struck out provisions relating to adjusted basis of a partner’s interest.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s213/c/2">Pub. L. 94–455, § 213(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “except as otherwise provided in this chapter” for “except as otherwise provided in this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s213/d">Pub. L. 94–455, § 213(d)</ref>, among other changes, substituted “Determination of distributive share” for “Distributive share determined by income or loss ratio” in heading, in provisions preceding par. (1) “the partner’s interest in the partnership (determined by taking into account all facts and circumstances)” for “his distributive share of taxable income or loss of the partnership, as described in section 702(a)(9), for the taxable year”, and in par. (2) provision relating to a lack of substantial economic effect in a partnership agreement for provisions relating to the partnership agreement’s purpose being the avoidance or evasion of taxes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s213/e">Pub. L. 94–455, § 213(e)</ref>, inserted provision relating to the determination of the adjusted basis of a partner’s liability where there is no personal liability and the applicability of such determination where <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s465">section 465 of this title</ref> applies or the principal activity of the partnership is real estate investment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s213/c/3/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 213(c)(3)(A)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id43fdca59-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca5a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2017 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13503/b">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13503(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2141">131 Stat. 2141</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13503/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to partnership taxable years beginning after <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca5b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/74/tXI/s1102/c">Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1102(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/639">129 Stat. 639</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/74/tXI/s1102/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s761">section 761 of this title</ref>] shall apply to partnership taxable years beginning after <date date="2015-12-31">December 31, 2015</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca5c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s833/d/1">Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 833(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1592">118 Stat. 1592</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s833/d/1">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to contributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca5d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tX/s1063/b">Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1063(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/947">111 Stat. 947</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/34/tX/s1063/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s737">section 737 of this title</ref>] shall apply to property contributed to a partnership after <date date="1997-06-08">June 8, 1997</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Binding contracts</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall not apply to any property contributed pursuant to a written binding contract in effect on <date date="1997-06-08">June 8, 1997</date>, and at all times thereafter before such contribution if such contract provides for the contribution of a fixed amount of property.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca5e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXIX/s1937/c">Pub. L. 102–486, title XIX, § 1937(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3033">106 Stat. 3033</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/486/tXIX/s1937/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s737">section 737 of this title</ref> and amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s731">section 731 of this title</ref>] shall apply to distributions on or after <date date="1992-06-25">June 25, 1992</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca5f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7642/b">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7642(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2381">103 Stat. 2381</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7642/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply in the case of property contributed to the partnership after <date date="1989-10-03">October 3, 1989</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca60-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s71/c">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 71(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/589">98 Stat. 589</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s71/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 613A and 743 of this title] shall apply with respect to property contributed to the partnership after <date date="1984-03-31">March 31, 1984</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca61-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref> and enactment of provision set out as a note under this section by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s201/b/2">section 201(b)(2) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1978-12-31">Dec. 31, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s204/a">section 204(a) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s465">section 465 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id43fdca62-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 213(c)(2), (c)(3)(A), (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable in the case of partnership taxable years beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s213/f/1">section 213(f)(1) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s709">section 709 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s213/e">section 213(e) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref> applicable to liabilities incurred after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s213/f/2">section 213(f)(2) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s709">section 709 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id43fdca63-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transitional Rule for Limitation on Allowance of Losses</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tII/s201/b/2">Pub. L. 95–600, title II, § 201(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2816">92 Stat. 2816</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“In the case of a loss which was not allowed for any taxable year by reason of the last 2 sentences of section 704(d) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] (as in effect before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>]), such loss shall be treated as a deduction (subject to section 465(a) of such Code) for the first taxable year beginning after <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>. Section 465(a) of such Code (as amended by this section) shall not apply with respect to partnership liabilities to which the last 2 sentences of section 704(d) of such Code (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act) did not apply because of the provisions of section 213(f)(2) of the Tax Reform Act of 1976 [set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s709">section 709 of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
