<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id4755cfa7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7442"><num value="7442">§ 7442.</num><heading> Jurisdiction</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Tax Court and its divisions shall have such jurisdiction as is conferred on them by this title, by chapters 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, by title II and title III of the Revenue Act of 1926 (<ref href="/us/stat/44/10-87">44 Stat. 10–87</ref>), or by laws enacted subsequent to <date date="1926-02-26">February 26, 1926</date>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id4755cfa8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/879">68A Stat. 879</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4755cfa9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4755cfaa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4755cfab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapters 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in text, were comprised of sections 1 to 482, 500 to 706, 800 to 939, and 1000 to 1031 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Chapters 1 and 2 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 were repealed by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7851/a/1/A">section 7851(a)(1)(A) of this title</ref>, and chapters 3 and 4 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 were repealed by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7851/a/2/A">section 7851(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref>. For table of comparisons of the 1939 Code to the 1986 Code, see Table I preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>. See also <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7851/e">section 7851(e) of this title</ref> for provision that references in the 1986 Code to a provision of the 1939 Code, not then applicable, shall be deemed a reference to the corresponding provision of the 1986 Code, which is then applicable.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Revenue Act of 1926, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1926-02-26/ch27">act Feb. 26, 1926, ch. 27</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/9">44 Stat. 9</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
