<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id475f6bf8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456"><num value="7456">§ 7456.</num><heading> Administration of oaths and procurement of testimony</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id475f6bf9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the efficient administration of the functions vested in the Tax Court or any division thereof, any judge or special trial judge of the Tax Court, the clerk of the court or his deputies, as such, or any other employee of the Tax Court designated in writing for the purpose by the chief judge, may administer oaths, and any judge or special trial judge of the Tax Court may examine witnesses and require, by subpoena ordered by the Tax Court or any division thereof and signed by the judge or special trial judge (or by the clerk of the Tax Court or by any other employee of the Tax Court when acting as deputy clerk)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id475f6bfa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the attendance and testimony of witnesses, and the production of all necessary returns, books, papers, documents, correspondence, and other evidence, from any place in the United States at any designated place of hearing, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id475f6bfb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the taking of a deposition before any designated individual competent to administer oaths under this title. In the case of a deposition the testimony shall be reduced to writing by the individual taking the deposition or under his direction and shall then be subscribed by the deponent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id475f6bfc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Production of records in the case of foreign corporations, foreign trusts or estates and nonresident alien individuals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Tax Court or any division thereof, upon motion and notice by the Secretary, and upon good cause shown therefor, shall order any foreign corporation, foreign trust or estate, or nonresident alien individual, who has filed a petition with the Tax Court, to produce, or, upon satisfactory proof to the Tax Court or any of its divisions, that the petitioner is unable to produce, to make available to the Secretary, and, in either case, to permit the inspection, copying, or photographing of, such books, records, documents, memoranda, correspondence and other papers, wherever situated, as the Tax Court or any division thereof, may deem relevant to the proceedings and which are in the possession, custody or control of the petitioner, or of any person directly or indirectly under his control or having control over him or subject to the same common control. If the petitioner fails or refuses to comply with any of the provisions of such order, after reasonable time for compliance has been afforded to him, the Tax Court or any division thereof, upon motion, shall make an order striking out pleadings or parts thereof, or dismissing the proceeding or any part thereof, or rendering a judgment by default against the petitioner. For the purpose of this subsection, the term “foreign trust or estate” includes an estate or trust, any fiduciary of which is a foreign corporation or nonresident alien individual; and the term “control” is not limited to legal control.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id475f6bfd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Incidental powers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Tax Court and each division thereof shall have power to punish by fine or imprisonment, at its discretion, such contempt of its authority, and none other, as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id475f6bfe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> misbehavior of any person in its presence or so near thereto as to obstruct the administration of justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id475f6bff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> misbehavior of any of its officers in their official transactions; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id475f6c00-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7456/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> disobedience or resistance to its lawful writ, process, order, rule, decree, or command.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">It shall have such assistance in the carrying out of its lawful writ, process, order, rule, decree, or command as is available to a court of the United States. The United States marshal for any district in which the Tax Court is sitting shall, when requested by the chief judge of the Tax Court, attend any session of the Tax Court in such district and may otherwise provide, when requested by the chief judge of the Tax Court, for the security of the Tax Court, including the personal protection of Tax Court judges, court officers, witnesses, and other threatened persons in the interests of justice, where criminal intimidation impedes on the functioning of the judicial process or any other official proceeding. The United States Marshals Service retains final authority regarding security requirements for the Tax Court.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id475f6c01-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/885">68A Stat. 885</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/tIX">Pub. L. 91–172, title IX</ref>, §§ 956, 958, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/732">83 Stat. 732</ref>, 734; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tIII/s336/b/1">Pub. L. 95–600, title III, § 336(b)(1)</ref>, title V, § 502(c), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2841">92 Stat. 2841</ref>, 2879; <ref href="/us/pl/96/222/tI/s105/a/1/B">Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 105(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/218">94 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s153/a">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 153(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/47">96 Stat. 47</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIV/s402/c/13">Pub. L. 97–248, title IV, § 402(c)(13)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/668">96 Stat. 668</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/362/tI/s106/c">Pub. L. 97–362, title I, § 106(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-25">Oct. 25, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1730">96 Stat. 1730</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 463(a), 464(a)–(c), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/824">98 Stat. 824</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXV">Pub. L. 99–514, title XV</ref>, §§ 1555(a), 1556(b)(1), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2754">100 Stat. 2754</ref>, 2755; <ref href="/us/pl/110/177/tI/s102/b">Pub. L. 110–177, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2535">121 Stat. 2535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id475f6c02-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id475f6c03-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id475f6c04-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/110/177">Pub. L. 110–177</ref> inserted before period at end of concluding provisions “and may otherwise provide, when requested by the chief judge of the Tax Court, for the security of the Tax Court, including the personal protection of Tax Court judges, court officers, witnesses, and other threatened persons in the interests of justice, where criminal intimidation impedes on the functioning of the judicial process or any other official proceeding. The United States Marshals Service retains final authority regarding security requirements for the Tax Court”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1556/b/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1556(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c). Former subsec. (c), which provided for the appointment of special trial judges, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1555/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1555(a)</ref>, inserted last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1556/b/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1556(b)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which set out proceedings which could be assigned to special trial judges appointed under former subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1556/b/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1556(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s464/a">Pub. L. 98–369, § 464(a)</ref>, substituted “special trial judge” for “commissioner” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s464/b">Pub. L. 98–369, § 464(b)</ref>, substituted “Special trial judges” for “Commissioners” in heading, and in text substituted “special trial judges” for “commissioners” and “special trial judge” for “commissioner”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s464/c">Pub. L. 98–369, § 464(c)</ref>, substituted “Special trial judges” for “Commissioners” in heading, and substituted “special trial judges” for “commissioners” and “special trial judge” for “commissioner” in provisions following par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s463/a">Pub. L. 98–369, § 463(a)</ref>, in amending subsec. (d) generally, struck out “and” at end of par. (2), substituted “any proceeding” for “any other proceeding” and “$10,000; and” for “$5,000,” in par. (3), added par. (4), and substituted “any proceeding described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3), subject to such conditions and review as the court may provide” for “any such proceeding, subject to such conditions and review as the court may by rule provide” in provisions following par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/362/s106/c/2">Pub. L. 97–362, § 106(c)(2)</ref>, struck out provision that the chief judge may assign proceedings under sections 6226, 6228(a), 7428, 7463, 7476, 7477, and 7478 to be heard by the commissioners of the court, and that the court may authorize a commissioner to make the decision of the court with respect to such proceedings, subject to such conditions and review as the court may by rule provide. See subsec. (d) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> inserted “6226, 6228(a),” after “proceedings under sections”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> substituted “Each commissioner shall receive pay at an annual rate determined under section 225 of the Federal Salary Act of 1967 (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s351–361">2 U.S.C. 351–361</ref>), as adjusted by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s461">section 461 of title 28</ref>, United States Code, and also necessary traveling expenses and per diem allowances, as provided in subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, United States Code, while traveling on official business and away from Washington, District of Columbia” for “Each commissioner shall receive the same compensation and travel and subsistence allowances provided by law for commissioners of the United States Court of Claims”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/362/s106/c/1">Pub. L. 97–362, § 106(c)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/222">Pub. L. 96–222</ref> substituted “sections 7428, 7463” for “sections 7428”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s502/c">Pub. L. 95–600, § 502(c)</ref>, substituted “any judge or commissioner of the Tax Court” for “any judge of the Tax Court” wherever appearing, and “by the judge or commissioner” for “by the judge” after “and signed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s336/b/1">Pub. L. 95–600, § 336(b)(1)</ref>, inserted provision that the chief judge may assign proceedings under sections 7428, 7476, 7477, and 7478 to be heard by the commissioners of the court, and the court may authorize a commissioner to make the decision of the court with respect to such proceedings, subject to such conditions and review as the court may by rule provide.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s958">Pub. L. 91–172, § 958</ref>, provided that commissioners be compensated at rates identical to those of commissioners of the United States Court of Claims, and substituted provisions authorizing the chief judge of the Tax Court to appoint Commissioners for provisions authorizing attorneys from the legal staff of the Tax Court to act as Commissioners.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s956">Pub. L. 91–172, § 956</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id475f6c05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id475f6c06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1555/b">Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1555(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2754">100 Stat. 2754</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1555/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1556/b/1">section 1556(b)(1) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> effective <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1556/c">section 1556(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7443A">section 7443A of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id475f6c07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV/s463/b">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 463(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/824">98 Stat. 824</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV/s463/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect as if enacted as part of the Miscellaneous Revenue Act of 1982 [<ref href="/us/pl/97/362">Pub. L. 97–362</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV/s464/e/1">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 464(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/825">98 Stat. 825</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV/s464/e/1">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7471">section 7471 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out below] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id475f6c08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to partnership taxable years beginning after <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, with provision for the applicability of the amendment to any partnership taxable year ending after <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, if the partnership, each partner, and each indirect partner requests such application and the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate consents to such application, see section 407(a)(1), (3) of <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s702">section 702 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id475f6c09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/222/tI/s105/b/1">Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 105(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/221">94 Stat. 221</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/222/tI/s105/b/1">“The amendments made by subsection (a)(1) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7463">section 7463 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id475f6c0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s336/b/1">section 336(b)(1) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref> applicable to requests for determinations made after <date date="1978-12-31">Dec. 31, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s336/d">section 336(d) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7478">section 7478 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s502/c">section 502(c) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref> effective <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s502/d/2">section 502(d)(2) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7463">section 7463 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id475f6c0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1969 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/172">Pub. L. 91–172</ref> effective <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/172/s962/a">section 962(a) of Pub. L. 91–172</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7441">section 7441 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id475f6c0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reimbursement</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/177/tI/s102/c">Pub. L. 110–177, title I, § 102(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2535">121 Stat. 2535</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/177/tI/s102/c">“The United States Tax Court shall reimburse the United States Marshals Service for protection provided under the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s566">section 566 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id475f6c0d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Commissioners Deemed References to Special Trial Judges</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV/s464/e/2">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 464(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/825">98 Stat. 825</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tIV/s464/e/2">“Any reference in any law to a commissioner of the Tax Court shall be treated as a reference to a special trial judge of the Tax Court.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id475f6c0e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Commissioners’ Salaries Pending Changes Under Federal Salary Act</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s153/b">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 153(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/47">96 Stat. 47</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“Notwithstanding the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section], until such time as a change in the salary rate of a commissioner of the United States Tax Court occurs in accordance with section 7456(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954], the salary of such commissioner shall be equal to the salary of a commissioner of the Court of Claims immediately prior to the effective date of this Act [<date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
