<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id47773a81-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609"><num value="7609">§ 7609.</num><heading> Special procedures for third-party summonses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a82-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a83-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If any summons to which this section applies requires the giving of testimony on or relating to, the production of any portion of records made or kept on or relating to, or the production of any computer software source code (as defined in 7612(d)(2)) with respect to, any person (other than the person summoned) who is identified in the summons, then notice of the summons shall be given to any person so identified within 3 days of the day on which such service is made, but no later than the 23rd day before the day fixed in the summons as the day upon which such records are to be examined. Such notice shall be accompanied by a copy of the summons which has been served and shall contain an explanation of the right under subsection (b)(2) to bring a proceeding to quash the summons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a84-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Sufficiency of notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Such notice shall be sufficient if, on or before such third day, such notice is served in the manner provided in section 7603 (relating to service of summons) upon the person entitled to notice, or is mailed by certified or registered mail to the last known address of such person, or, in the absence of a last known address, is left with the person summoned. If such notice is mailed, it shall be sufficient if mailed to the last known address of the person entitled to notice or, in the case of notice to the Secretary under section 6903 of the existence of a fiduciary relationship, to the last known address of the fiduciary of such person, even if such person or fiduciary is then deceased, under a legal disability, or no longer in existence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a85-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Nature of summons</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any summons to which this subsection applies (and any summons in aid of collection described in subsection (c)(2)(D)) shall identify the taxpayer to whom the summons relates or the other person to whom the records pertain and shall provide such other information as will enable the person summoned to locate the records required under the summons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a86-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Right to intervene; right to proceeding to quash</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a87-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Intervention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other law or rule of law, any person who is entitled to notice of a summons under subsection (a) shall have the right to intervene in any proceeding with respect to the enforcement of such summons under section 7604.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a88-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Proceeding to quash</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a89-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other law or rule of law, any person who is entitled to notice of a summons under subsection (a) shall have the right to begin a proceeding to quash such summons not later than the 20th day after the day such notice is given in the manner provided in subsection (a)(2). In any such proceeding, the Secretary may seek to compel compliance with the summons.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a8a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement of notice to person summoned and to Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If any person begins a proceeding under subparagraph (A) with respect to any summons, not later than the close of the 20-day period referred to in subparagraph (A) such person shall mail by registered or certified mail a copy of the petition to the person summoned and to such office as the Secretary may direct in the notice referred to in subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a8b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Intervention; etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other law or rule of law, the person summoned shall have the right to intervene in any proceeding under subparagraph (A). Such person shall be bound by the decision in such proceeding (whether or not the person intervenes in such proceeding).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a8c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Summons to which section applies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a8d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), this section shall apply to any summons issued under paragraph (2) of section 7602(a) or under section 6420(e)(2), 6421(g)(2), 6427(j)(2), or 7612.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a8e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This section shall not apply to any summons—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773a8f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> served on the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued, or any officer or employee of such person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773a90-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> issued to determine whether or not records of the business transactions or affairs of an identified person have been made or kept;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773a91-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> issued solely to determine the identity of any person having a numbered account (or similar arrangement) with a bank or other institution described in section 7603(b)(2)(A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773a92-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> issued in aid of the collection of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47773a93-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an assessment made or judgment rendered against the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47773a94-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the liability at law or in equity of any transferee or fiduciary of any person referred to in clause (i); or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773a95-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773a96-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> issued by a criminal investigator of the Internal Revenue Service in connection with the investigation of an offense connected with the administration or enforcement of the internal revenue laws; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773a97-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/2/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> served on any person who is not a third-party recordkeeper (as defined in section 7603(b)).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a98-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> John Doe and certain other summonses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subsection (a) shall not apply to any summons described in subsection (f) or (g).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a99-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “records” includes books, papers, and other data.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a9a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on examination of records</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No examination of any records required to be produced under a summons as to which notice is required under subsection (a) may be made—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47773a9b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> before the close of the 23rd day after the day notice with respect to the summons is given in the manner provided in subsection (a)(2), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47773a9c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> where a proceeding under subsection (b)(2)(A) was begun within the 20-day period referred to in such subsection and the requirements of subsection (b)(2)(B) have been met, except in accordance with an order of the court having jurisdiction of such proceeding or with the consent of the person beginning the proceeding to quash.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a9d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of statute of limitations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a9e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Subsection (b) action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If any person takes any action as provided in subsection (b) and such person is the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued (or is the agent, nominee, or other person acting under the direction or control of such person), then the running of any period of limitations under section 6501 (relating to the assessment and collection of tax) or under section 6531 (relating to criminal prosecutions) with respect to such person shall be suspended for the period during which a proceeding, and appeals therein, with respect to the enforcement of such summons is pending.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47773a9f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension after 6 months of service of summons</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the absence of the resolution of the summoned party’s response to the summons, the running of any period of limitations under section 6501 or under section 6531 with respect to any person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued (other than a person taking action as provided in subsection (b)) shall be suspended for the period—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773aa0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> beginning on the date which is 6 months after the service of such summons, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47773aa1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ending with the final resolution of such response.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773aa2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional requirement in the case of a John Doe summons</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any summons described in subsection (c)(1) which does not identify the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued may be served only after a court proceeding in which the Secretary establishes that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47773aa3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the summons relates to the investigation of a particular person or ascertainable group or class of persons,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47773aa4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> there is a reasonable basis for believing that such person or group or class of persons may fail or may have failed to comply with any provision of any internal revenue law, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47773aa5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the information sought to be obtained from the examination of the records or testimony (and the identity of the person or persons with respect to whose liability the summons is issued) is not readily available from other sources.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall not issue any summons described in the preceding sentence unless the information sought to be obtained is narrowly tailored to information that pertains to the failure (or potential failure) of the person or group or class of persons referred to in paragraph (2) to comply with one or more provisions of the internal revenue law which have been identified for purposes of such paragraph.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773aa6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Special exception for certain summonses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A summons is described in this subsection if, upon petition by the Secretary, the court determines, on the basis of the facts and circumstances alleged, that there is reasonable cause to believe the giving of notice may lead to attempts to conceal, destroy, or alter records relevant to the examination, to prevent the communication of information from other persons through intimidation, bribery, or collusion, or to flee to avoid prosecution, testifying, or production of records.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47773aa7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of district court; etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaa8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The United States district court for the district within which the person to be summoned resides or is found shall have jurisdiction to hear and determine any proceeding brought under subsection (b)(2), (f), or (g). An order denying the petition shall be deemed a final order which may be appealed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaa9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for proceedings under subsections (f) and (g)</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The determinations required to be made under subsections (f) and (g) shall be made ex parte and shall be made solely on the petition and supporting affidavits.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaaa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Duty of summoned party</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Recordkeeper must assemble records and be prepared to produce records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">On receipt of a summons to which this section applies for the production of records, the summoned party shall proceed to assemble the records requested, or such portion thereof as the Secretary may prescribe, and shall be prepared to produce the records pursuant to the summons on the day on which the records are to be examined.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaac-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary may give summoned party certificate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may issue a certificate to the summoned party that the period prescribed for beginning a proceeding to quash a summons has expired and that no such proceeding began within such period, or that the taxpayer consents to the examination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaad-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection for summoned party who discloses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any summoned party, or agent or employee thereof, making a disclosure of records or testimony pursuant to this section in good faith reliance on the certificate of the Secretary or an order of a court requiring production of records or the giving of such testimony shall not be liable to any customer or other person for such disclosure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaae-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/i/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of suspension of statute of limitations in the case of a John Doe summons</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a summons described in subsection (f) with respect to which any period of limitations has been suspended under subsection (e)(2), the summoned party shall provide notice of such suspension to any person described in subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4779aaaf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s7609/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of summons not required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the Secretary’s ability to obtain information, other than by summons, through formal or informal procedures authorized by sections 7601 and 7602.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4779aab0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXII/s1205/a">Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1205(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1699">90 Stat. 1699</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/tV/s505/c/6">Pub. L. 95–599, title V, § 505(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2760">92 Stat. 2760</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 95–600, title VII, § 703</ref>(<i>l</i>)(4), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2943">92 Stat. 2943</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/tII/s232/d/4/E">Pub. L. 96–223, title II, § 232(d)(4)(E)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/278">94 Stat. 278</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII">Pub. L. 97–248, title III</ref>, §§ 311(b), 331(a)–(d), 332(a), <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/601">96 Stat. 601</ref>, 620, 621; <ref href="/us/pl/97/424/tV/s515/b/12">Pub. L. 97–424, title V, § 515(b)(12)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2182">96 Stat. 2182</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tVII/s714/i">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 714(i)</ref>, title IX, § 911(d)(2)(G), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/962">98 Stat. 962</ref>, 1007; <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tIV/s402/28/D">Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(28)(D)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3359">98 Stat. 3359</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tVI/s656/a">Pub. L. 99–514, title VI, § 656(a)</ref>, title XV, § 1561(a), (b), title XVII, § 1703(e)(2)(G), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2299">100 Stat. 2299</ref>, 2761, 2778; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI">Pub. L. 100–647, title I</ref>, §§ 1015(<i>l</i>)(1), (2), 1017(c)(9), (12), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3571">102 Stat. 3571</ref>, 3572, 3576, 3577; <ref href="/us/pl/104/168/tX/s1001/a">Pub. L. 104–168, title X, § 1001(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1467">110 Stat. 1467</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3415/a">Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3415(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/755">112 Stat. 755</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s408/a">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 408(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2635">119 Stat. 2635</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/25/tI/s1204/a">Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1204(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/988">133 Stat. 988</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4779aab1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4779aab2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id4779aab3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 7609 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7613">section 7613 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4779aab4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/25">Pub. L. 116–25</ref> inserted concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (c)(2)(D) to (F). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s408/a/1">Pub. L. 109–135, § 408(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “or” at end of subpar. (D), substituted period for “; or” at end of subpar. (E), and struck out subpar. (F) which read as follows: “described in subsection (f) or (g).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s408/a/2">Pub. L. 109–135, § 408(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/a">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(a)</ref>, reenacted heading without change and in text substituted “If any summons to which this section applies requires the giving of testimony on or relating to, the production of any portion of records made or kept on or relating to, or the production of any computer software source code (as defined in 7612(d)(2)) with respect to, any person (other than the person summoned) who is identified in the summons, then” for “If—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) any summons described in subsection (c) is served on any person who is a third-party recordkeeper, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the summons requires the production of any portion of records made or kept of the business transactions or affairs of any person (other than the person summoned) who is identified in the description of the records contained in the summons,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/1">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (3), substituted “subsection (c)(2)(D)” for “subsection (c)(2)(B)”, and struck out heading and text of former par. (3). Text read as follows: “For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘third-party recordkeeper’ means—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) any mutual savings bank, cooperative bank, domestic building and loan association, or other savings institution chartered and supervised as a savings and loan or similar association under Federal or State law, any bank (as defined in section 581), or any credit union (within the meaning of section 501(c)(14)(A));</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) any consumer reporting agency (as defined under section 603(d) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1681a/f">15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)</ref>));</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) any person extending credit through the use of credit cards or similar devices;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(D) any broker (as defined in section 3(a)(4) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c/a/4">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(4)</ref>));</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(E) any attorney;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(F) any accountant;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(G) any barter exchange (as defined in section 6045(c)(3));</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(H) any regulated investment company (as defined in section 851) and any agent of such regulated investment company when acting as an agent thereof; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(I) any enrolled agent.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/1">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(1)</ref>, struck out heading and text of par. (4). Text read as follows: “Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any summons—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) served on the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued, or any officer or employee of such person,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) to determine whether or not records of the business transactions or affairs of an identified person have been made or kept, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) described in subsection (f).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/1">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/2">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(2)</ref>, reenacted heading without change and amended text generally, substituting present provisions for provisions which had: in par. (1) declared a general rule of including within subsection summons issued under sections 6420(e)(2), 6421(g)(2), 6427(j)(2), or 7602(a)(2); in par. (2) set forth exceptions where summons was solely to determine identity of person having a numbered account, or was in aid of collection of liability of person against whom assessment or judgment had been made, or his transferee or fiduciary; and in par. (3) defined “records” and declared that summons requiring testimony about records would be treated as summons requiring production of such records.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/3">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “summoned party’s response to the summons” for “third-party recordkeeper’s response to the summons described in subsection (c), or the summoned party’s response to a summons described in subsection (f)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/4/A">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c)(1)” for “subsection (c)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/4/B">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(4)(B)</ref>, inserted “or testimony” after “records”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/5">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(5)</ref>, substituted “A summons is described in this subsection if” for “In the case of any summons described in subsection (c), the provisions of subsections (a)(1) and (b) shall not apply if”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/6/A">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(6)(A)</ref>, struck out “third-party recordkeeper and” after “Duty of” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/6/B">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(6)(B)</ref>, substituted “to which this section applies for the production of records, the summoned party” for “described in subsection (c), the third-party recordkeeper”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/6/C">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(6)(C)</ref>, substituted “summoned party” for “recordkeeper” in heading and “the summoned party” for “the third-party recordkeeper” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/c/6/D">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(c)(6)(D)</ref>, substituted “summoned party” for “recordkeeper” in heading and amended text of par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Any third-party recordkeeper, or agent or employee thereof, making a disclosure of records pursuant to this section in good-faith reliance on the certificate of the Secrtetary or an order of a court requiring production of records shall not be liable to any customer or other person for such disclosure.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/105/206/s3415/b">Pub. L. 105–206, § 3415(b)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/104/168">Pub. L. 104–168</ref> added subpar. (I).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1017/c/12">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1017(c)(12)</ref>, made technical correction to language of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1703/e/2/G">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1703(e)(2)(G)</ref>, see 1986 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1017/c/9">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1017(c)(9)</ref>, substituted “6421(g)(2)” for “6421(f)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1015">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1015</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), inserted “or the summoned party’s response to a summons described in subsection (f),” after “the summons described in subsection (c),” and substituted “the summons is issued” for “the summons is issued other”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1015">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1015</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2)(B), inserted “and summoned party” after “recordkeeper” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1015">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1015</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2)(A), substituted “the summoned party” for “the third-party recordkeeper”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(3)(H). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s656/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 656(a)</ref>, added subpar. (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1703/e/2/G">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1703(e)(2)(G)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1017/c/12">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1017(c)(12)</ref>, substituted “6427(j)(2)” for “6427(i)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1561/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1561(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally, designating existing provisions as par. (1), inserting heading, and adding par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1561/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1561(b)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s714/i">Pub. L. 98–369, § 714(i)</ref>, substituted “7602(a)” for “7602”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s911/d/2/G">Pub. L. 98–369, § 911(d)(2)(G)</ref>, substituted “6427(i)(2)” for “6427(h)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> struck out par. (3) which had provided that except as to cases the court considered to be of greater importance, proceedings brought for the enforcement of any summons, or proceedings under this section, and appeals, would take precedence on the docket over all other cases and would be assigned for hearing and decided at the earliest practicable date.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/424">Pub. L. 97–424</ref> struck out “6424(d)(2),” after “6421(f)(2),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s331/d/1">Pub. L. 97–248, § 331(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “the 23rd day” for “the 14th day”, and substituted “an explanation of the right under subsection (b)(2) to bring a proceeding to quash the summons” for “directions for staying compliance with the summons under subsection (b)(2)” at the end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s311/b">Pub. L. 97–248, § 311(b)</ref>, added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s331/a">Pub. L. 97–248, § 331(a)</ref>, (d)(2), substituted “right to proceeding to quash” for “right to stay compliance” in heading, and in par. (2) substituted “Proceeding to quash” for “Right to stay compliance” as par. (2) heading, designated former undesignated matter as subpar. (A), in (A) as so designated substituted provisions giving persons entitled to notice 20 days to begin a proceeding to quash, for provisions giving persons entitled to notice the right to stay compliance if they complied with the provisions of former subpars. (A) and (B) within 14 days, and inserted provision that the Secretary may seek to compel compliance with the summons, struck out former subpar. (A) which provided that notice to the person summoned not to comply with the summons be given in writing, in subpar. (B) substituted provisions that copies of the petition in the proceeding to quash the summons be mailed within the 20-day period, for provisions that copies of the notice not to comply with the summons be mailed, and added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s331/b">Pub. L. 97–248, § 331(b)</ref>, substituted in par. (1) provision that, no examination of records be made before the close of the 23rd day after the notice of summons, for provision that the examination may not be made before the end of the former 14-day period allowed for notice to be given to the person summoned not to comply, and in par. (2) substituted “where a proceeding under subsection (b)(2)(A) was begun within the 20-day period referred to in such subsection and the requirements of subsection (b)(2)(B) have been met,” for “when the requirements of subsection (b)(2) have been met,” and “of the court having jurisdiction of such proceeding or with the consent of the person beginning the proceeding to quash” for “issued by a court of competent jurisdiction authorizing examination of such records or with the consent of the person staying compliance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s331/c">Pub. L. 97–248, § 331(c)</ref>, inserted “; etc.” after “court” in heading, in par. (1) added heading and substituted “any proceeding” for “proceedings” after “determine”, substituted “subsection (b)(2), (f), or (g)” for “subsections (f) or (g)”, designated former second sentence of par. (1) as par. (2) and added heading, redesignated former par. (2) as (3) and in par. (3) as so redesignated, added heading and substituted “all other cases” for “all cases”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s332/a">Pub. L. 97–248, § 332(a)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> substituted “6427(h)(2)” for “6427(g)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref> which purported to substitute “6427(f)(2)” for “6427(e)(2)” was not executed in view of the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/95/599">Pub. L. 95–599</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/599">Pub. L. 95–599</ref> substituted “6427(g)(2)” for “6427(e)(2)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4779aab5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aab6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2019 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/25/tI/s1204/b">Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1204(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/989">133 Stat. 989</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/25/tI/s1204/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to summonses served after the date that is 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aab7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s408/b">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 408(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2635">119 Stat. 2635</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s408/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect as if included in section 3415 of the Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998 [<ref href="/us/pl/105/206">Pub. L. 105–206</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aab8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3415/d">Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3415(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/756">112 Stat. 756</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/206/tIII/s3415/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to summonses served after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aab9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/168/tX/s1001/b">Pub. L. 104–168, title X, § 1001(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1468">110 Stat. 1468</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/168/tX/s1001/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to summonses issued after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aaba-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1015">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3572">102 Stat. 3572</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/stat/102/3572">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1017(c)(9), (12) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aabb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tVI/s656/b">Pub. L. 99–514, title VI, § 656(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2299">100 Stat. 2299</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tVI/s656/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to summonses served after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1561/c">Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1561(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2761">100 Stat. 2761</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXV/s1561/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1703/e/2/G">section 1703(e)(2)(G) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to gasoline removed (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4082">section 4082 of this title</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1703">section 1703 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>) after <date date="1987-12-31">Dec. 31, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1703/h">section 1703(h) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4081">section 4081 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aabc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> not applicable to cases pending on <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1657">section 1657 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s714/i">section 714(i) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective as if included in the provision of the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s715">section 715 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s31">section 31 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s911/d/2/G">section 911(d)(2)(G) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-08-01">Aug. 1, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s911/e">section 911(e) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6427">section 6427 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aabd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/424">Pub. L. 97–424</ref> applicable with respect to articles sold after <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/424/s515/c">section 515(c) of Pub. L. 97–424</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s34">section 34 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aabe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s311/c/2">Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 311(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/601">96 Stat. 601</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s311/c/2">“The amendments made by subsection (b) [amending this section] shall apply to summonses served after <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s331/e">Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 331(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/621">96 Stat. 621</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s331/e">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to summonses served after <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s332/b">Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 332(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/622">96 Stat. 622</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/248/tIII/s332/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to summonses served after <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aabf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/223">Pub. L. 96–223</ref> effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/223/s232/h/2">section 232(h)(2) of Pub. L. 96–223</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6427">section 6427 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4779aac0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/600">Pub. L. 95–600</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/600/s703/r">section 703(r) of Pub. L. 95–600</ref>, set out a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s46">section 46 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/599">Pub. L. 95–599</ref> effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/599/s505/d">section 505(d) of Pub. L. 95–599</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6427">section 6427 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id4779aac1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXII/s1205/c">Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1205(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1703">90 Stat. 1703</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/94/528/s2/b">Pub. L. 94–528, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2483">90 Stat. 2483</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/528/s2/b">“The amendments made by this section [enacting this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7610">section 7610 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to any summons issued after <date date="1977-02-28">February 28, 1977</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
