<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id441597ff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832"><num value="832">§ 832.</num><heading> Insurance company taxable income</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44159800-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of taxable income</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831, the term “taxable income” means the gross income as defined in subsection (b)(1) less the deductions allowed by subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44159801-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44159802-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Gross income</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “gross income” means the sum of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159803-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the combined gross amount earned during the taxable year, from investment income and from underwriting income as provided in this subsection, computed on the basis of the underwriting and investment exhibit of the annual statement approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159804-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> gain during the taxable year from the sale or other disposition of property,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159805-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> all other items constituting gross income under subchapter B, except that, in the case of a mutual fire insurance company exclusively issuing perpetual policies, the amount of single deposit premiums paid to such company shall not be included in gross income,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159806-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> in the case of a mutual fire or flood insurance company whose principal business is the issuance of policies—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159807-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for which the premium deposits are the same (regardless of the length of the term for which the policies are written), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159808-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> under which the unabsorbed portion of such premium deposits not required for losses, expenses, or establishment of reserves is returned or credited to the policyholder on cancellation or expiration of the policy,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">an amount equal to 2 percent of the premiums earned on insurance contracts during the taxable year with respect to such policies after deduction of premium deposits returned or credited during the same taxable year, and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159809-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> in the case of a company which writes mortgage guaranty insurance, the amount required by subsection (e)(5) to be subtracted from the mortgage guaranty account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4415980a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment income</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “investment income” means the gross amount of income earned during the taxable year from interest, dividends, and rents, computed as follows: To all interest, dividends, and rents received during the taxable year, add interest, dividends, and rents due and accrued at the end of the taxable year, and deduct all interest, dividends, and rents due and accrued at the end of the preceding taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4415980b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Underwriting income</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “underwriting income” means the premiums earned on insurance contracts during the taxable year less losses incurred and expenses incurred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4415980c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Premiums earned</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “premiums earned on insurance contracts during the taxable year” means an amount computed as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4415980d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> From the amount of gross premiums written on insurance contracts during the taxable year, deduct return premiums and premiums paid for reinsurance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4415980e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To the result so obtained, add 80 percent of the unearned premiums on outstanding business at the end of the preceding taxable year and deduct 80 percent of the unearned premiums on outstanding business at the end of the taxable year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4415980f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> To the result so obtained, in the case of a taxable year beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, and before <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>, add an amount equal to 3⅓ percent of unearned premiums on outstanding business at the end of the most recent taxable year beginning before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this subsection, unearned premiums shall include life insurance reserves, as defined in section 816(b) but determined as provided in section 807. For purposes of this subsection, unearned premiums of mutual fire or flood insurance companies described in paragraph (1)(D) means (with respect to the policies described in paragraph (1)(D)) the amount of unabsorbed premium deposits which the company would be obligated to return to its policyholders at the close of the taxable year if all of its policies were terminated at such time; and the determination of such amount shall be based on the schedule of unabsorbed premium deposit returns for each such company then in effect. Premiums paid by the subscriber of a mutual flood insurance company described in paragraph (1)(D) or issuing exclusively perpetual policies shall be treated, for purposes of computing the taxable income of such subscriber, in the same manner as premiums paid by a policyholder to a mutual fire insurance company described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44159810-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Losses incurred</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159811-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “losses incurred” means losses incurred during the taxable year on insurance contracts computed as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159812-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> To losses paid during the taxable year, deduct salvage and reinsurance recovered during the taxable year.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159813-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> To the result so obtained, add all unpaid losses on life insurance contracts plus all discounted unpaid losses (as defined in section 846) outstanding at the end of the taxable year and deduct all unpaid losses on life insurance contracts plus all discounted unpaid losses outstanding at the end of the preceding taxable year.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159814-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> To the results so obtained, add estimated salvage and reinsurance recoverable as of the end of the preceding taxable year and deduct estimated salvage and reinsurance recoverable as of the end of the taxable year.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The amount of estimated salvage recoverable shall be determined on a discounted basis in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159815-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction of deduction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount which would (but for this subparagraph) be taken into account under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by an amount equal to the applicable percentage of the sum of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159816-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> tax-exempt interest received or accrued during such taxable year,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159817-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the aggregate amount of deductions provided by sections 243 and 245 for—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159818-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> dividends (other than 100 percent dividends) received during the taxable year, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159819-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> 100 percent dividends received during the taxable year to the extent attributable (directly or indirectly) to prorated amounts, and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4415981a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the increase for the taxable year in policy cash values (within the meaning of section 805(a)(4)(F)) of life insurance policies and annuity and endowment contracts to which section 264(f) applies.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">In the case of a 100 percent dividend paid by an insurance company, the portion attributable to prorated amounts shall be determined under subparagraph (E)(ii). For purposes of this subparagraph, the applicable percentage is 5.25 percent divided by the highest rate in effect under section 11(b).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4415981b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for investments made before <date date="1986-08-08">August 8, 1986</date></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4415981c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), subparagraph (B) shall not apply to any dividend or interest received or accrued on any stock or obligation acquired before <date date="1986-08-08">August 8, 1986</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id4415981d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for 100 percent dividends</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), the portion of any 100 percent dividend which is attributable to prorated amounts shall be treated as received with respect to stock acquired on the later of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4415981e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the date the payor acquired the stock or obligation to which the prorated amounts are attributable, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4415981f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the 1st day on which the payor and payee were members of the same affiliated group (as defined in section 243(b)(2)).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159820-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159821-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Prorated amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “prorated amounts” means tax-exempt interest and dividends with respect to which a deduction is allowable under section 243 or 245 (other than 100 percent dividends).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159822-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> 100 percent dividend</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id44159823-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/D/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The term “100 percent dividend” means any dividend if the percentage used for purposes of determining the deduction allowable under section 243 or 245(b) is 100 percent.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id44159824-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/D/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain dividends received by foreign corporations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">A dividend received by a foreign corporation from a domestic corporation which would be a 100 percent dividend if section 1504(b)(3) did not apply for purposes of applying section 243(b)(2) shall be treated as a 100 percent dividend.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159825-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for dividends subject to proration at subsidiary level</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159826-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of any 100 percent dividend paid to an insurance company to which this part applies by any insurance company, the amount of the decrease in the deductions of the payee company by reason of the portion of such dividend attributable to prorated amounts shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount of the decrease in the deductions (or increase in income) of the payor company attributable to the application of this section or section 805(a)(4)(A) to such amounts.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159827-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Portion of dividend attributable to prorated amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph, in determining the portion of any dividend attributable to prorated amounts—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159828-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any dividend by the paying corporation shall be treated as paid first out of earnings and profits attributable to prorated amounts (to the extent thereof), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159829-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/5/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> by determining the portion of earnings and profits so attributable without any reduction for the tax imposed by this chapter.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4415982a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Expenses incurred</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “expenses incurred” means all expenses shown on the annual statement approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, and shall be computed as follows: To all expenses paid during the taxable year, add expenses unpaid at the end of the taxable year and deduct expenses unpaid at the end of the preceding taxable year. For purposes of this subchapter, the term “expenses unpaid” shall not include any unpaid loss adjustment expenses shown on the annual statement, but such unpaid loss adjustment expenses shall be included in unpaid losses. For the purpose of computing the taxable income subject to the tax imposed by section 831, there shall be deducted from expenses incurred (as defined in this paragraph) all expenses incurred which are not allowed as deductions by subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4415982b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for applying paragraph (4)</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4415982c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction not to apply to life insurance reserves</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4) shall be applied with respect to insurance contracts described in section 816(b)(1)(B) by substituting “100 percent” for “80 percent” each place it appears in such subparagraph (B), and subparagraph (C) of paragraph (4) shall be applied by not taking such contracts into account.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4415982d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Special treatment of premiums attributable to insuring certain securities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of premiums attributable to insurance against default in the payment of principal or interest on securities described in section 165(g)(2)(C) with maturities of more than 5 years—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4415982e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4) shall be applied by substituting “90 percent” for “80 percent” each place it appears, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4415982f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subparagraph (C) of paragraph (4) shall be applied by substituting “1⅔ percent” for “3⅓ percent”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159830-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination as insurance company taxable under section 831(a)</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in section 381(c)(22) (relating to carryovers in certain corporate readjustments), if, for any taxable year beginning before <date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>, the taxpayer ceases to be an insurance company taxable under section 831(a), the aggregate adjustments which would be made under paragraph (4)(C) for such taxable year and subsequent taxable years but for such cessation shall be made for the taxable year preceding such cessation year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159831-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of companies which become taxable under section 831(a)</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159832-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception to phase-in for companies which were not taxable, etc., before 1987</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Subparagraph (C) of paragraph (4) shall not apply to any insurance company which, for each taxable year beginning before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, was not subject to the tax imposed by section 821(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002135">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002135"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or 831(a) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Tax Reform Act of 1986) by reason of being—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159833-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> subject to tax under section 821(c) <sup>1</sup> (as so in effect), or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159834-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> described in section 501(c) (as so in effect) and exempt from tax under section 501(a).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159835-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Phase-in beginning at later date for companies not 1st taxable under section 831(a) in 1987</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of an insurance company—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159836-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> which was not subject to the tax imposed by section 831(a) for its 1st taxable year beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, by reason of being subject to tax under section 831(b), or described in section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159837-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> which, for any taxable year beginning before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, was subject to the tax imposed by section 821(a) <sup>1</sup> or 831(a) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Tax Reform Act of 1986),</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> subparagraph (C) of paragraph (4) shall apply beginning with the 1st taxable year beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, for which such company is subject to the tax imposed by section 831(a) and shall be applied by substituting the last day of the preceding taxable year for “<date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>” and the 1st day of the 7th succeeding taxable year for “<date date="1993-01-01">January 1, 1993</date>”.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159838-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain reciprocal insurers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a reciprocal (within the meaning of section 835(a)) which reports (as required by State law) on its annual statement reserves on unearned premiums net of premium acquisition expenses—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159839-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4) shall be applied by treating unearned premiums as including an amount equal to such expenses, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4415983a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> appropriate adjustments shall be made under subparagraph (c) of paragraph (4) to reflect the amount by which—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4415983b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> such reserves at the close of the most recent taxable year beginning before <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, are greater or less than,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4415983c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/7/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> 80 percent of the sum of the amount under subclause (I) plus such premium acquisition expenses.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4415983d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for applying paragraph (4) to title insurance premiums</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4415983e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of premiums attributable to title insurance—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4415983f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4) shall be applied by substituting “the discounted unearned premiums” for “80 percent of the unearned premiums” each place it appears, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159840-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subparagraph (C) of paragraph (4) shall not apply.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159841-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Method of discounting</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the amount of the discounted unearned premiums as of the end of any taxable year shall be the present value of such premiums (as of such time and separately with respect to premiums received in each calendar year) determined by using—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159842-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of the undiscounted unearned premiums at such time,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159843-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the applicable interest rate, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44159844-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the applicable statutory premium recognition pattern.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44159845-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of applicable factors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In determining the amount of the discounted unearned premiums as of the end of any taxable year—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159846-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Undiscounted unearned premiums</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “undiscounted unearned premiums” means the unearned premiums shown in the yearly statement filed by the taxpayer for the year ending with or within such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159847-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable interest rate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “applicable interest rate” means the annual rate determined under 846(c)(2) for the calendar year in which the premiums are received.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44159848-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicable statutory premium recognition pattern</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “applicable statutory premium recognition pattern” means the statutory premium recognition pattern—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44159849-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> which is in effect for the calendar year in which the premiums are received, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id4415984a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/b/8/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> which is based on the statutory premium recognition pattern which applies to premiums received by the taxpayer in such calendar year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> For purposes of the preceding sentence, premiums received during any calendar year shall be treated as received in the middle of such year.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4415984b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Deductions allowed</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In computing the taxable income of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831, there shall be allowed as deductions:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4415984c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> all ordinary and necessary expenses incurred, as provided in section 162 (relating to trade or business expenses);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4415984d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> all interest, as provided in section 163;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4415984e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> taxes, as provided in section 164;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4415984f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> losses incurred, as defined in subsection (b)(5) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159850-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> capital losses to the extent provided in subchapter P (relating to capital gains and losses) plus losses from capital assets sold or exchanged in order to obtain funds to meet abnormal insurance losses and to provide for the payment of dividends and similar distributions to policyholders. Capital assets shall be considered as sold or exchanged in order to obtain funds to meet abnormal insurance losses and to provide for the payment of dividends and similar distributions to policyholders to the extent that the gross receipts from their sale or exchange are not greater than the excess, if any, for the taxable year of the sum of dividends and similar distributions paid to policyholders in their capacity as such, losses paid, and expenses paid over the sum of the items described in section 834(b) (other than paragraph (1)(D) thereof) and net premiums received. In the application of section 1212 for purposes of this section, the net capital loss for the taxable year shall be the amount by which losses for such year from sales or exchanges of capital assets exceeds the sum of the gains from such sales or exchanges and whichever of the following amounts is the lesser:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159851-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the taxable income (computed without regard to gains or losses from sales or exchanges of capital assets); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159852-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> losses from the sale or exchange of capital assets sold or exchanged to obtain funds to meet abnormal insurance losses and to provide for the payment of dividends and similar distributions to policyholders;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159853-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> debts in the nature of agency balances and bills receivable which become worthless within the taxable year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159854-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the amount of interest earned during the taxable year which under section 103 is excluded from gross income;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159855-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the depreciation deduction allowed by section 167 and the deduction allowed by section 611 (relating to depletion);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159856-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> charitable, etc., contributions, as provided in section 170;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159857-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> deductions (other than those specified in this subsection) as provided in part VI of subchapter B (sec. 161 and following, relating to itemized deductions for individuals and corporations) and in part I of subchapter D (sec. 401 and following, relating to pension, profit-sharing, stock bonus plans, etc.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159858-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> dividends and similar distributions paid or declared to policyholders in their capacity as such, except in the case of a mutual fire insurance company described in subsection (b)(1)(C). For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “dividends and similar distributions” includes amounts returned or credited to policyholders on cancellation or expiration of policies described in subsection (b)(1)(D). For purposes of this paragraph, the term “paid or declared” shall be construed according to the method of accounting regularly employed in keeping the books of the insurance company;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44159859-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> the special deductions allowed by part VIII of subchapter B (sec. 241 and following, relating to dividends received); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4415985a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/c/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> in the case of a company which writes mortgage guaranty insurance, the deduction allowed by subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4415985b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Double deductions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall permit the same item to be deducted more than once.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4415985c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Special deduction and income account</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a company which writes mortgage guaranty insurance—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4415985d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional deduction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year, if bonds are purchased as required by paragraph (2), the sum of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4415985e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an amount representing the amount required by State law or regulation to be set aside in a reserve for mortgage guaranty insurance losses resulting from adverse economic cycles; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4415985f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an amount representing the aggregate of amounts so set aside in such reserve for the 8 preceding taxable years to the extent such amounts were not deducted under this paragraph in such preceding taxable years,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that the deduction allowable for the taxable year under this paragraph shall not exceed the taxable income for the taxable year computed without regard to this paragraph or to any carryback of a net operating loss. For purposes of this paragraph, the amount required by State law or regulation to be so set aside in any taxable year shall not exceed 50 percent of premiums earned on insurance contracts (as defined in subsection (b)(4)) with respect to mortgage guaranty insurance for such year. For purposes of this subsection, all amounts shall be taken into account on a first-in-time basis. The computation and deduction under this section of losses incurred (including losses resulting from adverse economic cycles) shall not be affected by the provisions of this subsection. For purposes of this subsection, the terms “preceding taxable years” and “preceding taxable year” shall not include taxable years which began before <date date="1967-01-01">January 1, 1967</date>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44159860-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchase of bonds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The deduction under paragraph (1) shall be allowed only to the extent that tax and loss bonds are purchased in an amount equal to the tax benefit attributable to such deduction, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, on or before the date that any taxes (determined without regard to this subsection) due for the taxable year for which the deduction is allowed are due to be paid. If a deduction would be allowed but for the fact that tax and loss bonds were not timely purchased, such deduction shall be allowed to the extent such purchases are made within a reasonable time, as determined by the Secretary, if all interest and penalties, computed as if this sentence did not apply, are paid.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44159861-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Mortgage guaranty account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each company which writes mortgage guaranty insurance shall, for purposes of this part, establish and maintain a mortgage guaranty account.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44159862-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Additions to account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There shall be added to the mortgage guaranty account for each taxable year an amount equal to the amount allowed as a deduction for the taxable year under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44159863-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Subtractions from account and inclusion in gross income</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After applying paragraph (4), there shall be subtracted for the taxable year from the mortgage guaranty account and included in gross income—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159864-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount (if any) remaining which was added to the account for the tenth preceding taxable year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159865-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the excess (if any) of the aggregate amount in the mortgage guaranty account over the aggregate amount in the reserve referred to in paragraph (1)(A). For purposes of determining such excess, the aggregate amount in the mortgage guaranty account shall be determined after applying subparagraph (A), and the aggregate amount in the reserve referred to in paragraph (1)(A) shall be determined by disregarding any amounts remaining in such reserve added for taxable years beginning before <date date="1967-01-01">January 1, 1967</date>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159866-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an amount (if any) equal to the net operating loss for the taxable year computed without regard to this subparagraph, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44159867-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any amount improperly subtracted from the account under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) to the extent that tax and loss bonds were redeemed with respect to such amount.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If a company liquidates or otherwise terminates its mortgage guaranty insurance business and does not transfer or distribute such business in an acquisition of assets referred to in section 381(a), the entire amount remaining in such account shall be subtracted. Except in the case where a company transfers or distributes its mortgage guaranty insurance in an acquisition of assets referred to in section 381(a), if the company is not subject to the tax imposed by section 831 for any taxable year, the entire amount in the account at the close of the preceding taxable year shall be subtracted from the account in such preceding taxable year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44159868-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Lease guaranty insurance; insurance of State and local obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of this subsection shall also apply in all respects to a company which writes lease guaranty insurance or insurance on obligations the interest on which is excludable from gross income under section 103. In applying this subsection to such a company, any reference to mortgage guaranty insurance contained in this section shall be deemed to be a reference also to lease guaranty insurance and to insurance on obligations the interest on which is excludable from gross income under section 103; and in the case of insurance on obligations the interest on which is excludable from gross income under section 103, the references in paragraph (1) to “losses resulting from adverse economic cycles” include losses from declining revenues related to such obligations (as well as losses resulting from adverse economic cycles), and the time specified in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (5) shall be the twentieth preceding taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44159869-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Interinsurers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a mutual insurance company which is an interinsurer or reciprocal underwriter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4415986a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> there shall be allowed as a deduction the increase for the taxable year in savings credited to subscriber accounts, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4415986b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> there shall be included as an item of gross income the decrease for the taxable year in savings credited to subscriber accounts.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “savings credited to subscriber accounts” means such portion of the surplus as is credited to the individual accounts of subscribers before the 16th day of the 3rd month following the close of the taxable year, but only if the company would be obligated to pay such amount promptly to such subscriber if he terminated his contract at the close of the company’s taxable year. For purposes of determining his taxable income, the subscriber shall treat any such savings credited to his account as a dividend paid or declared.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4418096c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s832/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Dividends within group</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of an insurance company subject to tax under section 831(a) filing or required to file a consolidated return under section 1501 with respect to any affiliated group for any taxable year, any determination under this part with respect to any dividend paid by one member of such group to another member of such group shall be made as if such group were not filing a consolidated return.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4418096d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/264">68A Stat. 264</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-03-13/ch83/s3/b">Mar. 13, 1956, ch. 83, § 3(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/48">70 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s8/e/2">Pub. L. 87–834, § 8(e)(2)</ref>–(5), <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/997">76 Stat. 997</ref>, 998; <ref href="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s228/c">Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 228(c)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/99">78 Stat. 99</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tI/s104/i/7">Pub. L. 89–809, title I, § 104(i)(7)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1562">80 Stat. 1562</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/240/s5/a">Pub. L. 90–240, § 5(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/776">81 Stat. 776</ref>, 777; <ref href="/us/pl/93/483/s5">Pub. L. 93–483, § 5</ref>, <date date="1974-10-26">Oct. 26, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1458">88 Stat. 1458</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1901(a)(108), (b)(1)(T), (U), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1782">90 Stat. 1782</ref>, 1792, 1834; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tII/s234/b/2/A">Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 234(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/503">96 Stat. 503</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tII/s211/b/9">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title II, § 211(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/755">98 Stat. 755</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tX">Pub. L. 99–514, title X</ref>, §§ 1021(a), (b), 1022(a), 1023(a), 1024(c)(1)–(6), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2395">100 Stat. 2395</ref>, 2397, 2399, 2406, 2407; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1010/c">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1010(c)</ref>, (d)(1), (2), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3451-3453">102 Stat. 3451–3453</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, §§ 11303(a), (b), 11305(a), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-450">104 Stat. 1388–450</ref>, 1388–451; <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI">Pub. L. 104–188, title I</ref>, §§ 1702(h)(3), 1704(t)(45), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1873">110 Stat. 1873</ref>, 1889; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tX/s1084/b/4">Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1084(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/955">111 Stat. 955</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/dA/tII/s221/a/41/G">Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(41)(G)</ref>, (69), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/4044">128 Stat. 4044</ref>, 4048; <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI">Pub. L. 115–97, title I</ref>, §§ 13001(b)(2)(I), 13515(a), <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2096">131 Stat. 2096</ref>, 2144; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/a/143">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(143)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1191">132 Stat. 1191</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4418096e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4418096f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id44180970-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 821, referred to in subsec. (b)(7)(D), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tX/s1024/a/1">Pub. L. 99–514, title X, § 1024(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2405">100 Stat. 2405</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (b)(7)(D), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, which was approved <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id44180971-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1084/b">section 1084(b) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref> amended sections 101 and 264 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id44180972-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(7)(E)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> substituted period for comma at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13515/a">Pub. L. 115–97, § 13515(a)</ref>, substituted “the applicable percentage” for “15 percent” in introductory provisions and inserted “For purposes of this subparagraph, the applicable percentage is 5.25 percent divided by the highest rate in effect under section 11(b).” at end of concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13001/b/2/I">Pub. L. 115–97, § 13001(b)(2)(I)</ref>, struck out “sec. 1201 and following,” before “relating to capital gains and losses” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b)(5)(B)(ii), (D)(i), (ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/41/G">Pub. L. 113–295, § 221(a)(41)(G)</ref>, struck out “, 244,”after “sections 243” in subpar. (B)(ii) and after “section 243” in subpar. (D)(i), (ii)(I).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/69/A">Pub. L. 113–295, § 221(a)(69)(A)</ref>, struck out “of taxable years beginning after <date date="1966-12-31">December 31, 1966</date>,” after “In the case” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/69/B">Pub. L. 113–295, § 221(a)(69)(B)</ref>, substituted “The” for “In the case of any taxable year beginning after <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(5)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, which directed amendment of subpar. (B) by adding cl. (iii) at the end, was executed by adding cl. (iii) after cl. (ii) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(5)(C)(ii)(II), (D)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1702/h/3">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1702(h)(3)</ref>, substituted “243(b)(2)” for “243(b)(5)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1704/t/45">Pub. L. 104–188, § 1704(t)(45)</ref>, provided that <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11303/b/1">section 11303(b)(1) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref> shall be applied as if “paragraph” appeared instead of “subparagraph” in the material proposed to be stricken. See 1990 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11303/a">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11303(a)</ref>, substituted “section 807.” for “section 807, pertaining to the life, burial, or funeral insurance, or annuity business of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831 and not qualifying as a life insurance company under section 816.” in first sentence after subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11305/a">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11305(a)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “The term ‘losses incurred’ means losses incurred during the taxable year on insurance contracts, computed as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) To losses paid during the taxable year, add salvage and reinsurance recoverable outstanding at the end of the preceding taxable year and deduct salvage and reinsurance recoverable outstanding at the end of the taxable year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) To the result so obtained, add all unpaid losses on life insurance contracts plus all discounted unpaid losses (as defined in section 846) outstanding at the end of the taxable year and deduct unpaid losses on life insurance contracts plus all discounted unpaid losses outstanding at the end of the preceding taxable year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11303/b/2">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11303(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “such contracts into account” for “such amounts into account”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11303/b/1">Pub. L. 101–508, § 11303(b)(1)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “insurance contracts described in section 816(b)(1)(B)” for “amounts included in unearned premiums under the 2nd sentence of such subparagraph”, was executed by making the substitution for “amounts included in unearned premiums under the 2nd sentence of such paragraph”. See 1996 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(5)(B)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1010/d/2">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1010(d)(2)</ref>, inserted “(directly or indirectly)” after “attributable”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1010/c/1">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1010(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “insurance company taxable under section 831(a)” for “nonlife insurance company” in heading and “section 831(a)” for “this part” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(D), (E). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1010/c/2">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1010(c)(2)</ref>, added subpars. (D) and (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1010/c/3">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1010(c)(3)</ref>, struck out “and” after “preceding taxable year,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1010/c/3">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1010(c)(3)</ref>, which directed amendment of subpar. (B) by substituting a comma for the period at end, could not be executed because there was no period at end of subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1010/d/1">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1010(d)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1024/c/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1024(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “exclusively issuing perpetual policies” for “described in section 831(a)(3)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1024/c/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1024(c)(2)</ref>, amended subpar. (D) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (D) read as follows: “in the case of a mutual fire or flood insurance company described in section 831(a)(3)(B), an amount equal to 2 percent of the premiums earned on insurance contracts during the taxable year with respect to policies described in section 831(a)(3)(B) after deduction of premium deposits returned or credited during the same taxable year, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1024/c/3">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1024(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(D)” for “section 831(a)(3)(B)” in two places and amended last sentence generally, substituting “described in paragraph (1)(D) or issuing exclusively perpetual policies” for “referred to in paragraph (3) of section 831(a)” and “described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1)” for “referred to in such paragraph (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1021/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1021(a)</ref>, added subpars. (B) and (C) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “To the result so obtained, add unearned premiums on outstanding business at the end of the preceding taxable year and deduct unearned premiums on outstanding business at the end of the taxable year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1022/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1022(a)</ref>, in amending par. (5) generally, designated existing provisions of par. (5) as subpar. (A), inserted subpar. heading “In general”, and redesignated former subpars. (A) and (B) as cls. (i) and (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1023/a/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1023(a)(1)</ref>, amended cl. (ii) generally, inserting “on life insurance contracts plus all discounted unpaid losses (as defined in section 846)” and “on life insurance contracts plus all discounted unpaid losses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1022/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1022(a)</ref>, in amending par. (5) generally, added subpars. (B) to (E). Former subpar. (B) redesignated (A)(ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1023/a/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1023(a)(2)</ref>, inserted second sentence defining “expenses unpaid”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1021/b">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1021(b)</ref>, added pars. (7) and (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1024/c/4">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1024(c)(4)</ref>, substituted “section 834(b)” for “section 822(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1024/c/5">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1024(c)(5)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)(1)(C)” for “section 831(a)(3)(A)” and “subsection (b)(1)(D)” for “section 831(a)(3)(B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1024/c/6">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1024(c)(6)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, in provisions following subpar. (B), substituted “section 816(b) but determined as provided in section 807” and “section 816” for “section 801(b)” and “section 801”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> struck out “, as if no election to make installment payments under section 6152 is made” after “due to be paid”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b)(1), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/108">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(108)</ref>, substituted “Association” for “Convention”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/1/T">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(1)(T)</ref>, struck out “or to the deductions provided in section 242 for partially tax-exempt interest” after “exchanges of capital assets”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/b/1/U">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(b)(1)(U)</ref>, struck out “partially tax-exempt interest and to” after “and following, relating to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/93/483">Pub. L. 93–483</ref> added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/90/240/s5/a">Pub. L. 90–240, § 5(a)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/90/240/s5/b">Pub. L. 90–240, § 5(b)</ref>, added par. (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/90/240/s5/c">Pub. L. 90–240, § 5(c)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref> redesignated subsec. (e) as (d). Former subsec. (d), having reference to the taxable income of foreign insurance companies other than life or mutual and foreign mutual marine, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref> redesignated subsec. (e) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (c)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/88/272">Pub. L. 88–272</ref> inserted reference to part I of subchapter D.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s8/e/3">Pub. L. 87–834, § 8(e)(3)</ref>, (5), substituted “section 831(a)(3)(A)” for “section 831(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s8/e/5">Pub. L. 87–834, § 8(e)(5)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s8/e/2">Pub. L. 87–834, § 8(e)(2)</ref>, inserted provisions defining unearned premiums of mutual fire or flood insurance companies, and which require premiums paid by the subscriber of a mutual flood insurance company to be treated, for purposes of computing the taxable income of such subscriber, in the same manner as premiums paid by a policyholder to a mutual fire insurance company referred to in par. (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s831/a">section 831(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s8/e/4">Pub. L. 87–834, § 8(e)(4)</ref>, substituted “section 831(a)(3)(A)” for “section 831(a)”, and inserted definition of “dividends and similar distributions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (b)(4). Act <date date="1956-03-13">Mar. 13, 1956</date>, § 3(b)(1), substituted “section 801(b)” for “section 806”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1956-03-13">Mar. 13, 1956</date>, § 3(b)(2), (3), substituted “the items described in section 822(b) (other than paragraph (1)(D) thereof) and net premiums received. In the application of section 1212” for “interest, dividends, rents, and net premiums received. In the application of section 1211” in par. (5), and authorized the deduction for depletion in par. (8).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id44180973-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180974-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2017 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13001/b/2/I">section 13001(b)(2)(I) of Pub. L. 115–97</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="2017-12-31">Dec. 31, 2017</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13001/c/1">section 13001(c)(1) of Pub. L. 115–97</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s11">section 11 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13515/b">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13515(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2144">131 Stat. 2144</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13515/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180975-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section (a)(41)(G) of <ref href="/us/pl/113/295">Pub. L. 113–295</ref> not applicable to preferred stock issued before <date date="1942-10-01">Oct. 1, 1942</date> (determined in the same manner as under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s247">section 247 of this title</ref> as in effect before its repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/113/295">Pub. L. 113–295</ref>), see <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a/41/K">section 221(a)(41)(K) of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s172">section 172 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/a">section 221(a) of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/295">Pub. L. 113–295</ref> effective <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, subject to a savings provision, see <ref href="/us/pl/113/295/s221/b">section 221(b) of Pub. L. 113–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180976-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> applicable to contracts issued after <date date="1997-06-08">June 8, 1997</date>, in taxable years ending after such date, with special provisions relating to changes in contracts to be treated as new contracts, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/s1084/d">section 1084(d) of Pub. L. 105–34</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180977-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1702/h/3">section 1702(h)(3) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref> effective, except as otherwise expressly provided, as if included in the provision of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990, <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/188/s1702/i">section 1702(i) of Pub. L. 104–188</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s38">section 38 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180978-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11303/c">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11303(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-450">104 Stat. 1388–450</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11303/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amendments treated as change in method of accounting</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of any taxpayer who is required by reason of the amendments made by this section to change his method of computing reserves—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> such change shall be treated as a change in a method of accounting,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such change shall be treated as initiated by the taxpayer,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> such change shall be treated as having been made with the consent of the Secretary, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the net adjustments which are required by section 481 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to be taken into account by the taxpayer shall be taken into account over a period not to exceed 4 taxable years beginning with the taxpayer’s first taxable year beginning on or after <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination with section</inline> 832(b)(4)(C).—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section shall not affect the application of section 832(b)(4)(C) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11305/c">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11305(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-451">104 Stat. 1388–451</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11305/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s846">section 846 of this title</ref>] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amendments treated as change in method of accounting.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of any taxpayer who is required by reason of the amendments made by this section to change his method of computing losses incurred—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> such change shall be treated as a change in a method of accounting,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> such change shall be treated as initiated by the taxpayer, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> such change shall be treated as having been made with the consent of the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustments</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In applying section 481 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to the change referred to in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> only 13 percent of the net amount of adjustments (otherwise required by such section 481 to be taken into account by the taxpayer) shall be taken into account, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the portion of such net adjustments which is required to be taken into account by the taxpayer (after the application of clause (i)) shall be taken into account over a period not to exceed 4 taxable years beginning with the taxpayer’s 1st taxable year beginning after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of companies which took into account salvage recoverable</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of any insurance company which took into account salvage recoverable in determining losses incurred for its last taxable year beginning before <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, 87 percent of the discounted amount of estimated salvage recoverable as of the close of such last taxable year shall be allowed as a deduction ratably over its 1st 4 taxable years beginning after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for overestimates</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If for any taxable year beginning after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the amount of the section 481 adjustment which would have been required without regard to paragraph (2) and any discounting, exceeds</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the sum of the amount of salvage recovered taken into account under section 832(b)(5)(A)(i) for the taxable year and any preceding taxable year beginning after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>, attributable to losses incurred with respect to any accident year beginning before 1990 and the undiscounted amount of estimated salvage recoverable as of the close of the taxable year on account of such losses,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">87 percent of such excess (adjusted for discounting used in determining the amount of salvage recoverable as of the close of the last taxable year of the taxpayer beginning before <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>) shall be included in gross income for such taxable year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on earnings and profits</inline>.—</heading><content>The earnings and profits of any insurance company for its 1st taxable year beginning after <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>, shall be increased by the amount of the section 481 adjustment which would have been required but for paragraph (2). For purposes of applying sections 56, [former] 902, 952(c)(1), and 960 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, earnings and profits of a corporation shall be determined by applying the principles of paragraph (2)(B).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180979-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4418097a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tX/s1021/c">Pub. L. 99–514, title X, § 1021(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2397">100 Stat. 2397</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tX/s1021/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special transitional rule for title insurance companies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For the 1st taxable year beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, in the case of premiums attributable to title insurance—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The unearned premiums at the end of the preceding taxable year as defined in paragraph (4) of section 832(b) [of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986] shall be determined as if the amendments made by this section had applied to such unearned premiums in the preceding taxable year and by using the interest rate and premium recognition pattern applicable to years ending in calendar year 1987.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fresh start</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), any difference between—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the amount determined to be unearned premiums for the year preceding the first taxable year of a title insurance company beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, determined without regard to subparagraph (A), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> such amount determined with regard to subparagraph (A),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall not be taken into account for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on earnings and profits</inline>.—</heading><content>The earnings and profits of any insurance company for its 1st taxable year beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, shall be increased by the amount of the difference determined under subparagraph (A) with respect to such company.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tX/s1022/b">Pub. L. 99–514, title X, § 1022(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2399">100 Stat. 2399</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tX/s1022/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1023/a">section 1023(a) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1023/e">section 1023(e) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s846">section 846 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1024(c)(1)–(6) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1024/e">section 1024(e) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s831">section 831 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4418097b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1983-12-31">Dec. 31, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s215">section 215 of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4418097c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1982-12-31">Dec. 31, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s234/e">section 234(e) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6655">section 6655 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4418097d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1901(a)(108), (b)(1)(T), (U) of <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/d">section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4418097e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/90/240/s5/e">Pub. L. 90–240, § 5(e)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/778">81 Stat. 778</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“The amendments made by subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s381">section 381 of this title</ref>] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1966-12-31">December 31, 1966</date>, except that so much of section 832(e)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] (as added by the amendment made by subsection (c)) as provides for payment of interest and penalties for failure to make a timely purchase of tax and loss bonds shall not apply with respect to any period during which such bonds are not available for purchase.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4418097f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1966-12-31">Dec. 31, 1966</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s104/n">section 104(n) of Pub. L. 89–809</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s11">section 11 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180980-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s228/d">Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 228(d)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/99">78 Stat. 99</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/88/272/tII/s228/d">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending former <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s809">section 809 of this title</ref>] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1961-12-31">December 31, 1961</date>. The amendment made by subsection (c) [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1953-12-31">December 31, 1953</date>, and ending after <date date="1954-08-16">August 16, 1954</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180981-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/834">Pub. L. 87–834</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1962-12-31">Dec. 31, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s8/h">section 8(h) of Pub. L. 87–834</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501">section 501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id44180982-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1956 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1956-03-13">Mar. 13, 1956</date>, applicable only to taxable years beginning after <date date="1954-12-31">Dec. 31, 1954</date>, see section 6 of act <date date="1956-03-13">Mar. 13, 1956</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s316">section 316 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id44180983-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deduction From Earnings and Profits of Insurance Companies to Which <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s11305/c/3">Section 11305(c)(3) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref> Applies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1702/c/4">Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1702(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1869">110 Stat. 1869</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/188/tI/s1702/c/4">“The earnings and profits of any insurance company to which section 11305(c)(3) of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out above] applies shall be determined without regard to any deduction allowed under such section; except that, for purposes of applying sections 56 and [former] 902, and subpart F of part III of subchapter N of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, such deduction shall be taken into account.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id44180984-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acquisition Date of Certain Stocks or Obligations for Purposes of Subsection (b)(5)(C)(i)</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1010/d/3">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1010(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3453">102 Stat. 3453</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1010/d/3">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I00" class="inline"><num value="" /><chapeau>“For purposes of section 832(b)(5)(C)(i) of the 1986 Code, any stock or obligation acquired on or after <date date="1986-08-08">August 8, 1986</date>, by an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831 of the 1986 Code (hereinafter in this paragraph referred to as the ‘acquiring company’) from another insurance company so subject (hereinafter in this paragraph referred to as the ‘transferor company’) shall be treated as acquired on the date on which such stock or obligation was acquired by the transferor company if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the transferor company acquired such stock or obligation before <date date="1986-08-08">August 8, 1986</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> at all times after the date on which such stock or obligation was acquired by the transferor company and before the date of the acquisition by the acquiring company, the transferor company and the acquiring company were members of the same affiliated group filing a consolidated return.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of the preceding sentence, the date on which the stock or obligation was acquired by the transferor company shall be determined with regard to any prior application of the preceding sentence. For purposes of this paragraph, if the acquiring corporation or transferor corporation was a party to a reorganization described in section 368(a)(1)(F) of the 1986 Code, any reference to such corporation shall include a reference to any predecessor thereof involved in such reorganization.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id44180985-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Treatment of Property and Casualty Insurance Companies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tX/s1025">Pub. L. 99–514, title X, § 1025</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2409">100 Stat. 2409</ref>, directed Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate to conduct a study of the treatment of policyholder dividends by mutual property and casualty insurance companies, the treatment of property and casualty insurance companies under the minimum tax, and the operation and effect of, and revenue raised by, the amendments made by this subtitle, and not later than <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date> (due date extended to <date date="1992-01-01">Jan. 1, 1992</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11831/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11831(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-559">104 Stat. 1388–559</ref>), such Secretary to submit to Committee on Ways and Means of House of Representatives, Committee on Finance of Senate, and Joint Committee on Taxation, the results of such study, together with such recommendations as he determined to be appropriate.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id44180986-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Physicians’ and Surgeons’ Mutual Protection and Interindemnity Arrangements or Associations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tX/s1031">Pub. L. 99–514, title X, § 1031</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2409">100 Stat. 2409</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1010/g">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1010(g)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3455">102 Stat. 3455</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1010/g">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Physicians’ and Surgeons’ Mutual Protection and Interindemnity Arrangements or Associations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of arrangements or associations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Capital contributions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>There shall not be included in the gross income of any eligible physicians’ and surgeons’ mutual protection and interindemnity arrangement or association any initial payment (whether made in a lump sum or a series of substantially equal payments over a period of not more than 6 years) made during any taxable year to such arrangement or association by a member joining such arrangement or association which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> does not release such member from obligations to pay current or future dues, assessments, or premiums; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> is a condition precedent to receiving benefits of membership.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I26" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">  Such initial payment shall be included in the gross income of such arrangement or association for such taxable year if it is reasonable to expect that such payment will be deductible pursuant to paragraph (2) by any member of such arrangement or association.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Return of contributions.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The repayment to any member of any amount of any payment excluded under subparagraph (A) shall not be treated as policyholder dividend, and is not deductible by the arrangement or association.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Source of returns</inline>.—</heading><content>Except in the case of the termination of a member’s interest in the arrangement or association, any amount distributed to any member shall be treated as paid out of surplus in excess of amounts excluded under subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deduction for members of eligible arrangements or associations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment as trade or business expenses</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent not otherwise allowable under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, any member of any eligible arrangement or association may treat any initial payment referred to in paragraph (1) made during a taxable year to such arrangement or association as an ordinary and necessary expense incurred in connection with a trade or business for purposes of the deduction allowable under section 162, to the extent such payment does not exceed the amount which would be payable to an independent insurance company for similar annual insurance coverage (as determined by the Secretary), and further reduced by any annual dues, assessments, or premiums paid during such taxable year. Such deduction shall not be allowable as to any initial payment referred to in paragraph (1) made to an eligible arrangement or association by any person who is a member of any other eligible arrangement or association on or after the effective date of the Tax Reform Act of 1986. Any excess amount not allowed as a deduction for the taxable year in which such payment was made pursuant to the limitation contained in the 1st sentence of this subparagraph shall, subject to such limitation, be allowable as a deduction in any of the 5 succeeding taxable years, in order of time, to the extent not previously allowed as a deduction under this sentence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Refunds of initial payments</inline>.—</heading><content>Any amount attributable to any initial payment referred to in paragraph (1) to such arrangement or association described in paragraph (1) which is later refunded for any reason shall be included in the gross income of the recipient in the taxable year received, to the extent a deduction for such payment was allowed. Any amount refunded in excess of such payment shall be included in gross income except to the extent otherwise excluded from income by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible arrangements or associations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The terms ‘eligible physicans’ [sic] and surgeons’ mutual protection and interindemnity arrangement or association’ and ‘eligible arrangement or association’ mean and are limited to any mutual protection and interindemnity arrangement or association that provides only medical malpractice liability protection for its members or medical malpractice liability protection in conjunction with protection against other liability claims incurred in the course of, or related to, the professional practice of a physician or surgeon and which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> was operative and was providing such protection, or had received a permit for the offer and sale of memberships, under the laws of any State before <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is not subject to regulation by any State insurance department,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> has a right to make unlimited assessments against all members to cover current claims and losses, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> is not a member of, nor subject to protection by, any insurance guaranty plan or association of any State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of subsection (a) shall apply to payments made to and receipts of physicians’ and surgeons’ mutual protection and interindemnity arrangements or associations, and refunds of payments by such arrangements or associations, after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>], in taxable years ending after such date.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id44180987-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Treatment as Unearned Premiums of Additions to Reserves Required by State Law or Regulations for Mortgage Guaranty Insurance Losses</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/90/240/s5/g">Pub. L. 90–240, § 5(g)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/779">81 Stat. 779</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> In the case of taxable years beginning before 1967, a company shall treat additions to a reserve, required by State law or regulations for mortgage guaranty insurance losses resulting from adverse economic cycles, as unearned premiums for purposes of section 832(b)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954], but the amount so treated as unearned premiums in a taxable year shall not exceed 50 percent of premiums earned on insurance contracts (as defined in section 832(b)(4) of such Code), determined without regard to amounts added to the reserve, with respect to mortgage guaranty insurance for such year. The amount of unearned premiums at the close of 1966 shall be determined without regard to the preceding sentence for the purpose of applying section 832(b)(4) of such Code to 1967. Additions to such a reserve shall not be treated as unearned premiums for any taxable year beginning after 1966.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> If a mortgage guaranty insurance company made additions to a reserve which were so treated as unearned premiums described in paragraph (1), such company, in taxable years beginning after 1966, shall include in gross income (in addition to the items specified in section 832(b)(1) of such Code) the sum of the following amounts until there is included in gross income an amount equal to the aggregate additions to the reserve described in paragraph (1) for taxable years beginning before 1967:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an amount (if any) equal to the excess of losses incurred (as defined in section 832(b)(5) of such Code) for the taxable year over 35 percent of premiums earned on insurance contracts during the taxable year (as defined in section 832(b)(4) of such Code), determined without regard to amounts added to the reserve referred to in paragraph (1), with respect to mortgage guaranty insurance,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the amount (if any) remaining which was added to the reserve for the tenth preceding taxable year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the aggregate of amounts so treated as unearned premiums for all taxable years beginning before 1967 less the total of the amounts included in gross income under this paragraph for prior taxable years and the amounts included in gross income under subparagraphs (A) and (B) for the taxable year, over</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the aggregate of the additions made for taxable years beginning before 1967 which remain in the reserve at the close of the taxable year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Amounts shall be taken into account on a first-in-time basis. For purposes of section 832(e) of such Code and this paragraph, if part of the reserve is reduced under State law or regulation, such reduction shall first apply to the extent of amounts added to the reserve for taxable years beginning before 1967, and only then to amounts added thereafter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The provisions of this subsection shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1956-12-31">December 31, 1956</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
