<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id44455a86-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864"><num value="864">§ 864.</num><heading> Definitions and special rules</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a87-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Produced</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this part, the term “produced” includes created, fabricated, manufactured, extracted, processed, cured, or aged.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a88-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Trade or business within the United States</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this part, part II, and chapter 3, the term “trade or business within the United States” includes the performance of personal services within the United States at any time within the taxable year, but does not include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a89-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance of personal services for foreign employer</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The performance of personal services—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455a8a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for a nonresident alien individual, foreign partnership, or foreign corporation, not engaged in trade or business within the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455a8b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for an office or place of business maintained in a foreign country or in a possession of the United States by an individual who is a citizen or resident of the United States or by a domestic partnership or a domestic corporation,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">by a nonresident alien individual temporarily present in the United States for a period or periods not exceeding a total of 90 days during the taxable year and whose compensation for such services does not exceed in the aggregate $3,000.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a8c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Trading in securities or commodities</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a8d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Stocks and securities</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a8e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Trading in stocks or securities through a resident broker, commission agent, custodian, or other independent agent.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a8f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Trading for taxpayer’s own account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Trading in stocks or securities for the taxpayer’s own account, whether by the taxpayer or his employees or through a resident broker, commission agent, custodian, or other agent, and whether or not any such employee or agent has discretionary authority to make decisions in effecting the transactions. This clause shall not apply in the case of a dealer in stocks or securities.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a90-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Commodities</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a91-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Trading in commodities through a resident broker, commission agent, custodian, or other independent agent.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a92-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Trading for taxpayer’s own account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Trading in commodities for the taxpayer’s own account, whether by the taxpayer or his employees or through a resident broker, commission agent, custodian, or other agent, and whether or not any such employee or agent has discretionary authority to make decisions in effecting the transactions. This clause shall not apply in the case of a dealer in commodities.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a93-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Clauses (i) and (ii) shall apply only if the commodities are of a kind customarily dealt in on an organized commodity exchange and if the transaction is of a kind customarily consummated at such place.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a94-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraphs (A)(i) and (B)(i) shall apply only if, at no time during the taxable year, the taxpayer has an office or other fixed place of business in the United States through which or by the direction of which the transactions in stocks or securities, or in commodities, as the case may be, are effected.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a95-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Effectively connected income, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a96-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this title—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455a97-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation engaged in trade or business within the United States during the taxable year, the rules set forth in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (6), (7), and (8) shall apply in determining the income, gain, or loss which shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455a98-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (6) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002141">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002141"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> (7), or (8) or in section 871(d) or sections 882(d) and (e), in the case of a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation not engaged in trade or business within the United States during the taxable year, no income, gain, or loss shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a99-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodical, etc., income from sources within United States—factors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In determining whether income from sources within the United States of the types described in section 871(a)(1), section 871(h), section 881(a), or section 881(c), or whether gain or loss from sources within the United States from the sale or exchange of capital assets, is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, the factors taken into account shall include whether—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455a9a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the income, gain, or loss is derived from assets used in or held for use in the conduct of such trade or business, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455a9b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the activities of such trade or business were a material factor in the realization of the income, gain, or loss.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In determining whether an asset is used in or held for use in the conduct of such trade or business or whether the activities of such trade or business were a material factor in realizing an item of income, gain, or loss, due regard shall be given to whether or not such asset or such income, gain, or loss was accounted for through such trade or business.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a9c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Other income from sources within United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">All income, gain, or loss from sources within the United States (other than income, gain, or loss to which paragraph (2) applies) shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455a9d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Income from sources without United States</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44455a9e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), no income, gain, or loss from sources without the United States shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44455a9f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Income, gain, or loss from sources without the United States shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States by a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation if such person has an office or other fixed place of business within the United States to which such income, gain, or loss is attributable and such income, gain, or loss—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aa0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> consists of rents or royalties for the use of or for the privilege of using intangible property described in section 862(a)(4) derived in the active conduct of such trade or business;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aa1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> consists of dividends, interest, or amounts received for the provision of guarantees of indebtedness, and either is derived in the active conduct of a banking, financing, or similar business within the United States or is received by a corporation the principal business of which is trading in stocks or securities for its own account; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aa2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> is derived from the sale or exchange (outside the United States) through such office or other fixed place of business of personal property described in section 1221(a)(1), except that this clause shall not apply if the property is sold or exchanged for use, consumption, or disposition outside the United States and an office or other fixed place of business of the taxpayer in a foreign country participated materially in such sale.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Any income or gain which is equivalent to any item of income or gain described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) shall be treated in the same manner as such item for purposes of this subparagraph.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44455aa3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of a foreign corporation taxable under part I or part II of subchapter L, any income from sources without the United States which is attributable to its United States business shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id44455aa4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> No income from sources without the United States shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States if it either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aa5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> consists of dividends, interest, or royalties paid by a foreign corporation in which the taxpayer owns (within the meaning of section 958(a)), or is considered as owning (by applying the ownership rules of section 958(b)), more than 50 percent of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aa6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is subpart F income within the meaning of section 952(a).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455aa7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules for application of paragraph (4)(B)</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aa8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in determining whether a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation has an office or other fixed place of business, an office or other fixed place of business of an agent shall be disregarded unless such agent (i) has the authority to negotiate and conclude contracts in the name of the nonresident alien individual or foreign corporation and regularly exercises that authority or has a stock of merchandise from which he regularly fills orders on behalf of such individual or foreign corporation, and (ii) is not a general commission agent, broker, or other agent of independent status acting in the ordinary course of his business,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aa9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> income, gain, or loss shall not be considered as attributable to an office or other fixed place of business within the United States unless such office or fixed place of business is a material factor in the production of such income, gain, or loss and such office or fixed place of business regularly carries on activities of the type from which such income, gain, or loss is derived, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aaa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the income, gain, or loss which shall be attributable to an office or other fixed place of business within the United States shall be the income, gain, or loss property allocable thereto, but, in the case of a sale or exchange described in clause (iii) of such subparagraph, the income which shall be treated as attributable to an office or other fixed place of business within the United States shall not exceed the income which would be derived from sources within the United States if the sale or exchange were made in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455aab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain deferred payments, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this title, in the case of any income or gain of a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aac-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is taken into account for any taxable year, but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aad-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is attributable to a sale or exchange of property or the performance of services (or any other transaction) in any other taxable year,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the determination of whether such income or gain is taxable under section 871(b) or 882 (as the case may be) shall be made as if such income or gain were taken into account in such other taxable year and without regard to the requirement that the taxpayer be engaged in a trade or business within the United States during the taxable year referred to in subparagraph (A).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455aae-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain property transactions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this title, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aaf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any property ceases to be used or held for use in connection with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ab0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such property is disposed of within 10 years after such cessation,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the determination of whether any income or gain attributable to such disposition is taxable under section 871(b) or 882 (as the case may be) shall be made as if such sale or exchange occurred immediately before such cessation and without regard to the requirement that the taxpayer be engaged in a trade or business within the United States during the taxable year for which such income or gain is taken into account.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ab1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Gain or loss of foreign persons from sale or exchange of certain partnership interests</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ab2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, if a nonresident alien individual or foreign corporation owns, directly or indirectly, an interest in a partnership which is engaged in any trade or business within the United States, gain or loss on the sale or exchange of all (or any portion of) such interest shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of such trade or business to the extent such gain or loss does not exceed the amount determined under subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ab3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount treated as effectively connected</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount determined under this subparagraph with respect to any partnership interest sold or exchanged—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455ab4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> in the case of any gain on the sale or exchange of the partnership interest, is—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44455ab5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the portion of the partner’s distributive share of the amount of gain which would have been effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States if the partnership had sold all of its assets at their fair market value as of the date of the sale or exchange of such interest, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44455ab6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> zero if no gain on such deemed sale would have been so effectively connected, and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455ab7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> in the case of any loss on the sale or exchange of the partnership interest, is—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44455ab8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the portion of the partner’s distributive share of the amount of loss on the deemed sale described in clause (i)(I) which would have been so effectively connected, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id44455ab9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> zero if no loss on such deemed sale would be have been so effectively connected.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> For purposes of this subparagraph, a partner’s distributive share of gain or loss on the deemed sale shall be determined in the same manner as such partner’s distributive share of the non-separately stated taxable income or loss of such partnership.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455aba-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with United States real property interests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a partnership described in subparagraph (A) holds any United States real property interest (as defined in section 897(c)) at the time of the sale or exchange of the partnership interest, then the gain or loss treated as effectively connected income under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by the amount so treated with respect to such United States real property interest under section 897.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455abb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale or exchange</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “sale or exchange” means any sale, exchange, or other disposition.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455abc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/8/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines appropriate for the application of this paragraph, including with respect to exchanges described in section 332, 351, 354, 355, 356, or 361.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44455abd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of related person factoring income</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455abe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of the provisions set forth in paragraph (2), if any person acquires (directly or indirectly) a trade or service receivable from a related person, any income of such person from the trade or service receivable so acquired shall be treated as if it were interest on a loan to the obligor under the receivable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455abf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Provisions to which paragraph (1) applies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions set forth in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ac0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Section 904 (relating to limitation on foreign tax credit).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ac1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subpart F of part III of this subchapter (relating to controlled foreign corporations).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ac2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Trade or service receivable</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “trade or service receivable” means any account receivable or evidence of indebtedness arising out of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ac3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the disposition by a related person of property described in section 1221(a)(1), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ac4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the performance of services by a related person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ac5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Related person</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “related person” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ac6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any person who is a related person (within the meaning of section 267(b)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ac7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any United States shareholder (as defined in section 951(b)) and any person who is a related person (within the meaning of section 267(b)) to such a shareholder.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ac8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain provisions not to apply</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The following provisions shall not apply to any amount treated as interest under paragraph (1) or (6):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ac9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Section 904(d)(2)(B)(iii)(I) (relating to exceptions for export financing interest).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455aca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subparagraph (A) of section 954(b)(3) (relating to exception where foreign base company income is less than 5 percent or $1,000,000).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455acb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Subparagraph (B) of section 954(c)(2) (relating to certain export financing).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455acc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Clause (i) of section 954(c)(3)(A) (relating to certain income received from related persons).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455acd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain income from loans of a controlled foreign corporation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any income of a controlled foreign corporation (within the meaning of section 957(a)) from a loan to a person for the purpose of financing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ace-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the purchase of property described in section 1221(a)(1) of a related person, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455acf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the payment for the performance of services by a related person,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be treated as interest described in paragraph (1).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for certain related persons doing business in same foreign country</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any trade or service receivable acquired by any person from a related person if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ad1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the person acquiring such receivable and such related person are created or organized under the laws of the same foreign country and such related person has a substantial part of its assets used in its trade or business located in such same foreign country, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455ad2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such related person would not have derived any foreign base company income (as defined in section 954(a), determined without regard to section 954(b)(3)(A)), or any income effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, from such receivable if it had been collected by such related person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/d/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to prevent the avoidance of the provisions of this subsection or section 956(c)(3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules for allocating interest, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of affiliated groups</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The taxable income of each member of an affiliated group shall be determined by allocating and apportioning interest expense of each member as if all members of such group were a single corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Gross income and fair market value methods may not be used for interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">All allocations and apportionments of interest expense shall be determined using the adjusted bases of assets rather than on the basis of the fair market value of the assets or gross income.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt assets not taken into account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of allocating and apportioning any deductible expense, any tax-exempt asset (and any income from such an asset) shall not be taken into account. A similar rule shall apply in the case of the portion of any dividend (other than a qualifying dividend as defined in section 243(b)) equal to the deduction allowable under section 243 or 245(a) with respect to such dividend and in the case of a like portion of any stock the dividends on which would be so deductible and would not be qualifying dividends (as so defined).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis of stock in nonaffiliated 10-percent owned corporations adjusted for earnings and profits changes</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ad9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of allocating and apportioning expenses on the basis of assets, the adjusted basis of any stock in a nonaffiliated 10-percent owned corporation shall be—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455ada-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> increased by the amount of the earnings and profits of such corporation attributable to such stock and accumulated during the period the taxpayer held such stock, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455adb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> reduced (but not below zero) by any deficit in earnings and profits of such corporation attributable to such stock for such period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455adc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonaffiliated 10-percent owned corporation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “nonaffiliated 10-percent owned corporation” means any corporation if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455add-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such corporation is not included in the taxpayer’s affiliated group, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455ade-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> members of such affiliated group own 10 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock of such corporation entitled to vote.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455adf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Earnings and profits of lower tier corporations taken into account</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If, by reason of holding stock in a nonaffiliated 10-percent owned corporation, the taxpayer is treated under clause (iii) as owning stock in another corporation with respect to which the stock ownership requirements of clause (ii) are met, the adjustment under subparagraph (A) shall include an adjustment for the amount of the earnings and profits (or deficit therein) of such other corporation which are attributable to the stock the taxpayer is so treated as owning and to the period during which the taxpayer is treated as owning such stock.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Stock ownership requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The stock ownership requirements of this clause are met with respect to any corporation if members of the taxpayer’s affiliated group own (directly or through the application of clause (iii)) 10 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock of such corporation entitled to vote.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Stock owned through entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph, stock owned (directly or indirectly) by a corporation, partnership, or trust shall be treated as being owned proportionately by its shareholders, partners, or beneficiaries. Stock considered to be owned by a person by reason of the application of the preceding sentence, shall, for purposes of applying such sentence, be treated as actually owned by such person.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with subpart F, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, proper adjustment shall be made to the earnings and profits of any corporation to take into account any earnings and profits included in gross income under section 951 or under any other provision of this title and reflected in the adjusted basis of the stock.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Affiliated group</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “affiliated group” has the meaning given such term by section 1504. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a foreign corporation shall be treated as a member of the affiliated group if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455ae6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> more than 50 percent of the gross income of such foreign corporation for the taxable year is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455ae7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> at least 80 percent of either the vote or value of all outstanding stock of such foreign corporation is owned directly or indirectly by members of the affiliated group (determined with regard to this sentence).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain financial institutions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), any corporation described in subparagraph (C) shall be treated as an includible corporation for purposes of section 1504 only for purposes of applying such section separately to corporations so described. This subparagraph shall not apply for purposes of paragraph (6).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455ae9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Description</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A corporation is described in this subparagraph if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455aea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such corporation is a financial institution described in section 581 or 591,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455aeb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the business of such financial institution is predominantly with persons other than related persons (within the meaning of subsection (d)(4)) or their customers, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455aec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such financial institution is required by State or Federal law to be operated separately from any other entity which is not such an institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id44455aed-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of bank holding companies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">To the extent provided in regulations—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455aee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a bank holding company (within the meaning of section 2(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id44455aef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/5/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any subsidiary of a financial institution described in section 581 or 591 or of any bank holding company if such subsidiary is predominantly engaged (directly or indirectly) in the active conduct of a banking, financing, or similar business,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">shall be treated as a corporation described in subparagraph (C).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455af0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation and apportionment of other expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Expenses other than interest which are not directly allocable or apportioned to any specific income producing activity shall be allocated and apportioned as if all members of the affiliated group were a single corporation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id44455af1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations providing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id44455af2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for the resourcing of income of any member of an affiliated group or modifications to the consolidated return regulations to the extent such resourcing or modification is necessary to carry out the purposes of this section,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4e3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for direct allocation of interest expense incurred to carry out an integrated financial transaction to any interest (or interest-type income) derived from such transaction and in other circumstances where such allocation would be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4e4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for the apportionment of expenses allocated to foreign source income among the members of the affiliated group and various categories of income described in section 904(d)(1),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4e5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> for direct allocation of interest expense in the case of indebtedness resulting in a disallowance under section 246A,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4e6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> for appropriate adjustments in the application of paragraph (3) in the case of an insurance company,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4e7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> preventing assets or interest expense from being taken into account more than once, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4e8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/e/7/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> that this subsection shall not apply for purposes of any provision of this subchapter to the extent the Secretary determines that the application of this subsection for such purposes would not be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4e9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/f"><num value="f" class="bold">[(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/117/2/tIX/s9671/a">Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9671(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/184">135 Stat. 184</ref>]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4ea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of research and experimental expenditures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4eb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of sections 861(b), 862(b), and 863(b), qualified research and experimental expenditures shall be allocated and apportioned as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4ec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any qualified research and experimental expenditures expended solely to meet legal requirements imposed by a political entity with respect to the improvement or marketing of specific products or processes for purposes not reasonably expected to generate gross income (beyond de minimis amounts) outside the jurisdiction of the political entity shall be allocated only to gross income from sources within such jurisdiction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4ed-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> In the case of any qualified research and experimental expenditures (not allocated under subparagraph (A)) to the extent—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4447a4ee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that such expenditures are attributable to activities conducted in the United States, 50 percent of such expenditures shall be allocated and apportioned to income from sources within the United States and deducted from such income in determining the amount of taxable income from sources within the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4447a4ef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> that such expenditures are attributable to activities conducted outside the United States, 50 percent of such expenditures shall be allocated and apportioned to income from sources outside the United States and deducted from such income in determining the amount of taxable income from sources outside the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4f0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The remaining portion of qualified research and experimental expenditures (not allocated under subparagraphs (A) and (B)) shall be apportioned, at the annual election of the taxpayer, on the basis of gross sales or gross income, except that, if the taxpayer elects to apportion on the basis of gross income, the amount apportioned to income from sources outside the United States shall at least be 30 percent of the amount which would be so apportioned on the basis of gross sales.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4f1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified research and experimental expenditures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “qualified research and experimental expenditures” means amounts which are foreign research or experimental expenditures within the meaning of section 174 or domestic research or experimental expenditures within the meaning of section 174A. For purposes of this paragraph, rules similar to the rules of subsection (c) of section 174 shall apply. Any qualified research and experimental expenditures allowed as an amortization deduction under section 174(a) or section 174A(c), shall be taken into account under this subsection for the taxable year for which such expenditures are allowed as a deduction under such section (as the case may be).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4f2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules for expenditures attributable to activities conducted in space, etc.</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4f3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any qualified research and experimental expenditures described in subparagraph (B)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4447a4f4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> if incurred by a United States person, shall be allocated and apportioned under this section in the same manner as if they were attributable to activities conducted in the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4447a4f5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if incurred by a person other than a United States person, shall be allocated and apportioned under this section in the same manner as if they were attributable to activities conducted outside the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4f6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Description of expenditures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), qualified research and experimental expenditures are described in this subparagraph if such expenditures are attributable to activities conducted—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4447a4f7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in space,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4447a4f8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> on or under water not within the jurisdiction (as recognized by the United States) of a foreign country, possession of the United States, or the United States, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id4447a4f9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in Antarctica.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a4fa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Affiliated group</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4447a4fb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the allocation and apportionment required by paragraph (1) shall be determined as if all members of the affiliated group (as defined in subsection (e)(5)) were a single corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4447a4fc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For purposes of the allocation and apportionment required by paragraph (1)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4fd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> sales and gross income from products produced in whole or in part in a possession by an electing corporation (within the meaning of section 936(h)(5)(E)),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002142">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002142"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id4447a4fe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> dividends from an electing corporation,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall not be taken into account, except that this subparagraph shall not apply to sales of (and gross income and dividends attributable to sales of) products with respect to which an election under section 936(h)(5)(F) <sup>2</sup> is not in effect.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4447a4ff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The qualified research and experimental expenditures taken into account for purposes of paragraph (1) shall be adjusted to reflect the amount of such expenditures included in computing the cost-sharing amount (determined under section 936(h)(5)(C)(i)(I)).<sup>2</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4447a500-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this paragraph, including regulations providing for the source of gross income and the allocation and apportionment of deductions to take into account the adjustments required by subparagraph (B) or (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id4447a501-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Paragraph (6) of subsection (e) shall not apply to qualified research and experimental expenditures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a502-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including regulations relating to the determination of whether any expenses are attributable to activities conducted in the United States or outside the United States and regulations providing such adjustments to the provisions of this subsection as may be appropriate in the case of cost-sharing arrangements and contract research.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id4447a503-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s864/g/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection shall apply to the taxpayer’s first taxable year (beginning on or before <date date="1994-08-01">August 1, 1994</date>) following the taxpayer’s last taxable year to which Revenue Procedure 92–56 applies or would apply if the taxpayer elected the benefits of such Revenue Procedure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id4447a504-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/278">68A Stat. 278</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tI/s102/d">Pub. L. 89–809, title I, § 102(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1544">80 Stat. 1544</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1901/a/113">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1901(a)(113)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1783">90 Stat. 1783</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I</ref>, §§ 123(a), 127(c), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/644">98 Stat. 644</ref>, 651; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXII">Pub. L. 99–514, title XII</ref>, §§ 1201(d)(4), 1211(b)(2), 1215(a), (b)(1), 1221(a)(2), 1223(b)(1), 1242(a), (b), 1275(c)(7), title XVIII, §§ 1810(c)(2), (3), 1899A(21), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2525">100 Stat. 2525</ref>, 2536, 2544, 2545, 2550, 2558, 2580, 2599, 2824, 2959; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tX/s10242/b">Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10242(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-423">101 Stat. 1330–423</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1012/a/1/B">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1012(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (d)(7), (10), (g)(5), (h)(1), (2)(A), (3)–(6), (p)(30), (r), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3494">102 Stat. 3494</ref>, 3498, 3499, 3501–3503, 3521, 3525; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVII/s7111">Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7111</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2326">103 Stat. 2326</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11401/a">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11401(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-472">104 Stat. 1388–472</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/227/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 102–227, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-11">Dec. 11, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1686">105 Stat. 1686</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/tXIII/s13234">Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13234</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/504">107 Stat. 504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1162/a">Pub. L. 105–34, title XI, § 1162(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/987">111 Stat. 987</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/tV/s532/c/2/N">Pub. L. 106–170, title V, § 532(c)(2)(N)</ref>–(P), <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1931">113 Stat. 1931</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/519/s4/3">Pub. L. 106–519, § 4(3)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-15">Nov. 15, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2432">114 Stat. 2432</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tI/s101/b/6">Pub. L. 108–357, title I, § 101(b)(6)</ref>, title IV, §§ 401(a), (b), 403(b)(6), 413(c)(12), title VIII, § 894(a), <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1423">118 Stat. 1423</ref>, 1488, 1491, 1494, 1507, 1647; <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/dC/tIII/s3093/a">Pub. L. 110–289, div. C, title III, § 3093(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2912">122 Stat. 2912</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/92/s15/a">Pub. L. 111–92, § 15(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2009-11-06">Nov. 6, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2996">123 Stat. 2996</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/147/tV/s551/a">Pub. L. 111–147, title V, § 551(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/117">124 Stat. 117</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/226/tII/s216/a">Pub. L. 111–226, title II, § 216(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-10">Aug. 10, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2400">124 Stat. 2400</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/240/tII/s2122/c">Pub. L. 111–240, title II, § 2122(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2568">124 Stat. 2568</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI">Pub. L. 115–97, title I</ref>, §§ 13501(a), 14502(a), <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2138">131 Stat. 2138</ref>, 2235; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/a/152">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(152)</ref>, (d)(1)(D)(x), (xvii)(IV), (V), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1191">132 Stat. 1191</ref>, 1207, 1208; <ref href="/us/pl/117/2/tIX/s9671/a">Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9671(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/184">135 Stat. 184</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/21/tVII/s70302/b/9">Pub. L. 119–21, title VII, § 70302(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2025-07-04">July 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/192">139 Stat. 192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id4447a505-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id4447a506-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id4447a507-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, referred to in subsec. (e)(5)(D)(i), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1841/a">section 1841(a) of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 936, referred to in subsec. (g)(4)(B), (C), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dU/tIV/s401/d/1/C">Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(d)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1206">132 Stat. 1206</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id4447a508-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/119/21">Pub. L. 119–21</ref> substituted “foreign research or experimental expenditures within the meaning of section 174 or domestic research or experimental expenditures within the meaning of section 174A” for “research and experimental expenditures within the meaning of section 174”, “allowed as an amortization deduction under section 174(a) or section 174A(c),” for “treated as deferred expenses under subsection (b) of section 174”, and “such section (as the case may be)” for “such subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/117/2">Pub. L. 117–2</ref> struck out subsec. (f) which related to election to allocate interest and other expenses on worldwide basis.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/d/1/D/x">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(d)(1)(D)(x)</ref>, amended par. (5) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (5) related to certain provisions that did not apply to any amount treated as interest under par. (1) or (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/a/152">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(a)(152)</ref>, substituted “section 956(c)(3)” for “section 956(b)(3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/d/1/D/xvii/IV">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(d)(1)(D)(xvii)(IV)</ref>, struck out “(determined without regard to paragraph (4) of section 1504(b))” after “section 1504” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/d/1/D/xvii/V">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(d)(1)(D)(xvii)(V)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (2)” for “paragraphs (2) and (4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/d/1/D/xvii/V">Pub. L. 115–141, § 401(d)(1)(D)(xvii)(V)</ref>, which directed amendment of par. (2) by substituting “paragraph (2)” for “paragraphs (2) and (4)”, was executed by making the substitution for “paragraph (4)”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13501/a/2/A">Pub. L. 115–97, § 13501(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “(7), and (8)” for “and (7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13501/a/2/B">Pub. L. 115–97, § 13501(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “(7), or (8)” for “or (7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s13501/a/1">Pub. L. 115–97, § 13501(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/s14502/a">Pub. L. 115–97, § 14502(a)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “All allocations and apportionments of interest expense shall be made on the basis of assets rather than gross income.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c)(4)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/240">Pub. L. 111–240</ref> substituted “dividends, interest, or amounts received for the provision of guarantees of indebtedness” for “dividends or interest”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/226">Pub. L. 111–226</ref> inserted at end “Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a foreign corporation shall be treated as a member of the affiliated group if—” and added cls. (i) and (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5)(D), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/147">Pub. L. 111–147</ref> substituted “<date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>” for “<date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (f)(5)(D), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/92/s15/a">Pub. L. 111–92, § 15(a)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>” for “<date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/111/92/s15/b">Pub. L. 111–92, § 15(b)</ref>, struck out par. (7). Text read as follows: “In the case of the first taxable year to which this subsection applies, the increase (if any) in the amount of the interest expense allocable to sources within the United States by reason of the application of this subsection shall be 30 percent of the amount of such increase determined without regard to this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (f)(5)(D), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s3093/a">Pub. L. 110–289, § 3093(a)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>” for “<date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/110/289/s3093/b">Pub. L. 110–289, § 3093(b)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (c)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s894/a">Pub. L. 108–357, § 894(a)</ref>, added concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s413/c/12">Pub. L. 108–357, § 413(c)(12)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (B) and (C) as (A) and (B), respectively, and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “Part III of subchapter G of this chapter (relating to foreign personal holding companies).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s403/b/6">Pub. L. 108–357, § 403(b)(6)</ref>, substituted “(C)(iii)(II)” for “(C)(iii)(III)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s101/b/6">Pub. L. 108–357, § 101(b)(6)</ref>, struck out “(A) In general” before “For purposes” and struck out heading and text of subpar. (B). Text read as follows: “For purposes of allocating and apportioning any interest expense, there shall not be taken into account any qualifying foreign trade property (as defined in section 943(a)) which is held by the taxpayer for lease or rental in the ordinary course of trade or business for use by the lessee outside the United States (as defined in section 943(b)(2)).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(7)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s401/b/1">Pub. L. 108–357, § 401(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “and in other circumstances where such allocation would be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection” before comma at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(7)(F), (G). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s401/b/2">Pub. L. 108–357, § 401(b)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (F) and redesignated former subpar. (F) as (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s401/a">Pub. L. 108–357, § 401(a)</ref>, added subsec. (f) and redesignated former subsec. (f) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/519">Pub. L. 106–519</ref> designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted heading, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsecs. (c)(4)(B)(iii), (d)(3)(A), (6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/170">Pub. L. 106–170</ref> substituted “section 1221(a)(1)” for “section 1221(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(2)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> struck out “, or in the case of a corporation (other than a corporation which is, or but for section 542(c)(7), 542(c)(10), or 543(b)(1)(C) would be, a personal holding company) the principal business of which is trading in stocks or securities for its own account, if its principal office is in the United States” after “dealer in stocks or securities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (f)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s13234/a">Pub. L. 103–66, § 13234(a)</ref>, substituted “50 percent” for “64 percent” in cls. (i) and (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s13234/b/2">Pub. L. 103–66, § 13234(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “subparagraph (B) or (C)” for “subparagraph (C)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s13234/b/1">Pub. L. 103–66, § 13234(b)(1)</ref>, added pars. (5) and (6) and struck out heading and text of former par. (5). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—This subsection shall apply to the taxpayer’s first 3 taxable years beginning after <date date="1989-08-01">August 1, 1989</date>, and on or before <date date="1992-08-01">August 1, 1992</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) <inline class="small-caps">Reduction</inline>.—Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), in the case of the taxpayer’s first taxable year beginning after <date date="1991-08-01">August 1, 1991</date>, this subsection shall only apply to qualified research and experimental expenditures incurred during the first 6 months of such taxable year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/227">Pub. L. 102–227</ref> amended par. (5) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (5) read as follows: “This subsection shall apply to the taxpayer’s first 2 taxable years beginning after <date date="1989-08-01">August 1, 1989</date>, and on or before <date date="1991-08-01">August 1, 1991</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> substituted “Years” for “Year” in heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—Except as provided in this paragraph, this subsection shall apply to the taxpayer’s first taxable year beginning after <date date="1989-08-01">August 1, 1989</date>, and before <date date="1990-08-02">August 2, 1990</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) <inline class="small-caps">Reduction</inline>.—Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), this subsection shall only apply to that portion of the qualified research and experimental expenditures for the taxable year referred to in subparagraph (A) which bears the same ratio to the total amount of such expenditures as—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the lesser of 9 months or the number of months in the taxable year, bears to</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the number of months in the taxable year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239">Pub. L. 101–239</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(2)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/p/30">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(p)(30)</ref>, substituted “section 542(c)(7), 542(c)(10),” for “section 542(c)(7)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/g/5">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(g)(5)</ref>, struck out at end “In applying this paragraph and paragraph (4), interest referred to in section 861(a)(1)(A) shall be considered income from sources within the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(B)(i), (ii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/d/10">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(d)(10)</ref>, struck out “(including any gain or loss realized on the sale or exchange of such property)” after “section 862(a)(4)” in cl. (i) and “, or gain or loss from the sale or exchange of stock or notes, bonds, or other evidences of indebtedness” after “dividends or interest” in cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/d/7">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(d)(7)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/r/2">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(r)(2)</ref>, amended par. (6) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (6) read as follows: “For purposes of this title, any income or gain of a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation for any taxable year which is attributable to a sale or exchange of property or the performance of services (or any other transaction) in any other taxable year shall be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States if it would have been so treated if such income or gain were taken into account in such other taxable year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/r/1">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(r)(1)</ref>, amended par. (7) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (7) read as follows: “For purposes of this title, if any property ceases to be used or held for use in connection with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, the determination of whether any income or gain attributable to a sale or exchange of such property occurring within 10 years after such cessation is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States shall be made as if such sale or exchange occurred immediately before such cessation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/a/1/B">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “(C)(iii)(III)” for “(C)(iii)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/6/B">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(6)(B)</ref>, struck out “(except as provided in regulations)” after “subchapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/2/A">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “from sources outside the United States” after “affiliated group”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/3">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(3)</ref>, inserted sentence at end and struck out former last sentence which read as follows: “A similar rule shall apply in the case of any dividend (other than a qualifying dividend as defined in section 243(b)) for which a deduction is allowable under section 243 or 245(a) and any stock the dividends on which would be so deductible and would not be qualifying dividends (as so defined).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/1">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(1)</ref>, substituted “nonaffiliated 10-percent owned corporations” for “certain corporations” in heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “For purposes of allocating and apportioning expenses on the basis of assets, the adjusted basis of any asset which is stock in a corporation which is not included in the affiliated group and in which members of the affiliated group own 10 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote in such corporation shall be—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) increased by the amount of the earnings and profits of such corporation attributable to such stock and accumulated during the period the taxpayer held such stock, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) reduced (but not below zero) by any deficit in earnings and profits of such corporation attributable to such stock for such period.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/4/B">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(4)(B)</ref>, inserted at end “This subparagraph shall not apply for purposes of paragraph (6).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/4/A">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(4)(A)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/5">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(5)</ref>, substituted “directly allocable or apportioned” for “directly allocable and apportioned”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(7)(D) to (F). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1012/h/6/A">Pub. L. 100–647, § 1012(h)(6)(A)</ref>, added subpars. (D) to (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (c)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> inserted “or part II” after “part I”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1215/b/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1215(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “and special rules” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1242/b/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1242(b)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to pars. (6) and (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1242/b/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1242(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “paragraph (6) or (7) or in”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1899A/21">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1899A(21)</ref>, inserted a comma between “section 871(h)” and “section 881(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1211/b/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1211(b)(2)</ref>, struck out cl. (iii), which read as follows: “is derived from the sale or exchange (without the United States) through such office or other fixed place of business of personal property described in section 1221(1), except that this clause shall not apply if the property is sold or exchanged for use, consumption, or disposition outside the United States and an office or other fixed place of business of the taxpayer outside the United States participated materially in such sale or exchange.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1242/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1242(a)</ref>, added pars. (6) and (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1201/d/4">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1201(d)(4)</ref>, amended cl. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, cl. (i) read as follows: “Subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of section 904(d)(2) (relating to interest income to which separate limitation applies) and subparagraph (J) of section 904(d)(3) (relating to interest from members of same affiliated group).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1810/c/3">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1810(c)(3)</ref>, inserted “and subparagraph (J) of section 904(d)(3) (relating to interest from members of same affiliated group)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1223/b/1">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1223(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “less than 5 percent or $1,000,000” for “less than 10 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1221/a/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1221(a)(2)</ref>, amended cl. (iii) generally, substituting “section 954(c)(2) (relating to certain export financing)” for “section 954(c)(3) (relating to certain income derived in active conduct of trade or business)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1221/a/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1221(a)(2)</ref>, amended cl. (iv) generally, substituting “Clause (i) of section 954(c)(3)(A) (relating to” for “Subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 954(c)(4) (relating to exception for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1275/c/7">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1275(c)(7)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally, striking out cl. (i) heading, substituting “An amount” for “Any amount”, and striking out cl. (ii), Virgin Islands corporations, which read as follows: “Subsection (b) of section 934 shall not apply to any amount treated as interest under paragraph (1) unless such amount is from sources within the Virgin Islands (determined after the application of paragraph (1)).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1810/c/2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1810(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (7) and redesignated former par. (7) as (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1215/a">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1215(a)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s127/c">Pub. L. 98–369, § 127(c)</ref>, substituted “section 871(a)(1), section 871(h) section 881(a), or section 881(c)” for “section 871(a)(1) or section 881(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s123/a">Pub. L. 98–369, § 123(a)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/113/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(113)(A)</ref>, substituted in heading “Produced” for “Sale, etc.” and struck out in text provisions relating to the definition of sale and sold.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/113/B">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(113)(B)</ref>, substituted “sale or exchange” for “sale”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/113/B">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(113)(B)</ref>, (C), substituted “sold or exchanged” for “sold” and “sale or exchange” for “sale” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/a/113/B">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1901(a)(113)(B)</ref>, substituted “sale or exchange” for “sale” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id4447a509-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a50a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2025 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/119/21">Pub. L. 119–21</ref> applicable to amounts paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after <date date="2024-12-31">Dec. 31, 2024</date>, subject to election for retroactive application by certain small businesses and election to deduct certain unamortized amounts paid or incurred in taxable years beginning before <date date="2025-01-01">Jan. 1, 2025</date>, see section 70302(e), (f) of <ref href="/us/pl/119/21">Pub. L. 119–21</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s174A">section 174A of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a50b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/2/tIX/s9671/b">Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9671(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/184">135 Stat. 184</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/2/tIX/s9671/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a50c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2017 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13501/c/1">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13501(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2141">131 Stat. 2141</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s13501/c/1">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to sales, exchanges, and dispositions on or after <date date="2017-11-27">November 27, 2017</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s14502/b">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 14502(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2235">131 Stat. 2235</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s14502/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a50d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/240">Pub. L. 111–240</ref> applicable to guarantees issued after <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/240/s2122/d">section 2122(d) of Pub. L. 111–240</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s861">section 861 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/226/tII/s216/b">Pub. L. 111–226, title II, § 216(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-10">Aug. 10, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2400">124 Stat. 2400</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/226/tII/s216/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-08-10">Aug. 10, 2010</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/147/tV/s551/b">Pub. L. 111–147, title V, § 551(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/117">124 Stat. 117</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/147/tV/s551/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a50e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/92/s15/c">Pub. L. 111–92, § 15(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-11-06">Nov. 6, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2996">123 Stat. 2996</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/92/s15/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a50f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/289/dC/tIII/s3093/c">Pub. L. 110–289, div. C, title III, § 3093(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2912">122 Stat. 2912</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/289/dC/tIII/s3093/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a510-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s101/b/6">section 101(b)(6) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref> applicable to transactions after <date date="2004-12-31">Dec. 31, 2004</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s101/c">section 101(c) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s56">section 56 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tIV/s401/c">Pub. L. 108–357, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1491">118 Stat. 1491</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/357/tIV/s401/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tIV/s403/c">Pub. L. 108–357, title IV, § 403(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1494">118 Stat. 1494</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/357/tIV/s403/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2002-12-31">December 31, 2002</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tIV/s403/d">Pub. L. 108–357, title IV, § 403(d)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 403</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2625">119 Stat. 2625</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/stat/119/2625">
<inline>“If the taxpayer elects (at such time and in such form and manner as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe) to have the rules of this subsection apply—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>] shall not apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="2002-12-31">December 31, 2002</date>, and before <date date="2005-01-01">January 1, 2005</date>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the case of taxable years beginning after <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>, clause (iv) of section 904(d)(4)(C) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as amended by this section) shall be applied by substituting ‘<date date="2005-01-01">January 1, 2005</date>’ for ‘<date date="2003-01-01">January 1, 2003</date>’ both places it appears.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/135">Pub. L. 109–135</ref> adding <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s403/d">section 403(d) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out above, effective as if included in the provision of the American Jobs Creation Act of 2004, <ref href="/us/pl/108/357">Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/s403/nn">section 403(nn) of Pub. L. 109–135</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2005 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s26">section 26 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s413/c/12">section 413(c)(12) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref> applicable to taxable years of foreign corporations beginning after <date date="2004-12-31">Dec. 31, 2004</date>, and to taxable years of United States shareholders with or within which such taxable years of foreign corporations end, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s413/d/1">section 413(d)(1) of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 2004 Amendments note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s894/b">Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 894(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1647">118 Stat. 1647</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/357/tVIII/s894/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a511-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/519">Pub. L. 106–519</ref> applicable to transactions after <date date="2000-09-30">Sept. 30, 2000</date>, with special rules relating to existing foreign sales corporations, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/519/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 106–519</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s56">section 56 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a512-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/170">Pub. L. 106–170</ref> applicable to any instrument held, acquired, or entered into, any transaction entered into, and supplies held or acquired on or after <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s532/d">section 532(d) of Pub. L. 106–170</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s170">section 170 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a513-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1162/b">Pub. L. 105–34, title XI, § 1162(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/987">111 Stat. 987</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1162/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a514-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/227/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 102–227, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-11">Dec. 11, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1686">105 Stat. 1686</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/227/tI/s101/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1989-08-01">August 1, 1989</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a515-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11401/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11401(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-472">104 Stat. 1388–472</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tXI/s11401/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1989-08-01">August 1, 1989</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a516-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provision of the Tax Reform Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s1019/a">section 1019(a) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a517-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1987-12-31">Dec. 31, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s10242/d">section 10242(d) of Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s816">section 816 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id4447a518-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1201/d/4">section 1201(d)(4) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1201/e">section 1201(e) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1211/b/2">section 1211(b)(2) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1211/c">section 1211(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s865">section 865 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXII/s1215/c">Pub. L. 99–514, title XII, § 1215(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2545">100 Stat. 2545</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tI/s1012/h/7">Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1012(h)(7)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3504">102 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tV/s521/a">Pub. L. 104–191, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2103">110 Stat. 2103</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/191/tV/s521/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transitional rules.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General phase-in.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of the 1st 3 taxable years of the taxpayer beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, the amendments made by this section shall not apply to interest expenses paid or accrued by the taxpayer during the taxable year with respect to an aggregate amount of indebtedness which does not exceed the general phase-in amount.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General phase-in amount</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in clause (iii), the general phase-in amount for purposes of clause (i) is the applicable percentage (determined under the following table) of the aggregate amount of indebtedness of the taxpayer outstanding on <date date="1985-11-16">November 16, 1985</date>:<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c2,L0,tp0,p1,7/8,s10,xs57,tp0,p1,7/8,s10,xs57; " id="id4447a519-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 145pt;" />
<html:col style="width:61pt ; max-width:61pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:1pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:td />
</html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I11;"><html:td style="min-width: 145.0pt; text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style="width:61.0pt ; max-width:61.0pt; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:b>The applicable</html:b></html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I12;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:3em;"><html:b>“In the case of the:</html:b></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:b>percentage is:</html:b></html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1st taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:2em;">75 </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>2nd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:2em;">50 </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>3rd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:2em;">25.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Lower limit where taxpayer reduces indebtedness</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of applying this subparagraph to interest expenses attributable to any month, the general phase-in amount shall in no event exceed the lowest amount of indebtedness of the taxpayer outstanding as of the close of any preceding month beginning after <date date="1985-11-16">November 16, 1985</date>. To the extent provided in regulations, the average amount of indebtedness outstanding during any month shall be used (in lieu of the amount outstanding as of the close of such month) for purposes of the preceding sentence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consolidation rule not to apply to certain interest.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of the 1st 5 taxable years of the taxpayer beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> subparagraph (A) shall not apply for purposes of paragraph (1) of section 864(e) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section), but</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> such paragraph (1) shall not apply to interest expenses paid or accrued by the taxpayer during the taxable year with respect to an aggregate amount of indebtedness which does not exceed the special phase-in amount.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special phase-in amount</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The special phase-in amount for purposes of clause (i) is the sum of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the general phase-in amount as determined for purposes of subparagraph (A),</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> the 5-year phase-in amount, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="III">“(III)</num><content> the 4-year phase-in amount.</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I26" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">  For purposes of applying this subparagraph to interest expense attributable to any month, the special phase-in amount shall in no event exceed the limitation determined under subparagraph (A)(iii).</continuation>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> 5-<inline class="small-caps">year phase-in amount</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The 5-year phase-in amount is the lesser of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the applicable percentage (determined under the following table for purposes of this subclause) of the 5-year debt amount, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> the applicable percentage (determined under the following table for purposes of this subclause) of the 5-year debt amount reduced by paydowns:<html:table class="Quoted" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c3,L0,tp0,p6,7/8,s10,xs60,xls60,tp0,p6,7/8,s10,xs60,xls60; " id="id4447a51a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 78pt;" />
<html:col style="width:64pt ; max-width:64pt;" />
<html:col style="width:64pt ; max-width:64pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 78.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:b>“In the case of the:</html:b></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:64.0pt ; max-width:64.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:b>The applicable percentage for purposes of subclause (I) is:</html:b></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:64.0pt ; max-width:64.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:b>The applicable percentage for purposes of subclause (II) is:</html:b></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1st taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>8⅓</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> 10 </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>2nd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>16⅔</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> 25 </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>3rd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>25</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> 50 </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>4th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>33⅓</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100 </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>16⅔</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><heading> 4-<inline class="small-caps">year phase-in amount</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The 4-year phase-in amount is the lesser of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the applicable percentage (determined under the following table for purposes of this subclause) of the 4-year debt amount, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> the applicable percentage (determined under the following table for purposes of this subclause) of the 4-year debt amount reduced by paydowns to the extent such paydowns exceed the 5-year debt amount:<html:table class="Quoted" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c3,L0,tp0,p6,7/8,s10,xs60,xls60,tp0,p6,7/8,s10,xs60,xls60; " id="id4447a51b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 78pt;" />
<html:col style="width:64pt ; max-width:64pt;" />
<html:col style="width:64pt ; max-width:64pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 78.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:b>“In the case of the:</html:b></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:64.0pt ; max-width:64.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:b>The applicable percentage for purposes of subclause (I) is:</html:b></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:64.0pt ; max-width:64.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:b>The applicable percentage for purposes of subclause (II) is:</html:b></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1st taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">6¼</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>2nd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>10</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">16⅔</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>3rd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>15</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">37½</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>4th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>20</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">100</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>0</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> 0. </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="v">“(v)</num><heading> 5-<inline class="small-caps">year debt amount</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘5-year debt amount’ means the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the amount of the outstanding indebtedness of the taxpayer on <date date="1985-05-29">May 29, 1985</date>, over</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> the amount of the outstanding indebtedness of the taxpayer as of the close of <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>.</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I26" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">  The 5-year debt amount shall not exceed the aggregate amount of indebtedness of the taxpayer outstanding on <date date="1985-11-16">November 16, 1985</date>.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><heading> 4-<inline class="small-caps">year debt amount</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘4-year debt amount’ means the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the amount referred to in clause (v)(II), over</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> the amount of the outstanding indebtedness of the taxpayer as of the close of <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>.</content>
</subclause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I26" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">  The 4-year debt amount shall not exceed the aggregate amount of indebtedness of the taxpayer outstanding on <date date="1985-11-16">November 16, 1985</date>, reduced by the 5-year debt amount.</continuation>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="vii">“(vii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Paydowns</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of applying this subparagraph to interest expenses attributable to any month, the term ‘paydowns’ means the excess (if any) of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the aggregate amount of indebtedness of the taxpayer outstanding on <date date="1985-11-16">November 16, 1985</date>, over</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="II">“(II)</num><content> the lowest amount of indebtedness of the taxpayer outstanding as of the close of any preceding month beginning after <date date="1985-11-16">November 16, 1985</date> (or, to the extent provided in regulations under subparagraph (A)(iii), the average amount of indebtedness outstanding during any such month).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination of subparagraphs (a) and (b)</inline>.—</heading><content>In applying subparagraph (B), there shall first be taken into account indebtedness to which subparagraph (A) applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rules.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> In the case of the 1st 9 taxable years of the taxpayer beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>, the amendments made by this section shall not apply to interest expenses paid or accrued by the taxpayer during the taxable year with respect to an aggregate amount of indebtedness which does not exceed the applicable percentage (determined under the following table) of the indebtedness described in clause (iii) or (iv):<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c2,L0,tp0,p7,7/8,s10,18,tp0,p7,7/8,s10,18; " id="id444a161c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 139pt;" />
<html:col style="width:67pt ; max-width:67pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:7pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 139.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:bottom;"><html:p style=" text-align:left;"><html:b />  “In the case of the:</html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:67.0pt ; max-width:67.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;"><html:b>The applicable percentage is:</html:b></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1st taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">90  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>2nd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">80  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>3rd taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">70  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>4th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">60  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>5th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">50  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>6th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">40  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>7th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">30  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>8th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">20  </html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:bottom; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9th taxable year</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:bottom; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:right;">10.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The provisions of this subparagraph shall apply in lieu of the provisions of subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Indebtedness outstanding on <date date="1985-05-29">may 29, 1985</date></inline>.—</heading><content>Indebtedness is described in this clause if it is indebtedness (which was outstanding on <date date="1985-05-29">May 29, 1985</date>) of a corporation incorporated on <date date="1917-06-13">June 13, 1917</date>, which has its principal place of business in Bartlesville, Oklahoma.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Indebtedness outstanding on <date date="1985-05-29">may 29, 1985</date></inline>.—</heading><content>Indebtedness is described in this clause if it is indebtedness (which was outstanding on <date date="1985-05-29">May 29, 1985</date>) of a member of an affiliated group (as defined in section 1504(a) [of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986]), the common parent of which was incorporated on <date date="1926-08-26">August 26, 1926</date>, and has its principal place of business in Harrison, New York.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of affiliated group</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this paragraph, all members of the same affiliated group of corporations (as defined in section 864(e)(5)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section) shall be treated as 1 taxpayer whether or not such members filed a consolidated return.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Election to have paragraph not apply</inline>.—</heading><content>A taxpayer may elect (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate may prescribe) to have this paragraph not apply. In the case of members of the same affiliated group (as so defined), such an election may be made only if each member consents to such election.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of a qualified corporation, in lieu of applying paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall not apply to interest expenses allocable to any indebtedness to the extent such indebtedness does not exceed $500,000,000 if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the indebtedness was incurred to develop or improve existing property that is owned by the taxpayer on <date date="1985-11-16">November 16, 1985</date>, and was acquired with the intent to develop or improve the property,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the loan agreement with respect to the indebtedness provides that the funds are to be utilized for purposes of developing or improving the above property, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the debt to equity ratio of the companies that join in the filing of the consolidated return is less than 15 percent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualified corporation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term ‘qualified corporation’ means a corporation—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> which was incorporated in Delaware on <date date="1964-06-29">June 29, 1964</date>,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the principal subsidiary of which is a resident of Arkansas, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> which is a member of an affiliated group the average daily United States production of oil of which is less than 50,000 barrels and the average daily United States refining of which is less than 150,000 barrels.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rules for subsidiary</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amendments made by this section shall not apply to interest on up to the applicable dollar amount of indebtedness of a subsidiary incorporated on <date date="1975-02-11">February 11, 1975</date>, the indebtedness of which on <date date="1986-05-06">May 6, 1986</date>, included—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> $100,000,000 face amount of 11¾ percent notes due in 1990,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> $100,000,000 of 8¾ percent notes due in 1989,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> 6¾ percent Japanese yen notes due in 1991, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> 5⅜ percent Swiss franc bonds due in 1994.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, the term ‘applicable dollar amount’ means $600,000,000 in the case of taxable years beginning in 1987 through 1991, $500,000,000 in the case of the taxable year beginning in 1992, $400,000,000 in the case of the taxable year beginning in 1993, $300,000,000 in the case of the taxable year beginning in 1994, $200,000,000 in the case of the taxable year beginning in 1995, $100,000,000 in the case of the taxable year beginning in 1996, and zero in the case of taxable years beginning after 1996.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0" status="repealed"><num value="5">“[(5)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tV/s521/a">Pub. L. 104–191, title V, § 521(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2103">110 Stat. 2103</ref>.]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rules for allocating general and administrative expenses.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of an affiliated group of domestic corporations the common parent of which has its principal office in New Brunswick, New Jersey, and has a certificate of organization which was filed with the Secretary of the State of New Jersey on <date date="1887-11-10">November 10, 1887</date>, the amendments made by this section shall not apply to the phase-in percentage of general and administrative expenses paid or incurred in its 1st 3 taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Phase-in percentage</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of subparagraph (A):<html:table width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse; border=0;  -uslm-lc: c2,L0,tp0,p1,7/8,s10,xs54,tp0,p1,7/8,s10,xs54; " id="id444a161d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 148pt;" />
<html:col style="width:58pt ; max-width:58pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:1pt;-uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:td />
</html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:8pt; font-size:7pt;">
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I12;"><html:td style="min-width: 148.0pt; text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:3em;"><html:b>“In the case of taxable</html:b></html:p></html:td><html:td style="width:58.0pt ; max-width:58.0pt; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:b>The phase-in</html:b></html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I12;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:3em;"><html:b> years beginning in:</html:b></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:b>percentage is:</html:b></html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1987</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:2em;">75</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1988</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:2em;">50</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I03;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:5em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1989</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:2em;">25.”</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tV/s521/b">Pub. L. 104–191, title V, § 521(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2103">110 Stat. 2103</ref>, provided that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“(1) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—The amendment made by this section [amending <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1215/c">section 1215(c) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out above] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“(2) <inline class="small-caps">Special rule</inline>.—In the case of the first taxable year beginning after <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, the pre-effective date portion of the interest expense of the corporation referred to in such paragraph (5) of such section 1215(c) [of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref>] for such taxable year shall be allocated and apportioned without regard to such amendment. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the pre-effective date portion is the amount which bears the same ratio to the interest expense for such taxable year as the number of days during such taxable year before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>] bears to 366.”]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1221/a/2">section 1221(a)(2) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to taxable years of foreign corporations beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1221/g">section 1221(g) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s954">section 954 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXII/s1223/c">Pub. L. 99–514, title XII, § 1223(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2558">100 Stat. 2558</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXII/s1223/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 881 and 954 of this title] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXII/s1242/c">Pub. L. 99–514, title XII, § 1242(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2580">100 Stat. 2580</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/tXII/s1242/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">December 31, 1986</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1275/c/7">section 1275(c)(7) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable to taxable years beginning after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, with certain exceptions and qualifications, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1277">section 1277 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s931">section 931 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1810(c)(2), (3) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in the provisions of the Tax Reform Act of 1984, <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A</ref>, to which such amendment relates, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1881">section 1881 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s48">section 48 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id444a161e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dA/tI/s123/c">Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 123(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/646">98 Stat. 646</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s956">section 956 of this title</ref>] shall apply to accounts receivable and evidences of indebtedness transferred after <date date="1984-03-01">March 1, 1984</date>, in taxable years ending after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transitional rule</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amendments made by this section shall not apply to accounts receivable and evidences of indebtedness acquired after <date date="1984-03-01">March 1, 1984</date>, and before <date date="1994-03-01">March 1, 1994</date>, by a Belgian corporation in existence on <date date="1984-03-01">March 1, 1984</date>, in any taxable year ending after such date, but only to the extent that the amount includible in gross income by reason of section 956 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] with respect to such corporation for all such taxable years is not reduced by reason of this paragraph by more than the lesser of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> $15,000,000 or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the amount of the Belgian corporation’s adjusted basis on <date date="1984-03-01">March 1, 1984</date>, in stock of a foreign corporation formed to issue bonds outside the United States to the public.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s127/c">section 127(c) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> applicable to interest received after <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, with respect to obligations issued after such date, in taxable years ending after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s127/g/1">section 127(g)(1) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s871">section 871 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id444a161f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> effective for taxable years beginning after <date date="1976-12-31">Dec. 31, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1901/d">section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id444a1620-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1966-12-31">Dec. 31, 1966</date>, except that in applying <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s864/c/4/B/iii">section 864(c)(4)(B)(iii) of this title</ref> with respect to a binding contract entered into on or before <date date="1966-02-24">Feb. 24, 1966</date>, activities in the United States on or before such date in negotiating or carrying out such contract shall not be taken into account, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s102/e/1">section 102(e)(1) of Pub. L. 89–809</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s861">section 861 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id444a1621-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions that nothing in amendment by section 401(d)(1)(D)(x), (xvii)(IV), (V) of <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> be construed to affect treatment of certain transactions occurring, property acquired, or items of income, loss, deduction, or credit taken into account prior to <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, for purposes of determining liability for tax for periods ending after <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s401/e">section 401(e) of Pub. L. 115–141</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s23">section 23 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id444a1622-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Certain Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> in Relation to Treaty Obligations of United States</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For applicability of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1201/d/4">section 1201(d)(4) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref> notwithstanding any treaty obligation of the United States in effect on <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, and for nonapplication of amendments by sections 1211(b)(2) and 1242(a) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> to the extent application of such amendments would be contrary to any treaty obligation of the United States in effect on <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, with provision that for such purposes any amendment by title I of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> be treated as if it had been included in the provision of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> to which such amendment relates, see section 1012(aa)(2) to (4) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s861">section 861 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id444a1623-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Amendments Not Required Until January 1, 1989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing that if any amendments made by subtitle A or subtitle C of title XI [§§ 1101–1147 and 1171–1177] or title XVIII [§§ 1800–1899A] of <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> require an amendment to any plan, such plan amendment shall not be required to be made before the first plan year beginning on or after <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1140">section 1140 of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
