<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id445d28f2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896"><num value="896">§ 896.</num><heading> Adjustment of tax on nationals, residents, and corporations of certain foreign countries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id445d28f3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Imposition of more burdensome taxes by foreign country</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the President finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28f4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> under the laws of any foreign country, considering the tax system of such foreign country, citizens of the United States not residents of such foreign country or domestic corporations are being subjected to more burdensome taxes, on any item of income received by such citizens or corporations from sources within such foreign country, than taxes imposed by the provisions of this subtitle on similar income derived from sources within the United States by residents or corporations of such foreign country,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28f5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such foreign country, when requested by the United States to do so, has not acted to revise or reduce such taxes so that they are no more burdensome than taxes imposed by the provisions of this subtitle on similar income derived from sources within the United States by residents or corporations of such foreign country, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28f6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> it is in the public interest to apply pre-1967 tax provisions in accordance with the provisions of this subsection to residents or corporations of such foreign country,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President shall proclaim that the tax on such similar income derived from sources within the United States by residents or corporations of such foreign country shall, for taxable years beginning after such proclamation, be determined under this subtitle without regard to amendments made to this subchapter and chapter 3 on or after the date of enactment of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id445d28f7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Imposition of discriminatory taxes by foreign country</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the President finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28f8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> under the laws of any foreign country, citizens of the United States or domestic corporations (or any class of such citizens or corporations) are, with respect to any item of income, being subjected to a higher effective rate of tax than are nationals, residents, or corporations of such foreign country (or a similar class of such nationals, residents, or corporations) under similar circumstances;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28f9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such foreign country, when requested by the United States to do so, has not acted to eliminate such higher effective rate of tax; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28fa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> it is in the public interest to adjust, in accordance with the provisions of this subsection, the effective rate of tax imposed by this subtitle on similar income of nationals, residents, or corporations of such foreign country (or such similar class of such nationals, residents, or corporations),</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President shall proclaim that the tax on similar income of nationals, residents, or corporations of such foreign country (or such similar class of such nationals, residents, or corporations) shall, for taxable years beginning after such proclamation, be adjusted so as to cause the effective rate of tax imposed by this subtitle on such similar income to be substantially equal to the effective rate of tax imposed by such foreign country on such item of income of citizens of the United States or domestic corporations (or such class of citizens or corporations). In implementing a proclamation made under this subsection, the effective rate of tax imposed by this subtitle on an item of income may be adjusted by the disallowance, in whole or in part, of any deduction, credit, or exemption which would otherwise be allowed with respect to that item of income or by increasing the rate of tax otherwise applicable to that item of income.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id445d28fb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Alleviation of more burdensome or discriminatory taxes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the President finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28fc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the laws of any foreign country with respect to which the President has made a proclamation under subsection (a) have been modified so that citizens of the United States not residents of such foreign country or domestic corporations are no longer subject to more burdensome taxes on the item of income derived by such citizens or corporations from sources within such foreign country, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id445d28fd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the laws of any foreign country with respect to which the President has made a proclamation under subsection (b) have been modified so that citizens of the United States or domestic corporations (or any class of such citizens or corporations) are no longer subject to a higher effective rate of tax on the item of income,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">he shall proclaim that the tax imposed by this subtitle on the similar income of nationals, residents, or corporations of such foreign country shall, for any taxable year beginning after such proclamation, be determined under this subtitle without regard to such subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id445d28fe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of Congress required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No proclamation shall be issued by the President pursuant to this section unless, at least 30 days prior to such proclamation, he has notified the Senate and the House of Representatives of his intention to issue such proclamation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id445d28ff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s896/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation by regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary or appropriate to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id445d2900-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 89–809, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1563">80 Stat. 1563</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id445d2901-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id445d2902-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id445d2903-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this section, referred to in the provisions following subsec. (a)(3), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/89/809">Pub. L. 89–809</ref>, which was approved <date date="1966-11-13">Nov. 13, 1966</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id445d2904-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id445d2905-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id445d2906-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1966-12-31">Dec. 31, 1966</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/809/s105/d">section 105(d) of Pub. L. 89–809</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1966 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s894">section 894 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
