<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id47a6d5fb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002"><num value="9002">§ 9002.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d5fc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “authorized committee” means, with respect to the candidates of a political party for President and Vice President of the United States, any political committee which is authorized in writing by such candidates to incur expenses to further the election of such candidates. Such authorization shall be addressed to the chairman of such political committee, and a copy of such authorization shall be filed by such candidates with the Commission. Any withdrawal of any authorization shall also be in writing and shall be addressed and filed in the same manner as the authorization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d5fd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “candidate” means, with respect to any presidential election, an individual who (A) has been nominated for election to the office of President of the United States or the office of Vice President of the United States by a major party, or (B) has qualified to have his name on the election ballot (or to have the names of electors pledged to him on the election ballot) as the candidate of a political party for election to either such office in 10 or more States. For purposes of paragraphs (6) and (7) of this section and purposes of section 9004(a)(2), the term “candidate” means, with respect to any preceding presidential election, an individual who received popular votes for the office of President in such election. The term “candidate” shall not include any individual who has ceased actively to seek election to the office of President of the United States or to the office of Vice President of the United States, in more than one State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d5fe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “Commission” means the Federal Election Commission established by section 306(a)(1) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d5ff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “eligible candidates” means the candidates of a political party for President and Vice President of the United States who have met all applicable conditions for eligibility to receive payments under this chapter set forth in section 9003.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d600-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “fund” means the Presidential Election Campaign Fund established by section 9006(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d601-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “major party” means, with respect to any presidential election, a political party whose candidate for the office of President in the preceding presidential election received, as the candidate of such party, 25 percent or more of the total number of popular votes received by all candidates for such office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d602-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “minor party” means, with respect to any presidential election, a political party whose candidate for the office of President in the preceding presidential election received, as the candidate of such party, 5 percent or more but less than 25 percent of the total number of popular votes received by all candidates for such office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d603-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “new party” means, with respect to any presidential election, a political party which is neither a major party nor a minor party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d604-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “political committee” means any committee, association, or organization (whether or not incorporated) which accepts contributions or makes expenditures for the purpose of influencing, or attempting to influence, the nomination or election of one or more individuals to Federal, State, or local elective public office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d605-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “presidential election” means the election of presidential and vice-presidential electors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d606-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><chapeau> The term “qualified campaign expense” means an expense—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47a6d607-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> incurred (i) by the candidate of a political party for the office of President to further his election to such office or to further the election of the candidate of such political party for the office of Vice President, or both (ii) by the candidate of a political party for the office of Vice President to further his election to such office or to further the election of the candidate of such political party for the office of President, or both, or (iii) by an authorized committee of the candidates of a political party for the offices of President and Vice President to further the election of either or both of such candidates to such offices,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47a6d608-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> incurred within the expenditure report period (as defined in paragraph (12)), or incurred before the beginning of such period to the extent such expense is for property, services, or facilities used during such period, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47a6d609-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> neither the incurring nor payment of which constitutes a violation of any law of the United States or of the State in which such expense is incurred or paid.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">An expense shall be considered as incurred by a candidate or an authorized committee if it is incurred by a person authorized by such candidate or such committee, as the case may be, to incur such expense on behalf of such candidate or such committee. If an authorized committee of the candidates of a political party for President and Vice President of the United States also incurs expenses to further the election of one or more other individuals to Federal, State, or local elective public office, expenses incurred by such committee which are not specifically to further the election of such other individual or individuals shall be considered as incurred to further the election of such candidates for President and Vice President in such proportion as the Commission prescribes by rules or regulations.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47a6d60a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><chapeau> The term “expenditure report period” with respect to any presidential election means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47a6d60b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a major party, the period beginning with the first day of September before the election, or, if earlier, with the date on which such major party at its national convention nominated its candidate for election to the office of President of the United States, and ending 30 days after the date of the presidential election; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47a6d60c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9002/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a party which is not a major party, the same period as the expenditure report period of the major party which has the shortest expenditure report period for such presidential election under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id47a6d60d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/92/178/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/563">85 Stat. 563</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/tIV/s404/c/1">Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 404(c)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1292">88 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/tI/s115/c/1">Pub. L. 94–283, title I, § 115(c)(1)</ref>, title III, § 306(a)(1), <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/495">90 Stat. 495</ref>, 499; <ref href="/us/pl/110/172/s11/a/42/A">Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(42)(A)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2488">121 Stat. 2488</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id47a6d60e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id47a6d60f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id47a6d610-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 306(a)(1) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, referred to in par. (3), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30106/a/1">section 30106(a)(1) of Title 52</ref>, Voting and Elections.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id47a6d611-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/172">Pub. L. 110–172</ref> substituted “section 306(a)(1)” for “section 309(a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/s306/a/1">Pub. L. 94–283, § 306(a)(1)</ref>, inserted provision that “candidate” shall not include any individual who has ceased actively to seek election to the office of President of the United States or to the office of Vice President of the United States, in more than one State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/s115/c/1">Pub. L. 94–283, § 115(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “309(a)(1)” for “310(a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s404/c/2">Pub. L. 93–443, § 404(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Commission” for “Comptroller General”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s404/c/1">Pub. L. 93–443, § 404(c)(1)</ref>, substituted definition of “Commission” for “Comptroller General”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (11). <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s404/c/3">Pub. L. 93–443, § 404(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “Commission” for “Comptroller General” in third sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id47a6d612-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id47a6d613-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/283/tIII/s306/c">Pub. L. 94–283, title III, § 306(c)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/501">90 Stat. 501</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/283/tIII/s306/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 9003, 9032, and 9033 of this title] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id47a6d614-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/443">Pub. L. 93–443</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s410/c/1">section 410(c)(1) of Pub. L. 93–443</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of Title 52</ref>, Voting and Elections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
