<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id47a6d64d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9006"><num value="9006">§ 9006.</num><heading> Payments to eligible candidates</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47a6d64e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9006/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of campaign fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established on the books of the Treasury of the United States a special fund to be known as the “Presidential Election Campaign Fund”. The Secretary of the Treasury shall, from time to time, transfer to the fund an amount not in excess of the sum of the amounts designated (subsequent to the previous Presidential election) to the fund by individuals under section 6096. There is appropriated to the fund for each fiscal year, out of amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, an amount equal to the amounts so designated during each fiscal year, which shall remain available to the fund without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47a6d64f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9006/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments from the fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receipt of a certification from the Commission under section 9005 for payment to the eligible candidates of a political party, the Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to such candidates out of the fund the amount certified by the Commission. Amounts paid to any such candidates shall be under the control of such candidates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47a6d650-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9006/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Insufficient amounts in fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If at the time of a certification by the Commission under section 9005 for payment to the eligible candidates of a political party, the Secretary determines that the moneys in the fund are not, or may not be, sufficient to satisfy the full entitlements of the eligible candidates of all political parties, he shall withhold from such payment such amount as he determines to be necessary to assure that the eligible candidates of each political party will receive their pro rata share of their full entitlement. Amounts withheld by reason of the preceding sentence shall be paid when the Secretary determines that there are sufficient moneys in the fund to pay such amounts, or portions thereof, to all eligible candidates from whom amounts have been withheld, but, if there are not sufficient moneys in the fund to satisfy the full entitlement of the eligible candidates of all political parties, the amounts so withheld shall be paid in such manner that the eligible candidates of each political party receive their pro rata share of their full entitlement. In any case in which the Secretary determines that there are insufficient moneys in the fund to make payments under subsection (b), section 9008(i)(2), and section 9037(b), moneys shall not be made available from any other source for the purpose of making such payments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id47a94651-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/92/178/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/567">85 Stat. 567</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/53/s6/b">Pub. L. 93–53, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/138">87 Stat. 138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/tIV">Pub. L. 93–443, title IV</ref>, §§ 403(a), 404(c)(8), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1291">88 Stat. 1291</ref>, 1292; <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 94–283, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/498">90 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1906(b)(13)(A), (B), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/172/s11/a/43">Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(43)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2488">121 Stat. 2488</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/94/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 113–94, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-04-03">Apr. 3, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1085">128 Stat. 1085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id47a94652-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id47a94653-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id47a94654-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/113/94">Pub. L. 113–94</ref> substituted “section 9008(i)(2),” for “section 9008(b)(3),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—<ref href="/us/pl/110/172">Pub. L. 110–172</ref>, which directed substitution of “Commission” for “Comptroller General” wherever appearing, could not be executed, because “Comptroller General” did not appear subsequent to amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s404/c/8">Pub. L. 93–443, § 404(c)(8)</ref>. See 1974 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> substituted “Secretary of the Treasury” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/283/s302/a">Pub. L. 94–283, § 302(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (b). Former subsec. (b), directing that moneys remaining in the fund after a Presidential election be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/283/s302/a">Pub. L. 94–283, § 302(a)</ref>, (b), redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and inserted provision that moneys not be made available from other sources for the purpose of making payments whenever the Secretary or his delegate determines that there are insufficient moneys in the fund to make payments under subsec. (b), section 9008(b)(3), and section 9037(b). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/283/s302/a">Pub. L. 94–283, § 302(a)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s403/a">Pub. L. 93–443, § 403(a)</ref>, substituted “from time to time” for “as provided by Appropriation Acts” and appropriated moneys for the Campaign Fund for each fiscal year out of the general fund of the Treasury.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s404/c/8">Pub. L. 93–443, § 404(c)(8)</ref>, substituted “Commission” for “Comptroller General” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/53">Pub. L. 93–53</ref> struck out second sentence requiring the Secretary to maintain in the fund (1) a separate account for the candidates of each major party, each minor party, and each new party for which a specific designation is made under section 6096 for payment into an account in the fund and (2) a general account for which no specific designation is made, and in the last sentences, substituted “transfer to the fund”, “Presidential”, and “to the fund by individuals under section 6096”, for “transfer to each account in the fund”, “presidential”, and “to such account by individuals under section 6096 for payment into such account of the fund”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/53">Pub. L. 93–53</ref> substituted “Presidential” for “presidential”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/53">Pub. L. 93–53</ref> substituted provisions for payment “out of the fund”, for such payment “out of the specific account in the fund” and struck out penultimate sentence limiting payments to eligible candidates from the account designated for them to the amounts in such account at the time of payment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/53">Pub. L. 93–53</ref> substituted provisions for payments to eligible candidates when there are insufficient amounts in the fund, for former provisions respecting transfers from general account to separate accounts to remedy insufficient moneys to satisfy any unpaid entitlement of the eligible candidates.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id47a94655-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id47a94656-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/443">Pub. L. 93–443</ref> applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s410/c/1">section 410(c)(1) of Pub. L. 93–443</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of Title 52</ref>, Voting and Elections.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id47a94657-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Additional Appropriations to Campaign Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/443/tIV/s403/b">Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 403(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1291">88 Stat. 1291</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/514/s2">“In addition to the amounts appropriated to the Presidential Election Campaign Fund established under section 9006 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [formerly I.R.C. 1954] (relating to payments to eligible candidates) by the last sentence of subsection (a) of such section (as amended by subsection (a) of this section), there is appropriated to such fund an amount equal to the sum of the amounts designated for payment under section 6096 of such Code (relating to designation by individuals to the Presidential Election Campaign Fund) before <date date="1975-01-01">January 1, 1975</date>, not otherwise taken into account under the provisions of such section 9006, as amended by this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Provision effective <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/443/s410/a">section 410(a) of Pub. L. 93–443</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s30101">section 30101 of Title 52</ref>, Voting and Elections.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id47a94658-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Designation to the Presidential Election Campaign Fund</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Designation made under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6096">section 6096 of this title</ref> (as in effect for taxable years beginning before <date date="1973-01-01">Jan. 1, 1973</date>) for the account of the candidates of any specified political party treated solely as a designation to the Presidential Election Campaign Fund, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/53/s6/d">section 6(d) of Pub. L. 93–53</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6096">section 6096 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
