<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id448ceb24-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961"><num value="961">§ 961.</num><heading> Adjustments to basis of stock in controlled foreign corporations and of other property</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id448ceb25-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Increase in basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the basis of a United States shareholder’s stock in a controlled foreign corporation, and the basis of property of a United States shareholder by reason of which he is considered under section 958(a)(2) as owning stock of a controlled foreign corporation, shall be increased by the amount required to be included in his gross income under section 951(a) with respect to such stock or with respect to such property, as the case may be, but only to the extent to which such amount was included in the gross income of such United States shareholder. In the case of a United States shareholder who has made an election under section 962 for the taxable year, the increase in basis provided by this subsection shall not exceed an amount equal to the amount of tax paid under this chapter with respect to the amounts required to be included in his gross income under section 951(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id448ceb26-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction in basis</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id448ceb27-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the adjusted basis of stock or other property with respect to which a United States shareholder or a United States person receives an amount which is excluded from gross income under section 959(a) shall be reduced by the amount so excluded. In the case of a United States shareholder who has made an election under section 962 for any prior taxable year, the reduction in basis provided by this paragraph shall not exceed an amount equal to the amount received which is excluded from gross income under section 959(a) after the application of section 962(d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id448ceb28-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount in excess of basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To the extent that an amount excluded from gross income under section 959(a) exceeds the adjusted basis of the stock or other property with respect to which it is received, the amount shall be treated as gain from the sale or exchange of property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id448ceb29-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis adjustments in stock held by foreign corporations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, if a United States shareholder is treated under section 958(a)(2) as owning stock in a controlled foreign corporation which is owned by another controlled foreign corporation, then adjustments similar to the adjustments provided by subsections (a) and (b) shall be made to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id448ceb2a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the basis of such stock, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id448ceb2b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the basis of stock in any other controlled foreign corporation by reason of which the United States shareholder is considered under section 958(a)(2) as owning the stock described in paragraph (1),</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">but only for the purposes of determining the amount included under section 951 in the gross income of such United States shareholder (or any other United States shareholder who acquires from any person any portion of the interest of such United States shareholder by reason of which such shareholder was treated as owning such stock, but only to the extent of such portion, and subject to such proof of identity of such interest as the Secretary may prescribe by regulations). The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to any stock to which a basis adjustment applies under subsection (a) or (b).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id448ceb2c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s961/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Basis in specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation reduced by nontaxed portion of dividend for purposes of determining loss</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a domestic corporation received a dividend from a specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation (as defined in section 245A) in any taxable year, solely for purposes of determining loss on any disposition of stock of such foreign corporation in such taxable year or any subsequent taxable year, the basis of such domestic corporation in such stock shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount of any deduction allowable to such domestic corporation under section 245A with respect to such stock except to the extent such basis was reduced under section 1059 by reason of a dividend for which such a deduction was allowable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id448ceb2d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/87/834/s12/a">Pub. L. 87–834, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1022">76 Stat. 1022</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/455/tXIX/s1906/b/13/A">Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1834">90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1112/b/1">Pub. L. 105–34, title XI, § 1112(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/969">111 Stat. 969</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s409/b">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 409(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2635">119 Stat. 2635</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s14102/b/1">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 14102(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2192">131 Stat. 2192</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id448ceb2e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id448ceb2f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id448ceb30-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/97">Pub. L. 115–97</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/135">Pub. L. 109–135</ref> amended heading and text of subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, if a United States shareholder is treated under section 958(a)(2) as owning any stock in a controlled foreign corporation which is actually owned by another controlled foreign corporation, adjustments similar to the adjustments provided by subsections (a) and (b) shall be made to the basis of such stock in the hands of such other controlled foreign corporation, but only for the purposes of determining the amount included under section 951 in the gross income of such United States shareholder (or any other United States shareholder who acquires from any person any portion of the interest of such United States shareholder by reason of which such shareholder was treated as owning such stock, but only to the extent of such portion, and subject to such proof of identity of such interest as the Secretary may prescribe by regulations).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsecs. (a), (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/455">Pub. L. 94–455</ref> struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id448ceb31-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id448ceb32-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2017 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s14102/b/2">Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 14102(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/2192">131 Stat. 2192</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/97/tI/s14102/b/2">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall apply to distributions made after <date date="2017-12-31">December 31, 2017</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id448ceb33-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2005 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s409/d">Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 409(d)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2636">119 Stat. 2636</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/135/tIV/s409/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 6038B, 6411, and 6601 of this title] shall take effect as if included in the provisions of the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 [<ref href="/us/pl/105/34">Pub. L. 105–34</ref>] to which they relate.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id448ceb34-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1112/b/2">Pub. L. 105–34, title XI, § 1112(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/969">111 Stat. 969</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/34/tXI/s1112/b/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply for purposes of determining inclusions for taxable years of United States shareholders beginning after <date date="1997-12-31">December 31, 1997</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id448ceb35-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Dual Resident Companies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Basis adjustments of this section not applicable in certain circumstances involving dual resident companies, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s6126">section 6126 of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1502">section 1502 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
