<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id47cf6c86-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816"><num value="9816">§ 9816.</num><heading> Preventing surprise medical bills</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c87-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Coverage of emergency services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c88-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a group health plan provides or covers any benefits with respect to services in an emergency department of a hospital or with respect to emergency services in an independent freestanding emergency department (as defined in paragraph (3)(D)), the plan shall cover emergency services (as defined in paragraph (3)(C))—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47cf6c89-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> without the need for any prior authorization determination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47cf6c8a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whether the health care provider furnishing such services is a participating provider or a participating emergency facility, as applicable, with respect to such services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47cf6c8b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> in a manner so that, if such services are provided to a participant or beneficiary by a nonparticipating provider or a nonparticipating emergency facility—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6c8c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such services will be provided without imposing any requirement under the plan for prior authorization of services or any limitation on coverage that is more restrictive than the requirements or limitations that apply to emergency services received from participating providers and participating emergency facilities with respect to such plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6c8d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the cost-sharing requirement is not greater than the requirement that would apply if such services were provided by a participating provider or a participating emergency facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6c8e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such cost-sharing requirement is calculated as if the total amount that would have been charged for such services by such participating provider or participating emergency facility were equal to the recognized amount (as defined in paragraph (3)(H)) for such services, plan, and year;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6c8f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> the group health plan—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6c90-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> not later than 30 calendar days after the bill for such services is transmitted by such provider or facility, sends to the provider or facility, as applicable, an initial payment or notice of denial of payment; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6c91-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> pays a total plan payment directly to such provider or facility, respectively (in accordance, if applicable, with the timing requirement described in subsection (c)(6)) that is, with application of any initial payment under subclause (I), equal to the amount by which the out-of-network rate (as defined in paragraph (3)(K)) for such services exceeds the cost-sharing amount for such services (as determined in accordance with clauses (ii) and (iii)) and year; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6c92-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any cost-sharing payments made by the participant or beneficiary with respect to such emergency services so furnished shall be counted toward any in-network deductible or out-of-pocket maximums applied under the plan (and such in-network deductible and out-of-pocket maximums shall be applied) in the same manner as if such cost-sharing payments were made with respect to emergency services furnished by a participating provider or a participating emergency facility; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47cf6c93-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> without regard to any other term or condition of such coverage (other than exclusion or coordination of benefits, or an affiliation or waiting period, permitted under section 2704 of the Public Health Service Act, including as incorporated pursuant to section 715 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and section 9815 of this Act, and other than applicable cost-sharing).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c94-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit process and regulations for qualifying payment amounts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c95-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit process</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c96-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Not later than <date date="2021-10-01">October 1, 2021</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Labor, shall establish through rulemaking a process, in accordance with clause (ii), under which group health plans are audited by the Secretary or applicable State authority to ensure that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6c97-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> such plans are in compliance with the requirement of applying a qualifying payment amount under this section; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6c98-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> such qualifying payment amount so applied satisfies the definition under paragraph (3)(E) with respect to the year involved, including with respect to a group health plan described in clause (ii) of such paragraph (3)(E).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c99-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit samples</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Under the process established pursuant to clause (i), the Secretary—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6c9a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> shall conduct audits described in such clause, with respect to a year (beginning with 2022), of a sample with respect to such year of claims data from not more than 25 group health plans; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6c9b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> may audit any group health plan if the Secretary has received any complaint or other information about such plan or coverage, respectively, that involves the compliance of the plan with either of the requirements described in subclauses (I) and (II) of such clause.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c9c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Beginning for 2022, the Secretary shall annually submit to Congress a report on the number of plans and issuers with respect to which audits were conducted during such year pursuant to this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6c9d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rulemaking</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than <date date="2021-07-01">July 1, 2021</date>, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish through rulemaking—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6c9e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the methodology the group health plan shall use to determine the qualifying payment amount, differentiating by large group market and small group market;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6c9f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the information such plan or issuer, respectively, shall share with the nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating facility, as applicable, when making such a determination;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6ca0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the geographic regions applied for purposes of this subparagraph, taking into account access to items and services in rural and underserved areas, including health professional shortage areas, as defined in section 332 of the Public Health Service Act; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6ca1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> a process to receive complaints of violations of the requirements described in subclauses (I) and (II) of subparagraph (A)(i) by group health plans.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">Such rulemaking shall take into account payments that are made by such plan that are not on a fee-for-service basis. Such methodology may account for relevant payment adjustments that take into account quality or facility type (including higher acuity settings and the case-mix of various facility types) that are otherwise taken into account for purposes of determining payment amounts with respect to participating facilities. In carrying out clause (iii), the Secretary shall consult with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to establish the geographic regions under such clause and shall periodically update such regions, as appropriate, taking into account the findings of the report submitted under section 109(a) of the No Surprises Act.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6ca2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subchapter:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6ca3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency department of a hospital</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “emergency department of a hospital” includes a hospital outpatient department that provides emergency services (as defined in subparagraph (C)(i)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6ca4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency medical condition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “emergency medical condition” means a medical condition manifesting itself by acute symptoms of sufficient severity (including severe pain) such that a prudent layperson, who possesses an average knowledge of health and medicine, could reasonably expect the absence of immediate medical attention to result in a condition described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of section 1867(e)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6ca5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency services</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6ca6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “emergency services”, with respect to an emergency medical condition, means—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6ca7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a medical screening examination (as required under section 1867 of the Social Security Act, or as would be required under such section if such section applied to an independent freestanding emergency department) that is within the capability of the emergency department of a hospital or of an independent freestanding emergency department, as applicable, including ancillary services routinely available to the emergency department to evaluate such emergency medical condition; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6ca8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> within the capabilities of the staff and facilities available at the hospital or the independent freestanding emergency department, as applicable, such further medical examination and treatment as are required under section 1867 of such Act, or as would be required under such section if such section applied to an independent freestanding emergency department, to stabilize the patient (regardless of the department of the hospital in which such further examination or treatment is furnished).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6ca9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion of additional services</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6caa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">For purposes of this subsection and section 2799B–1 of the Public Health Service Act, in the case of a participant or beneficiary who is enrolled in a group health plan and who is furnished services described in clause (i) with respect to an emergency medical condition, the term “emergency services” shall include, unless each of the conditions described in subclause (II) are met, in addition to the items and services described in clause (i), items and services—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47cf6cab-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> for which benefits are provided or covered under the plan; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47cf6cac-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> that are furnished by a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility (regardless of the department of the hospital in which such items or services are furnished) after the participant or beneficiary is stabilized and as part of outpatient observation or an inpatient or outpatient stay with respect to the visit in which the services described in clause (i) are furnished.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6cad-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">For purposes of subclause (I), the conditions described in this subclause, with respect to a participant or beneficiary who is stabilized and furnished additional items and services described in subclause (I) after such stabilization by a provider or facility described in subclause (I), are the following;</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47cf6cae-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> Such provider or facility determines such individual is able to travel using nonmedical transportation or nonemergency medical transportation.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47cf6caf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> Such provider furnishing such additional items and services satisfies the notice and consent criteria of section 2799B–2(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002367">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002367"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> with respect to such items and services.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47cf6cb0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/II/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> Such individual is in a condition to receive (as determined in accordance with guidelines issued by the Secretary pursuant to rulemaking) the information described in section 2799B–2 <sup>1</sup> and to provide informed consent under such section, in accordance with applicable State law.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47cf6cb1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/C/ii/II/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><content> Such other conditions, as specified by the Secretary, such as conditions relating to coordinating care transitions to participating providers and facilities.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6cb2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Independent freestanding emergency department</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “independent freestanding emergency department” means a health care facility that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6cb3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is geographically separate and distinct and licensed separately from a hospital under applicable State law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47cf6cb4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provides any of the emergency services (as defined in subparagraph (C)(i)).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6cb5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualifying payment amount</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47cf6cb6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “qualifying payment amount” means, subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), with respect to a sponsor of a group health plan—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6cb7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> for an item or service furnished during 2022, the median of the contracted rates recognized by the plan (determined with respect to all such plans of such sponsor that are offered within the same insurance market (specified in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of clause (iv)) as the plan) as the total maximum payment (including the cost-sharing amount imposed for such item or service and the amount to be paid by the plan) under such plans on <date date="2019-01-31">January 31, 2019</date> for the same or a similar item or service that is provided by a provider in the same or similar specialty and provided in the geographic region in which the item or service is furnished, consistent with the methodology established by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B), increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) over 2019, such percentage increase over 2020, and such percentage increase over 2021; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47cf6cb8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for an item or service furnished during 2023 or a subsequent year, the qualifying payment amount determined under this clause for such an item or service furnished in the previous year, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) over such previous year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcb9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> New plans and coverage</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “qualifying payment amount” means, with respect to a sponsor of a group health plan in a geographic region in which such sponsor, respectively, did not offer any group health plan or health insurance coverage during 2019—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcba-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> for the first year in which such group health plan is offered in such region, a rate (determined in accordance with a methodology established by the Secretary) for items and services that are covered by such plan and furnished during such first year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcbb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for each subsequent year such group health plan is offered in such region, the qualifying payment amount determined under this clause for such items and services furnished in the previous year, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) over such previous year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcbc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Insufficient information; newly covered items and services</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of a sponsor of a group health plan that does not have sufficient information to calculate the median of the contracted rates described in clause (i)(I) in 2019 (or, in the case of a newly covered item or service (as defined in clause (v)(III)), in the first coverage year (as defined in clause (v)(I)) for such item or service with respect to such plan) for an item or service (including with respect to provider type, or amount, of claims for items or services (as determined by the Secretary) provided in a particular geographic region (other than in a case with respect to which clause (ii) applies)) the term “qualifying payment amount”—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcbd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> for an item or service furnished during 2022 (or, in the case of a newly covered item or service, during the first coverage year for such item or service with respect to such plan), means such rate for such item or service determined by the sponsor through use of any database that is determined, in accordance with rulemaking described in paragraph (2)(B), to not have any conflicts of interest and to have sufficient information reflecting allowed amounts paid to a health care provider or facility for relevant services furnished in the applicable geographic region (such as a State all-payer claims database);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcbe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for an item or service furnished in a subsequent year (before the first sufficient information year (as defined in clause (v)(II)) for such item or service with respect to such plan), means the rate determined under subclause (I) or this subclause, as applicable, for such item or service for the year previous to such subsequent year, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) over such previous year;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcbf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> for an item or service furnished in the first sufficient information year for such item or service with respect to such plan, has the meaning given the term qualifying payment amount in clause (i)(I), except that in applying such clause to such item or service, the reference to “furnished during 2022” shall be treated as a reference to furnished during such first sufficient information year, the reference to “on <date date="2019-01-31">January 31, 2019</date>” shall be treated as a reference to in such sufficient information year, and the increase described in such clause shall not be applied; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcc0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> for an item or service furnished in any year subsequent to the first sufficient information year for such item or service with respect to such plan, has the meaning given such term in clause (i)(II), except that in applying such clause to such item or service, the reference to “furnished during 2023 or a subsequent year” shall be treated as a reference to furnished during the year after such first sufficient information year or a subsequent year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcc1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Insurance market</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i)(I), a health insurance market specified in this clause is one of the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcc2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The large group market (other than plans described in subclause (III)).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcc3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> The small group market (other than plans described in subclause (III)).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcc4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> In the case of a self-insured group health plan, other self-insured group health plans.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcc5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcc6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/v/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> First coverage year</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The term “first coverage year” means, with respect to a group health plan and an item or service for which coverage is not offered in 2019 under such plan or coverage, the first year after 2019 for which coverage for such item or service is offered under such plan.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcc7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/v/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> First sufficient information year</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The term “first sufficient information year” means, with respect to a group health plan—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47d1dcc8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/v/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> in the case of an item or service for which the plan does not have sufficient information to calculate the median of the contracted rates described in clause (i)(I) in 2019, the first year subsequent to 2022 for which such sponsor has such sufficient information to calculate the median of such contracted rates in the year previous to such first subsequent year; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id47d1dcc9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/v/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> in the case of a newly covered item or service, the first year subsequent to the first coverage year for such item or service with respect to such plan for which the sponsor has sufficient information to calculate the median of the contracted rates described in clause (i)(I) in the year previous to such first subsequent year.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcca-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/E/v/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Newly covered item or service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The term “newly covered item or service” means, with respect to a group health plan, an item or service for which coverage was not offered in 2019 under such plan or coverage, but is offered under such plan or coverage in a year after 2019.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dccb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonparticipating emergency facility; participating emergency facility</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dccc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/F/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonparticipating emergency facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “nonparticipating emergency facility” means, with respect to an item or service and a group health plan, an emergency department of a hospital, or an independent freestanding emergency department, that does not have a contractual relationship directly or indirectly with the plan for furnishing such item or service under the plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dccd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/F/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Participating emergency facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “participating emergency facility” means, with respect to an item or service and a group health plan, an emergency department of a hospital, or an independent freestanding emergency department, that has a contractual relationship directly or indirectly with the plan, with respect to the furnishing of such an item or service at such facility.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcce-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonparticipating providers; participating providers</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dccf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/G/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonparticipating provider</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “nonparticipating provider” means, with respect to an item or service and a group health plan, a physician or other health care provider who is acting within the scope of practice of that provider’s license or certification under applicable State law and who does not have a contractual relationship with the plan or issuer, respectively, for furnishing such item or service under the plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcd0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/G/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Participating provider</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “participating provider” means, with respect to an item or service and a group health plan, a physician or other health care provider who is acting within the scope of practice of that provider’s license or certification under applicable State law and who has a contractual relationship with the plan for furnishing such item or service under the plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcd1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/H"><num value="H" class="bold">(H)</num><heading class="bold"> Recognized amount</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “recognized amount” means, with respect to an item or service furnished by a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility during a year and a group health plan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcd2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subject to clause (iii), in the case of such item or service furnished in a State that has in effect a specified State law with respect to such plan; such a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility; and such an item or service, the amount determined in accordance with such law;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcd3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subject to clause (iii), in the case of such item or service furnished in a State that does not have in effect a specified State law, with respect to such plan; such a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility; and such an item or service, the amount that is the qualifying payment amount (as defined in subparagraph (E)) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002368">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002368"><num>2</num> Closing parentheses so in original.</note> for such year and determined in accordance with rulemaking described in paragraph (2)(B)) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002368">2</ref> for such item or service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcd4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/H/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in the case of such item or service furnished in a State with an All-Payer Model Agreement under section 1115A of the Social Security Act, the amount that the State approves under such system for such item or service so furnished.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcd5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Specified State law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “specified State law” means, with respect to a State, an item or service furnished by a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility during a year and a group health plan, a State law that provides for a method for determining the total amount payable under such a plan (to the extent such State law applies to such plan, subject to section 514 <sup>1</sup> ) in the case of a participant or beneficiary covered under such plan and receiving such item or service from such a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcd6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/J"><num value="J" class="bold">(J)</num><heading class="bold"> Stabilize</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “to stabilize”, with respect to an emergency medical condition (as defined in subparagraph (B)), has the meaning give <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002369">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002369"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “given”.</note> in section 1867(e)(3) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/3">42 U.S.C. 1395dd(e)(3)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcd7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/K"><num value="K" class="bold">(K)</num><heading class="bold"> Out-of-network rate</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “out-of-network rate” means, with respect to an item or service furnished in a State during a year to a participant or beneficiary of a group health plan receiving such item or service from a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcd8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/K/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> subject to clause (iii), in the case of such item or service furnished in a State that has in effect a specified State law with respect to such plan; such a nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility; and such an item or service, the amount determined in accordance with such law;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcd9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/K/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> subject to clause (iii), in the case such State does not have in effect such a law with respect to such item or service, plan, and provider or facility—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcda-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/K/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> subject to subclause (II), if the provider or facility (as applicable) and such plan or coverage agree on an amount of payment (including if such agreed on amount is the initial payment sent by the plan under subsection (a)(1)(C)(iv)(I), subsection (b)(1)(C), or section 9817(a)(3)(A), as applicable, or is agreed on through open negotiations under subsection (c)(1)) with respect to such item or service, such agreed on amount; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcdb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/K/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if such provider or facility (as applicable) and such plan or coverage enter the independent dispute resolution process under subsection (c) and do not so agree before the date on which a certified IDR entity (as defined in paragraph (4) of such subsection) makes a determination with respect to such item or service under such subsection, the amount of such determination; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcdc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/K/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in the case such State has an All-Payer Model Agreement under section 1115A of the Social Security Act, the amount that the State approves under such system for such item or service so furnished.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcdd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/a/3/L"><num value="L" class="bold">(L)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost-sharing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “cost-sharing” includes copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcde-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Coverage of non-emergency services performed by nonparticipating providers at certain participating facilities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcdf-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of items or services (other than emergency services to which subsection (a) applies) for which any benefits are provided or covered by a group health plan furnished to a participant or beneficiary of such plan by a nonparticipating provider (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(G)(i)) (and who, with respect to such items and services, has not satisfied the notice and consent criteria of section 2799B–2(d) of the Public Health Service Act) with respect to a visit (as defined by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2)(B)) at a participating health care facility (as defined in paragraph (2)(A)), with respect to such plan, the plan—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d1dce0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall not impose on such participant or beneficiary a cost-sharing requirement for such items and services so furnished that is greater than the cost-sharing requirement that would apply under such plan had such items or services been furnished by a participating provider (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(G)(ii));</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d1dce1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall calculate such cost-sharing requirement as if the total amount that would have been charged for such items and services by such participating provider were equal to the recognized amount (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(H)) for such items and services, plan, and year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d1dce2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> not later than 30 calendar days after the bill for such items or services is transmitted by such provider, shall send to the provider an initial payment or notice of denial of payment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d1dce3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> shall pay a total plan payment directly, in accordance, if applicable, with the timing requirement described in subsection (c)(6), to such provider furnishing such items and services to such participant or beneficiary that is, with application of any initial payment under subparagraph (C), equal to the amount by which the out-of-network rate (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(K)) for such items and services exceeds the cost-sharing amount imposed under the plan for such items and services (as determined in accordance with subparagraphs (A) and (B)) and year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d1dce4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> shall count toward any in-network deductible and in-network out-of-pocket maximums (as applicable) applied under the plan, any cost-sharing payments made by the participant or beneficiary (and such in-network deductible and out-of-pocket maximums shall be applied) with respect to such items and services so furnished in the same manner as if such cost-sharing payments were with respect to items and services furnished by a participating provider.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dce5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this section:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dce6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Participating health care facility</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dce7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “participating health care facility” means, with respect to an item or service and a group health plan, a health care facility described in clause (ii) that has a direct or indirect contractual relationship with the plan, with respect to the furnishing of such an item or service at the facility.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dce8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Health care facility described</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A health care facility described in this clause, with respect to a group health plan or health insurance coverage offered in the group or individual market, is each of the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dce9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> A hospital (as defined in 1861(e) of the Social Security Act).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcea-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> A hospital outpatient department.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dceb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> A critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of such Act).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dcec-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> An ambulatory surgical center described in section 1833(i)(1)(A) of such Act.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dced-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/A/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> Any other facility, specified by the Secretary, that provides items or services for which coverage is provided under the plan or coverage, respectively.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcee-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Visit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “visit” shall, with respect to items and services furnished to an individual at a health care facility, include equipment and devices, telemedicine services, imaging services, laboratory services, preoperative and postoperative services, and such other items and services as the Secretary may specify, regardless of whether or not the provider furnishing such items or services is at the facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcef-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of out-of-network rates to be paid by health plans; independent dispute resolution process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf0-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination through open negotiation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf1-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">With respect to an item or service furnished in a year by a nonparticipating provider or a nonparticipating facility, with respect to a group health plan, in a State described in subsection (a)(3)(K)(ii) with respect to such plan and provider or facility, and for which a payment is required to be made by the plan pursuant to subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1), the provider or facility (as applicable) or plan may, during the 30-day period beginning on the day the provider or facility receives an initial payment or a notice of denial of payment from the plan regarding a claim for payment for such item or service, initiate open negotiations under this paragraph between such provider or facility and plan for purposes of determining, during the open negotiation period, an amount agreed on by such provider or facility, respectively, and such plan for payment (including any cost-sharing) for such item or service. For purposes of this subsection, the open negotiation period, with respect to an item or service, is the 30-day period beginning on the date of initiation of the negotiations with respect to such item or service.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf2-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Accessing independent dispute resolution process in case of failed negotiations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of open negotiations pursuant to subparagraph (A), with respect to an item or service, that do not result in a determination of an amount of payment for such item or service by the last day of the open negotiation period described in such subparagraph with respect to such item or service, the provider or facility (as applicable) or group health plan that was party to such negotiations may, during the 4-day period beginning on the day after such open negotiation period, initiate the independent dispute resolution process under paragraph (2) with respect to such item or service. The independent dispute resolution process shall be initiated by a party pursuant to the previous sentence by submission to the other party and to the Secretary of a notification (containing such information as specified by the Secretary) and for purposes of this subsection, the date of initiation of such process shall be the date of such submission or such other date specified by the Secretary pursuant to regulations that is not later than the date of receipt of such notification by both the other party and the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf3-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Independent dispute resolution process available in case of failed open negotiations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf4-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Labor, shall establish by regulation one independent dispute resolution process (referred to in this subsection as the “IDR process”) under which, in the case of an item or service with respect to which a provider or facility (as applicable) or group health plan submits a notification under paragraph (1)(B) (in this subsection referred to as a “qualified IDR item or service”), a certified IDR entity under paragraph (4) determines, subject to subparagraph (B) and in accordance with the succeeding provisions of this subsection, the amount of payment under the plan for such item or service furnished by such provider or facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf5-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to continue negotiations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Under the independent dispute resolution process, in the case that the parties to a determination for a qualified IDR item or service agree on a payment amount for such item or service during such process but before the date on which the entity selected with respect to such determination under paragraph (4) makes such determination under paragraph (5), such amount shall be treated for purposes of subsection (a)(3)(K)(ii) as the amount agreed to by such parties for such item or service. In the case of an agreement described in the previous sentence, the independent dispute resolution process shall provide for a method to determine how to allocate between the parties to such determination the payment of the compensation of the entity selected with respect to such determination.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf6-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Clarification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A nonparticipating provider may not, with respect to an item or service furnished by such provider, submit a notification under paragraph (1)(B) if such provider is exempt from the requirement under subsection (a) of section 2799B–2 of the Public Health Service Act with respect to such item or service pursuant to subsection (b) of such section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf7-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of batching of items and services</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcf8-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Under the IDR process, the Secretary shall specify criteria under which multiple qualified IDR dispute items and services are permitted to be considered jointly as part of a single determination by an entity for purposes of encouraging the efficiency (including minimizing costs) of the IDR process. Such items and services may be so considered only if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcf9-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such items and services to be included in such determination are furnished by the same provider or facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcfa-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> payment for such items and services is required to be made by the same group health plan or health insurance issuer;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcfb-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such items and services are related to the treatment of a similar condition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dcfc-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> such items and services were furnished during the 30 day <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002370">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002370"><num>4</num> So in original. Probably should be “30-day”.</note> period following the date on which the first item or service included with respect to such determination was furnished or an alternative period as determined by the Secretary, for use in limited situations, such as by the consent of the parties or in the case of low-volume items and services, to encourage procedural efficiency and minimize health plan and provider administrative costs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcfd-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of bundled payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide that, in the case of items and services which are included by a provider or facility as part of a bundled payment, such items and services included in such bundled payment may be part of a single determination under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcfe-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification and selection of IDR entities</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dcff-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Labor, shall establish a process to certify (including to recertify) entities under this paragraph. Such process shall ensure that an entity so certified—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd00-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has (directly or through contracts or other arrangements) sufficient medical, legal, and other expertise and sufficient staffing to make determinations described in paragraph (5) on a timely basis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd01-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> is not—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd02-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> a group health plan, provider, or facility;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd03-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an affiliate or a subsidiary of such a group health plan, provider, or facility; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd04-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> an affiliate or subsidiary of a professional or trade association of such group health plans or of providers or facilities;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd05-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> carries out the responsibilities of such an entity in accordance with this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd06-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> meets appropriate indicators of fiscal integrity;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd07-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> maintains the confidentiality (in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary) of individually identifiable health information obtained in the course of conducting such determinations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd08-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> does not under the IDR process carry out any determination with respect to which the entity would not pursuant to subclause (I), (II), or (III) of subparagraph (F)(i) be eligible for selection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd09-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> meets such other requirements as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd0a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Period of certification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), each certification (including a recertification) of an entity under the process described in subparagraph (A) shall be for a 5-year period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd0b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Revocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A certification of an entity under this paragraph may be revoked under the process described in subparagraph (A) if the entity has a pattern or practice of noncompliance with any of the requirements described in such subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd0c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Petition for denial or withdrawal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The process described in subparagraph (A) shall ensure that an individual, provider, facility, or group health plan may petition for a denial of a certification or a revocation of a certification with respect to an entity under this paragraph for failure of meeting a requirement of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd0d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Sufficient number of entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The process described in subparagraph (A) shall ensure that a sufficient number of entities are certified under this paragraph to ensure the timely and efficient provision of determinations described in paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd0e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of certified IDR entity</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall, with respect to the determination of the amount of payment under this subsection of an item or service, provide for a method—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd0f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> that allows for the group health plan and the nonparticipating provider or the nonparticipating emergency facility (as applicable) involved in a notification under paragraph (1)(B) to jointly select, not later than the last day of the 3-business day period following the date of the initiation of the process with respect to such item or service, for purposes of making such determination, an entity certified under this paragraph that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd10-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is not a party to such determination or an employee or agent of such a party;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd11-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> does not have a material familial, financial, or professional relationship with such a party; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd12-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> does not otherwise have a conflict of interest with such a party (as determined by the Secretary); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd13-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> that requires, in the case such parties do not make such selection by such last day, the Secretary to, not later than 6 business days after such date of initiation—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd14-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> select such an entity that satisfies subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (i)); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd15-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/4/F/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> provide notification of such selection to the provider or facility (as applicable) and the plan or issuer (as applicable) party to such determination.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">An entity selected pursuant to the previous sentence to make a determination described in such sentence shall be referred to in this subsection as the “certified IDR entity” with respect to such determination.</continuation>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd16-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment determination</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd17-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after the date of selection of the certified IDR entity with respect to a determination for a qualified IDR item or service, the certified IDR entity shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd18-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> taking into account the considerations specified in subparagraph (C), select one of the offers submitted under subparagraph (B) to be the amount of payment for such item or service determined under this subsection for purposes of subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1), as applicable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd19-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> notify the provider or facility and the group health plan party to such determination of the offer selected under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd1a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of offers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 10 days after the date of selection of the certifed IDR entity with respect to a determination for a qualified IDR item or service, the provider or facility and the group health plan party to such determination—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd1b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> shall each submit to the certified IDR entity with respect to such determination—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd1c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> an offer for a payment amount for such item or service furnished by such provider or facility; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd1d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> such information as requested by the certified IDR entity relating to such offer; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd1e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may each submit to the certified IDR entity with respect to such determination any information relating to such offer submitted by either party, including information relating to any circumstance described in subparagraph (C)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd1f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations in determination</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd20-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In determining which offer is the payment to be applied pursuant to this paragraph, the certified IDR entity, with respect to the determination for a qualified IDR item or service shall consider—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd21-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the qualifying payment amounts (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(E)) for the applicable year for items or services that are comparable to the qualified IDR item or service and that are furnished in the same geographic region (as defined by the Secretary for purposes of such subsection) as such qualified IDR item or service; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd22-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> subject to subparagraph (D), information on any circumstance described in clause (ii), such information as requested in subparagraph (B)(i)(II), and any additional information provided in subparagraph (B)(ii).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd23-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional circumstances</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i)(II), the circumstances described in this clause are, with respect to a qualified IDR item or service of a nonparticipating provider, nonparticipating emergency facility, or group health plan, the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd24-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The level of training, experience, and quality and outcomes measurements of the provider or facility that furnished such item or service (such as those endorsed by the consensus-based entity authorized in section 1890 of the Social Security Act).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd25-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> The market share held by the nonparticipating provider or facility or that of the plan or issuer in the geographic region in which the item or service was provided.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd26-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> The acuity of the individual receiving such item or service or the complexity of furnishing such item or service to such individual.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd27-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> The teaching status, case mix, and scope of services of the nonparticipating facility that furnished such item or service.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd28-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/C/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> Demonstrations of good faith efforts (or lack of good faith efforts) made by the nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating facility or the plan or issuer to enter into network agreements and, if applicable, contracted rates between the provider or facility, as applicable, and the plan or issuer, as applicable, during the previous 4 plan years.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd29-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on consideration of certain factors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In determining which offer is the payment to be applied with respect to qualified IDR items and services furnished by a provider or facility, the certified IDR entity with respect to a determination shall not consider usual and customary charges, the amount that would have been billed by such provider or facility with respect to such items and services had the provisions of section 2799B–1 of the Public Health Service Act or 2799B–2 of such Act (as applicable) not applied, or the payment or reimbursement rate for such items and services furnished by such provider or facility payable by a public payor, including under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act, under the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act, under the Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of such Act, under the TRICARE program under chapter 55 of title 10, United States Code, or under chapter 17 of title 38, United States Code.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd2a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Effects of determination</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd2b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A determination of a certified IDR entity under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd2c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/E/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> shall be binding upon the parties involved, in the absence of a fraudulent claim or evidence of misrepresentation of facts presented to the IDR entity involved regarding such claim; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id47d1dd2d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/E/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> shall not be subject to judicial review, except in a case described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t9/s10/a">section 10(a) of title 9</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd2e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of certain subsequent IDR requests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of a determination of a certified IDR entity under subparagraph (A), with respect to an initial notification submitted under paragraph (1)(B) with respect to qualified IDR items and services and the two parties involved with such notification, the party that submitted such notification may not submit during the 90-day period following such determination a subsequent notification under such paragraph involving the same other party to such notification with respect to such an item or service that was the subject of such initial notification.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd2f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/E/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Subsequent submission of requests permitted</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of a notification that pursuant to clause (ii) is not permitted to be submitted under paragraph (1)(B) during a 90-day period specified in such clause, if the end of the open negotiation period specified in paragraph (1)(A), that but for this clause would otherwise apply with respect to such notification, occurs during such 90-day period, such paragraph (1)(B) shall be applied as if the reference in such paragraph to the 4-day period beginning on the day after such open negotiation period were instead a reference to the 30-day period beginning on the day after the last day of such 90-day period.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd30-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/E/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of the Health and Human Services, shall examine the impact of the application of clause (ii) and whether the application of such clause delays payment determinations or impacts early, alternative resolution of claims (such as through open negotiations), and shall submit to Congress, not later than 2 years after the date of implementation of such clause an interim report (and not later than 4 years after such date of implementation, a final report) on whether any group health plans or health insurance issuers offering group or individual health insurance coverage or types of such plans or coverage have a pattern or practice of routine denial, low payment, or down-coding of claims, or otherwise abuse the 90-day period described in such clause, including recommendations on ways to discourage such a pattern or practice.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d1dd31-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs of independent dispute resolution process</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a notification under paragraph (1)(B) submitted by a nonparticipating provider, nonparticipating emergency facility, or group health plan and submitted to a certified IDR entity—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd32-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> if such entity makes a determination with respect to such notification under subparagraph (A), the party whose offer is not chosen under such subparagraph shall be responsible for paying all fees charged by such entity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d1dd33-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/5/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the parties reach a settlement with respect to such notification prior to such a determination, each party shall pay half of all fees charged by such entity, unless the parties otherwise agree.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42724-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing of payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The total plan payment required pursuant to subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1), with respect to a qualified IDR item or service for which a determination is made under paragraph (5)(A) or with respect to an item or service for which a payment amount is determined under open negotiations under paragraph (1), shall be made directly to the nonparticipating provider or facility not later than 30 days after the date on which such determination is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42725-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of information relating to the IDR process</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42726-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For each calendar quarter in 2022 and each calendar quarter in a subsequent year, the Secretary shall make available on the public website of the Department of the Treasury—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42727-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the number of notifications submitted under paragraph (1)(B) during such calendar quarter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42728-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the size of the provider practices and the size of the facilities submitting notifications under paragraph (1)(B) during such calendar quarter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42729-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the number of such notifications with respect to which a determination was made under paragraph (5)(A);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d4272a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the information described in subparagraph (B) with respect to each notification with respect to which such a determination was so made;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d4272b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the number of times the payment amount determined (or agreed to) under this subsection exceeds the qualifying payment amount, specified by items and services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d4272c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the amount of expenditures made by the Secretary during such calendar quarter to carry out the IDR process;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d4272d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> the total amount of fees paid under paragraph (8) during such calendar quarter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d4272e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/A/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> the total amount of compensation paid to certified IDR entities under paragraph (5)(F) during such calendar quarter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d4272f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the information described in this subparagraph is, with respect to a notification under paragraph (1)(B) by a nonparticipating provider, nonparticipating emergency facility, or group health plan—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42730-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a description of each item and service included with respect to such notification;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42731-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the geography in which the items and services with respect to such notification were provided;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42732-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the amount of the offer submitted under paragraph (5)(B) by the group health plan and by the nonparticipating provider or nonparticipating emergency facility (as applicable) expressed as a percentage of the qualifying payment amount;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42733-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> whether the offer selected by the certified IDR entity under paragraph (5) to be the payment applied was the offer submitted by such plan or by such provider or facility (as applicable) and the amount of such offer so selected expressed as a percentage of the qualifying payment amount;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42734-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the category and practice specialty of each such provider or facility involved in furnishing such items and services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42735-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the identity of the group health plan, provider, or facility, with respect to the notification;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42736-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> the length of time in making each determination;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42737-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> the compensation paid to the certified IDR entity with respect to the settlement or determination; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42738-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/B/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> any other information specified by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42739-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> IDR entity requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For 2022 and each subsequent year, an IDR entity, as a condition of certification as an IDR entity, shall submit to the Secretary such information as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d4273a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/7/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Clarification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall ensure the public reporting under this paragraph does not contain information that would disclose privileged or confidential information of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage or of a provider or facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d4273b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative fee</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d4273c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each party to a determination under paragraph (5) to which an entity is selected under paragraph (3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002371">5</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002371"><num>5</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (4)”.</note> in a year shall pay to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as specified by the Secretary, a fee for participating in the IDR process with respect to such determination in an amount described in subparagraph (B) for such year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d4273d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of fee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount described in this subparagraph for a year is an amount established by the Secretary in a manner such that the total amount of fees paid under this paragraph for such year is estimated to be equal to the amount of expenditures estimated to be made by the Secretary for such year in carrying out the IDR process.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d4273e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/c/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may modify any deadline or other timing requirement specified under this subsection (other than the establishment date for the IDR process under paragraph (2)(A) and other than under paragraph (6)) in cases of extenuating circumstances, as specified by the Secretary, or to ensure that all claims that occur during a 90-day period described in paragraph (5)(E)(ii), but with respect to which a notification is not permitted by reason of such paragraph to be submitted under paragraph (1)(B) during such period, are eligible for the IDR process.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47d4273f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain access fees to certain databases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a sponsor of a group health plan that, pursuant to subsection (a)(3)(E)(iii), uses a database described in such subsection to determine a rate to apply under such subsection for an item or service by reason of having insufficient information described in such subsection with respect to such item or service, such sponsor shall cover the cost for access to such database.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42740-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Transparency regarding in-network and out-of-network deductibles and out-of-pocket limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A group health plan providing or covering any benefit with respect to items or services shall include, in clear writing, on any physical or electronic plan or insurance identification card issued to the participants or beneficiaries in the plan the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47d42741-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any deductible applicable to such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47d42742-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any out-of-pocket maximum limitation applicable to such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id47d42743-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A telephone number and Internet website address through which such individual may seek consumer assistance information, such as information related to hospitals and urgent care facilities that have in effect a contractual relationship with such plan for furnishing items and services under such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42744-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Advanced explanation of benefits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42745-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For plan years beginning on or after <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>, each group health plan shall, with respect to a notification submitted under section 2799B–6 of the Public Health Service Act by a health care provider or health care facility to the plan for a participant or beneficiary under plan scheduled to receive an item or service from the provider or facility (or authorized representative of such participant or beneficiary), not later than 1 business day (or, in the case such item or service was so scheduled at least 10 business days before such item or service is to be furnished (or in the case of a request made to such plan or coverage by such participant or beneficiary), 3 business days) after the date on which the plan receives such notification (or such request), provide to the participant or beneficiary (through mail or electronic means, as requested by the participant or beneficiary) a notification (in clear and understandable language) including the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d42746-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Whether or not the provider or facility is a participating provider or a participating facility with respect to the plan with respect to the furnishing of such item or service and—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42747-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case the provider or facility is a participating provider or facility with respect to the plan or coverage with respect to the furnishing of such item or service, the contracted rate under such plan for such item or service (based on the billing and diagnostic codes provided by such provider or facility); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id47d42748-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case the provider or facility is a nonparticipating provider or facility with respect to such plan, a description of how such individual may obtain information on providers and facilities that, with respect to such plan, are participating providers and facilities, if any.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d42749-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The good faith estimate included in the notification received from the provider or facility (if applicable) based on such codes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d4274a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A good faith estimate of the amount the plan is responsible for paying for items and services included in the estimate described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d4274b-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A good faith estimate of the amount of any cost-sharing for which the participant or beneficiary would be responsible for such item or service (as of the date of such notification).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d4274c-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A good faith estimate of the amount that the participant or beneficiary has incurred toward meeting the limit of the financial responsibility (including with respect to deductibles and out-of-pocket maximums) under the plan (as of the date of such notification).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d4274d-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> In the case such item or service is subject to a medical management technique (including concurrent review, prior authorization, and step-therapy or fail-first protocols) for coverage under the plan, a disclaimer that coverage for such item or service is subject to such medical management technique.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d4274e-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> A disclaimer that the information provided in the notification is only an estimate based on the items and services reasonably expected, at the time of scheduling (or requesting) the item or service, to be furnished and is subject to change.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id47d4274f-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Any other information or disclaimer the plan determines appropriate that is consistent with information and disclaimers required under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42750-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to modify timing requirements in the case of specified items and services</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42751-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a participant or beneficiary scheduled to receive an item or service that is a specified item or service (as defined in subparagraph (B)), the Secretary may modify any timing requirements relating to the provision of the notification described in paragraph (1) to such participant or beneficiary with respect to such item or service. Any modification made by the Secretary pursuant to the previous sentence may not result in the provision of such notification after such participant or beneficiary has been furnished such item or service.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id47d42752-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a" identifier="/us/usc/t26/s9816/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Specified item or service defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “specified item or service” means an item or service that has low utilization or significant variation in costs (such as when furnished as part of a complex treatment), as specified by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id47d42753-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tI">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title I</ref>, §§ 102(c)(1), 103(c), 107(c), 111(b), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2784">134 Stat. 2784</ref>, 2815, 2859, 2863.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id47d42754-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id47d42755-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id47d42756-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2704 of the Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(D), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–3">section 300gg–3 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 715 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(D), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1185d">section 1185d of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 9815 of this Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(D), is section 9815 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s9815">section 9815 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 332 of the Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(B)(iii), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254e">section 254e of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 109(a) of the No Surprises Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s109/a">section 109(a) of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, div. BB, title I, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2859">134 Stat. 2859</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3)(B), (C)(i), (H)(iii), (K)(iii), (b)(2)(A)(ii), and (c)(5)(C)(ii)(I), (D), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Titles XVIII, XIX, and XXI of the Act are classified generally to subchapters XVIII (§ 1395 et seq.), XIX (§ 1396 et seq.), and XXI (§ 1397aa et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Sections 1115A, 1833, 1861, 1867, and 1890 are classified to sections 1315a, 1395<i>l</i>, 1395x, 1395dd, and 1395aaa, respectively, of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2799B–1 of the Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3)(C)(ii)(I) and (c)(5)(D), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–131">section 300gg–131 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2799B–2 of the Public Health Service Act, cited also as “section 2799B–2”, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3)(C)(ii)(II)(bb), (cc), (b)(1), and (c)(2)(C), (5)(D), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–132">section 300gg–132 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 514, referred to in subsec. (a)(3)(I), probably means section 514 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, which relates to application of State laws and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1144">section 1144 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of this subsection, referred to in subsec. (c)(2)(A), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, which was approved <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2799B–6 of the Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (f)(1), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–136">section 300gg–136 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id47d42757-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s103/c">Pub. L. 116–260, § 103(c)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s107/c">Pub. L. 116–260, § 107(c)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s111/b">Pub. L. 116–260, § 111(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id47d42758-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id47d42759-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tI/s107/d">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2859">134 Stat. 2859</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tI/s107/d">“The amendments made by this subsection [probably means “this section”, amending this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1185e">section 1185e of Title 29</ref>, Labor, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300gg–111">section 300gg–111 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare] shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id47d4275a-3a70-11f1-a967-d35dac11796a"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable with respect to plan years beginning on or after <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/s102/e">section 102(e) of div. BB of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2020 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8902">section 8902 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
