<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf3ba719f-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s105"><num value="105">§ 105.</num><heading> Inventions in outer space</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3ba71a0-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s105/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any invention made, used or sold in outer space on a space object or component thereof under the jurisdiction or control of the United States shall be considered to be made, used or sold within the United States for the purposes of this title, except with respect to any space object or component thereof that is specifically identified and otherwise provided for by an international agreement to which the United States is a party, or with respect to any space object or component thereof that is carried on the registry of a foreign state in accordance with the Convention on Registration of Objects Launched into Outer Space.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3ba71a1-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s105/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any invention made, used or sold in outer space on a space object or component thereof that is carried on the registry of a foreign state in accordance with the Convention on Registration of Objects Launched into Outer Space, shall be considered to be made, used or sold within the United States for the purposes of this title if specifically so agreed in an international agreement between the United States and the state of registry.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf3ba71a2-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/580/s1/a">Pub. L. 101–580, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2863">104 Stat. 2863</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf3ba71a3-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf3ba71a4-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idf3ba71a5-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Special Rules</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/580/s2">Pub. L. 101–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2863">104 Stat. 2863</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/580/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, the amendments made by the first section of this Act [enacting this section] shall apply to all United States patents granted before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>], and to all applications for United States patents pending on or filed on or after such date of enactment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final Decisions</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by the first section of this Act [enacting this section] shall not affect any final decision made by a court or the Patent and Trademark Office before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>] with respect to a patent or an application for a patent, if no appeal from such decision is pending and the time for filing an appeal has expired.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pending Cases</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by the first section of this Act [enacting this section] shall not affect the right of any party in any case pending in a court on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>] to have the party’s rights determined on the basis of the substantive law in effect before such date of enactment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by the first section of this Act [enacting this section] shall not apply to any process, machine, article of manufacture, or composition of matter, an embodiment of which was launched prior to the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
