<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf3bf2c42-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s120"><num value="120">§ 120.</num><heading> Benefit of earlier filing date in the United States</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An application for patent for an invention disclosed in the manner provided by section 112(a) (other than the requirement to disclose the best mode) in an application previously filed in the United States, or as provided by section 363 or 385, which names an inventor or joint inventor in the previously filed application shall have the same effect, as to such invention, as though filed on the date of the prior application, if filed before the patenting or abandonment of or termination of proceedings on the first application or on an application similarly entitled to the benefit of the filing date of the first application and if it contains or is amended to contain a specific reference to the earlier filed application. No application shall be entitled to the benefit of an earlier filed application under this section unless an amendment containing the specific reference to the earlier filed application is submitted at such time during the pendency of the application as required by the Director. The Director may consider the failure to submit such an amendment within that time period as a waiver of any benefit under this section. The Director may establish procedures, including the requirement for payment of the fee specified in section 41(a)(7), to accept an unintentionally delayed submission of an amendment under this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idf3bf2c43-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-07-19/ch950">July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/800">66 Stat. 800</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/131/s9">Pub. L. 94–131, § 9</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/691">89 Stat. 691</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/622/tI/s104/b">Pub. L. 98–622, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3385">98 Stat. 3385</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4503/b/1">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4503(b)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–563; <ref href="/us/pl/112/29">Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 3(f), 15(b), 20(j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/288">125 Stat. 288</ref>, 328, 335; <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/tI/s102/5">Pub. L. 112–211, title I, § 102(5)</ref>, title II, § 202(b)(3), <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1531">126 Stat. 1531</ref>, 1536.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf3bf2c44-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idf3bf2c45-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section represents present law not expressed in the statute, except for the added requirement that the first application must be specifically mentioned in the second.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf3bf2c46-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf3bf2c47-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s202/b/3">Pub. L. 112–211, § 202(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “including the requirement for payment of the fee specified in section 41(a)(7)” for “including the payment of a surcharge”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s102/5">Pub. L. 112–211, § 102(5)</ref>, substituted “section 363 or 385” for “section 363”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, struck out “of this title” after “363”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s15/b">Pub. L. 112–29, § 15(b)</ref>, substituted “section 112(a) (other than the requirement to disclose the best mode)” for “the first paragraph of <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s112">section 112 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/f">Pub. L. 112–29, § 3(f)</ref>, substituted “which names an inventor or joint inventor” for “which is filed by an inventor or inventors named”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> inserted at end “No application shall be entitled to the benefit of an earlier filed application under this section unless an amendment containing the specific reference to the earlier filed application is submitted at such time during the pendency of the application as required by the Director. The Director may consider the failure to submit such an amendment within that time period as a waiver of any benefit under this section. The Director may establish procedures, including the payment of a surcharge, to accept an unintentionally delayed submission of an amendment under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/622">Pub. L. 98–622</ref> substituted “which is filed by an inventor or inventors named in the previously filed application” for “by the same inventor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—<ref href="/us/pl/94/131">Pub. L. 94–131</ref> inserted “, or as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s363">section 363 of this title</ref>,” after “filed in the United States”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf3bf2c48-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3bf2c49-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s102/5">section 102(5) of Pub. L. 112–211</ref> effective on the later of the date that is 1 year after <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, or the date that the Geneva Act of the Hague Agreement Concerning the International Registration of Industrial Designs enters into force with respect to the United States (<date date="2015-05-13">May 13, 2015</date>), and applicable only to certain applications filed on and after that effective date and patents issuing thereon, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s103">section 103 of Pub. L. 112–211</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s100">section 100 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s202/b/3">section 202(b)(3) of Pub. L. 112–211</ref> effective on the date that is 1 year after <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, applicable to patents issued before, on, or after that effective date and patent applications pending on or filed after that effective date, and not effective with respect to patents in litigation commenced before that effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 112–211</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s27">section 27 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3bf2c4a-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/f">section 3(f) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref> effective upon the expiration of the 18-month period beginning on <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, and applicable to certain applications for patent and any patents issuing thereon, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/n">section 3(n) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2011 Amendment; Savings Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s100">section 100 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s15/b">section 15(b) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref> effective on <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, and applicable to proceedings commenced on or after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s15/c">section 15(c) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s119">section 119 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">section 20(j) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref> effective upon the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, and applicable to proceedings commenced on or after that effective date, see section 20(<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/29">Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3bf2c4b-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> effective <date date="2000-11-29">Nov. 29, 2000</date>, and applicable only to applications (including international applications designating the United States) filed on or after that date, see section 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4508] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s10">section 10 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3bf2c4c-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/622">Pub. L. 98–622</ref> applicable to all United States patents granted before, on, or after <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, and to all applications for United States patents pending on or filed after that date, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/622/s106">section 106 of Pub. L. 98–622</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s103">section 103 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3bf2c4d-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/131">Pub. L. 94–131</ref> effective <date date="1978-01-24">Jan. 24, 1978</date>, and applicable on and after that date to patent applications filed in the United States and to international applications, where applicable, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/131/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 94–131</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s351">section 351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
