<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf3c6583d-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154"><num value="154">§ 154.</num><heading> Contents and term of patent; provisional rights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3c6583e-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c6583f-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><content>Every patent shall contain a short title of the invention and a grant to the patentee, his heirs or assigns, of the right to exclude others from making, using, offering for sale, or selling the invention throughout the United States or importing the invention into the United States, and, if the invention is a process, of the right to exclude others from using, offering for sale or selling throughout the United States, or importing into the United States, products made by that process, referring to the specification for the particulars thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65840-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the payment of fees under this title, such grant shall be for a term beginning on the date on which the patent issues and ending 20 years from the date on which the application for the patent was filed in the United States or, if the application contains a specific reference to an earlier filed application or applications under section 120, 121, 365(c), or 386(c), from the date on which the earliest such application was filed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65841-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading><content>Priority under section 119, 365(a), 365(b), 386(a), or 386(b) shall not be taken into account in determining the term of a patent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65842-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specification and drawing</inline>.—</heading><content>A copy of the specification and drawing shall be annexed to the patent and be a part of such patent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3c65843-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment of Patent Term.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65844-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Patent term guarantees.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65845-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guarantee of prompt patent and trademark office responses</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to the limitations under paragraph (2), if the issue of an original patent is delayed due to the failure of the Patent and Trademark Office to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c65846-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> provide at least one of the notifications under section 132 or a notice of allowance under section 151 not later than 14 months after—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf3c65847-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the date on which an application was filed under section 111(a); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf3c65848-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the date of commencement of the national stage under section 371 in an international application;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c65849-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> respond to a reply under section 132, or to an appeal taken under section 134, within 4 months after the date on which the reply was filed or the appeal was taken;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6584a-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> act on an application within 4 months after the date of a decision by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board under section 134 or 135 or a decision by a Federal court under section 141, 145, or 146 in a case in which allowable claims remain in the application; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6584b-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> issue a patent within 4 months after the date on which the issue fee was paid under section 151 and all outstanding requirements were satisfied,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">the term of the patent shall be extended 1 day for each day after the end of the period specified in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv), as the case may be, until the action described in such clause is taken.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c6584c-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guarantee of no more than 3-year application pendency</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to the limitations under paragraph (2), if the issue of an original patent is delayed due to the failure of the United States Patent and Trademark Office to issue a patent within 3 years after the actual filing date of the application under section 111(a) in the United States or, in the case of an international application, the date of commencement of the national stage under section 371 in the international application, not including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6584d-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any time consumed by continued examination of the application requested by the applicant under section 132(b);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6584e-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any time consumed by a proceeding under section 135(a), any time consumed by the imposition of an order under section 181, or any time consumed by appellate review by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board or by a Federal court; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6584f-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any delay in the processing of the application by the United States Patent and Trademark Office requested by the applicant except as permitted by paragraph (3)(C),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">the term of the patent shall be extended 1 day for each day after the end of that 3-year period until the patent is issued.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65850-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guarantee of adjustments for delays due to derivation proceedings, secrecy orders, and appeals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to the limitations under paragraph (2), if the issue of an original patent is delayed due to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c65851-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a proceeding under section 135(a);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c65852-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the imposition of an order under section 181; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c65853-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> appellate review by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board or by a Federal court in a case in which the patent was issued under a decision in the review reversing an adverse determination of patentability,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">the term of the patent shall be extended 1 day for each day of the pendency of the proceeding, order, or review, as the case may be.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65854-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65855-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent that periods of delay attributable to grounds specified in paragraph (1) overlap, the period of any adjustment granted under this subsection shall not exceed the actual number of days the issuance of the patent was delayed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65856-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disclaimed term</inline>.—</heading><content>No patent the term of which has been disclaimed beyond a specified date may be adjusted under this section beyond the expiration date specified in the disclaimer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65857-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reduction of period of adjustment.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c65858-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The period of adjustment of the term of a patent under paragraph (1) shall be reduced by a period equal to the period of time during which the applicant failed to engage in reasonable efforts to conclude prosecution of the application.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c65859-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> With respect to adjustments to patent term made under the authority of paragraph (1)(B), an applicant shall be deemed to have failed to engage in reasonable efforts to conclude processing or examination of an application for the cumulative total of any periods of time in excess of 3 months that are taken to respond to a notice from the Office making any rejection, objection, argument, or other request, measuring such 3-month period from the date the notice was given or mailed to the applicant.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6585a-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The Director shall prescribe regulations establishing the circumstances that constitute a failure of an applicant to engage in reasonable efforts to conclude processing or examination of an application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c6585b-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedures for patent term adjustment determination.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c6585c-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director shall prescribe regulations establishing procedures for the application for and determination of patent term adjustments under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c6585d-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Under the procedures established under subparagraph (A), the Director shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6585e-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> make a determination of the period of any patent term adjustment under this subsection, and shall transmit a notice of that determination no later than the date of issuance of the patent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf3c6585f-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provide the applicant one opportunity to request reconsideration of any patent term adjustment determination made by the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65860-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Director shall reinstate all or part of the cumulative period of time of an adjustment under paragraph (2)(C) if the applicant, prior to the issuance of the patent, makes a showing that, in spite of all due care, the applicant was unable to respond within the 3-month period, but in no case shall more than three additional months for each such response beyond the original 3-month period be reinstated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65861-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Director shall proceed to grant the patent after completion of the Director’s determination of a patent term adjustment under the procedures established under this subsection, notwithstanding any appeal taken by the applicant of such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65862-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appeal of patent term adjustment determination.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65863-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An applicant dissatisfied with the Director’s decision on the applicant’s request for reconsideration under paragraph (3)(B)(ii) shall have exclusive remedy by a civil action against the Director filed in the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia within 180 days after the date of the Director’s decision on the applicant’s request for reconsideration. Chapter 7 of title 5 shall apply to such action. Any final judgment resulting in a change to the period of adjustment of the patent term shall be served on the Director, and the Director shall thereafter alter the term of the patent to reflect such change.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65864-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The determination of a patent term adjustment under this subsection shall not be subject to appeal or challenge by a third party prior to the grant of the patent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3c65865-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65866-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading><content>The term of a patent that is in force on or that results from an application filed before the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act shall be the greater of the 20-year term as provided in subsection (a), or 17 years from grant, subject to any terminal disclaimers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65867-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Remedies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The remedies of sections 283, 284, and 285 shall not apply to acts which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65868-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> were commenced or for which substantial investment was made before the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65869-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> became infringing by reason of paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c6586a-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Remuneration</inline>.—</heading><content>The acts referred to in paragraph (2) may be continued only upon the payment of an equitable remuneration to the patentee that is determined in an action brought under chapter 28 and chapter 29 (other than those provisions excluded by paragraph (2)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3c6586b-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provisional Rights.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c6586c-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In addition to other rights provided by this section, a patent shall include the right to obtain a reasonable royalty from any person who, during the period beginning on the date of publication of the application for such patent under section 122(b), or in the case of an international application filed under the treaty defined in section 351(a) designating the United States under Article 21(2)(a) of such treaty or an international design application filed under the treaty defined in section 381(a)(1) designating the United States under Article 5 of such treaty, the date of publication of the application, and ending on the date the patent is issued—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c6586d-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c6586e-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> makes, uses, offers for sale, or sells in the United States the invention as claimed in the published patent application or imports such an invention into the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c6586f-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the invention as claimed in the published patent application is a process, uses, offers for sale, or sells in the United States or imports into the United States products made by that process as claimed in the published patent application; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65870-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> had actual notice of the published patent application and, in a case in which the right arising under this paragraph is based upon an international application designating the United States that is published in a language other than English, had a translation of the international application into the English language.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65871-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Right based on substantially identical inventions</inline>.—</heading><content>The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty shall not be available under this subsection unless the invention as claimed in the patent is substantially identical to the invention as claimed in the published patent application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65872-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Time limitation on obtaining a reasonable royalty</inline>.—</heading><content>The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty shall be available only in an action brought not later than 6 years after the patent is issued. The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty shall not be affected by the duration of the period described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3c65873-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for international applications.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65874-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty based upon the publication under the treaty defined in section 351(a) of an international application designating the United States shall commence on the date of publication under the treaty of the international application, or, if the publication under the treaty of the international application is in a language other than English, on the date on which the Patent and Trademark Office receives a translation of the publication in the English language.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3c65875-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s154/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Copies</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director may require the applicant to provide a copy of the international application and a translation thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf3c65876-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-07-19/ch950">July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/804">66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/83/s5">Pub. L. 89–83, § 5</ref>, <date date="1965-07-24">July 24, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/261">79 Stat. 261</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/517/s4">Pub. L. 96–517, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3018">94 Stat. 3018</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tIX/s9002">Pub. L. 100–418, title IX, § 9002</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1563">102 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tV/s532/a/1">Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 532(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4983">108 Stat. 4983</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/295/s20/e/1">Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3529">110 Stat. 3529</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4402/a">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4402(a), 4504]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–557, 1501A–564; <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tIII">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13204, 13206(a)(8), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1902">116 Stat. 1902</ref>, 1904; <ref href="/us/pl/112/29">Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 3(j)(1), (2)(B), 9(a), 20(j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/290">125 Stat. 290</ref>, 316, 335; <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/tI/s102/6">Pub. L. 112–211, title I, § 102(6)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1531">126 Stat. 1531</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/274/s1/h">Pub. L. 112–274, § 1(h)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2457">126 Stat. 2457</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf3c65877-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idf3c65878-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on Title 35, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 40 (R.S. 4884, amended <ref href="/us/act/1930-05-23/ch312/s1">May 23, 1930, ch. 312, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/376">46 Stat. 376</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The reference to plants is omitted for inclusion in another section and the reference to the title is shortened since the title is of no legal significance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The wording of the granting clause is changed to “the right to exclude others from making, using, or selling”, following language used by the Supreme Court, to render the meaning clearer.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States” is defined in section 100.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf3c65879-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf3c6587a-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), (2)(A), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, which was approved <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf3c6587b-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/112/274/s1/h/1/A">Pub. L. 112–274, § 1(h)(1)(A)</ref>, which directed substitution of “of commencement of the national stage under section 371 in an international application” for “on which an international application fulfilled the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s371">section 371 of this title</ref>”, was executed by making the substitution for “on which an international application fulfilled the requirements of section 371”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the intervening amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>. See 2011 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/274/s1/h/1/B">Pub. L. 112–274, § 1(h)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “the application under section 111(a) in the United States or, in the case of an international application, the date of commencement of the national stage under section 371 in the international application” for “the application in the United States” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/274/s1/h/2">Pub. L. 112–274, § 1(h)(2)</ref>, substituted “no later than the date of issuance of the patent” for “with the written notice of allowance of the application under section 151”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/274/s1/h/3">Pub. L. 112–274, § 1(h)(3)</ref>, substituted “the Director’s decision on the applicant’s request for reconsideration under paragraph (3)(B)(ii) shall have exclusive remedy” for “a determination made by the Director under paragraph (3) shall have remedy” and “the date of the Director’s decision on the applicant’s request for reconsideration” for “the grant of the patent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s102/6/A/i">Pub. L. 112–211, § 102(6)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “section 120, 121, 365(c), or 386(c)” for “section 120, 121, or 365(c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s102/6/A/ii">Pub. L. 112–211, § 102(6)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “section 119, 365(a), 365(b), 386(a), or 386(b)” for “section 119, 365(a), or 365(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s102/6/B">Pub. L. 112–211, § 102(6)(B)</ref>, inserted “or an international design application filed under the treaty defined in section 381(a)(1) designating the United States under Article 5 of such treaty” after “Article 21(2)(a) of such treaty” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, struck out “of this title” after “365(c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, struck out “of this title” after “365(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, in introductory provisions, struck out “of this title” after “132” and after “151”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(i)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, struck out “of this title” after “111(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, struck out “of this title” after “371”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A)(iii), (B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/j/1">Pub. L. 112–29, § 3(j)(1)</ref>, substituted “Patent Trial and Appeal Board” for “Board of Patent Appeals and Interferences”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/j/2/B">Pub. L. 112–29, § 3(j)(2)(B)</ref>, amended heading generally. Prior to amendment, heading read as follows: “Guarantee or adjustments for delays due to interferences, secrecy orders, and appeals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/j/1">Pub. L. 112–29, § 3(j)(1)</ref>, substituted “Patent Trial and Appeal Board” for “Board of Patent Appeals and Interferences”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s9/a">Pub. L. 112–29, § 9(a)</ref>, substituted “United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia” for “United States District Court for the District of Columbia”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, in introductory provisions, struck out “of this title” after “285”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, struck out “of this title” after “excluded by paragraph (2))”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13206/a/8">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13206(a)(8)</ref>, struck out “, United States Code,” after “title 5”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/s13204">Pub. L. 107–273, § 13204</ref>, amended subsec. (d)(4)(A) as in effect on <date date="2000-11-29">Nov. 29, 2000</date>, by substituting “the date of” for “the date on which the Patent and Trademark Office receives a copy of the” and “publication in the English language” for “international application in the English language”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4504/1">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4504(1)]</ref>, inserted “; provisional rights” after “patent” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4402/a">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4402(a)]</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, text provided for interference delay or secrecy orders, extensions for appellate review, a limitations period, and a maximum period of 5 years duration for all extensions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4504/2">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4504(2)]</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/295">Pub. L. 104–295</ref> substituted “acts” for “Acts” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Every patent shall contain a short title of the invention and a grant to the patentee, his heirs or assigns, for the term of seventeen years, subject to the payment of fees as provided for in this title, of the right to exclude others from making, using, or selling the invention throughout the United States and, if the invention is a process, of the right to exclude others from using or selling throughout the United States, or importing into the United States, products made by that process,, referring to the specification for the particulars thereof. A copy of the specification and drawings shall be annexed to the patent and be a part thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> inserted “and, if the invention is a process, of the right to exclude others from using or selling throughout the United States, or importing into the United States, products made by that process,” after “United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/517">Pub. L. 96–517</ref> substituted “payment of fees” for “payment of issue fees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/83">Pub. L. 89–83</ref> added “subject to the payment of issue fees as provided for in this title”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf3c8c97c-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c97d-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/274">Pub. L. 112–274</ref> effective <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, and applicable to proceedings commenced on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/274/s1/n">section 1(n) of Pub. L. 112–274</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s5">section 5 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c97e-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/211">Pub. L. 112–211</ref> effective on the later of the date that is 1 year after <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, or the date that the Geneva Act of the Hague Agreement Concerning the International Registration of Industrial Designs enters into force with respect to the United States (<date date="2015-05-13">May 13, 2015</date>), and applicable only to certain applications filed on and after that effective date and patents issuing thereon, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/211/s103">section 103 of Pub. L. 112–211</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s100">section 100 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c97f-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 3(j)(1), (2)(B) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/29">Pub. L. 112–29</ref> effective upon the expiration of the 18-month period beginning on <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, and applicable to certain applications for patent and any patents issuing thereon, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/n">section 3(n) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2011 Amendment; Savings Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s100">section 100 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s9/a">section 9(a) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref> effective <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, and applicable to any civil action commenced on or after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s9/b">section 9(b) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1071">section 1071 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s20/j">section 20(j) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref> effective upon the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, and applicable to proceedings commenced on or after that effective date, see section 20(<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/29">Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c980-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4405/a">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4405(a)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–560, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4405/a">“The amendments made by sections 4402 and 4404 [amending this section, sections 156 and 282 of this title, and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1295">section 1295 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure] shall take effect on the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>] and, except for a design patent application filed under chapter 16 of title 35, United States Code, shall apply to any application filed on or after the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4504] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> effective <date date="2000-11-29">Nov. 29, 2000</date>, applicable only to applications (including international applications designating the United States) filed on or after that date, and additionally applicable to any pending application filed before <date date="2000-11-29">Nov. 29, 2000</date>, if such pending application is published pursuant to a request of the applicant under such procedures as may be established by the Director, see section 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4508] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s10">section 10 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c981-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tV/s534">Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 534</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4990">108 Stat. 4990</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/465/tV/s534">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subsection (b), the amendments made by this subtitle [subtitle C (§§ 531–534) of title V of <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, amending this section and sections 41, 104, 111, 119, 156, 172, 173, 252, 262, 271, 272, 287, 292, 295, 307, 365, and 373 of this title] take effect on the date that is one year after the date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States [<date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Patent Applications.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by section 532 [amending this section and sections 41, 111, 119, 156, 172, 173, 365, and 373 of this title] take effect on the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>] and shall apply to all patent applications filed in the United States on or after the effective date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Section 154</inline>(a)<inline class="small-caps">(1)</inline>.—</heading><content><ref href="/us/usc/t35/s154/a/1">Section 154(a)(1) of title 35</ref>, United States Code, as amended by section 532(a)(1) of this Act, shall take effect on the effective date described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Earliest filing</inline>.—</heading><content>The term of a patent granted on an application that is filed on or after the effective date described in subsection (a) and that contains a specific reference to an earlier application filed under the provisions of section 120, 121, or 365(c) of title 35, United States Code, shall be measured from the filing date of the earliest filed application.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c982-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> effective 6 months after <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, and, subject to enumerated exceptions, applicable only with respect to products made or imported after such effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s9006">section 9006 of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s271">section 271 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c983-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/517">Pub. L. 96–517</ref> effective <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/517/s8/a">section 8(a) of Pub. L. 96–517</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s41">section 41 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3c8c984-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1965 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/89/83">Pub. L. 89–83</ref> effective three months after <date date="1965-07-24">July 24, 1965</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/83/s7/a">section 7(a) of Pub. L. 89–83</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s41">section 41 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf3c8c985-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tV/s532/a/2">Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 532(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4985">108 Stat. 4985</ref>, authorized the Commissioner of Patents and Trademarks to prescribe regulations for further limited reexamination of applications pending 2 years or longer and for examination of more than 1 independent and distinct invention in applications pending 3 years or longer, as of the effective date of <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s154/a/2">section 154(a)(2) of this title</ref>, and to establish appropriate related fees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
