<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf3d96baf-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s292"><num value="292">§ 292.</num><heading> False marking</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3d96bb0-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s292/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Whoever, without the consent of the patentee, marks upon, or affixes to, or uses in advertising in connection with anything made, used, offered for sale, or sold by such person within the United States, or imported by the person into the United States, the name or any imitation of the name of the patentee, the patent number, or the words “patent,” “patentee,” or the like, with the intent of counterfeiting or imitating the mark of the patentee, or of deceiving the public and inducing them to believe that the thing was made, offered for sale, sold, or imported into the United States by or with the consent of the patentee; or<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever marks upon, or affixes to, or uses in advertising in connection with any unpatented article, the word “patent” or any word or number importing that the same is patented, for the purpose of deceiving the public; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever marks upon, or affixes to, or uses in advertising in connection with any article, the words “patent applied for,” “patent pending,” or any word importing that an application for patent has been made, when no application for patent has been made, or if made, is not pending, for the purpose of deceiving the public—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Shall be fined not more than $500 for every such offense. Only the United States may sue for the penalty authorized by this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3d96bb1-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s292/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A person who has suffered a competitive injury as a result of a violation of this section may file a civil action in a district court of the United States for recovery of damages adequate to compensate for the injury.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3d96bb2-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s292/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The marking of a product, in a manner described in subsection (a), with matter relating to a patent that covered that product but has expired is not a violation of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf3d96bb3-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-07-19/ch950">July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/814">66 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tV/s533/b/6">Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 533(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4990">108 Stat. 4990</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s16/b/1">Pub. L. 112–29, § 16(b)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/329">125 Stat. 329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf3d96bb4-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idf3d96bb5-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on Title 35, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 50 (R.S. 4901).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This is a criminal provision. The first two paragraphs of the corresponding section of existing statute are consolidated, a new paragraph relating to false marking of “patent applied for” is added, and false advertising is included in all the offenses. The minimum fine which has been interpreted by the courts as a maximum, is replaced by a higher maximum. The informer action is included as additional to an ordinary criminal action.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf3d96bb6-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf3d96bb7-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s16/b/1">Pub. L. 112–29, § 16(b)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “Only the United States may sue for the penalty authorized by this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s16/b/2">Pub. L. 112–29, § 16(b)(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “Any person may sue for the penalty, in which event one-half shall go to the person suing and the other to the use of the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s16/b/3">Pub. L. 112–29, § 16(b)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, in first par., substituted “used, offered for sale, or sold by such person within the United States, or imported by the person into the United States” for “used, or sold by him” and “made, offered for sale, sold, or imported into the United States” for “made or sold”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf3d96bb8-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3d96bb9-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s16/b/4">Pub. L. 112–29, § 16(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/329">125 Stat. 329</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/29/s16/b/4">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall apply to all cases, without exception, that are pending on, or commenced on or after, the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf3d96bba-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref> effective on date that is one year after date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States [<date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>], with provisions relating to earliest filed patent application, see section 534(a), (b)(3) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/465">Pub. L. 103–465</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s154">section 154 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
