<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf3dbdce5-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297"><num value="297">§ 297.</num><heading> Improper and deceptive invention promotion</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3dbdce6-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An invention promoter shall have a duty to disclose the following information to a customer in writing, prior to entering into a contract for invention promotion services:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdce7-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the total number of inventions evaluated by the invention promoter for commercial potential in the past 5 years, as well as the number of those inventions that received positive evaluations, and the number of those inventions that received negative evaluations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdce8-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the total number of customers who have contracted with the invention promoter in the past 5 years, not including customers who have purchased trade show services, research, advertising, or other nonmarketing services from the invention promoter, or who have defaulted in their payment to the invention promoter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdce9-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the total number of customers known by the invention promoter to have received a net financial profit as a direct result of the invention promotion services provided by such invention promoter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcea-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the total number of customers known by the invention promoter to have received license agreements for their inventions as a direct result of the invention promotion services provided by such invention promoter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdceb-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the names and addresses of all previous invention promotion companies with which the invention promoter or its officers have collectively or individually been affiliated in the previous 10 years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3dbdcec-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Civil Action</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3dbdced-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any customer who enters into a contract with an invention promoter and who is found by a court to have been injured by any material false or fraudulent statement or representation, or any omission of material fact, by that invention promoter (or any agent, employee, director, officer, partner, or independent contractor of such invention promoter), or by the failure of that invention promoter to disclose such information as required under subsection (a), may recover in a civil action against the invention promoter (or the officers, directors, or partners of such invention promoter), in addition to reasonable costs and attorneys’ fees—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcee-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount of actual damages incurred by the customer; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcef-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> at the election of the customer at any time before final judgment is rendered, statutory damages in a sum of not more than $5,000, as the court considers just.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3dbdcf0-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), in a case where the customer sustains the burden of proof, and the court finds, that the invention promoter intentionally misrepresented or omitted a material fact to such customer, or willfully failed to disclose such information as required under subsection (a), with the purpose of deceiving that customer, the court may increase damages to not more than three times the amount awarded, taking into account past complaints made against the invention promoter that resulted in regulatory sanctions or other corrective actions based on those records compiled by the Commissioner of Patents under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3dbdcf1-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcf2-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a “contract for invention promotion services” means a contract by which an invention promoter undertakes invention promotion services for a customer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcf3-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a “customer” is any individual who enters into a contract with an invention promoter for invention promotion services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcf4-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the term “invention promoter” means any person, firm, partnership, corporation, or other entity who offers to perform or performs invention promotion services for, or on behalf of, a customer, and who holds itself out through advertising in any mass media as providing such services, but does not include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3dbdcf5-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any department or agency of the Federal Government or of a State or local government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3dbdcf6-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any nonprofit, charitable, scientific, or educational organization, qualified under applicable State law or described under section 170(b)(1)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3dbdcf7-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any person or entity involved in the evaluation to determine commercial potential of, or offering to license or sell, a utility patent or a previously filed nonprovisional utility patent application;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3dbdcf8-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any party participating in a transaction involving the sale of the stock or assets of a business; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf3dbdcf9-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> any party who directly engages in the business of retail sales of products or the distribution of products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcfa-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “invention promotion services” means the procurement or attempted procurement for a customer of a firm, corporation, or other entity to develop and market products or services that include the invention of the customer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3dbdcfb-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records of Complaints.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcfc-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Release of complaints</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commissioner of Patents shall make all complaints received by the Patent and Trademark Office involving invention promoters publicly available, together with any response of the invention promoters. The Commissioner of Patents shall notify the invention promoter of a complaint and provide a reasonable opportunity to reply prior to making such complaint publicly available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf3dbdcfd-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s297/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Request for complaints</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commissioner of Patents may request complaints relating to invention promotion services from any Federal or State agency and include such complaints in the records maintained under paragraph (1), together with any response of the invention promoters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf3dbdcfe-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4102/a">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4102(a)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–552.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf3dbdcff-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf3dbdd00-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf3dbdd01-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 170(b)(1)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (c)(3)(B), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s170/b/1/A">section 170(b)(1)(A) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf3dbdd02-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idf3dbdd03-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4103">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, subtitle A, § 4103]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–554, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4103">“This subtitle [enacting this section and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>] and the amendments made by this subtitle shall take effect 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
