<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf3e09743-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s327"><num value="327">§ 327.</num><heading> Settlement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3e09744-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s327/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>A post-grant review instituted under this chapter shall be terminated with respect to any petitioner upon the joint request of the petitioner and the patent owner, unless the Office has decided the merits of the proceeding before the request for termination is filed. If the post-grant review is terminated with respect to a petitioner under this section, no estoppel under section 325(e) shall attach to the petitioner, or to the real party in interest or privy of the petitioner, on the basis of that petitioner’s institution of that post-grant review. If no petitioner remains in the post-grant review, the Office may terminate the post-grant review or proceed to a final written decision under section 328(a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf3e09745-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc" identifier="/us/usc/t35/s327/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreements in Writing</inline>.—</heading><content>Any agreement or understanding between the patent owner and a petitioner, including any collateral agreements referred to in such agreement or understanding, made in connection with, or in contemplation of, the termination of a post-grant review under this section shall be in writing, and a true copy of such agreement or understanding shall be filed in the Office before the termination of the post-grant review as between the parties. At the request of a party to the proceeding, the agreement or understanding shall be treated as business confidential information, shall be kept separate from the file of the involved patents, and shall be made available only to Federal Government agencies on written request, or to any person on a showing of good cause.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf3e09746-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s6/d">Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/310">125 Stat. 310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf3e09747-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf3e09748-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idf3e09749-d790-11f0-9f07-ba4fc64746bc"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon the expiration of the 1-year period beginning <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, and applicable only to patents described in <ref href="/us/pl/112/29/s3/n/1">section 3(n)(1) of Pub. L. 112–29</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t35/s100">35 U.S.C. 100</ref> note), with certain exceptions and limitations, see section 6(f)(2), (3) of <ref href="/us/pl/112/29">Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s321">section 321 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
