<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf68fe4d3-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s11204"><num value="11204">§ 11204.</num><heading> Processing fees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf68fe4d4-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s11204/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Collection of Fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, or in the case of personnel of the Army Transport Service or the Naval Transport Service, the Secretary of Defense, shall collect a fee of $30 from each applicant for processing an application submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s11203/a">section 11203(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf68fe4d5-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s11204/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Fees Collected</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts received by the Secretary under this section shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury as offsetting receipts of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and ascribed to Coast Guard activities. Amounts received by the Secretary of Defense under this section shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury as offsetting receipts of the Department of Defense. In either case, such amounts shall be available, subject to appropriation, for the administrative costs of processing applications under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s11203">section 11203 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf68fe4d6-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 105–368, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3337">112 Stat. 3337</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf68fe4d7-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf68fe4d8-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idf68fe4d9-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
