<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf69e3b7e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s14504"><num value="14504">§ 14504.</num><heading> Remeasurement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf69e3b7f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s14504/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> To the extent necessary, the Secretary shall remeasure a vessel to which this chapter applies if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf69e3b80-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s14504/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary or the owner alleges an error in its measurement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf69e3b81-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s14504/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the vessel or the use of its space is changed in a way that substantially affects its tonnage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf69e3b82-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s14504/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> after being measured under subchapter III of this chapter, the vessel becomes subject to subchapter II of this chapter because the vessel or its use is changed; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf69e3b83-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s14504/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> although not required to be measured under subchapter II of this chapter, the vessel was measured under subchapter II and the owner requests that the vessel be measured under subchapter III of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf69e3b84-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s14504/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Except as provided in this section and chapter 143 of this title, a vessel that has been measured does not have to be remeasured to obtain another document or endorsement under chapter 121 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf69e3b85-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tV/s5101/3">Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1923">100 Stat. 1923</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf69e3b86-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idf69e3b87-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I580467" class="indent2 firstIndent-2 bold"><i>Revised section 14504</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Source: Section (U.S. Code) 46 App. U.S.C. 71.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 14504(a) provides that the Secretary shall remeasure a vessel that has been measured under the regulatory measurement system if either the Secretary or the owner alleges an error in its measurement; if the vessel, or its use, undergoes a substantial change affecting its tonnage; if the vessel loses its eligibility for measurement under the simplified system because of a change in the vessel or its use; or if the vessel owner requests that the vessel be measured under the simplified system after having been measured under the standard regulatory measurement system. Section 14504(b) provides that a vessel that has been measured does not have to be remeasured to obtain another document or endorsement under chapter 121—“Documentation of Vessels”—except as provided above or in chapter 143 of this subtitle.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
