<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf65b65fb-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201"><num value="3201">§ 3201.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf65b65fc-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “International Safety Management Code” has the same meaning given that term in chapter IX of the Annex to the International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea, 1974;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf65b65fd-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> “responsible person” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf65b65fe-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the owner of a vessel to which this chapter applies; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf65b65ff-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> any other person that has—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf65b6600-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> assumed the responsibility for operation of a vessel to which this chapter applies from the owner; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf65b6601-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> agreed to assume with respect to the vessel responsibility for complying with all the requirements of this chapter and the regulations prescribed under this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf65b6602-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> “vessel engaged on a foreign voyage” means a vessel to which this chapter applies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf65b6603-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> arriving at a place under the jurisdiction of the United States from a place in a foreign country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf65b6604-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> making a voyage between places outside the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf65b6605-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3201/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> departing from a place under the jurisdiction of the United States for a place in a foreign country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idf65b6606-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/tVI/s602/a">Pub. L. 104–324, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3928">110 Stat. 3928</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf65b6607-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf65b6608-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf65b6609-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Safety Management System</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s205">Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3745">132 Stat. 3745</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s205">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit regarding the implementation and effectiveness of the Coast Guard’s oversight and enforcement of safety management plans required under chapter 32 of title 46, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The audit conducted under subsection (a) shall include an evaluation of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> the effectiveness and implementation of safety management plans, including such plans for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a range of vessel types and sizes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> vessels that operate in a cross-section of regional operating areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the effectiveness and implementation of safety management plans in addressing the impact of heavy weather.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>], the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report detailing the results of the audit and providing recommendations related to such results, including ways to streamline and focus such plans on ship safety.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Marine Safety Alert</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date the report is submitted under subsection (c), the Commandant [of the Coast Guard] shall publish a Marine Safety Alert providing notification of the completion of the report and including a link to the report on a publicly accessible website.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Actions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon completion of the report under subsection (c), the Commandant shall consider additional guidance or a rulemaking to address any deficiencies identified, and any additional actions recommended, in the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date the report is submitted under subsection (c), the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the actions the Commandant has taken to address any deficiencies identified, and any additional actions recommended, in the report submitted under subsection (c).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf65b660a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Timely Weather Forecasts and Hazard Advisories for Merchant Mariners</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s216">Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 216</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3751">132 Stat. 3751</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s216">
<inline>“Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>], the Commandant [of the Coast Guard] shall seek to enter into negotiations through the International Maritime Organization to amend the International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea to require that vessels subject to the requirements of such Convention receive—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> timely synoptic and graphical chart weather forecasts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> where available, timely hazard advisories for merchant mariners, including broadcasts of tropical cyclone forecasts and advisories, intermediate public advisories, and tropical cyclone updates to mariners via appropriate technologies.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf65b660b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Safety Management Code Report and Policy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/383/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 105–383, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3420">112 Stat. 3420</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/383/tIII/s306">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on Implementation and Enforcement of the International Safety Management Code.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Transportation (in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’) shall conduct a study—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> reporting on the status of implementation of the International Safety Management Code (hereafter referred to in this section as ‘Code’);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> detailing enforcement actions involving the Code, including the role documents and reports produced pursuant to the Code play in such enforcement actions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> evaluating the effects the Code has had on marine safety and environmental protection, and identifying actions to further promote marine safety and environmental protection through the Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> identifying actions to achieve full compliance with and effective implementation of the Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> evaluating the effectiveness of internal reporting and auditing under the Code, and recommending actions to ensure the accuracy and candidness of such reporting and auditing.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">These recommended actions may include proposed limits on the use in legal proceedings of documents produced pursuant to the Code.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide opportunity for the public to participate in and comment on the study conducted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Not later than 9 months after submission of the report in subsection (a)(3), the Secretary shall develop a policy to achieve full compliance with and effective implementation of the Code. The policy may include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> enforcement penalty reductions and waivers, limits on the use in legal proceedings of documents produced pursuant to the Code, or other incentives to ensure accurate and candid reporting and auditing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any other measures to achieve full compliance with and effective implementation of the Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> if appropriate, recommendations to Congress for any legislation necessary to implement one or more elements of the policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide opportunity for the public to participate in the development of the policy in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Upon completion of the policy in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish the policy in the Federal Register and provide opportunity for public comment on the policy.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf65b660c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Vessel Management Methods Study</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/324/tVI/s602/c">Pub. L. 104–324, title VI, § 602(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3930">110 Stat. 3930</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/324/tVI/s602/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall conduct, in cooperation with the owners, charterers, and managing operators of vessels documented under chapter 121 of title 46, United States Code, and other interested persons, a study of the methods that may be used to implement and enforce the International Management Code for the Safe Operation of Ships and for Pollution Prevention under chapter IX of the Annex to the International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea, 1974.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report of the results of the study required under paragraph (1) before the earlier of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the date that final regulations are prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3203">section 3203 of title 46</ref>, United States Code (as enacted by subsection (a)[)]; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>].”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf65b660d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Convention for Safety of Life at Sea</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For International Conventions for the Safety of Life at Sea to which the United States has been a party, see <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1602">section 1602 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters, and notes thereunder.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
