<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf660482e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306"><num value="3306">§ 3306.</num><heading> Regulations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf660482f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> To carry out this part and to secure the safety of individuals and property on board vessels subject to inspection, including covered small passenger vessels (as defined in subsection (n)(5)), the Secretary shall prescribe necessary regulations to ensure the proper execution of, and to carry out, this part in the most effective manner for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604830-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the design, construction, alteration, repair, and operation of those vessels, including superstructures, hulls, fittings, equipment, appliances, propulsion machinery, auxiliary machinery, boilers, unfired pressure vessels, piping, electric installations, and accommodations for passengers and crew, sailing school instructors, and sailing school students;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604831-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> lifesaving equipment and its use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604832-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> firefighting equipment, its use, and precautionary measures to guard against fire;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604833-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> inspections and tests related to paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of this subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604834-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the use of vessel stores and other supplies of a dangerous nature, including rechargeable devices utilized for personal or commercial electronic equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604835-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604836-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Equipment and material subject to regulation under this section may not be used on any vessel without prior approval of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604837-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Except with respect to use on a public vessel, the Secretary may treat an approval of equipment or materials by a foreign government as approval by the Secretary for purposes of paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604838-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the design standards and testing procedures used by that government meet the requirements of the International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea, 1974;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604839-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the approval of the equipment or material by the foreign government will secure the safety of individuals and property on board vessels subject to inspection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf660483a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> for lifesaving equipment, the foreign government—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf660483b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has given equivalent treatment to approvals of lifesaving equipment by the Secretary; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf660483c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> otherwise ensures that lifesaving equipment approved by the Secretary may be used on vessels that are documented and subject to inspection under the laws of that country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf660483d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> In prescribing regulations for sailing school vessels, the Secretary shall consult with representatives of the private sector having experience in the operation of vessels likely to be certificated as sailing school vessels. The regulations shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf660483e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> reflect the specialized nature of sailing school vessel operations, and the character, design, and construction of vessels operating as sailing school vessels; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf660483f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> include requirements for notice to sailing school instructors and sailing school students about the specialized nature of sailing school vessels and applicable safety regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604840-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> In prescribing regulations for nautical school vessels operated by the United States Merchant Marine Academy or by a State maritime academy (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s51102">section 51102 of this title</ref>), the Secretary shall consider the function, purpose, and operation of the vessels, their routes, and the number of individuals who may be carried on the vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604841-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> When the Secretary finds it in the public interest, the Secretary may suspend or grant exemptions from the requirements of a regulation prescribed under this section related to lifesaving and firefighting equipment, muster lists, ground tackle and hawsers, and bilge systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604842-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> In prescribing regulations for offshore supply vessels, the Secretary shall consider the characteristics, methods of operation, and the nature of the service of offshore supply vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604843-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> In prescribing regulations for fish processing or fish tender vessels, the Secretary shall consult with representatives of the private sector having experience in the operation of these vessels. The regulations shall reflect the specialized nature and economics of fish processing or fish tender vessel operations and the character, design, and construction of fish processing or fish tender vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604844-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish appropriate structural fire protection, manning, operating, and equipment requirements for vessels of at least 100 gross tons but less than 300 gross tons as measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14502">section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14302">section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14104">section 14104 of this title</ref> carrying not more than 150 passengers on domestic voyages, which meet the eligibility criteria of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s2113/4">section 2113(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604845-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish appropriate structural fire protection, manning, operating, and equipment requirements for former public vessels of the United States of at least 100 gross tons but less that 500 gross tons as measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14502">section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14302">section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14104">section 14104 of this title</ref> carrying not more than 150 passengers on domestic voyages, which meet the eligibility criteria of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s2113/4">section 2113(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604846-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> The Secretary may establish by regulation a safety management system appropriate for the characteristics, methods of operation, and nature of service of towing vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604847-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604848-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each vessel of the United States that is constructed under a contract entered into after the date of enactment of the Maritime Safety Act of 2010, or that is delivered after <date date="2011-01-01">January 1, 2011</date>, with an aggregate capacity of 600 cubic meters or more of oil fuel, shall comply with the requirements of Regulation 12A under Annex I to the Protocol of 1978 relating to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships, 1973, entitled “Oil Fuel Tank Protection”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604849-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may prescribe regulations to apply the requirements described in Regulation 12A to vessels described in paragraph (1) that are not otherwise subject to that convention. Any such regulation shall be considered to be an interpretive rule for the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf660484a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In this subsection the term “oil fuel” means any oil used as fuel in connection with the propulsion and auxiliary machinery of the vessel in which such oil is carried.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf660484b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf660484c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall require that a freight vessel inspected under this chapter be outfitted with distress signaling and location technology for the higher of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf660484d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the minimum complement of officers and crew specified on the certificate of inspection for such vessel; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf660484e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the number of persons onboard the vessel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf660484f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the requirement described in paragraph (1) shall not apply to vessels operating within the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604850-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604851-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall promulgate regulations requiring companies to maintain records of all incremental weight changes made to freight vessels inspected under this chapter, and to track weight changes over time to facilitate rapid determination of the aggregate total.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604852-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Records maintained under paragraph (1) shall be stored, in paper or electronic form, onboard such vessels for not less than 3 years and shoreside for the life of the vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6604853-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Small Passenger Vessels.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604854-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall prescribe additional regulations to secure the safety of individuals and property on board covered small passenger vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604855-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comprehensive review</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to prescribe the regulations under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall conduct a comprehensive review of all requirements (including calculations), in existence on the date of enactment of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020, that apply to covered small passenger vessels, with respect to fire detection, protection, and suppression systems, and avenues of egress, on board such vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604856-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6604857-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to subparagraph (B), the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to covered small passenger vessels, regulations for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6604858-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> marine firefighting training programs to improve crewmember training and proficiency, including emergency egress training for each member of the crew, to occur for all members on the crew—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf6604859-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> at least monthly while such members are employed on board the vessel; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf660485a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> each time a new crewmember joins the crew of such vessel;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf660485b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> in all areas on board the vessel where passengers and crew have access, including dining areas, sleeping quarters, and lounges—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf660485c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> interconnected fire detection equipment, including audible and visual alarms; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf660485d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> additional fire extinguishers and other firefighting equipment;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf660485e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the installation and use of monitoring devices to ensure the wakefulness of the required night watch;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf660485f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> increased fire detection and suppression systems (including additional fire extinguishers) on board such vessels in unmanned areas with machinery or areas with other potential heat sources;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6604860-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><chapeau> all general areas accessible to passengers to have no less than 2 independent avenues of escape that are—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf6604861-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> constructed and arranged to allow for free and unobstructed egress from such areas;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf6604862-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> located so that if one avenue of escape is not available, another avenue of escape is available; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf6604863-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> not located directly above, or dependent on, a berth;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6604864-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the handling, storage, and operation of flammable items, such as rechargeable batteries, including lithium ion batteries utilized for commercial purposes on board such vessels;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6604865-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> passenger emergency egress drills for all areas on the vessel to which passengers have access, which shall occur prior to the vessel beginning each excursion; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6604866-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> all passengers to be provided a copy of the emergency egress plan for the vessel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6604867-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability to certain covered small passenger vessels</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirements described in clauses (iii), (v), (vii), and (viii) of subparagraph (A) shall only apply to a covered small passenger vessel that has overnight passenger accommodations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6604868-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim requirements.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6604869-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall, prior to issuing final regulations under paragraph (1), implement interim requirements to enforce the requirements under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf660486a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall implement the interim requirements under subparagraph (A) without regard to chapters 5 and 6 of title 5 and Executive Order Nos. 12866 and 13563 (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s601">5 U.S.C. 601</ref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review and relating to improving regulation and regulatory review).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf660486b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of covered small passenger vessel</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term “covered small passenger vessel”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf660486c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> except as provided in subparagraph (B), means a small passenger vessel (as defined in section 2101) that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf660486d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has overnight passenger accommodations; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf660486e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is operating on a coastwise or oceans route; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf660486f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not include a ferry (as defined in section 2101) or fishing vessel (as defined in section 2101).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf6604870-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/89">Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, <date date="1983-08-26">Aug. 26, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/513">97 Stat. 513</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/364/tIV/s402/5">Pub. L. 98–364, title IV, § 402(5)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-17">July 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/446">98 Stat. 446</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/206/tV/s512/a">Pub. L. 103–206, title V, § 512(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2442">107 Stat. 2442</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/tVI/s604/a">Pub. L. 104–324, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, (c), title VII, § 712, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3930">110 Stat. 3930</ref>, 3931, 3936; <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/tIV/s415/b">Pub. L. 108–293, title IV, § 415(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1047">118 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/304/s15/12">Pub. L. 109–304, § 15(12)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1703">120 Stat. 1703</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tVI/s612">Pub. L. 111–281, title VI, § 612</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2970">124 Stat. 2970</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dC/tXXXV/s3542/b">Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3542(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2324">132 Stat. 2324</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s206/a/1">Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 206(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3746">132 Stat. 3746</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dG/tLVXXXIV">Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIV</ref> [LXXXIV], § 8441(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4742">134 Stat. 4742</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf6604871-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idf6604872-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c2,L1,tp7,s10,xs94,tp7,s10,xs94; " id="idf6604873-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 108pt;" />
<html:col style="width:98pt ; max-width:98pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="2">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 108.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Revised section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:98.0pt ; max-width:98.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source section (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>3306</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:366</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:369</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:375</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:390b</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:392</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:404</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:408</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:411</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:412</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:416</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:420</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:445</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:459</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:473</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:477</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:478</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:479</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:481</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:482</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:483</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:489</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:526p</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:justify; vertical-align:top; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:justify; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">46:1295f(c)</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 3306 contains broad authority to prescribe regulations for the proper inspection and certification of vessels. It provides regulatory flexibility for meeting technological changes. The section also permits flexibility in prescribing regulations for nautical school vessels operated by the United States Merchant Marine Academy or by a State maritime academy. The Secretary may suspend or grant exemptions to certain limited inspection requirements when the Secretary finds that this is necessary in the public interest. It also contains the requirement that in regulating offshore supply vessels consideration must be given to the special nature of their operations.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf6604874-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf6604875-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Maritime Safety Act of 2010, referred to in subsec. (k)(1), is the date of enactment of title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/111/281">Pub. L. 111–281</ref>, which was approved <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020, referred to in subsec. (n)(2), is the date of enactment of div. G of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, which was approved <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf6604876-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s8441/a/1/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 8441(a)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “, including covered small passenger vessels (as defined in subsection (n)(5))” after “vessels subject to inspection” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s8441/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 8441(a)(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “, including rechargeable devices utilized for personal or commercial electronic equipment” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s8441/a/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 8441(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> substituted “section 2113(4)” for “section 2113(5)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (<i>l</i>), (m). <ref href="/us/pl/115/265">Pub. L. 115–265</ref> added subsecs. (<i>l</i>) and (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/111/281">Pub. L. 111–281</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/304">Pub. L. 109–304</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t46/s51102">section 51102 of this title</ref>” for “section 1302(3) of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 (46 App. U.S.C. 1295a(3))”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/108/293">Pub. L. 108–293</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s604/c">Pub. L. 104–324, § 604(c)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (1), (2), and (3)” for “clauses (1)–(3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s604/a">Pub. L. 104–324, § 604(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “Equipment subject to regulation under this section may not be used on any vessel without prior approval as prescribed by regulation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s712/1">Pub. L. 104–324, § 712(1)</ref>, inserted “as measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14502">section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14302">section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14104">section 14104 of this title</ref>” after “300 gross tons”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/324/s712/2">Pub. L. 104–324, § 712(2)</ref>, inserted “as measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14502">section 14502 of this title</ref>, or an alternate tonnage measured under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14302">section 14302 of this title</ref> as prescribed by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s14104">section 14104 of this title</ref>” after “500 gross tons”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/206">Pub. L. 103–206</ref> added subsecs. (h) and (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/364">Pub. L. 98–364</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf6604877-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idf6604878-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1984-04-15">Apr. 15, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/89/s2/g/1">section 2(g)(1) of Pub. L. 98–89</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3101">section 3101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6604879-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Small Passenger Vessels With Overnight Accommodations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dC/tXXXV/s3531/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. C, title XXXV, § 3531(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/826">137 Stat. 826</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dC/tXXXV/s3531/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extension authority.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall not enforce the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, against an operator of an overnight fishing charter before <date date="2024-04-01">April 1, 2024</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2024-04-01">April 1, 2024</date>, an operator of an overnight fishing charter not in compliance with such section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) shall submit to the Commandant a plan for complying with such requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extension</inline>.—</heading><content>On and after <date date="2024-04-01">April 1, 2024</date>, with respect to an operator of an overnight fishing charter which has submitted a plan for compliance in accordance with subparagraph (B), a captain of the port may extend the period described under subparagraph (A) until a date not later than <date date="2026-01-01">January 1, 2026</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Without further Congressional action, a captain of the port may not extend the period of nonenforcement of the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, with respect to an overnight fishing charter, to a date later than <date date="2026-01-01">January 1, 2026</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice to passengers</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning on the date on which the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, take effect, the owner or operator of a vessel for which an extension is granted under paragraph (1)(C) shall provide on the website of such owner or operator of the vessel, the vessel, and each ticket for a passenger a prominently displayed notice that the vessel is exempt from meeting the Coast Guard safety compliance standards concerning egress as described in such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Overnight fishing charter defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘overnight fishing charter’ means a vessel that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is engaged in ‘charter fishing’ as such term is defined in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> has overnight accommodations for passengers.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf660487a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/206/tV/s512/b">Pub. L. 103–206, title V, § 512(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2442">107 Stat. 2442</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/206/tV/s512/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Secretary of Transportation shall, within twenty-four months of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>], prescribe regulations establishing the structural fire protection, manning, operating, and equipment requirements for vessels which meet the requirements of subsections (h) and (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306">section 3306 of title 46</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Before the Secretary of Transportation prescribes regulations under subsections (h) and (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306">section 3306 of title 46</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this Act, the Secretary may prescribe the route, service, manning, and equipment for those vessels based on existing passenger vessel and small passenger vessel regulations.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf660487b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deadlines for Implementation of Distress Signaling and Location Technology Requirement and Promulgation of Incremental Weight Change Records Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s206/a/2">Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 206(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3746">132 Stat. 3746</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s206/a/2">
<inline>“The Secretary shall—</inline>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> begin implementing the requirement under section 3306(<i>l</i>) of title 46, United States Code, as amended by this subsection, by not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> promulgate the regulations required under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/m">section 3306(m) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this subsection, by not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “Secretary” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/115/265/s206/a/2">section 206(a)(2) of Pub. L. 115–265</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/265/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 115–265</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf662926c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Oil Spill Response; Exceptions to Regulations for Towing Vessels</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXIII/s11316">Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXIII, § 11316</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4089">136 Stat. 4089</ref>, which related to updating Coast Guard policies with respect to exceptions to the applicability of subchapter M of chapter I of this title for certain oil spill response vessels, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dG/tLXXIV/s7406/b">Pub. L. 119–60, div. G, title LXXIV, § 7406(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1787">139 Stat. 1787</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf662926d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirements for DUKW Amphibious Passenger Vessels</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXV/s11502">Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11502</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4127">136 Stat. 4127</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXV/s11502">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking Required.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Commandant [of the Coast Guard] shall initiate a rulemaking to establish additional safety standards for DUKW amphibious passenger vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall take effect not later than 18 months after the Commandant promulgates a final rule pursuant to such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The regulations required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A requirement that operators of DUKW amphibious passenger vessels provide reserve buoyancy for such vessels through passive means, including watertight compartmentalization, built-in flotation, or such other means as determined appropriate by the Commandant, in order to ensure that such vessels remain afloat and upright in the event of flooding, including when carrying a full complement of passengers and crew.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> An identification, in consultation with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, of limiting environmental conditions, such as weather, in which DUKW amphibious passenger vessels may safely operate and a requirement that such limiting conditions be described in the certificate of inspection of each DUKW amphibious passenger vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> Requirements that an operator of a DUKW amphibious passenger vessel—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> proceed to the nearest harbor or safe refuge in any case in which a watch or warning is issued for wind speeds exceeding the wind speed equivalent used to certify the stability of such DUKW amphibious passenger vessel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> maintain and monitor a weather monitor radio receiver at the operator station of the vessel that is automatically activated by the warning alarm device of the National Weather Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> A requirement that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> operators of DUKW amphibious passenger vessels inform passengers that seat belts may not be worn during waterborne operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> before the commencement of waterborne operations, a crew member shall visually check that the seatbelt of each passenger is unbuckled; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> operators or crew maintain a log recording the actions described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><chapeau> A requirement for annual training for operators and crew of DUKW amphibious passenger vessels, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> training for personal flotation and seat belt requirements, verifying the integrity of the vessel at the onset of each waterborne departure, identification of weather hazards, and use of National Weather Service resources prior to operation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> training for crew to respond to emergency situations, including flooding, engine compartment fires, man-overboard situations, and in water emergency egress procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading><content>In issuing the regulations required under subsection (a), the Commandant shall consider whether personal flotation devices should be required for the duration of the waterborne transit of a DUKW amphibious passenger vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant may waive the reserve buoyancy requirements described in subsection (b)(1) for a DUKW amphibious passenger vessel if the Commandant certifies in writing, using the best available science, to the appropriate congressional committees that such requirement is not practicable or technically or practically achievable for such vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice to Passengers</inline>.—</heading><content>A DUKW amphibious passenger vessel that receives a waiver under subsection (d) shall provide a prominently displayed notice on its website, ticket counter, and each ticket for passengers that the vessel is exempt from meeting Coast Guard safety compliance standards concerning reserve buoyancy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Prior to issuing final regulations pursuant to subsection (a) and not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Commandant shall require that operators of DUKW amphibious passenger vessels implement the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Remove the canopies and any window coverings of such vessels for waterborne operations, or install in such vessels a canopy that does not restrict horizontal or vertical escape by passengers in the event of flooding or sinking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> If a canopy and window coverings are removed from any such vessel pursuant to paragraph (1), require that all passengers wear a personal flotation device approved by the Coast Guard before the onset of waterborne operations of such vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Reengineer such vessels to permanently close all unnecessary access plugs and reduce all through-hull penetrations to the minimum number and size necessary for operation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Install in such vessels independently powered electric bilge pumps that are capable of dewatering such vessels at the volume of the largest remaining penetration in order to supplement an operable Higgins pump or a dewatering pump of equivalent or greater capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Install in such vessels not fewer than 4 independently powered bilge alarms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Conduct an in-water inspection of any such vessel after each time a through-hull penetration of such vessel has been removed or uncovered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Verify through an in-water inspection the watertight integrity of any such vessel at the outset of each waterborne departure of such vessel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> Install underwater LED lights that activate automatically in an emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> Otherwise comply with any other provisions of relevant Coast Guard guidance or instructions in the inspection, configuration, and operation of such vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant shall implement the interim requirements under subsection (f) without regard to chapters 5 and 6 of title 5, United States Code, and Executive Order Nos. 12866 and 13563 (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s601">5 U.S.C. 601</ref> note).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means the Committee Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">DUKW amphibious passenger vessel</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘DUKW amphibious passenger vessel’ means a vessel that uses, modifies, or is derived from the GMC DUKW–353 design, and which is operating as a small passenger vessel in waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, as defined in section 2.38 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf662926e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historic Wood Sailing Vessels</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXV/s11505">Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXV, § 11505</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4134">136 Stat. 4134</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXV/s11505">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on Historic Wood Sailing Vessels.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report evaluating the practicability of the application of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, to historic wood sailing vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An assessment of the compliance, as of the date on which the report is submitted under paragraph (1), of historic wood sailing vessels with <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> An assessment of the safety record of historic wood sailing vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> An assessment of any risk that modifying the requirements under such section would have on the safety of passengers and crew of historic wood sailing vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> An evaluation of the economic practicability of requiring the compliance of historic wood sailing vessels with such section and whether such compliance would meaningfully improve safety of passengers and crew in a manner that is both feasible and economically practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Any recommendations to improve safety in addition to, or in lieu of, applying such section to historic wood sailing vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Any other recommendations as the Comptroller General determines are appropriate with respect to the applicability of such section to historic wood sailing vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> An assessment to determine if historic wood sailing vessels could be provided an exemption to such section and the changes to legislative or rulemaking requirements, including modifications to section 177.500(q) of title 46, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>]), that are necessary to provide the Commandant [of the Coast Guard] the authority to make such exemption or to otherwise provide for such exemption.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In completing the report required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General may consult with—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the National Transportation Safety Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Coast Guard; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the maritime industry, including relevant federally funded research institutions, nongovernmental organizations, and academia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver for Covered Historic Vessels</inline>.—</heading><content>The captain of a port may waive the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, with respect to covered historic vessels for not more than 2 years after the date on which the report required under subsection (a) is submitted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver for Other Historic Wood Sailing Vessels.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The captain of a port may, upon the request of the owner or operator of a historic wood sailing vessel that is not a covered historic vessel, waive the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, with respect to the historic wood sailing vessel for not more than 2 years after date on which the report required under subsection (a) is submitted, if the captain of the port—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> determines that it is technically infeasible for the historic wood sailing vessel to comply with the requirements described in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, due to its age; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> approves the alternative arrangements proposed for the historic wood sailing vessel in accordance with paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Request and alternative arrangements</inline>.—</heading><content>An owner or operator of a historic wood sailing vessel requesting a waiver under paragraph (1) shall submit such a request to the captain of a port that includes the alternative arrangements the owner or operator will take to ensure an equivalent level of safety, to the maximum extent practicable, to the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/A/v">section 3306(n)(3)(A)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings Clause</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall limit any authority available, as of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], to the captain of a port with respect to safety measures or any other authority as necessary for the safety of historic wood sailing vessels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice to Passengers</inline>.—</heading><content>Any vessel that receives a waiver under subsection (c) or subsection (d) shall, beginning on the date on which the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/3/v">section 3306(n)(3)(v) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, take effect, provide a prominently displayed notice on its website, ticket counter, and each ticket for a passenger that the vessel is exempt from meeting the Coast Guard safety compliance standards concerning egress as described under such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered historic vessels</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘covered historic vessels’ means each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Adventuress (Official Number 210877).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> American Eagle (Official Number 229913).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Angelique (Official Number 623562).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Heritage (Official Number 649561).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> J &amp; E Riggin (Official Number 226422).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Ladona (Official Number 222228).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Lady Washington (Official Number 944970).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> Lettie G. Howard (Official Number 222838).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> Lewis R. French (Official Number 015801).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> Mary Day (Official Number 288714).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="K">“(K)</num><content> Stephen Taber (Official Number 115409).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="L">“(L)</num><content> Victory Chimes (Official Number 136784).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="M">“(M)</num><content> Grace Bailey (Official Number 085754).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="N">“(N)</num><content> Mercantile (Official Number 214388).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="O">“(O)</num><content> Mistress (Official Number 509004).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="P">“(P)</num><content> Wendameen (Official Number 210173).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Historic wood sailing vessel</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘historic wood sailing vessel’ means a covered small passenger vessel, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/n/5">section 3306(n)(5) of title 46</ref>, United States Code, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> has overnight passenger accommodations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is a wood sailing vessel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> has a hull constructed of wood;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> is principally equipped for propulsion by sail, even if the vessel has an auxiliary means of production;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> has no fewer than three masts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> was constructed before 1986.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf662926f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Alcohol at Sea</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXVI/s11606">Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVI, § 11606</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4149">136 Stat. 4149</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dK/tCXVI/s11606">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commandant [of the Coast Guard] shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>] under which the National Academy of Sciences shall prepare an assessment to determine safe levels of alcohol consumption and possession by crew members aboard vessels of the United States engaged in commercial service, except when such possession is associated with the commercial sale to individuals aboard the vessel who are not crew members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The assessment prepared pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> take into account the safety and security of every individual on the vessel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> take into account reported incidences of sexual harassment or sexual assault, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s2101">section 2101 of title 46</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> provide any appropriate recommendations for any changes to laws, regulations, or employer policies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon completion of the assessment under this section, the National Academy of Sciences shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Commandant, and the Secretary the assessment prepared pursuant to subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Commandant—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall, not later than 180 days after receiving the submission of the assessment under subsection (c), review the changes to regulations recommended in such assessment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> taking into account the safety and security of every individual on vessels of the United States engaged in commercial service, may issue regulations relating to alcohol consumption on such vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings Clause</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To the extent the Commandant issues regulations establishing safe levels of alcohol consumption in accordance with subsection (d), the Commandant may not issue regulations which prohibit—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the owner or operator of a vessel from imposing additional restrictions on the consumption of alcohol, including the prohibition of the consumption of alcohol on such vessels; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> possession of alcohol associated with the commercial sale to individuals aboard the vessel who are not crew members.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If, by the date that is 2 years after the receipt of the assessment under subsection (c), the Commandant does not issue regulations under subsection (d), the Commandant shall provide a report by such date to the committees described in subsection (c)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> containing the rationale for not issuing such regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> providing other recommendations as necessary to ensure safety at sea.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “Secretary” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s11606">section 11606 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s11002">section 11002 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s106">section 106 of Title 14</ref>, Coast Guard.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6629270-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Negotiations To Amend International Regulations Related to Vessel Equipment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s206/b">Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 206(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3746">132 Stat. 3746</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s206/b">“Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>], the Commandant [of the Coast Guard] shall seek to enter into negotiations through the International Maritime Organization to amend regulation 25 of chapter II–1 of the International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea to require a high-water alarm sensor in each cargo hold of a freight vessel (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s2101">section 2101 of title 46</ref>, United States Code), that connects with audible and visual alarms on the navigation bridge of the vessel.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s208/a/1">Pub. L. 115–265, title II, § 208(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3747">132 Stat. 3747</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/265/tII/s208/a/1">“Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-11">Oct. 11, 2018</date>], the Commandant [of the Coast Guard] shall seek to enter into negotiations through the International Maritime Organization to amend regulation 20 of chapter V of the International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea to require that all voyage data recorders are installed in a float-free arrangement and contain an integrated emergency position indicating radio beacon.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6629271-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Towing Vessels</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tVII/s701/c">Pub. L. 111–281, title VII, § 701(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2980">124 Stat. 2980</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/281/tVII/s701/c">“No later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>], the Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking regarding inspection requirements for towing vessels required under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s3306/j">section 3306(j) of title 46</ref>, United States Code. The Secretary shall issue a final rule pursuant to that rulemaking no later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[“Secretary” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/s701/c">section 701(c) of Pub. L. 111–281</ref>, set out above, probably means the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/s701/a/1">section 701(a)(1) of Pub. L. 111–281</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1321">section 1321 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6629272-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Foreign Approvals</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/324/tVI/s604/b">Pub. L. 104–324, title VI, § 604(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3931">110 Stat. 3931</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/324/tVI/s604/b">“The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with other interested Federal agencies, shall work with foreign governments to have those governments approve the use of the same equipment and materials on vessels documented under the laws of those countries that the Secretary requires on United States documented vessels.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6629273-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Convention for Safety of Life at Sea</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For International Conventions for the Safety of Life at Sea to which the United States has been a party, see <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1602">section 1602 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters, and notes thereunder.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
