<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf675a5ab-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s5116"><num value="5116">§ 5116.</num><heading> Penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf675a5ac-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s5116/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, the owner, charterer, managing operator, agent, master, and individual in charge of a vessel violating this chapter or a regulation prescribed under this chapter are each liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000. Each day of a continuing violation is a separate violation. The vessel also is liable in rem for the penalty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf675a5ad-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s5116/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The owner, charterer, managing operator, agent, master, and individual in charge of a vessel allowing, causing, attempting to cause, or failing to take reasonable care to prevent a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s5112/a">section 5112(a) of this title</ref> are each liable to the Government for a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 plus an additional amount equal to twice the economic benefit of the overloading. The vessel also is liable in rem for the penalty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf675a5ae-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s5116/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The master or individual in charge of a vessel violating <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s5112/b">section 5112(b) of this title</ref> is liable to the Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000. The vessel also is liable in rem for the penalty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf675a5af-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s5116/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> A person causing or allowing the departure of a vessel from a place within the jurisdiction of the United States in violation of a detention order issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s5113">section 5113 of this title</ref> commits a class A misdemeanor.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf675a5b0-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s5116/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> A person causing or allowing the alteration, concealment, or removal of a mark placed on a vessel under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s5103/b">section 5103(b) of this title</ref> and the regulations prescribed under this chapter, except to make a lawful change or to escape enemy capture in time of war, commits a class A misdemeanor.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf675a5b1-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tV/s5101/2">Pub. L. 99–509, title V, § 5101(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1918">100 Stat. 1918</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/tIV/s4302/d">Pub. L. 101–380, title IV, § 4302(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/538">104 Stat. 538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf675a5b2-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idf675a5b3-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I580467" class="indent2 firstIndent-2 bold"><i>Revised section 5116</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Source: Section (U.S. Code) 46 App. U.S.C. 86i, 88g.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5116 provides penalties for violations of load line requirements. The penalties are raised substantially from existing law to provide a sufficient deterrence against violations of the load line requirements and to conform with the level of penalties throughout the subtitle. The monetary penalties have not been changed since the 1930’s.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5116(a) raises from $1,000 to $5,000 the maximum penalty for violation of a load line provision under this chapter or a regulation promulgated under this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5116(b) raises from $1,000 to $10,000 the maximum penalty for loading a vessel in such a way as to submerge the load line. In addition, a violator must pay up to two times the amount of the economic benefit of the overloading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5116(c) raises from $500 to $5,000 the maximum penalty for a violation of the requirement in section 5112(b) that the load line position and draft of a vessel be noted in the logbook.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5116(a)–(c) also states that the vessel is liable in rem for the penalty.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5116(d) raises from $1,000 to $10,000 the maximum penalty for a violation of a detention order and may also include imprisonment for up to one year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5116(e) raises from $2,000 to $10,000 the maximum penalty for the alteration, removal, or concealment of a load line mark and may also include imprisonment for two years.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf675a5b4-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf675a5b5-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/s4302/d/1">Pub. L. 101–380, § 4302(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “commits a class A misdemeanor” for “shall be fined not more than $10,000, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/s4302/d/2">Pub. L. 101–380, § 4302(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “commits a class A misdemeanor” for “shall be fined not more than $10,000, imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf675a5b6-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf675a5b7-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/380">Pub. L. 101–380</ref> applicable to incidents occurring after <date date="1990-08-18">Aug. 18, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/380/s1020">section 1020 of Pub. L. 101–380</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2701">section 2701 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
