<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf6c1f15a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318"><num value="51318">§ 51318.</num><heading> Policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6c1f15b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Policy.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f15c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Transportation shall direct the Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to prescribe a policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking applicable to the cadets and other personnel of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f15d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters to be specified in policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prescribed under this subsection shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f15e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a program to promote awareness and prevention of the incidence of rape, acquaintance rape, domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and other sexual offenses of a criminal nature that involve cadets or other Academy personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f15f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> procedures for documenting, tracking, and maintaining the data required to conduct the annual assessments to determine the effectiveness of the policies, procedures, and training program of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking involving cadets or other Academy personnel, as required by subsection (c);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f160-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> procedures that a cadet or other Academy personnel should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f161-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> specifying the person or persons to whom an alleged occurrence of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking should be reported by the victim and the options for confidential reporting;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f162-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> specifying any other person whom the victim should contact; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f163-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> procedures on the preservation of evidence potentially necessary for proof of a criminal sexual offense;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f164-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> procedures for investigating sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking involving a cadet or other Academy personnel to determine whether disciplinary action is necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f165-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a procedure for disciplinary action in cases of alleged criminal sexual assault involving a cadet or other Academy personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f166-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> any other sanction authorized to be imposed in a substantiated case of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking involving a cadet or other Academy personnel in rape, acquaintance rape, or any other criminal sexual offense, whether forcible or nonforcible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f167-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> procedures through which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f168-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> questions regarding sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking can be confidentially asked and confidentially answered;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f169-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> victims can report incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking confidentially; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f16a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the privacy of victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking will be protected; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f16b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> required training on the policy for all cadets and other Academy personnel, including the specific training required for personnel who process allegations of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking involving Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f16c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum training requirements for certain individuals regarding sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f16d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall direct the Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to develop a mandatory training program at the Academy for each individual who is involved in implementing the Academy’s student disciplinary grievance procedures, including each individual who is responsible for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f16e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> resolving complaints of reported sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f16f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> resolving complaints of reported violations of the sexual misconduct policy of the Academy; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f170-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> conducting an interview with a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f171-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Superintendent shall develop the training program described in subparagraph (A) in consultation with national, State, or local sexual assault, dating violence, domestic violence, or stalking victim advocacy, victim services, or prevention organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f172-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The training required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f173-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Information on working with and interviewing persons subjected to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f174-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Information on particular types of conduct that would constitute sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, regardless of gender, including same-sex sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f175-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Information on consent and the effect that drugs or alcohol may have on an individual’s ability to consent.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f176-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Information on the effects of trauma, including the neurobiology of trauma.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f177-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Training regarding the use of trauma-informed interview techniques, which means asking questions of an individual who has been a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking in a manner that is focused on the experience of the victim, does not judge or blame the victim, and is informed by evidence-based research on the neurobiology of trauma.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f178-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> Training on cultural awareness regarding how dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking may impact midshipmen differently depending on their cultural background.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f179-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> Information on sexual assault dynamics, sexual assault perpetrator behavior, and barriers to reporting.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f17a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f17b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development and approval schedule</inline>.—</heading><content>The training program required by subparagraph (A) shall be developed not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f17c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Completion of training</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each individual who is required to complete the training described in subparagraph (A) shall complete such training not later than—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf6c1f17d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> 270 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf6c1f17e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/3/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> 180 days after starting a position with responsibilities that include the activities described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f17f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under this subsection is available to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f180-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all cadets and employees of the Academy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f181-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the public.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f182-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation and assistance</inline>.—</heading><content>In developing the policy under this subsection, the Secretary may consult with or receive assistance from such Federal, State, local, and national organizations and subject matter experts as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f183-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consistency with the higher education act of 1965</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under this subsection meets the requirements set out in section 485(f)(8) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1092/f/8">20 U.S.C. 1092(f)(8)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6c1f184-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f185-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall ensure that the development program of the Academy includes a section that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f186-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> describes the relationship between honor, respect, and character development and the prevention of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking at the Academy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f187-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes a brief history of the problem of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking in the merchant marine, in the Armed Forces, and at the Academy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f188-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> includes information relating to reporting sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking, victims’ rights, and dismissal for offenders.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f189-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum requirements to combat retaliation.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f18a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018, the Maritime Administrator shall direct the Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to implement and maintain a plan to combat retaliation against cadets at the Academy and other Academy personnel who report sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f18b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Violation of code of conduct</inline>.—</heading><content>The Superintendent shall consider an act of retaliation against a cadet at the Academy who reports sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking as a Class I violation of the Midshipman Regulations of the Academy or equivalent code of conduct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f18c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retaliation definition</inline>.—</heading><content>The Superintendent shall work with the sexual assault prevention and response staff of the Academy to define “retaliation” for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f18d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum resource requirements.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f18e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Maritime Administrator shall ensure the staff at the Academy are provided adequate and appropriate sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response training materials and resources. Such resources shall include staff as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f18f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Sexual assault response coordinator.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f190-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Prevention educator.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f191-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Civil rights officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f192-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Staff member to oversee Sea Year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f193-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Communication</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Office of Civil Rights of the Maritime Administration shall create and maintain a direct line of communication to the sexual assault response staff of the Academy that is outside of the chain of command of the Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f194-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum training requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Superintendent shall ensure that all cadets receive training on the sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response sections of the development program of the Academy, as described in paragraph (1), as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f195-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An initial training session, which shall occur not later than 7 days after a cadet’s initial arrival at the Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f196-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Additional training sessions, which shall occur biannually following the cadet’s initial training session until the cadet graduates or leaves the Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6c1f197-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Assessment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f198-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, in cooperation with the Superintendent, shall conduct an assessment at the Academy, during each Academy program year, to determine the effectiveness of the policies, procedures, and training program of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f199-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Biennial survey</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For each assessment of the Academy under paragraph (1) during an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year, the Secretary shall conduct a survey of cadets and other Academy personnel—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f19a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> to measure—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f19b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual assault events involving cadets or other Academy personnel, on or off the Academy campus, that have been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f19c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual assault events involving cadets or other Academy personnel, on or off the Academy campus, that have not been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f19d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> to assess the perceptions of cadets and other Academy personnel on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f19e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the policies, procedures, and training programs of the Academy on sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f19f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the enforcement of the policies described in clause (i);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f1a0-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the incidence of sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c1f1a1-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any other issues relating to sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f1a2-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Focus groups for years when survey not required</inline>.—</heading><content>In any year in which the Secretary is not required to conduct the survey described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall conduct focus groups at the Academy for the purposes of ascertaining information relating to sexual assault and sexual harassment issues at the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6c1f1a3-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f1a4-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>For each Academy program year, the Superintendent shall submit to the Secretary a report that provides information about sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c1f1a5-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, for the Academy program year covered by the report—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f1a6-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the number of sexual assaults, rapes, and other sexual offenses, including sexual harassment, involving cadets or other Academy personnel that have been reported to Academy officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c1f1a7-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the number of the reported cases described in subparagraph (A) that have been substantiated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c461a8-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the policies, procedures, and training implemented by the Superintendent and the leadership of the Academy in response to incidents of sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets and other Academy personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c461a9-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a plan for the actions that will be taken in the following Academy program year regarding prevention of, and response to, incidents of sexual harassment and sexual assault involving cadets and other Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c461aa-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Survey and focus group results.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c461ab-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Survey results</inline>.—</heading><content>Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year shall include the results of the survey conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c461ac-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Focus group results</inline>.—</heading><content>Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year in which the Secretary is not required to conduct the survey described in subsection (c)(2) shall include the results of the focus group conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c461ad-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting requirement.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c461ae-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">By the superintendent</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For each incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault reported to the Superintendent, the Superintendent shall provide to the Secretary and the Board of Visitors of the Academy a report that includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c461af-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the facts surrounding the incident, except for any details that would reveal the identities of the people involved; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf6c461b0-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Academy’s response to the incident.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf6c461b1-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">By the secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than January 15 of each year, the Secretary shall submit a copy of each report received under subparagraph (A) and the Secretary’s comments on the report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6c461b2-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Data for Aggregate Reporting.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c461b3-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>No requirement related to confidentiality in this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s51319">section 51319 of this title</ref> may be construed to prevent a sexual assault response coordinator from providing information for any report required by law regarding sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c461b4-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Identity protection</inline>.—</heading><content>Any information provided for a report referred to in paragraph (1) shall be provided in a manner that protects the identity of the victim or witness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf6c461b5-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s51319">section 51319 of this title</ref>:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c461b6-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dating violence; domestic violence; stalking</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms “dating violence”, “domestic violence”, and “stalking” have the meanings given those terms is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002027">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002027"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “in”.</note> section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13925/a">42 U.S.C. 13925(a)</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002028">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002028"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf6c461b7-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s51318/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sexual assault</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “sexual assault” means an offense classified as a forcible or nonforcible sex offense under the uniform crime reporting system of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf6c461b8-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dC/tXXXV/s3510/a">Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3510(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2782">130 Stat. 2782</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dC/tXXXV/s3514/a">Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3514(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1920-1923">131 Stat. 1920–1923</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dC/tXXXV/s3507/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2309">132 Stat. 2309</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf6c461b9-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf6c461ba-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf6c461bb-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3)(D)(i), (ii)(I) and (b)(2)(A), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Pub. L. 115–91</ref>, which was approved <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994, referred to in subsec. (f)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tIV/s40002">section 40002 of title IV of Pub. L. 103–322</ref>, which was classified as <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13925">section 13925 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12291">section 12291 of Title 34</ref>, Crime Control and Law Enforcement.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf6c461bc-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3507/a/1/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3507(a)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “and prevention” after “awareness”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3507/a/1/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3507(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (C), added subpar. (B) and redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C). Former subpar. (C) redesignated (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D) to (H). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3507/a/1/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3507(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (D), added subpar. (D) and redesignated former subpars. (C) to (F) as (E) to (H), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3507/a/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3507(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “and other Academy personnel” after “cadets at the Academy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3507/a/3/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3507(a)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “, including sexual harassment,” after “sexual assaults, rapes, and other sexual offenses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s3507/a/3/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 3507(a)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “Not later than January 15 of each year, the Secretary” for “The Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—<ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/d/1">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “Policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking” for “Policy on sexual harassment and sexual assault” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/1">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking” for “harassment and sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/A">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking” for “harassment and sexual assault” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/B">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “domestic violence, dating violence, stalking,” after “acquaintance rape,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/C/i">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking,” for “harassment or sexual assault,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking” for “harassment or sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/C/iii">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(C)(iii)</ref>, substituted “a criminal sexual offense” for “criminal sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/D">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(D)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking” for “harassment or sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(E)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/E/i">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(E)(i)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking” for “harassment or sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(E)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/E/ii">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(E)(ii)</ref>, substituted “sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking” for “sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(E)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/E/iii">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(E)(iii)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking” for “harassment and sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/2/F">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(2)(F)</ref>, substituted “harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking” for “harassment or sexual assault”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/3">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(3)</ref>, (4), added par. (3) and redesignated former pars. (3) and (4) as (4) and (5), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/a/5">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(a)(5)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/b">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) related to development program and minimum training requirements regarding the prevention of sexual harassment and sexual assault.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3514/c">Pub. L. 115–91, § 3514(c)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf6c461bd-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6c461be-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States Merchant Marine Academy Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dC/tXXXV/s3517">Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3517</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1986">133 Stat. 1986</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dC/tXXXV/s3517">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this title [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the recommendations in report of the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation on the effectiveness sexual assault prevention and response program of the United States Merchant Marine Academy (mandated under section 3512 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/130/2786">130 Stat. 2786</ref>)), are fully implemented.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this title, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> confirmation that the recommendations described in subsection (a) have been fully implemented, and explaining how those recommendations have been implemented; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> if such recommendations have not been fully implemented as of the date of the report, an explanation of why such recommendations have not been fully implemented and a description of the resources that are needed to fully implement such recommendations.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6c461bf-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dC/tXXXV/s3507/b">Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2310">132 Stat. 2310</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dC/tXXXV/s3507/b">“The Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy may implement the amendment to subsection (b)(2)(A) of <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s51318">section 51318 of title 46</ref>, United States Code, made by subsection (a)(2), by updating an existing plan issued pursuant to the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Public Law 115–91</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6c461c0-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Access of Academy Cadets to DOD SAFE or Equivalent Helpline</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dC/tXXXV/s3515/b">Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3515(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1926">131 Stat. 1926</ref>, which directed the Secretary of Transportation to provide cadets at the United States Merchant Marine Academy access to the Department of Defense SAFE Helpline or an equivalent helpline to report incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dC/tXXXV/s3513/c">Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3513(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3068">136 Stat. 3068</ref>, which also redesignated <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3515/c">section 3515(c) of Pub. L. 115–91</ref> (amending <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s51319">section 51319 of this title</ref>) as <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s3515/b">section 3515(b) of Pub. L. 115–91</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6c461c1-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sea Year Compliance</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dC/tXXXV/s3514">Pub. L. 114–328, div. C, title XXXV, § 3514</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2788">130 Stat. 2788</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dC/tXXXV/s3513">Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3513</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1919">131 Stat. 1919</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dC/tXXXV/s3515/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3515(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2312">132 Stat. 2312</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dC/tXXXV/s3516/b">Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3516(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1986">133 Stat. 1986</ref>, which directed the Maritime Administrator to establish criteria for participation in the Sea Year program of the United States Merchant Marine Academy that addresses sexual harassment, sexual assault, and other inappropriate conduct and a process for verifying compliance, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dC/tXXXV/s3513/c/1">Pub. L. 117–263, div. C, title XXXV, § 3513(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3068">136 Stat. 3068</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf6c461c2-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Actions To Address Sexual Harassment and Violence at the United States Merchant Marine Academy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/417/dC/tXXXV/s3507">Pub. L. 110–417, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4765">122 Stat. 4765</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/417/dC/tXXXV/s3507">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Policy</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Transportation shall direct the Superintendent of the United States Merchant Marine Academy to prescribe a policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence applicable to the cadets and other personnel of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Specified in Policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence prescribed under this section shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a program to promote awareness of the incidence of rape, acquaintance rape, and other sexual offenses of a criminal nature that involve cadets or other Academy personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> procedures that a cadet should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a specification of the person or persons to whom an alleged occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence should be reported by a cadet and the options for confidential reporting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a specification of any other person whom the victim should contact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> procedures on the preservation of evidence potentially necessary for proof of criminal sexual assault;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a procedure for disciplinary action in cases of alleged criminal sexual assault involving a cadet or other Academy personnel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> any other sanction authorized to be imposed in a substantiated case of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving a cadet or other Academy personnel in rape, acquaintance rape, or any other criminal sexual offense, whether forcible or nonforcible; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> required training on the policy for all cadets and other Academy personnel, including the specific training required for personnel who process allegations of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Assessment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall direct the Superintendent to conduct an assessment at the Academy during each Academy program year, to be administered by the Department of Transportation, to determine the effectiveness of the policies, training, and procedures of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> For the assessment at the Academy under paragraph (1) with respect to an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year, the Superintendent shall conduct a survey, to be administered by the Department, of Academy personnel—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> to measure—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have not been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> to assess the perceptions of Academy personnel of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the policies, training, and procedures on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the enforcement of such policies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the incidence of sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> any other issues relating to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall direct the Superintendent of the Academy to submit to the Secretary a report on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other personnel at the Academy for each Academy program year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, for the Academy program year covered by the report, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The number of sexual assaults, rapes, and other sexual offenses involving cadets or other Academy personnel that have been reported to Academy officials during the program year and, of those reported cases, the number that have been substantiated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The policies, procedures, and processes implemented by the Superintendent and the leadership of the Academy in response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other Academy personnel during the program year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A plan for the actions that are to be taken in the following Academy program year regarding prevention of and response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year shall include the results of the survey conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Superintendent shall transmit to the Secretary, and to the Board of Visitors of the Academy, each report received by the Superintendent under this subsection, together with the Superintendent’s comments on the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall transmit each such report, together with the Secretary’s comments on the report, to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
