<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf704c622-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107"><num value="70107">§ 70107.</num><heading> Grants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c623-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish a grant program for the allocation of funds based on risk to implement Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans among port authorities, facility operators, and State and local government agencies required to provide port security services and to train public safety personnel under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70132">section 70132 of this title</ref>. Before awarding a grant under the program, the Secretary shall provide for review and comment by the appropriate Federal Maritime Security Coordinators and the Maritime Administrator. In administering the grant program, the Secretary shall take into account national economic, energy, and strategic defense concerns based upon the most current risk assessments available.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c624-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Costs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The following costs of funding the correction of Coast Guard identified vulnerabilities in port security and ensuring compliance with Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans are eligible to be funded:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c625-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Salary, benefits, overtime compensation, retirement contributions, and other costs of additional Coast Guard mandated security personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c626-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The cost of acquisition, operation, and maintenance of security equipment or facilities to be used for security monitoring and recording, security gates and fencing, marine barriers for designated security zones, security-related lighting systems, remote surveillance, concealed video systems, security vessels, and other security-related infrastructure or equipment that contributes to the overall security of passengers, cargo, or crewmembers. Grants awarded under this section may not be used to construct buildings or other physical facilities, except those which are constructed under terms and conditions consistent with the requirements under section 611(j)(8) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5196/j/8">42 U.S.C. 5196(j)(8)</ref>), including those facilities in support of this paragraph, and specifically approved by the Secretary. Costs eligible for funding under this paragraph may not exceed the greater of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c627-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> $1,000,000 per project; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c628-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such greater amount as may be approved by the Secretary, which may not exceed 10 percent of the total amount of the grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c629-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The cost of screening equipment, including equipment that detects weapons of mass destruction and conventional explosives, and of testing and evaluating such equipment, to certify secure systems of transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c62a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The cost of conducting vulnerability assessments to evaluate and make recommendations with respect to security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c62b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The cost of conducting exercises or training for prevention and detection of, preparedness for, response to, or recovery from terrorist attacks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c62c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The cost of establishing or enhancing mechanisms for sharing terrorism threat information and ensuring that the mechanisms are interoperable with Federal, State, and local agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c62d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The cost of equipment (including software) required to receive, transmit, handle, and store classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c62e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> The cost of training public safety personnel—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c62f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to enforce a security zone under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70132">section 70132 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c630-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assist in the enforcement of a security zone.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c631-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matching Requirements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c632-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> 75<inline class="small-caps">-percent federal funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), Federal funds for any eligible project under this section shall not exceed 75 percent of the total cost of such project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c633-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c634-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Small projects</inline>.—</heading><content>There are no matching requirements for grants under subsection (a) for projects costing not more than $25,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c635-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Higher level of support required</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary determines that a proposed project merits support and cannot be undertaken without a higher rate of Federal support, then the Secretary may approve grants under this section with a matching requirement other than that specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c636-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Training</inline>.—</heading><content>There are no matching requirements for grants under subsection (a) to train public safety personnel in the enforcement of security zones under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70132">section 70132 of this title</ref> or in assisting in the enforcement of such security zones.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c637-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination and Cooperation Agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall ensure that projects paid for, or the costs of which are reimbursed, under this section within any area or port are coordinated with other projects, and may require cooperative agreements among users of the port and port facilities with respect to projects funded under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c638-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Multiple-Year Projects.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c639-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Letters of intent</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may execute letters of intent to commit funding to such authorities, operators, and agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c63a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not more than 20 percent of the grant funds awarded under this subsection in any fiscal year may be awarded for projects that span multiple years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c63b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consistency With Plans</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that each grant awarded under subsection (e)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c63c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is used to supplement and support, in a consistent and coordinated manner, the applicable Area Maritime Transportation Security Plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c63d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is coordinated with any applicable State or Urban Area Homeland Security Plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c63e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading><content>Any entity subject to an Area Maritime Transportation Security Plan may submit an application for a grant under this section, at such time, in such form, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c63f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the SAFE Port Act, the Secretary, acting through the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall submit a report to Congress, in a secure format, describing the methodology used to allocate port security grant funds on the basis of risk.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c640-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c641-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall require eligible port authorities, facility operators, and State and local agencies required to provide security services, to submit an application, at such time, in such form, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require, and shall include appropriate application, review, and delivery mechanisms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c642-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum standards for payment or reimbursement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each application for payment or reimbursement of eligible costs shall include, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c643-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A copy of the applicable Area Maritime Transportation Security Plan or facility security plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c644-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A comprehensive description of the need for the project, and a statement of the project’s relationship to the applicable Area Maritime Transportation Security Plan or facility security plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c645-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A determination by the Captain of the Port that the security project addresses or corrects Coast Guard identified vulnerabilities in security and ensures compliance with Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c646-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedural safeguards</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall by regulation establish appropriate accounting, reporting, and review procedures to ensure that amounts paid or reimbursed under this section are used for the purposes for which they were made available, all expenditures are properly accounted for, and amounts not used for such purposes and amounts not obligated or expended are recovered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c647-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Project approval required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may approve an application for the payment or reimbursement of costs under this section only if the Secretary is satisfied that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c648-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the project is consistent with Coast Guard vulnerability assessments and ensures compliance with Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c649-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> enough money is available to pay the project costs that will not be reimbursed by the United States Government under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c64a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the project will be completed without unreasonable delay; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c64b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/i/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the recipient has authority to carry out the project as proposed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c64c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Audits and Examinations</inline>.—</heading><content>A recipient of amounts made available under this section shall keep such records as the Secretary may require, and make them available for review and audit by the Secretary, the Comptroller General of the United States, or the Inspector General of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c64d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports on Security Funding and Compliance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c64e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Within 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall transmit an unclassified report to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c64f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> includes a funding proposal and rationale to fund the correction of Coast Guard identified vulnerabilities in port security and to help ensure compliance with Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans for fiscal years 2003 through 2008; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c650-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> includes projected funding proposals for fiscal years 2003 through 2008 for the following security programs:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c651-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Sea Marshall program.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c652-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Automated Identification System and a system of polling vessels on entry into United States waters.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c653-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The maritime intelligence requirements in this Act.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c654-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The issuance of transportation security cards required by section 70105.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c655-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/1/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The program of certifying secure systems of transportation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c656-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other expenditures</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall, as part of the report required by paragraph (1) report, in coordination with the Commissioner of Customs, on projected expenditures of screening and detection equipment and on cargo security programs over fiscal years 2003 through 2008.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c657-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Annually, beginning 1 year after transmittal of the report required by paragraph (1) until <date date="2009-10-01">October 1, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall transmit an unclassified annual report to the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the House of Representatives Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, on progress in achieving compliance with the correction of Coast Guard identified vulnerabilities in port security and compliance with Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c658-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identifies any modifications necessary in funding to ensure the correction of Coast Guard identified vulnerabilities and ensure compliance with Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c659-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes an assessment of progress in implementing the grant program established by subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c65a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> includes any recommendations the Secretary may make to improve these programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c65b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/k/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> with respect to a port selected by the Secretary, describes progress and enhancements of applicable Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans and how the Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002 has improved security at that port.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c65c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated $400,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2007 through 2013 to carry out this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf704c65d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Investigations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c65e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall conduct investigations, fund pilot programs, and award grants, to examine or develop—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c65f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> methods or programs to increase the ability to target for inspection vessels, cargo, crewmembers, or passengers that will arrive or have arrived at any port or place in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c660-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> equipment to detect accurately explosives, chemical, or biological agents that could be used in a transportation security incident against the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c661-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> equipment to detect accurately nuclear or radiological materials, including scintillation-based detection equipment capable of signalling the presence of nuclear or radiological materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c662-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> improved tags and seals designed for use on shipping containers to track the transportation of the merchandise in such containers, including sensors that are able to track a container throughout its entire supply chain, detect hazardous and radioactive materials within that container, and transmit that information to the appropriate law enforcement authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c663-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> tools, including the use of satellite tracking systems, to increase the awareness of maritime areas and to identify potential transportation security incidents that could have an impact on facilities, vessels, and infrastructure on or adjacent to navigable waterways, including underwater access;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c664-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> tools to mitigate the consequences of a transportation security incident on, adjacent to, or under navigable waters of the United States, including sensor equipment, and other tools to help coordinate effective response to a transportation security incident;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c665-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> applications to apply existing technologies from other areas or industries to increase overall port security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c666-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> improved container design, including blast-resistant containers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c667-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> methods to improve security and sustainability of port facilities in the event of a maritime transportation security incident, including specialized inspection facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c668-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of technology.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c669-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conjunction with ongoing efforts to improve security at United States ports, the Secretary may conduct pilot projects at United States ports to test the effectiveness and applicability of new port security projects, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c66a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> testing of new detection and screening technologies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c66b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> projects to protect United States ports and infrastructure on or adjacent to the navigable waters of the United States, including underwater access; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c66c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> tools for responding to a transportation security incident at United States ports and infrastructure on or adjacent to the navigable waters of the United States, including underwater access.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c66d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2009 to carry out this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c66e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National port security centers.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c66f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may make grants or enter into cooperative agreements with eligible nonprofit institutions of higher learning to conduct investigations in collaboration with ports and the maritime transportation industry focused on enhancing security of the Nation’s ports in accordance with this subsection through National Port Security Centers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c670-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading><content>To be eligible to receive a grant under this paragraph, a nonprofit institution of higher learning, or a consortium of such institutions, shall submit an application to the Secretary in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c671-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Competitive selection process</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall select grant recipients under this paragraph through a competitive process on the basis of the following criteria:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c672-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Whether the applicant can demonstrate that personnel, laboratory, and organizational resources will be available to the applicant to carry out the investigations authorized in this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c673-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The applicant’s capability to provide leadership in making national and regional contributions to the solution of immediate and long-range port and maritime transportation security and risk mitigation problems.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c674-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Whether the applicant can demonstrate that the applicant has an established, nationally recognized program in disciplines that contribute directly to maritime transportation safety and education.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c675-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Whether the applicant’s investigations will involve major United States ports on the East Coast, the Gulf Coast, and the West Coast, and Federal agencies and other entities with expertise in port and maritime transportation.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf704c676-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/3/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Whether the applicant has a strategic plan for carrying out the proposed investigations under the grant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c677-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative provisions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c678-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No duplication of effort</inline>.—</heading><content>Before making any grant, the Secretary shall coordinate with other Federal agencies to ensure the grant will not duplicate work already being conducted with Federal funding.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c679-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Accounting</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall by regulation establish accounting, reporting, and review procedures to ensure that funds made available under paragraph (1) are used for the purpose for which they were made available, that all expenditures are properly accounted for, and that amounts not used for such purposes and amounts not expended are recovered.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf704c67a-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recordkeeping</inline>.—</heading><content>Recipients of grants shall keep all records related to expenditures and obligations of funds provided under paragraph (1) and make them available upon request to the Inspector General of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and the Secretary for audit and examination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf704c67b-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s70107/m/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual review and report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Inspector General of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall annually review the programs established under this subsection to ensure that the expenditures and obligations of funds are consistent with the purposes for which they are provided, and report the findings to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf704c67c-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/295/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 107–295, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2075">116 Stat. 2075</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/tVIII">Pub. L. 108–293, title VIII</ref>, §§ 804(a), (b), 808(a), <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1081">118 Stat. 1081</ref>, 1083; <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/tI/s112">Pub. L. 109–347, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1894">120 Stat. 1894</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tVIII/s828/b">Pub. L. 111–281, title VIII, § 828(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3007">124 Stat. 3007</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/120/tIII/s306/a/10">Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 306(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-08">Feb. 8, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/54">130 Stat. 54</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dG/tLVXXXIII">Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII</ref> [LXXXIII], § 8314(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4699">134 Stat. 4699</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf704c67d-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf704c67e-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf704c67f-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the SAFE Port Act, referred to in subsec. (h), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/109/347">Pub. L. 109–347</ref>, which was approved <date date="2006-10-13">Oct. 13, 2006</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this Act, referred to in subsec. (k)(1), probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/295">Pub. L. 107–295</ref>, which enacted this section and was approved <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (k)(1)(B)(iii), probably means the Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002, which enacted this subtitle, see note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">With respect to “transportation security cards required by section 70105”, referred to in subsec. (k)(1)(B)(iv), amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> to <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70105">section 70105 of this title</ref> are such that section 70105 now refers to “transportation worker identification credential” rather than “transportation security card”. See <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70105">section 70105 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (k)(3)(D), is <ref href="/us/pl/107/295">Pub. L. 107–295</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2064">116 Stat. 2064</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf704c680-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s8314/1/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 8314(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “public safety personnel” for “law enforcement personnel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s8314/1/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 8314(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “public safety personnel—” for “law enforcement personnel—” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s8314/1/C">Pub. L. 116–283, § 8314(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “public safety personnel” for “law enforcement agency personnel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/120/s306/a/10/A">Pub. L. 114–120, § 306(a)(10)(A)</ref>, substituted “5196(j)(8)),” for “5121(j)(8)),” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(3)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/120/s306/a/10/B">Pub. L. 114–120, § 306(a)(10)(B)</ref>, substituted “that the applicant” for “that is”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/s828/b/1">Pub. L. 111–281, § 828(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “services and to train law enforcement personnel under <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s70132">section 70132 of this title</ref>.” for “services.” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/s828/b/2">Pub. L. 111–281, § 828(b)(2)</ref>, added par.(8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/s828/b/3">Pub. L. 111–281, § 828(b)(3)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/s828/b/4">Pub. L. 111–281, § 828(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “2013” for “2011”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/a">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(a)</ref>, (e), substituted “for the allocation of funds based on risk” for “for making a fair and equitable allocation of funds” and “national economic, energy, and strategic defense concerns based upon the most current risk assessments available” for “national economic and strategic defense concerns”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/b/1">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(b)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “Grants awarded under this section may not be used to construct buildings or other physical facilities, except those which are constructed under terms and conditions consistent with the requirements under section 611(j)(8) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/j/8">42 U.S.C. 5121(j)(8)</ref>), including those facilities in support of this paragraph, and specifically approved by the Secretary. Costs eligible for funding under this paragraph may not exceed the greater of—” and subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/b/2">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(b)(2)</ref>, added pars. (5) to (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/c/1">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(c)(1)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) to (h). Former subsecs. (e) to (i) redesignated (i) to (m), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/c/2">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary shall require” for “program shall require”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j), (k). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/c/1">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (f) and (g) as (j) and (k), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/d">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(d)</ref>, amended subsec. (<i>l</i>) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (<i>l</i>) read as follows: “There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for each of fiscal years 2003 through 2008 such sums as are necessary to carry out subsections (a) through (g).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/c/1">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/109/347/s112/c/1">Pub. L. 109–347, § 112(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/s804/a">Pub. L. 108–293, § 804(a)</ref>, reenacted heading without change and amended text of subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Maritime Administrator, shall establish a grant program for making a fair and equitable allocation among port authorities, facility operators, and State and local agencies required to provide security services of funds to implement Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and facility security plans. The program shall take into account national economic and strategic defense considerations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/s804/b/1">Pub. L. 108–293, § 804(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary determines” for “Secretary of Transportation determines”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/s804/b/1">Pub. L. 108–293, § 804(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Secretary of Transportation” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/s804/b">Pub. L. 108–293, § 804(b)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Secretary of Transportation” in two places and “department in which the Coast Guard is operating” for “Department of Transportation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/s804/b/1">Pub. L. 108–293, § 804(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Secretary of Transportation” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/293/s808/a">Pub. L. 108–293, § 808(a)</ref>, added subsec. (i) and struck out former subsec. (i) which related to research and development grants for port security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf704c681-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf704c682-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/293/tVIII/s804/c">Pub. L. 108–293, title VIII, § 804(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1081">118 Stat. 1081</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/293/tVIII/s804/c">
<inline>“Subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section]—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall take effect <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall not affect any grant made before that date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idf704c683-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
