<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf683fcb5-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s8107"><num value="8107">§ 8107.</num><heading> Use of force against piracy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf683fcb6-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s8107/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Liability</inline>.—</heading><content>An owner, operator, time charterer, master, mariner, or individual who uses force or authorizes the use of force to defend a vessel of the United States against an act of piracy shall not be liable for monetary damages for any injury or death caused by such force to any person engaging in an act of piracy if such force was in accordance with standard rules for the use of force in self-defense of vessels prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf683fcb7-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s8107/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Promotion of Coordinated Action</inline>.—</heading><content>To carry out the purpose of this section, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall work through the International Maritime Organization to establish agreements to promote coordinated action among flag- and port-states to deter, protect against, and rapidly respond to piracy against the vessels of, and in the waters under the jurisdiction of, those nations, and to ensure limitations on liability similar to those established by subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idf683fcb8-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5" identifier="/us/usc/t46/s8107/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purpose of this section, the term “act of piracy” means any act of aggression, search, restraint, depredation, or seizure attempted against a vessel of the United States by an individual not authorized by the United States, a foreign government, or an international organization recognized by the United States to enforce law on the high seas.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf683fcb9-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tIX/s912/a">Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 912(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3016">124 Stat. 3016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf683fcba-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf683fcbb-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf683fcbc-2930-11f1-96a8-b9bd2a0a99b5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Standard Rules for the Use of Force for Self-Defense of Vessels of the United States</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/281/tIX/s912/c">Pub. L. 111–281, title IX, § 912(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3017">124 Stat. 3017</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/281/tIX/s912/c">“Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this act [<date date="2010-10-15">Oct. 15, 2010</date>], the secretary [sic] of the department in which the coast guard [sic] is operating, in consultation with representatives of industry and labor, shall develop standard rules for the use of force for self-defense of vessels of the United States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
