<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddccd6e24-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1105"><num value="1105">§ 1105.</num><heading> John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Development Trust Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccd6e25-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1105/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Development Trust Fund”. The fund shall consist of amounts appropriated to it pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1110">section 1110 of this title</ref> and amounts credited to it under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccd6e26-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1105/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment of fund assets</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddccd6e27-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1105/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> At the request of the Center, it shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury to invest in full the amounts appropriated to the fund. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States issued directly to the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddccd6e28-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1105/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of special obligations directly to the fund. Such special obligations shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average rate of interest, computed as to the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of such issue, borne by all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt; except that where such average rate is not a multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum, the rate of interest of such special obligations shall be the multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum next lower than such average rate. All requests of the Center to the Secretary of the Treasury provided for in this section shall be binding upon the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccd6e29-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1105/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to sell obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the request of the Center, the Secretary of the Treasury shall redeem any obligation issued directly to the fund. Obligations issued to the fund under subsection (b)(2) shall be redeemed at par plus accrued interest. Any other obligations issued directly to the fund shall be redeemed at the market price.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccd6e2a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1105/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Proceeds from certain transactions credited to fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to the appropriations received pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1110">section 1110 of this title</ref>, the interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the fund pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1108/a">section 1108(a) of this title</ref>, shall be credited to and form a part of the fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddccd6e2b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/458/tI/s116">Pub. L. 100–458, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2174">102 Stat. 2174</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/tIII/s313/a">Pub. L. 101–520, title III, § 313(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2282">104 Stat. 2282</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dJ/tI/s125">Pub. L. 108–7, div. J, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/439">117 Stat. 439</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddccd6e2c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddccd6e2d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddccd6e2e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s125/1">Pub. L. 108–7, § 125(1)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (b). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) It shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury to invest in full the amounts appropriated to the fund. Such investments may be made only in interest bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States. For such purpose, such obligations may be acquired on original issue at the issue price or by purchase of outstanding obligations at the marketplace.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of special obligations exclusively to the fund. Such special obligations shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average rate of interest, computed as to the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of such issue, borne by all marketable interest bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt, except that when such average rate is not a multiple of one-eighth of one percent, the rate of interest of such special obligations shall be the multiple of one-eighth of one percent next lower than such average rate. Such special obligations shall be issued only if the Secretary determines that the purchase of other interest bearing obligations of the United States, or of obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States or original issue or at the market price, is not in the public interest.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s125/2">Pub. L. 108–7, § 125(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “Any obligation acquired by the fund (except special obligations issued exclusively to the fund) may be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price, and such special obligations may be redeemed at par plus accrued interest.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/520">Pub. L. 101–520</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the fund shall be credited to and form a part of the fund.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
