<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcd49a7d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351"><num value="1351">§ 1351.</num><heading> Application of chapter 71 of title 5 relating to Federal service labor-management relations; procedures for remedy of violations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a7e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Labor-management rights</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a7f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The rights, protections, and responsibilities established under sections 7102, 7106, 7111 through 7117, 7119 through 7122, and 7131 of title 5 shall apply to employing offices and to covered employees and representatives of those employees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a80-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of the application under this section of the sections referred to in paragraph (1), the term “agency” shall be deemed to include an employing office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a81-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” does not include an employee of the Library of Congress, and the term “employing office” does not include the Library of Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a82-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Remedy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy, including a remedy under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7118/a/7">section 7118(a)(7) of title 5</ref>, as would be appropriate if awarded by the Federal Labor Relations Authority to remedy a violation of any provision made applicable by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a83-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorities and procedures for implementation and enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a84-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General authorities of Board; petitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section and except as otherwise provided in this section, the Board shall exercise the authorities of the Federal Labor Relations Authority under sections 7105, 7111, 7112, 7113, 7115, 7117, 7118, and 7122 of title 5 and of the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7103/b">section 7103(b) of title 5</ref>. For purposes of this section, any petition or other submission that, under chapter 71 of title 5, would be submitted to the Federal Labor Relations Authority shall, if brought under this section, be submitted to the Board. The Board shall refer any matter under this paragraph to a hearing officer for decision pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1405">section 1405 of this title</ref>, subject to review by the Board pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1406">section 1406 of this title</ref>. The Board may direct that the General Counsel carry out the Board’s investigative authorities under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a85-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> General authorities of the General Counsel; charges of unfair labor practice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section and except as otherwise provided in this section, the General Counsel shall exercise the authorities of the General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority under sections 7104 and 7118 of title 5. For purposes of this section, any charge or other submission that, under chapter 71 of title 5, would be submitted to the General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority shall, if brought under this section, be submitted to the General Counsel. If any person charges an employing office or a labor organization with having engaged in or engaging in an unfair labor practice and makes such charge within 180 days of the occurrence of the alleged unfair labor practice, the General Counsel shall investigate the charge and may file a complaint with the Office. The complaint shall be submitted to a hearing officer for decision pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1405">section 1405 of this title</ref>, subject to review by the Board pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1406">section 1406 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a86-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except for matters referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7123/a">section 7123(a) of title 5</ref>, the General Counsel or the respondent to the complaint, if aggrieved by a final decision of the Board under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, may file a petition for judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1407">section 1407 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a87-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Exercise of impasses panel authority; requests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section and except as otherwise provided in this section, the Board shall exercise the authorities of the Federal Service Impasses Panel under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7119">section 7119 of title 5</ref>. For purposes of this section, any request that, under chapter 71 of title 5, would be presented to the Federal Service Impasses Panel shall, if made under this section, be presented to the Board. At the request of the Board, the Executive Director shall appoint a mediator or mediators to perform the functions of the Federal Service Impasses Panel under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7119">section 7119 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a88-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations to implement section</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a89-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board shall, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1384">section 1384 of this title</ref>, issue regulations to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a8a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency regulations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (e), the regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Federal Labor Relations Authority to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a8b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a8c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> as the Board deems necessary to avoid a conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a8d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific regulations regarding application to certain offices of Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a8e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations required</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board shall issue regulations pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1384">section 1384 of this title</ref> on the manner and extent to which the requirements and exemptions of chapter 71 of title 5 should apply to covered employees who are employed in the offices listed in paragraph (2). The regulations shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be consistent with the provisions and purposes of chapter 71 of title 5 and of this chapter, and shall be the same as substantive regulations issued by the Federal Labor Relations Authority under chapter 71 of title 5, except—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a8f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to the extent that the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a90-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> that the Board shall exclude from coverage under this section any covered employees who are employed in offices listed in paragraph (2) if the Board determines that such exclusion is required because of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcd49a91-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcd49a92-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Congress’ constitutional responsibilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a93-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Offices referred to</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The offices referred to in paragraph (1) include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a94-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the personal office of any Member of the House of Representatives or of any Senator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a95-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a standing, select, special, permanent, temporary, or other committee of the Senate or House of Representatives, or a joint committee of Congress;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a96-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Office of the Vice President (as President of the Senate), the Office of the President pro tempore of the Senate, the Office of the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Office of the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Office of the Majority Whip of the Senate, the Office of the Minority Whip of the Senate, the Conference of the Majority of the Senate, the Conference of the Minority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary of the Conference of the Majority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary of the Conference of the Minority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary for the Majority of the Senate, the Office of the Secretary for the Minority of the Senate, the Majority Policy Committee of the Senate, the Minority Policy Committee of the Senate, and the following offices within the Office of the Secretary of the Senate: Offices of the Parliamentarian, Bill Clerk, Legislative Clerk, Journal Clerk, Executive Clerk, Enrolling Clerk, Official Reporters of Debate, Daily Digest, Printing Services, Captioning Services, and Senate Chief Counsel for Employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a97-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the Office of the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Office of the Majority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Office of the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Offices of the Chief Deputy Majority Whips, the Offices of the Chief Deputy Minority Whips and the following offices within the Office of the Clerk of the House of Representatives: Offices of Legislative Operations, Official Reporters of Debate, Official Reporters to Committees, Printing Services, and Legislative Information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a98-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the Senate, the Office of the Senate Legal Counsel, the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the House of Representatives, the Office of the General Counsel of the House of Representatives, the Office of the Parliamentarian of the House of Representatives, and the Office of the Law Revision Counsel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a99-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the offices of any caucus or party organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a9a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the Congressional Budget Office, the Office of Technology Assessment, and the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcd49a9b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/e/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> such other offices that perform comparable functions which are identified under regulations of the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a9c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a9d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective on <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcd49a9e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1351/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain offices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to the offices listed in subsection (e)(2), to the covered employees of such offices, and to representatives of such employees, subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective on the effective date of regulations under subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcd49a9f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/1/tII/s220">Pub. L. 104–1, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/19">109 Stat. 19</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dI/tI/s153/a/1/C">Pub. L. 115–141, div. I, title I, § 153(a)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/785">132 Stat. 785</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/397/tIII/s308/b/10">Pub. L. 115–397, title III, § 308(b)(10)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5326">132 Stat. 5326</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcd49aa0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcd49aa1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcd49aa2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (e)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/104/1">Pub. L. 104–1</ref>, <date date="1995-01-23">Jan. 23, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/3">109 Stat. 3</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1301">section 1301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcd49aa3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s153/a/1/C/i">Pub. L. 115–141, § 153(a)(1)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “Application” for “Definition” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/141/s153/a/1/C/ii">Pub. L. 115–141, § 153(a)(1)(C)(ii)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/115/397">Pub. L. 115–397</ref> substituted “Office of Congressional Workplace Rights” for “Office of Compliance”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcd49aa4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcd49aa5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/397">Pub. L. 115–397</ref> effective <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, and any reference to the Office of Compliance in any law, rule, regulation, or other official paper in effect as of such date to be considered to refer and apply to the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/397/s308/d">section 308(d) of Pub. L. 115–397</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1381">section 1381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcd49aa6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Senate Democratic Leadership Offices Funding and Authorities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to the Office of the Secretary of the majority or minority conference of the Senate, as applicable, that represents the Democratic party deemed to be a reference to the office of the designated officer of the applicable conference, under certain conditions during the 118th and any subsequent Congress, see <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s6161">section 6161 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
