<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc839434-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141"><num value="141">§ 141.</num><heading> Allocation of responsibilities for Library buildings and grounds</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc839435-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Architect of the Capitol</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc839436-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Architect of the Capitol shall have charge of all work at the Library of Congress buildings and grounds (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s167j">section 167j of this title</ref>) that affects—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc839437-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the structural integrity of the buildings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc839438-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> buildings systems, including mechanical, electrical, plumbing, and elevators;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc839439-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the architectural features of the buildings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc83943a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> compliance with building and fire codes, laws, and regulations with respect to the specific responsibilities set for <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002003"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “forth”.</note> under this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc83943b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the care and maintenance of Library grounds; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddc83943c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> purchase of all equipment necessary to fulfill the responsibilities set forth under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddc83943d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The employees required for the performance of the duties under paragraph (1) shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc83943e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Librarian of Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Librarian of Congress shall have charge of all work (other than work under subsection (a)) at the Library of Congress buildings and grounds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc83943f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s141/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol and the Librarian of Congress may enter into agreements with each other to perform work under this section, and, subject to the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Joint Committee on the Library, may transfer between themselves appropriations or other available funds to pay the costs therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc839440-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1922-06-29/ch251/s1">June 29, 1922, ch. 251, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/715">42 Stat. 715</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/280">Pub. L. 91–280</ref>, <date date="1970-06-12">June 12, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/309">84 Stat. 309</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/tII/s205/b">Pub. L. 101–520, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2272">104 Stat. 2272</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/562/s2/a">Pub. L. 101–562, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2780">104 Stat. 2780</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dH/tI/s1208/a">Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1208(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/375">117 Stat. 375</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc839441-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc839442-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc839443-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—<ref href="/us/pl/108/7">Pub. L. 108–7</ref> inserted section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Architect of the Capitol shall have charge of all structural work at the Library of Congress buildings and grounds (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s167j">section 167j of this title</ref>), including all necessary repairs, the operation, maintenance, and repair of the mechanical plant and elevators, the care and maintenance of the grounds, and the purchasing of all equipment other than office equipment. The employees required for the performance of the foregoing duties shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol. All other duties on <date date="1922-06-29">June 29, 1922</date>, required to be performed by the Superintendent of the Library Building and Grounds shall be performed under the direction of the Librarian of Congress, who shall appoint the employees necessary therefor. The Librarian of Congress shall provide for the purchase and supply of office equipment and furniture for library purposes.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/520">Pub. L. 101–520</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/101/562">Pub. L. 101–562</ref> made substantively identical amendments, substituting reference to the Library of Congress buildings and grounds (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s167j">section 167j of this title</ref>) for reference to the Library Building and on the grounds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/280">Pub. L. 91–280</ref> substituted “purchasing of all equipment other than office equipment” for “purchasing and supplying of all furniture and equipment for the building” in second sentence and inserted sentence at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc85dd34-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc85dd35-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dH/tI/s1208/b">Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1208(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/376">117 Stat. 376</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/7/dH/tI/s1208/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s142">section 142 of this title</ref>] shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc85dd36-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/520">Pub. L. 101–520</ref> and 101–562 effective on date [<date date="1991-11-06">Nov. 6, 1991</date>] Architect of the Capitol acquires the property and improvements described in <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/s205/a">Pub. L. 101–520, § 205(a)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/101/562/s1">Pub. L. 101–562, § 1</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/s205/e">section 205(e) of Pub. L. 101–520</ref> and former <ref href="/us/pl/101/562/s2/d">section 2(d) of Pub. L. 101–562</ref>, set out as a Special Facilities Center; Acquisition note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd37-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acquisition of Real Property for Library of Congress</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/144">Pub. L. 105–144</ref>, <date date="1997-12-15">Dec. 15, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2667">111 Stat. 2667</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/2/tII/s207">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(2) [title II, § 207]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–114; <ref href="/us/pl/108/83/tI/s1203/a">Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 1203(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1031">117 Stat. 1031</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/83/tI/s1203/a">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> ACQUISITION OF FACILITY IN CULPEPER, VIRGINIA.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acquisition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Architect of the Capitol may acquire on behalf of the United States Government by transfer of title, without reimbursement or transfer of funds, the following property:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Three parcels totaling approximately 45 acres, more or less, located in Culpeper County, Virginia, and identified as Culpeper County Tax Parcel Numbers 51–80B, 51–80C, and 51–80D, further described as real estate (consisting of 40.949 acres) conveyed to David and Lucile Packard Foundation by deed from Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, dated <date date="1998-05-15">May 15, 1998</date>, and recorded <date date="1998-05-19">May 19, 1998</date>, in the Clerk’s Office, Circuit Court of Culpeper County, Virginia, in Deed Book 644, page 372; and real estate (consisting of 4.181 acres) conveyed to Packard Humanities Institute by deed from Russell H. Inskeep, dated <date date="2002-02-13">February 13, 2002</date>, and recorded <date date="2002-02-13">February 13, 2002</date>, in the Clerk’s Office, Circuit Court of Culpeper County, Virginia, as instrument number 020001299.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Improvements to such real property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Uses</inline>.—</heading><content>Effective on the date on which the Architect of the Capitol acquires the property under subsection (a), such property shall be available to the Librarian of Congress for use as a national audiovisual conservation center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer Payment by Architect</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the limitation on reimbursement or transfer of funds under subsection (a) of this section, the Architect of the Capitol may, not later than 90 days after acquisition of the property under this section, transfer funds to the entity from which the property was acquired by the Architect of the Capitol. Such transfers may not exceed a total of $16,500,000.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> LIBRARY BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS.</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" style="-uslm-lc:I21" id="iddc85dd38-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<p class="indent0">“[Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s167j">section 167j of this title</ref>.]</p></note>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> ACCEPTANCE OF TRANSFERRED GIFTS OR TRUST FUNDS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Gifts or trust funds given to the Library or the Library of Congress Trust Fund Board for the structural and mechanical work and refurbishment of Library buildings and grounds specified in section 1 shall be transferred to the Architect of the Capitol to be spent in accordance with the provisions of the first section of the Act of <date date="1922-06-29">June 29, 1922</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s141">2 U.S.C. 141</ref>).</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> FUND FOR TRANSFERRED FUNDS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund consisting of those gifts or trust funds transferred to the Architect of the Capitol under section 3. Upon prior approval of the Committee on House Oversight [now Committee on House Administration] of the House of Representatives and Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, amounts in the fund shall be available to the Architect of the Capitol, subject to appropriation, to remain available until expended, for the structural and mechanical work and refurbishment of Library buildings and grounds. Such funds shall be available for expenditure in fiscal year 1998, subject to the prior approval of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> EFFECTIVE DATE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the provisions of this Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-12-15">Dec. 15, 1997</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Inclusion of Property Within Library Buildings and Grounds</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by section 2 shall take effect upon the acquisition by the Architect of the Capitol of the property described in section 1.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd39-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Property by Secretary of Army To Provide Facilities To Accommodate Long-Term Storage and Service Needs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/110/s122">Pub. L. 103–110, § 122</ref>, <date date="1993-10-21">Oct. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1043">107 Stat. 1043</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/110/s122">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Army shall transfer, no later than <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>, without reimbursement or transfer of funds, to the Architect of the Capitol, a portion of the real property, including improvements thereon, consisting of not more than 100 acres located at Fort George G. Meade in Anne Arundel County, Maryland, as determined under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The Architect of the Capitol shall, upon completion of the survey performed pursuant to subsection (c) and the transfer effected pursuant to subsection (a), utilize the transferred property to provide facilities to accommodate the varied long-term storage and service needs of the Library of Congress and other Legislative Branch agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The exact acreage and legal description of the property to be transferred under this section shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Architect of the Capitol and the Secretary of the Army, and in consultation with officials of Anne Arundel County, Maryland.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> Any real property and improvements thereon transferred pursuant to this section shall be under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol, subject to the rules and regulations providing for the use of such property as may be approved by the House Office Building Commission and the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration: <i>Provided</i>, That any existing improvements made available by the Architect to the Librarian of Congress, under the direction of the Joint Committee on the Library, or hereafter erected upon such real property pursuant to law for the purposes of providing for the long-term storage and service needs of the Library of Congress shall be subject to the provisions of sections 136, 141 and 167 to 167j of title 2, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> Portions of the real property and any improvements thereon transferred pursuant to this section that are not determined to be immediately required for storage or service needs by the Architect are authorized to be leased temporarily to the Secretary of the Army: <i>Provided</i>, That nominal lease payments made by the Secretary of the Army shall be credited to the appropriation ‘Architect of the Capitol, Library Buildings and Grounds, Structural and Mechanical Care, No Year’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd3a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Facilities Center; Temporary Restriction on Evening Use</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/451/s4">Pub. L. 102–451, § 4</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2253">106 Stat. 2253</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/451/s4">“No evening meetings may be held at the Library of Congress Special Facilities Center until an on-site parking plan for the property is approved by the Joint Committee on the Library.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd3b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Facilities Center; Acquisition</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/520/tII/s205">Pub. L. 101–520, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2272">104 Stat. 2272</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/451">Pub. L. 102–451</ref>, §§ 1–3, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2253">106 Stat. 2253</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/451">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Architect of the Capitol may acquire on behalf of the United States Government by purchase, condemnation, transfer, or otherwise (1) all publicly or privately owned real property in lot 51 in square 869 in the District of Columbia, as that lot appears on the records in the office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia on <date date="1990-08-01">August 1, 1990</date>, extending to the outer face of the curbs of the square in which it is located and including all alleys or parts of alleys and streets within the lot lines and curb lines surrounding such real property, and (2) improvements to such real property. The property acquired under this section shall be known as the ‘Library of Congress Special Facilities Center’ (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Center’).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> [Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s141">section 141 of this title</ref>.]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The property and improvements acquired under subsection (a) shall be repaired and altered, to the maximum extent feasible as determined by the Architect of the Capitol, in compliance with one of the nationally recognized model building codes and with other applicable nationally recognized codes (including electrical codes, fire and life safety codes, plumbing codes, as determined appropriate by the Architect), using the latest edition of the nationally recognized codes referred to in this paragraph.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> [Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s167j">section 167j of this title</ref>.]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> Subsections (b) and (c) and the amendment made by subsection (d) shall take effect on the date [<date date="1991-11-06">Nov. 6, 1991</date>] the Architect of the Capitol acquires the property and improvements described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> There is authorized to be appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol $5,000,000 for carrying out the purposes of this section, to remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><chapeau> Effective on the date [<date date="1991-11-06">Nov. 6, 1991</date>] on which the Architect of the Capitol acquires the property known as St. Cecilia’s School (Lot 51 in square 869) in the District of Columbia, as provided by law, such property shall be available to the Librarian of Congress for use—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> as a day care center for children of employees of the Library of Congress and children of other employees of the legislative branch of the Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> for staff training and development for employees of the Library of Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> for external training;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> for general assembly and education programs of the Library;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> for temporary living quarters and common areas for visiting scholars using the collections of the Library or participating in the programs of the Library; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> for other purposes relating to the operations of the Library of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any use of such property shall be subject to approval by the Joint Committee on the Library, the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Librarian of Congress—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> may charge fees for use of the Center under paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of subsection (g); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> shall deposit the fees in the fund under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> There is established in the Treasury a fund which shall consist of amounts deposited under paragraph (1) and such other amounts as may be appropriated to the fund. The fund shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> available to the Librarian of Congress, in amounts specified in appropriations Acts, for the expenses of the Center; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> subject to audit by the Comptroller General at the discretion of the Comptroller General.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/101/562">Pub. L. 101–562</ref>, §§ 1, 2, 4, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2780">104 Stat. 2780</ref>, 2781, which was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/102/451/s5">Pub. L. 102–451, § 5</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2254">106 Stat. 2254</ref>, eff. <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd3c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Additional Building for Library of Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/86/469">Pub. L. 86–469</ref>, <date date="1960-05-14">May 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/132">74 Stat. 132</ref>, authorized Architect of the Capitol, under direction and supervision of Joint Committee on the Library, to prepare preliminary plans and estimates of cost for an additional building for Library of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd3d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tV/s5402">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title V, § 5402</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-511">110 Stat. 3009–511</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tV/s5402">“The Founders Hall instructional area in the House of Representatives Page School, located in the Thomas Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress, shall be known and designated as ‘Bill Emerson Hall’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/96/269/s1">Pub. L. 96–269, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-06-13">June 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/486">94 Stat. 486</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/269/s1">“That the building in the block bounded by East Capitol Street, Second Street Southeast, Independence Avenue Southeast, and First Street Southeast, in the District of Columbia (commonly known as the Library of Congress Building or the Library of Congress Main Building), shall hereafter be known and designated as the ‘Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building’. Any reference in any law, map, regulation, document, record, or other paper of the United States to such building shall be held to be a reference to the Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/264">Pub. L. 94–264</ref>, <date date="1976-04-13">Apr. 13, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/329">90 Stat. 329</ref>, which had designated the Library of Congress Annex as the Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/96/269/s3">Pub. L. 96–269, § 3</ref>, <date date="1980-06-13">June 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/486">94 Stat. 486</ref>, as part of the redesignation of that building as the Library of Congress John Adams Building and the designation of the main building of the Library of Congress as the Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd3e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Library of Congress John Adams Building</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/269/s2">Pub. L. 96–269, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-06-13">June 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/486">94 Stat. 486</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/269/s2">“The building in the block bounded by East Capitol Street, Second Street Southeast, Third Street Southeast, and Pennsylvania Avenue Southeast, in the District of Columbia (commonly known as the Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building or the Library of Congress Annex Building), shall hereafter be known and designated as the ‘Library of Congress John Adams Building’. Any reference in any law, map, regulation, document, record, or other paper of the United States to such building shall be held to be a reference to the Library of Congress John Adams Building.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc85dd3f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Library of Congress James Madison Memorial Building</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/214/s2">Pub. L. 91–214, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-03-16">Mar. 16, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/69">84 Stat. 69</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/214/s2">“Nothing contained in the Act of <date date="1965-10-19">October 19, 1965</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/79/986">79 Stat. 986</ref>) [set out as a note under this section], shall be construed to authorize the use of the third Library of Congress building authorized by such Act for general office building purposes.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/89/260">Pub. L. 89–260</ref>, <date date="1965-10-19">Oct. 19, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/987">79 Stat. 987</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/91/214/s1">Pub. L. 91–214, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-03-16">Mar. 16, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/69">84 Stat. 69</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/219">Pub. L. 94–219</ref>, <date date="1976-02-27">Feb. 27, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/194">90 Stat. 194</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/548">Pub. L. 95–548</ref>, <date date="1978-10-30">Oct. 30, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2064">92 Stat. 2064</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/548">

<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0 inline">“That </chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> the Architect of the Capitol under the direction jointly of the House Office Building Commission, the Senate Office Building Commission, and the Joint Committee on the Library, after consultation with a committee designated by the American Institute of Architects, is authorized and directed to construct (including, but not limited to, the preparation of all necessary designs, plans, and specifications) in square 732 in the District of Columbia a third Library of Congress fireproof building, which shall be known as the Library of Congress James Madison Memorial Building. The design of such building shall include a Madison Memorial Hall and shall be in keeping with the prevailing architecture of the Federal buildings on Capitol Hill. The Madison Memorial Hall shall be developed in consultation with the James Madison Memorial Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> In carrying out his authority under this joint resolution, the Architect of the Capitol, under the direction jointly of the House Office Building Commission, the Senate Office Building Commission, and the Joint Committee on the Library, is authorized (1) to provide for such equipment, such connections with the Capitol Power Plant and other utilities, such access facilities over or under public streets, such changes in the present Library of Congress buildings, such changes in or additions to the present tunnels, and such other appurtenant facilities, as may be necessary, and (2) to do such landscaping as may be necessary by reason of the construction authorized by this joint resolution.</content>
</subsection>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="2">“Sec. 2.</num><content> The structural and mechanical care of the building authorized by this joint resolution and the care of the surrounding grounds shall be under the Architect of the Capitol.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="3">“Sec. 3.</num><content> There is hereby authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $130,675,000 to construct the building authorized by this joint resolution (including the preparation of all necessary designs, plans, and specifications).<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“There is also authorized to be appropriated not exceeding $10,000 to pay the expenses of the James Madison Memorial Commission.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
