<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc85dd76-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s142f"><num value="142f">§ 142f.</num><heading> Office of Technology Assessment; disbursement of funds, computation and disbursement of basic pay, and provision of financial management support by Library of Congress</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">From and after <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, the Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress is authorized to disburse funds appropriated for the Office of Technology Assessment, and the Library of Congress shall provide financial management support to the Office of Technology Assessment as may be required and mutually agreed to by the Librarian of Congress and the Director of the Office of Technology Assessment. The Library of Congress is further authorized to compute and disburse the basic pay of all personnel of the Office of Technology Assessment pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5504">section 5504 of title 5</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All vouchers certified for payment by duly authorized certifying officers of the Library of Congress shall be supported with a certification by an officer or employee of the Office of Technology Assessment duly authorized in writing by the Director of the Office of Technology Assessment to certify payments from appropriations of the Office of Technology Assessment. The Office of Technology Assessment certifying officers shall (1) be held responsible for the existence and correctness of the facts recited in the certificate or otherwise stated on the voucher or its supporting paper and the legality of the proposed payment under the appropriation or fund involved, (2) be held responsible and accountable for the correctness of the computations of certifications made, and (3) be held accountable for and required to make good to the United States the amount of any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate made by him, as well as for any payment prohibited by law which did not represent a legal obligation under the appropriation or fund involved: <i>Provided</i>, That the Comptroller General of the United States may, at his discretion, relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for any payment otherwise proper whenever he finds (1) that the certification was based on official records and that such certifying officer or employee did not know, and by reasonable diligence and inquiry could not have ascertained the actual facts, or (2) that the obligation was incurred in good faith, that the payment was not contrary to any statutory provision specifically prohibiting payments of the character involved, and the United States has received value for such payment: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Comptroller General shall relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for an overpayment for transportation services made to any common carrier covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3726">section 3726 of title 31</ref>, whenever he finds that the overpayment occurred solely because of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002004"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “of” probably should not appear.</note> the administrative examination made prior to payment of the transportation bill did not include a verification of transportation rates, freight classifications, or land grant deductions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Disbursing Officer of the Library of Congress shall not be held accountable or responsible for any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate, the responsibility for which is imposed upon a certifying officer or employee of the Office of Technology Assessment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddc85dd77-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/51/s101/c">Pub. L. 97–51, § 101(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/959">95 Stat. 959</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc85dd78-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc85dd79-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddc85dd7a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In the second par., “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3726">section 3726 of title 31</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s244">section 244 of title 31</ref>” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on section 205 of title II of H.R. 4120, as reported <date date="1981-07-09">July 9, 1981</date>, and incorporated by reference in <ref href="/us/pl/97/51/s101/c">section 101(c) of Pub. L. 97–51</ref>, to be effective as if enacted into law.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
