<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc884f10-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s158a"><num value="158a">§ 158a.</num><heading> Temporary possession of gifts of money or securities to Library of Congress; investment</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a gift of money or securities offered to the Library of Congress, if, because of conditions attached by the donor or similar considerations, expedited action is necessary, the Librarian of Congress may take temporary possession of the gift, subject to approval under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s156">section 156 of this title</ref>. The gift shall be receipted for and invested, reinvested, or retained as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s157">section 157 of this title</ref>, except that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc884f11-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s158a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a gift of securities may not be invested or reinvested; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc884f12-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s158a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any investment or reinvestment of a gift of money shall be made in an interest bearing obligation of the United States or an obligation guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the gift is not so approved within the 12-month period after the Librarian so takes possession, the principal of the gift shall be returned to the donor and any income earned during that period shall be available for use with respect to the Library of Congress as provided by law.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="iddc884f13-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1925-03-03/ch423/s2">Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 423, § 2</ref> (par.), as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/246/s3">Pub. L. 102–246, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-02-18">Feb. 18, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/31">106 Stat. 31</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc884f14-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc884f15-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddc884f16-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of fourth par. of section 2 of act <date date="1925-03-03">Mar. 3, 1925</date>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/246">Pub. L. 102–246</ref>. First, second, and third pars. of section 2 are classified to sections 156, 157, and 158 of this title, respectively.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
