<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcea1df2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1833"><num value="1833">§ 1833.</num><heading> Lighting, heating, and ventilating House of Representatives</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The electrician, together with everything pertaining to the electrical machinery and apparatus, and the ventilation and heating of the House of Representatives, and all laborers and others connected with the lighting, heating, and ventilating thereof, shall be subject exclusively to the orders, and in all respects under the direction, of the Architect of the Capitol, subject to the control of the Speaker; and no removal or appointment shall be made except with his approval. And all engineers and others who are engaged in heating and ventilating the House shall be subject to the orders, and in all respects under the direction, of the Architect of the Capitol, subject to the control of the Speaker; and no removal or appointment shall be made except with his approval.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddcea1df3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1877-03-03/ch105">Mar. 3, 1877, ch. 105</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/19/348">19 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1881-03-03/ch130/s1">Mar. 3, 1881, ch. 130, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/21/388">21 Stat. 388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcea1df4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcea1df5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcea1df6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 167 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section, except the words “and the ventilation and heating of the House of Representatives,” is based on act <date date="1881-03-03">Mar. 3, 1881</date>, popularly known as the “Legislative, Executive, and Judicial Appropriation Act”. The excepted words were based on act <date date="1877-03-03">Mar. 3, 1877</date>, popularly known as the “Sundry Civil Appropriation Act, fiscal year 1878”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcea1df7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddcea1df8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Change of name of Architect of the Capitol, functions abolished, transferred, etc., by prior acts, see Prior Provisions and Change of Name notes set out under former <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
