<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc91ec35-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s190d"><num value="190d">§ 190d.</num><heading> Legislative review by standing committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc91ec36-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s190d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to assist the Congress in—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc91ec37-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s190d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> its analysis, appraisal, and evaluation of the application, administration, and execution of the laws enacted by the Congress, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc91ec38-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s190d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> its formulation, consideration, and enactment of such modifications of or changes in those laws, and of such additional legislation, as may be necessary or appropriate,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">each standing committee of the Senate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002016"><num>1</num> See Partial Repeal note below.</note> and the House of Representatives shall review and study, on a continuing basis, the application, administration, and execution of those laws, or parts of laws, the subject matter of which is within the jurisdiction of that committee. Such committees may carry out the required analysis, appraisal, and evaluation themselves, or by contract, or may require a Government agency to do so and furnish a report thereon to the Congress. Such committees may rely on such techniques as pilot testing, analysis of costs in comparison with benefits, or provision for evaluation after a defined period of time.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc91ec39-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s190d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to the Senate and the House of Representatives</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In each odd-numbered year beginning on or after <date date="1973-01-01">January 1, 1973</date>, each standing committee of the Senate shall submit, not later than March 31, to the Senate,<sup>1</sup> and each standing committee of the House shall submit, not later than January 2, to the House, a report on the activities of that committee under this section during the Congress ending at noon on January 3 of such year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc91ec3a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s190d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The preceding provisions of this section do not apply to the Committees on Appropriations and the Budget of the Senate <sup>1</sup> and the Committees on Appropriations, the Budget, House Oversight, Rules, and Standards of Official Conduct of the House.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc91ec3b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/ch753">Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, title I, § 136, <ref href="/us/stat/60/832">60 Stat. 832</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/510/tI/s118/a/1">Pub. L. 91–510, title I, § 118(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1156">84 Stat. 1156</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/136/s1">Pub. L. 92–136, § 1</ref>, <date date="1971-10-11">Oct. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/376">85 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 93–344, title VII, § 701</ref>, title IX, § 903(b), <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/325">88 Stat. 325</ref>, 331; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s206/1">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 206(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1742">110 Stat. 1742</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc91ec3c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc91ec3d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc91ec3e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186">Pub. L. 104–186</ref> substituted “House Oversight” for “House Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/344/s701">Pub. L. 93–344, § 701</ref>, authorized the committees to carry out the required analysis, appraisal, and evaluation themselves, or by contract, or to require a Government agency to do so and furnish a report thereon to the Congress, and authorized the committees to rely on such techniques as pilot testing, analysis of costs in comparison with benefits, or provision for evaluation after a defined period of time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/344/s903/b">Pub. L. 93–344, § 903(b)</ref>, substituted “Committees on Appropriations and the Budget of the Senate and the Committees on Appropriations, the Budget,” for “Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/136">Pub. L. 92–136</ref> substituted “Congress” for “Senate” in provisions preceding cl. (1) and inserted reference to the House of Representatives in provisions following cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/92/136">Pub. L. 92–136</ref> substituted “In each odd-numbered year beginning on or after <date date="1973-01-01">January 1, 1973</date>, each” for “Each” and “March 31, to the Senate, and each standing committee of the House shall submit, not later than January 2, to the House,” for “March 31 of each odd-numbered year beginning on and after <date date="1973-01-01">January 1, 1973</date>, to the Senate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/136">Pub. L. 92–136</ref> inserted reference to Committees on Appropriations, House Administration, Rules, and Standards of Official Conduct of the House.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/510">Pub. L. 91–510</ref> incorporated existing subject matter in provisions designated as subsec. (a), restricted the text to standing committees of Senate, revised phraseology to require standing committees to review and study, on a continuing basis, application, administration, and execution of laws and parts of laws for prior provision for exercise of continuous watchfulness of execution of laws by administrative agencies concerned, and in providing for assistance to the Senate, rather than the Congress, included analysis and evaluation of laws enacted by Congress and substituted provision for formulation, consideration, and enactment of modifications or changes in the laws and of additional legislation as necessary or appropriate for prior provisions for assistance in developing amendments or related legislation as may be necessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/510">Pub. L. 91–510</ref> added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc91ec3f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddc91ec40-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on House Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on House Administration of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>. Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Ethics of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Twelfth Congress, <date date="2011-01-05">Jan. 5, 2011</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc91ec41-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1971 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/136/s9/a">Pub. L. 92–136, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-10-11">Oct. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/378">85 Stat. 378</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/136/s9/a">“The amendments made by the first section [amending this section] section 2, and section 5 of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>] shall become effective as of noon on <date date="1971-01-03">January 3, 1971</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc91ec42-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/510">Pub. L. 91–510</ref> effective immediately prior to noon on <date date="1971-01-03">Jan. 3, 1971</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/510/s601/1">section 601(1) of Pub. L. 91–510</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddc91ec43-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1947-01-02">Jan. 2, 1947</date>, see section 142 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/ch753/tI">act Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753, title I</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/834">60 Stat. 834</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc91ec44-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Partial Repeal</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2(a), S. Res. 274, Ninety-sixth Congress, <date date="1979-11-14">Nov. 14, 1979</date>, provided in part that this section, insofar as it relates to the Senate, is repealed. See Standing Rules of the Senate.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
