<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcf39434-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1954"><num value="1954">§ 1954.</num><heading> Administration by Capitol Police Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf39435-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1954/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Capitol Police Board shall administer and manage the Fund (including establishing the timing and manner of making payments under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1952">section 1952 of this title</ref>) in accordance with regulations issued by the Board, subject to the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives. Under such regulations, the Board shall pay any balance remaining in the Fund upon the expiration of the 6-month period which begins on <date date="1998-08-07">August 7, 1998</date>, to the families of Detective John Michael Gibson and Private First Class Jacob Joseph Chestnut in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1952">section 1952 of this title</ref>, and shall disburse any amounts in the Fund after the expiration of such period in such manner as the Board may establish. Under such regulations, and using amounts in the Fund, a financial adviser or trustee, as appropriate, for the families of Detective John Michael Gibson and Private First Class Jacob Joseph Chestnut of the United States Capitol Police shall be appointed to advise the families respecting disbursements to them of amounts in the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcf39436-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1954/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations governing payments for employees killed in the line of duty or sustaining serious line-of-duty injuries</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Capitol Police Board shall issue specific regulations governing the use of the Fund for making payments to families of employees of the United States Capitol Police who were killed in the line of duty and employees of the United States Capitol Police who have sustained serious line-of-duty injuries (as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1952/b">section 1952(b) of this title</ref>), including regulations—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf39437-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1954/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establishing the conditions under which the family of an employee or an employee is eligible to receive such a payment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf39438-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1954/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing for the amount, timing, and manner of such payments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcf39439-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s1954/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> ensuring that any such payment is in addition to, and does not otherwise affect, any other form of compensation payable to the family of an employee or the employee, including benefits for workers’ compensation under chapter 81 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcf3943a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/223/s4">Pub. L. 105–223, § 4</ref>, <date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1250">112 Stat. 1250</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/45/s2/b">Pub. L. 115–45, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-04">Aug. 4, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/956">131 Stat. 956</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcf3943b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcf3943c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcf3943d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 207c–3 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcf3943e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—<ref href="/us/pl/115/45">Pub. L. 115–45</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcf3943f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddcf39440-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on House Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on House Administration of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
