<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcfac008-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2025"><num value="2025">§ 2025.</num><heading> Senate Garage</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcfac009-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2025/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The employees of the Senate garage engaged by the Architect of the Capitol for the primary purpose of servicing official motor vehicles, together with the functions performed by such employees, shall, on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, be transferred to the jurisdiction of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate: <i>Provided further</i>, That, effective <date date="1965-07-01">July 1, 1965</date>, the underground space in the north extension of the Capitol Grounds, known as the Legislative Garage shall hereafter be known as the Senate Garage and shall be under the jurisdiction and control of the Architect of the Capitol, subject to such regulations respecting the use thereof as may be promulgated by the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration: <i>Provided further</i>, That, such regulations shall provide for the continued assignment of space and the continued furnishing of service in such garage for official motor vehicles of the House and the Senate and the Architect of the Capitol and Capitol Grounds maintenance equipment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcfac00a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2025/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> As used in subsection (a), the term “servicing” includes, with respect to an official motor vehicle, the washing and fueling of such vehicle, the checking of its tires and battery, and checking and adding oil.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcfac00b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1932-06-30/ch314">June 30, 1932, ch. 314</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/391">47 Stat. 391</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/454">Pub. L. 88–454</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/545">78 Stat. 545</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/444/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 96–444, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1889">94 Stat. 1889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfac00c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfac00d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcfac00e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 185a of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcfac00f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/444/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 96–444, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, designated existing provision as subsec. (a) and substituted provision transferring, on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, employees of the Senate garage engaged by the Architect of the Capitol for the primary purpose of servicing official motor vehicles, together with the functions performed by such employees, to the jurisdiction of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate for provision transferring, on <date date="1932-07-01">July 1, 1932</date>, employees engaged in the care and maintenance of the Senate garage to the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol, without any reduction in compensation to these employees as the result of such transfer.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/444/s1/b">Pub. L. 96–444, § 1(b)</ref>, added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—<ref href="/us/pl/88/454">Pub. L. 88–454</ref> redesignated the Legislative Garage as the Senate Garage, transferred the authority to promulgate rules from the Vice President and the Speaker of the House to the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, and directed that the regulations provide for the continued assignment of space and the continued furnishing of service for official motor vehicles of the House and the Senate and the Architect of the Capitol and Capitol Grounds maintenance equipment.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcfac010-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcfac011-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Availability of Appropriations for Expenses of Senate Garage</heading><p>Title I of S. 2939, Ninety-seventh Congress, 2d Session, as reported <date date="1982-09-22">Sept. 22, 1982</date>, and incorporated by reference in <ref href="/us/pl/97/276/s101/e">Pub. L. 97–276, § 101(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-02">Oct. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1189">96 Stat. 1189</ref>, to be effective as if enacted into law, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/276/s101/e">“That appropriations under this head <inline class="small-caps">[senate office buildings]</inline> shall hereafter be available for maintenance, alternations [alterations], personal and other services, and for all other necessary expenses of the Senate Garage as authorized by the paragraph beginning ‘Capitol Garages’ under the general heading ‘ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL’ in the first section of the Act entitled ‘An Act making appropriations for the Legislative Branch of the Government for the fiscal year ending <date date="1933-06-30">June 30, 1933</date>, and for other purposes’, approved <date date="1933-06-30">June 30, 1933</date> [1932] (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s185a">40 U.S.C. 185a</ref>) [now this section] and <ref href="/us/pl/96/444">Public Law 96–444</ref> [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and section 185a of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcfac012-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appointment of Garage Attendants; Compensation; Longevity Compensation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/444/s2">Pub. L. 96–444, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1889">94 Stat. 1889</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/444/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Effective <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of four garage attendants at not to exceed $14,100 per annum each.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> If, and to the extent that, positions established by subsection (a) are first filled by individuals transferred under subsection (a)(1) of the first section [amending subsec. (a) of this section], the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to fix, in lieu of the compensation prescribed in subsection (a), the compensation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> of not more than two of such positions so filled at not to exceed $16,560 per annum each;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> of one of such positions so filled at not to exceed $15,485 per annum; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> of one of such positions so filled at not to exceed $14,390 per annum.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Compensation fixed under this subsection for a position first filled by an individual transferred under subsection (a)(1) of the first section shall cease to be applicable with respect to such position on the date that such individual first ceases to occupy such position.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> During any period with respect to which subsection (b) is applicable to a position occupied by an individual described in such subsection, such individual shall be credited, for purposes of longevity compensation, as authorized by section 106(a), (b), and (d) of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1963 (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s60j">2 U.S.C. 60j</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s4507">2 U.S.C. 4507</ref>], for service performed by such individual in the position of garage attendant, as an employee of the Architect of the Capitol, as certified to the Secretary of the Senate by the Architect of the Capitol.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
