<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcfac021-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2041"><num value="2041">§ 2041.</num><heading> House of Representatives restaurant, cafeteria, and food services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac022-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2041/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Management and duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other authority with respect to the jurisdiction and control over the management of the House Restaurant and the cafeteria and other food service facilities of the House of Representatives, the jurisdiction over such restaurant and facilities and authority over the direction and supervision of the immediate management and operation thereof shall be vested in the Committee on House Oversight; and the immediate management and operation of such restaurant and facilities may be vested in such official or other authority, acting as the agent of the committee, as the committee may designate; and the official or authority so designated shall perform the duties vested in the Architect of the Capitol by section 208 of the First Supplemental Civil Functions Appropriation Act, 1941 (<ref href="/us/stat/54/1056">54 Stat. 1056</ref>; Public, No. 812, Seventy-sixth Congress).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac023-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2041/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of accounts, records, supplies, equipment, and assets</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Architect of the Capitol is hereby authorized and directed to transfer, as the Committee on House Oversight directs, all accounts, records, supplies, equipment, and assets of the House Restaurant and the cafeteria and other food service facilities of the House which are in the possession or under the control of the Architect of the Capitol in order that all such items may be available for the maintenance and operation of the House Restaurant under the authority of, and as directed by, the Committee on House Oversight.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac024-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2041/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Special deposit account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All authority, responsibility, and functions vested in or imposed upon the Architect of the Capitol in connection with the special deposit account established by section 208 of the First Supplemental Civil Functions Appropriation Act, 1941, shall be vested in or imposed upon such other official, authority, or authorities as the Committee on House Oversight may designate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfac025-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2041/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall become effective on the first day of the first calendar month beginning after the date of adoption of this resolution, until otherwise provided by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcfac026-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/51">Pub. L. 92–51</ref>, <date date="1971-07-09">July 9, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/133">85 Stat. 133</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s221/3/A">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 221(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1748">110 Stat. 1748</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfac027-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfac028-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcfac029-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 208 of the First Supplemental Civil Functions Appropriation Act, 1941, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), means section 208 of <ref href="/us/act/1940-10-09/ch780/tII">act Oct. 9, 1940, ch. 780, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1056">54 Stat. 1056</ref>, which was classified to section 174k of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s221/3/B">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 221(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1748">110 Stat. 1748</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of adoption of this resolution, referred to in subsec. (d), is <date date="1971-03-25">Mar. 25, 1971</date>. See Codification note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcfac02a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 174k of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on section 2 of House Resolution No. 317, Ninety-second Congress, <date date="1971-03-25">Mar. 25, 1971</date>, which was enacted into permanent law by <ref href="/us/pl/92/51">Pub. L. 92–51</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcfac02b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (a) to (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186">Pub. L. 104–186</ref> substituted “House Oversight” for “House Administration” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcfac02c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddcfac02d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on House Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on House Administration of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcfac02e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Deposit Account From Vending Operations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/53/tI/s107A">Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 107A</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/522">109 Stat. 522</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/197/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2400">110 Stat. 2400</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/197/tI/s101/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Subject to the direction of the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives, the amounts deposited in the account specified in subsection (b) from vending operations of the House of Representatives Restaurant System shall be available to pay the cost of goods sold for such operations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The account referred to in subsection (a) is the special deposit account established for the House of Representatives Restaurant by section 208 of the First Supplemental Civil Functions Appropriation Act, 1941 (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s174k">40 U.S.C. 174k</ref> note) [former <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s174k">40 U.S.C. 174k</ref>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/104/197/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 104–197, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-16">Sept. 16, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2401">110 Stat. 2401</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/197/tI/s101/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending <ref href="/us/pl/104/53/s107A">section 107A of Pub. L. 104–53</ref>, set out above] shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcfac02f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Food Service Operations; Election by Certain Affected Employees; Disability and Retirement Benefits; Promulgation of Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s111">Pub. L. 99–500, § 111</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-348">100 Stat. 1783–348</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s111">Pub. L. 99–591, § 111</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-348">100 Stat. 3341–348</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/591/s111">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> Any individual who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> on the day before the date on which food services operations for the House of Representatives are transferred by contract to a corporation or other person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is a congressional employee (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2107">section 2107 of title 5</ref>, United States Code), other than an employee of the Architect of the Capitol, engaged in providing such food services under the administrative control of the Architect of the Capitol; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is subject to subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5, United States Code, or chapter 84 of such title;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> as a result of such contract, ceases to be an employee described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> becomes employed to provide such food services under contract, including a successor contract;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may, for purposes of the provisions of law specified in subsection (b), elect to be treated, for so long as such individual continues to be employed (without a break in service) as described in paragraph (3), as if such individual had not ceased to be an employee described in paragraph (1). Such election shall be made on or before the day referred to in paragraph (1) and shall be available only to an individual whose transition from the employment described in paragraph (1) to the employment described in paragraph (3) takes place without a break in service.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The provisions of law referred to in subsection (a) are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5, United States Code (including section 8339(m) of such title (which shall be applied, when an employee retires on an immediate annuity or dies, as if the employment at the time of retirement or death were under a formal leave system), with respect to unused sick leave to the credit of an employee on the day referred to in subsection (a)(1));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> title III of the Federal Employees’ Retirement System Act of 1986 [sections 301 to 312 of <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref>, see Tables for classification].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> At the earliest practicable opportunity, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, in consultation with the Architect of the Capitol, prescribe regulations to carry out this section with respect to matters within the jurisdiction of the Office, including regulations under which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an individual who makes an election under subsection (a) shall pay into the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund any employee contributions which would be required if such individual were a Congressional employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the employer furnishing food services under a contract referred to in subsection (a) shall pay into the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund amounts equal to any agency contributions which would be required if the individual were a Congressional employee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> At the earliest practicable opportunity, the Executive Director of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board shall, in consultation with the Architect of the Capitol, prescribe regulations to carry out this section with respect to matters within the jurisdiction of the Board.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
