<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcfd303c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2044"><num value="2044">§ 2044.</num><heading> Special deposit account</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established with the Treasurer of the United States a special deposit account in the name of the Architect of the Capitol for the United States Senate Restaurants, into which shall be deposited all sums received pursuant to sections 2042 to 2047 of this title or any amendatory or supplementary resolutions hereafter adopted and from the operations thereunder and from which shall be disbursed the sums necessary in connection with the exercise of the duties required under sections 2042 to 2047 of this title or any amendatory or supplementary resolutions and the operations thereunder. Any amounts appropriated for fiscal year 1973 and thereafter from the Treasury of the United States, which shall be part of a “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” item for the particular fiscal year involved, shall be paid to the Architect of the Capitol by the Secretary of the Senate at such times and in such sums as the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration may approve. Any such payment shall be deposited by the Architect in full under such special deposit account.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddcfd303d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/82/s4">Pub. L. 87–82, § 4</ref>, <date date="1961-07-06">July 6, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/199">75 Stat. 199</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/51">Pub. L. 92–51</ref>, <date date="1971-07-09">July 9, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/129">85 Stat. 129</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/342/s101">Pub. L. 92–342, § 101</ref>, <date date="1972-07-10">July 10, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/435">86 Stat. 435</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfd303e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfd303f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcfd3040-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 174j–4 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcfd3041-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—<ref href="/us/pl/92/342">Pub. L. 92–342</ref> substituted provision that amounts appropriated for 1973 and thereafter which shall be part of “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” be paid to the Architect of the Capitol, for provision that amounts appropriated for 1972 and thereafter specifically for Senate Restaurants as “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” be paid to Architect of the Capitol.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—<ref href="/us/pl/92/51">Pub. L. 92–51</ref> substituted “amounts appropriated for fiscal year 1972 and thereafter” for Senate Restaurants for “amounts hereafter appropriated” for such Restaurants, provision that amounts appropriated specifically for such Restaurants as a Contingent Expense of the Senate item for fiscal year involved shall be paid to Architect of the Capitol, for prior provision declaring amounts appropriated for such Restaurants shall be a part of such Restaurants as a Contingent Expense of Senate for fiscal year involved and for payment of such part to Architect of the Capitol, and provision for approval of payments by Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, including times for payments, for prior provision for payments as appropriations shall specify.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
