<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcfd3059-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2049"><num value="2049">§ 2049.</num><heading> Loans for Senate Restaurants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfd305a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2049/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Borrowing authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, the Architect of the Capitol shall have authority to borrow (and be accountable for), from time to time, from the appropriation account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for “Miscellaneous Items”, such amount as he may determine necessary to carry out the provisions of the joint resolution entitled “Joint Resolution transferring the management of the Senate Restaurants to the Architect of the Capitol, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1961-07-06">July 6, 1961</date>, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s174j–1">40 U.S.C. 174j–1</ref> through 174j–8) [<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2042">2 U.S.C. 2042</ref> et seq.],<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002077">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002077"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and resolutions of the Senate amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfd305b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2049/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount and period of loan; voucher</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any such loan authorized pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be for such amount and for such period as the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration shall prescribe, and shall be made by the Secretary of the Senate to the Architect of the Capitol upon a voucher approved by the Chairman of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfd305c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2049/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposit, credit, and future availability of proceeds from repayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All proceeds from the repayment of any such loan shall be deposited in the appropriation account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for “Miscellaneous Items”, shall be credited to the fiscal year during which such loan was made, and shall thereafter be available for the same purposes for which the amount loaned was initially appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcfd305d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/396/tI">Pub. L. 98–396, title I</ref>, <date date="1984-08-22">Aug. 22, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1395">98 Stat. 1395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfd305e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfd305f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcfd3060-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Joint Resolution entitled “Joint Resolution transferring the management of the Senate Restaurants to the Architect of the Capitol, and for other purposes”, approved <date date="1961-07-06">July 6, 1961</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/82">Pub. L. 87–82</ref>, <date date="1961-07-06">July 6, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/199">75 Stat. 199</ref>, which enacted sections 174j–1 to 174j–7 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works. Sections 174j–1 and 174j–3 to 174j–7 of former Title 40 were transferred to sections 2042 and 2043 to 2047 of this title, respectively. Section 174j–2 of former Title 40 was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s6/b">Pub. L. 107–217, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1304">116 Stat. 1304</ref>. Section 174j–8 of former Title 40, which was not enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/87/82">Pub. L. 87–82</ref>, was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2048">section 2048 of this title</ref> and subsequently repealed. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcfd3061-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 174j–9 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
