<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcfd3062-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2050"><num value="2050">§ 2050.</num><heading> Transfer of appropriations for management personnel and miscellaneous restaurant expenses to special deposit account</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appropriations under this heading for management personnel and miscellaneous restaurant expenses on and after <date date="1997-10-07">October 7, 1997</date>, shall be transferred at the beginning of each fiscal year to the special deposit account in the United States Treasury established under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2044">section 2044 of this title</ref>, and effective <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>, all management personnel of the Senate Restaurant facilities shall be paid from the special deposit account. Management personnel transferred hereunder shall be paid at the same rates of pay applicable immediately prior to the date of transfer, and annual and sick leave balances shall be credited to leave accounts of such personnel in the Senate Restaurants.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddcfd3063-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/55/tI">Pub. L. 105–55, title I</ref>, <date date="1997-10-07">Oct. 7, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1189">111 Stat. 1189</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfd3064-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfd3065-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcfd3066-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Appropriations under this heading, referred to in text, probably means appropriations under the headings “ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL”, “<inline class="small-caps">Capital Buildings and Grounds</inline>”, and “<inline class="small-caps">senate office buildings</inline>” in the annual Legislative Branch Appropriations Act.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcfd3067-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 174j–10 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Congressional Operations Appropriations Act, 1998, which is title I of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1998.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
