<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcfd30d9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061"><num value="2061">§ 2061.</num><heading> Designation of play areas on Capitol grounds for children attending day care center</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfd30da-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Capitol Police Board</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to the provisions of paragraph (1) of subsection (b), the Capitol Police Board is authorized to designate certain portions of the Capitol grounds (other than a portion within the area bounded on the North by Constitution Avenue, on the South by Independence Avenue, on the East by First Street, and on the West by First Street) for use exclusively as play areas for the benefit of children attending a day care center which is established for the primary purpose of providing child care for the children of Members and employees of the Senate or the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfd30db-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Required approval; fences; termination of authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcfd30dc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of any such designation referred to in subsection (a) involving a day care center established for the benefit of children of Members and employees of the Senate, the designation shall be with the approval of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, and in the case of such a center established for the benefit of children of Members and employees of the House of Representatives, the designation shall be with the approval of the House Committee on House Oversight, with the concurrence of the House Office Building Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcfd30dd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Architect of the Capitol shall enclose with a fence any area designated pursuant to subsection (a) as a play area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcfd30de-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The authority to use an area designated pursuant to subsection (a) as a play area may be terminated at any time by the Committee which approved such designation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfd30df-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Playground equipment; required approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this or any other Act shall be construed as prohibiting any day care center referred to in subsection (a) from placing playground equipment within an area designated pursuant to subsection (a) for use solely in connection with the operation of such center, subject to, in the case of a day care center established for the benefit of children of Members and employees of the Senate, the approval of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, and in the case of such a center established for the benefit of children of Members and employees of the House of Representatives, the approval of the House Committee on House Oversight, with the concurrence of the House Office Building Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcfd30e0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2061/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Day care center</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The day care center referred to in S. Res. 269, Ninety-eighth Congress, first session, is a day care center for which space may be designated under subsection (a) for use as a play area.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcfd30e1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/392/s3">Pub. L. 98–392, § 3</ref>, <date date="1984-08-21">Aug. 21, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1362">98 Stat. 1362</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s221/14">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 221(14)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1750">110 Stat. 1750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcfd30e2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcfd30e3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcfd30e4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">S. Res. 269, Ninety-eighth Congress, first session, referred to in subsec. (d), is dated <date date="1983-11-14">Nov. 14, 1983</date>, and reads as follows: “<i>Resolved</i>, That payment is authorized from the contingent fund of the Senate in an amount not to exceed $20,000 for the start-up costs, including the procurement of the services of individual consultants or organizations, for a Senate day care center, which shall be ready for occupancy by <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. Payments under this resolution shall be paid from the appropriation account for ‘Miscellaneous Items’ in the contingent fund of the Senate upon vouchers approved by the chairman of the Committee on Rules and Administration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. The Committee on Rules and Administration shall supervise any contract entered into on behalf of the Senate, under authority of this resolution. Such contract shall not be subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">section 5 of title 41</ref> of the United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">41 U.S.C. 6101</ref>] or any other provision of law requiring advertising.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcfd30e5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 214b of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcfd30e6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (b)(1), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186">Pub. L. 104–186</ref> substituted “House Oversight” for “House Administration”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcfd30e7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddcfd30e8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on House Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on House Administration of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
