<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd045c1f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2131"><num value="2131">§ 2131.</num><heading> National Statuary Hall</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Suitable structures and railings shall be erected in the old hall of Representatives for the reception and protection of statuary, and the same shall be under the supervision and direction of the Architect of the Capitol. And the President is authorized to invite all the States to provide and furnish statues, in marble or bronze, not exceeding two in number for each State, of deceased persons who have been citizens thereof, and illustrious for their historic renown or for distinguished civic or military services, such as each State may deem to be worthy of this national commemoration; and when so furnished, the same shall be placed in the old hall of the House of Representatives, in the Capitol of the United States, which is set apart, or so much thereof as may be necessary, as a national statuary hall for the purpose herein indicated.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd045c20-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(R.S. § 1814; <ref href="/us/act/1876-08-15/ch287">Aug. 15, 1876, ch. 287</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/19/147">19 Stat. 147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd045c21-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd045c22-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd045c23-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was classified to section 187 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s1">Pub. L. 107–217, § 1</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1062">116 Stat. 1062</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 1814 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1864-07-02/ch210/s2">act July 2, 1864, ch. 210, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/13/347">13 Stat. 347</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2 of act <date date="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>, gave the supervision and direction of the National Statuary Hall to the Commissioner of Public Buildings.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd045c24-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddd045c25-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Change of name of Architect of the Capitol, functions abolished, transferred, etc., by prior acts, see Prior Provisions and Change of Name notes set out under former <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
