<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd0b8866-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252"><num value="2252">§ 2252.</num><heading> Transfer from Capitol Guide Service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0b8867-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of authorities and personnel of Congressional Special Services Office of Capitol Guide Service</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, effective on the transfer date—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd0b8868-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the contracts, liabilities, records, property, appropriations, and other assets and interests of the Congressional Special Services Office of the Capitol Guide Service, and the employees of such Office, are transferred to the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services established under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2172/a">section 2172(a) of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2251">section 2251 of this title</ref>), except that the transfer of any amounts appropriated to the Congressional Special Services Office that remain available as of the transfer date shall occur only upon the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd0b8869-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the employees of such Office shall be subject to the direction, supervision, and control of the Director of Accessibility Services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0b886a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of employees at time of transfer</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0b886b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any individual who is an employee of the Congressional Special Services Office of the Capitol Guide Service on a non-temporary basis on the transfer date who is transferred under subsection (a) shall be subject to the authority of the Director of Accessibility Services under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2172/b">section 2172(b) of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2251">section 2251 of this title</ref>), except that the individual’s grade, compensation, rate of leave, or other benefits that apply with respect to the individual at the time of transfer shall not be reduced while such individual remains continuously so employed in the same position within the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services established under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2172/a">section 2172(a) of this title</ref> (as amended by <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2251">section 2251 of this title</ref>), other than for cause.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0b886c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility for immediate retirement on basis of involuntary separation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of section 8336(d) and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8414/b">section 8414(b) of title 5</ref>, an individual described in paragraph (1) who is separated from service with the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services shall be considered to have separated from the service involuntarily if, at the time the individual is separated from service—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd0b886d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the individual has completed 25 years of service under such title; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddd0b886e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the individual has completed 20 years of service under such title and is 50 years of age or older.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0b886f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s2252/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibiting imposition of probationary period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director of Accessibility Services may not impose a period of probation with respect to the transfer of any individual who is transferred to the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd0b8870-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/437/tIV/s412">Pub. L. 110–437, title IV, § 412</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4995">122 Stat. 4995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd0b8871-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd0b8872-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd0b8873-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this title”, meaning title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/110/437">Pub. L. 110–437</ref>, <date date="2008-10-20">Oct. 20, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4990">122 Stat. 4990</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of title IV to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
