<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc96a698-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s285d"><num value="285d">§ 285d.</num><heading> Staff; Deputy Law Revision Counsel; delegation of functions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc96a699-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s285d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> With the approval of the Speaker, or in accordance with policies and procedures approved by the Speaker, the Law Revision Counsel shall appoint such employees as may be necessary for the prompt and efficient performance of the functions of the Office. Any such appointment shall be made without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position. Any person so appointed may be removed by the Law Revision Counsel with the approval of the Speaker, or in accordance with policies and procedures approved by the Speaker.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc96a69a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s285d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc96a69b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s285d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> One of the employees appointed under paragraph (1) shall be designated by the Law Revision Counsel as Deputy Law Revision Counsel. During the absence or disability of the Law Revision Counsel, or when the office is vacant, the Deputy Law Revision Counsel shall perform the functions of the Law Revision Counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc96a69c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s285d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Law Revision Counsel may delegate to the Deputy Law Revision Counsel and to other employees appointed under paragraph (1) such of his or her functions as he or she considers necessary or appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddc96a69d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/554/tI">Pub. L. 93–554, title I</ref>, ch. III, § 101, <date date="1974-12-27">Dec. 27, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1777">88 Stat. 1777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc96a69e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc96a69f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddc96a6a0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on section 205(e) of House Resolution No. 988, Ninety-third Congress, <date date="1974-10-08">Oct. 8, 1974</date>, which was enacted into permanent law by <ref href="/us/pl/93/554">Pub. L. 93–554</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
