<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc98f15a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s288i"><num value="288i">§ 288i.</num><heading> Representation conflict or inconsistency</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc98f15b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s288i/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the carrying out of the provisions of this chapter, the Counsel shall notify the Joint Leadership Group, and any party represented or person affected, of the existence and nature of any conflict or inconsistency between the representation of such party or person and the carrying out of any other provision of this chapter or compliance with professional standards and responsibilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc98f15c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s288i/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Solution; publication in Congressional Record; review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receipt of such notification, the members of the Joint Leadership Group shall recommend the action to be taken to avoid or resolve the conflict or inconsistency. If such recommendation is made by a two-thirds vote, the Counsel shall take such steps as may be necessary to resolve the conflict or inconsistency as recommended. If not, the members of the Joint Leadership Group shall cause the notification of conflict or inconsistency and recommendation with respect to resolution thereof to be published in the Congressional Record of the Senate. If the Senate does not direct the Counsel within fifteen days from the date of publication in the Record to resolve the conflict in another manner, the Counsel shall take such action as may be necessary to resolve the conflict or inconsistency as recommended. Any instruction or determination made pursuant to this subsection shall not be reviewable in any court of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc98f15d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s288i/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Computation of period following publication</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of the computation of the fifteen day period in subsection (b)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc98f15e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s288i/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> continuity of session is broken only by an adjournment of Congress sine die; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc98f15f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s288i/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the days on which the Senate is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a date certain are excluded.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddc98f160-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s288i/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Senate may by resolution authorize the reimbursement of any Member, officer, or employee of the Senate who is not represented by the Counsel for fees and costs, including attorneys’ fees, reasonably incurred in obtaining representation. Such reimbursement shall be from funds appropriated to the contingent fund of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc98f161-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/521/tVII/s710">Pub. L. 95–521, title VII, § 710</ref>, <date date="1978-10-26">Oct. 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1882">92 Stat. 1882</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc98f162-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc98f163-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc98f164-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this title”, meaning title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/95/521">Pub. L. 95–521</ref>, which enacted this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s5504">section 5504 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1364">section 1364 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, and amended sections 3210, 3216, and 3219 of Title 39, Postal Service. For complete classification of title VII to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc98f165-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddc98f166-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1979-01-03">Jan. 3, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/521/s717">section 717 of Pub. L. 95–521</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s288">section 288 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
