<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddc9b61b5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293"><num value="293">§ 293.</num><heading> Compensation schedules</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc9b61b6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc9b61b7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives (hereinafter referred to as the “committee”) shall establish and maintain, and, from time to time, may revise, for positions to which this chapter applies (other than positions within the purview of subsection (b) of this section the compensation for which is fixed and adjusted from time to time in accordance with prevailing rates), a compensation schedule of per annum rates, which shall be known as the “House Employees Schedule” and for which the symbol shall be “HS”, subject to the following provisions:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc9b61b8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Such schedule shall be composed of such number of compensation levels as the committee deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc9b61b9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Each compensation level shall consist of twelve compensation steps.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddc9b61ba-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The per annum rate of compensation for each compensation step of each compensation level shall be in such amount as the committee deems appropriate, except that the per annum rate of compensation for the maximum compensation step of the highest compensation level shall not exceed the maximum rate of compensation authorized by chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc9b61bb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The rates of compensation for such positions shall be in accordance with such schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddc9b61bc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s293/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The committee shall establish and maintain, and, from time to time, may revise, for positions under the Clerk, the Sergeant at Arms, the Chief Administrative Officer, and the Inspector General of the House of Representatives, the compensation for which, in the judgment of the committee, should be fixed and adjusted from time to time in accordance with prevailing rates, a compensation schedule providing for per annum or per hour rates, or both, established in accordance with prevailing rates and consisting of such number of compensation levels and steps as the committee deems appropriate, which shall be known as the “House Wage Schedule” and for which the symbol shall be “HWS”. The rates of compensation for such positions shall be in accordance with such schedule. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, for purposes of applying the adjustment made by the committee under this subsection for 2002 and each succeeding year (other than any period during which a memorandum of understanding described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2168/a">section 2168(a) of this title</ref> is in effect), positions under the Chief Administrative Officer shall include positions of the United States Capitol telephone exchange under the Chief Administrative Officer.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddc9b61bd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/652/s4">Pub. L. 88–652, § 4</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1079">78 Stat. 1079</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/53/tI/s108/2">Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 108(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/522">109 Stat. 522</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s209/1">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 209(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1743">110 Stat. 1743</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/68/tIII/s310">Pub. L. 107–68, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/592">115 Stat. 592</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dG/tII/s215/d">Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title II, § 215(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3198">118 Stat. 3198</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddc9b61be-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddc9b61bf-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddc9b61c0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/88/652">Pub. L. 88–652</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1079">78 Stat. 1079</ref>, known as the House Employees Position Classification Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s291">section 291 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddc9b61c1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Pub. L. 108–447</ref> in last sentence substituted “succeeding year (other than any period during which a memorandum of understanding described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2168/a">section 2168(a) of this title</ref> is in effect),” for “succeeding year,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/68">Pub. L. 107–68</ref> inserted at end “Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, for purposes of applying the adjustment made by the committee under this subsection for 2002 and each succeeding year, positions under the Chief Administrative Officer shall include positions of the United States Capitol telephone exchange under the Chief Administrative Officer.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186">Pub. L. 104–186</ref> substituted “House Oversight” for “House Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/53">Pub. L. 104–53</ref> substituted “Chief Administrative Officer, and the Inspector General” for “Doorkeeper, and the Postmaster,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddc9b61c2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddc9b61c3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on House Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on House Administration of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddc9b61c4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/447">Pub. L. 108–447</ref> applicable with respect to fiscal year 2005 and each succeeding fiscal year, see <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s2168/f">section 2168(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddc9b61c5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1965-01-01">Jan. 1, 1965</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/652/s17">section 17 of Pub. L. 88–652</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s291">section 291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddc9b61c6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Increases in Compensation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Increases in compensation for House officers and employees under authority of Federal Salary Act of 1967 (<ref href="/us/pl/90/206">Pub. L. 90–206</ref>), Federal Pay Comparability Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/pl/91/656">Pub. L. 91–656</ref>), and Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1988 (<ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref>), see sections 4531 and 4532 of this title, and Salary Directives of Speaker of the House, set out as notes under those sections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
