<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd0dd1f5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4111"><num value="4111">§ 4111.</num><heading> Annual report by Comptroller General of the United States on cybersecurity and surveillance threats to Congress</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd1f6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4111/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, and not less frequently than once each year thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on cybersecurity and surveillance threats to Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd1f7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4111/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Statistics</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include statistics on cyber attacks and other incidents of espionage or surveillance targeted against Senators or the immediate families or staff of the Senators, and Representatives, Delegates, and the Resident Commissioner, or the immediate families or staff of the Representatives, Delegates, and the Resident Commissioner, in which the nonpublic communications and other private information of such targeted individuals were lost, stolen, or otherwise subject to unauthorized access.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd1f8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4111/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In preparing a report to be submitted under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall consult with the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives, and the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd1f9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4111/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The report under subsection (a), including the contents of the report in subsection (b), shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex to protect sources and methods and any appropriate redactions of personally identifiable information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd0dd1fa-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/tLVII/s5710">Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LVII, § 5710</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2170">133 Stat. 2170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd0dd1fb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd0dd1fc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="iddd0dd1fd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of “congressional intelligence committees” as used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dE/s5003">section 5003 of div. E of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
