<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd0dd243-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131"><num value="4131">§ 4131.</num><heading> House Recording Studio; Senate Recording Studio and Senate Photographic Studio</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd244-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established the House Recording Studio, the Senate Recording Studio, and the Senate Photographic Studio.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd245-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance in making disk, film, and tape recordings; exclusiveness of use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The House Recording Studio shall assist Members of the House of Representatives in making disk, film, and tape recordings, and in performing such other functions and duties in connection with the making of such recordings as may be necessary. The Senate Recording Studio and the Senate Photographic Studio shall assist Members of the Senate and committees of the Senate in making disk, film, and tape recordings, and in performing such other functions and duties in connection with the making of such recordings as may be necessary. The House Recording Studio shall be for the exclusive use of Members of the House of Representatives (including the Delegates and the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico); the Senate Recording Studio and the Senate Photographic Studio shall be for the exclusive use of Members of the Senate, the Vice President, committees of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate, and the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd246-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Operation of studios</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The House Recording Studio shall be operated by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives under the direction and control of a committee which is created (hereinafter referred to as the committee) composed of three Members of the House. Two members of the committee shall be from the majority party and one member shall be from the minority party, to be appointed by the Speaker. The committee is authorized to issue such rules and regulations relating to operation of the House Recording Studio as it may deem necessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Senate Recording Studio and the Senate Photographic Studio shall be operated by the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate under the direction and control of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate. The Committee on Rules and Administration is authorized to issue such rules and regulations relating to operation of the Senate Recording Studio and the Senate Photographic Studio as it may deem necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd247-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Prices of disk, film, and tape recordings; collection of moneys</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall, subject to the approval of the committee, set the price of making disk, film, and tape recordings, and collect all moneys owed the House Recording Studio. The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate shall set the price of making disk, film, and tape recordings and all moneys owed the Senate Recording Studio and the Senate Photographic Studio shall be collected by the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd248-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on expenditures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No moneys shall be expended or obligated for the House Recording Studio except as shall be pursuant to such regulations as the committee may approve. No moneys shall be expended or obligated by the Director of the Senate Recording Studio or the Director of the Senate Photographic Studio until approval therefor has been obtained from the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd249-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of Director and other employees of House Recording Studio</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives is authorized, subject to the approval of the committee, to appoint a Director of the House Recording Studio and such other employees as are deemed necessary to the operation of the House Recording Studio.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd24a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Revolving funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States, a revolving fund for the House Recording Studio for the purposes of administering the duties of that studio. There is also established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund, within the contingent fund of the Senate, which shall be known as the “Senate Photographic Studio Revolving Fund”, for the purpose of administering the duties of the Senate Photographic Studio; and there is established in the Treasury of the United States, a revolving fund, within the contingent fund of the Senate, which shall be known as the “Senate Recording Studio Revolving Fund”, for the purpose of administering the duties of the Senate Recording Studio.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd24b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Deposits in funds; availability of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All moneys received by the House Recording Studio from Members of the House of Representatives for disk, film, or tape recordings, or from any other source, shall be deposited by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives in the revolving fund established for the House Recording Studio by the preceding paragraph; moneys in such fund shall be available for disbursement therefrom by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives for the care, maintenance, operation, and other expenses of the studio upon vouchers signed and approved in such manner as the committee shall prescribe. All moneys received by the Senate Recording Studio shall be deposited in the Senate Recording Studio Revolving Fund established by subsection (g) and all funds received by the Senate Photographic Studio shall be deposited in the Senate Photographic Studio Revolving Fund established by such subsection; moneys in the Senate Recording Studio Revolving Fund shall be available for disbursement therefrom upon vouchers signed by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate for the care, maintenance, operation, and other expenses of the Senate Recording Studio, and moneys in the Senate Photographic Studio Revolving Fund shall be available for disbursement therefrom upon vouchers signed by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate for the care, maintenance, operation, and other expenses of the Senate Photographic Studio.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd24c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution of equity of Joint Senate and House Recording Facility Revolving Fund; assignment of existing studio facilities, equipment, materials and supplies; transfer of accounts; reserve fund; distribution of balance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd0dd24d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> As soon as practicable after <date date="1956-06-27">June 27, 1956</date>, but no later than <date date="1956-09-30">September 30, 1956</date>, the equity of the Joint Senate and House Recording Facility Revolving Fund shall be distributed equally to the Senate and House of Representatives on the basis of an audit to be made by the General Accounting Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd0dd24e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Sergeant at Arms of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives shall, subject to the approval of the committees mentioned in subsection (c) hereof, determine the assignment of existing studio facilities to the Senate and the House of Representatives, and also the existing equipment, materials and supplies to be transferred to the respective studios. The evaluation of equipment, materials and supplies transferred to each studio shall be on the basis of market value. Any other equipment, materials and supplies determined to be obsolete or not needed for the operation of the respective studio shall be disposed of to the best interest of the Government and the proceeds thereof deposited in the Joint Senate and House Recording Facility Revolving Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd0dd24f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Accounts receivable, which on the effective date of liquidation, are due from Members and committees of the Senate shall be transferred to the Senate Studio, and those due from Members and committees of the House of Representatives shall be transferred to the House Studio.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd0dd250-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A sufficient reserve shall be set aside from the Joint Senate and House Recording Facility Revolving Fund to liquidate any outstanding accounts payable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd0dd251-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> After appropriate adjustments for the value of assets assigned or transferred to the Senate and House of Representatives, respectively, the balance in the Joint Senate and House Recording Facility Revolving Fund shall be distributed equally to the Senate and House of Representatives for deposit to the respective revolving funds authorized by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd252-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of existing services and facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pending acquisition of the stock, supplies, materials, and equipment necessary to properly equip both studios, the present services and facilities shall be made available to both studios in order that each studio may carry out its duty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd253-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on employment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No person shall be an officer or employee of the House Recording Studio, Senate Recording Studio, or Senate Photographic Studio while he is engaged in any other business, profession, occupation, or employment which involves the performance of duties which are similar to those which would be performed by him as such an officer or employee of such studio unless approved in writing by the committee in the case of the House Recording Studio and the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration in the case of the Senate Recording Studio and the Senate Photographic Studio.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd254-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Abolition of Joint Recording Facility positions and salaries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Joint Recording Facility positions and salaries established pursuant to the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1948, and all subsequent Acts are abolished.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd255-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Repeals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective with the completion of the transfer provided for by subsection (i) hereof the joint resolution entitled “Joint resolution establishing in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the House of Representatives”, approved <date date="1953-08-07">August 7, 1953</date>, is repealed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd256-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/92/310/tII/s220/j">Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 220(j)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/205">86 Stat. 205</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd0dd257-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4131/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section are authorized to be appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd0dd258-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-06-27/ch453/s105">June 27, 1956, ch. 453, § 105</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/370">70 Stat. 370</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/652/s16/a">Pub. L. 88–652, § 16(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1084">78 Stat. 1084</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/310/tII/s220/j">Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 220(j)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/205">86 Stat. 205</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/304/tI/s108/a">Pub. L. 96–304, title I, § 108(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-08">July 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/890">94 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/257/tI/s102">Pub. L. 97–257, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1982-09-10">Sept. 10, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/849">96 Stat. 849</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/tI/s7/a">Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 7(a)</ref>, (c), (d), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2258">104 Stat. 2258</ref>, 2259; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s204/68">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(68)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1740">110 Stat. 1740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd0dd259-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd0dd25a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd0dd25b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s123b">section 123b of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd0dd25c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (c), (d), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/s204/68/A">Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(68)(A)</ref>, substituted “Chief Administrative Officer” for “Clerk”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/s204/68/B">Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(68)(B)</ref>, struck out “within the contingent fund of the House of Representatives” before “for the House Recording Studio”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/s204/68/A">Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(68)(A)</ref>, substituted “Chief Administrative Officer” for “Clerk” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/s7/a">Pub. L. 101–520, § 7(a)</ref>, amended second sentence generally. Prior to amendment, second sentence read as follows: “There is also established in the Treasury of the United States, a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate for the Senate Recording and Photographic Studios for the purposes of administering the duties of that studio.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/s7/c">Pub. L. 101–520, § 7(c)</ref>, amended second sentence generally. Prior to amendment, second sentence read as follows: “All moneys received by the Senate Recording and Photographic Studios for disk, film, or tape recordings or from any other source, shall be deposited in the revolving fund established for the Senate Recording and Photographic Studios by subsection (g) of this section; moneys in such fund shall be available for disbursement therefrom upon vouchers signed and approved by the Sergeant at Arms for the care, maintenance, operation, and other expenses of the Senate Recording and Photographic Studios.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/257">Pub. L. 97–257</ref> inserted reference to Secretary of Senate and Sergeant at Arms of Senate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/92/310">Pub. L. 92–310</ref> repealed subsec. (n) which required Directors of House and Senate Recording Studios to give bonds in sum of $20,000 each.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/88/652">Pub. L. 88–652</ref> struck out “and fix the compensation of” after “to appoint”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd0dd25d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddd0dd25e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">General Accounting Office redesignated Government Accountability Office by <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 108–271</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s702">section 702 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd0dd25f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/520/tI/s7/b">Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2259">104 Stat. 2259</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/520/tI/s7/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="1991-04-01">April 1, 1991</date>, and, of the monies in the revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate for the Recording and Photographic Studios, as such fund was in existence immediately prior to the amendment made by subsection (a), $100,000 shall be deposited in the Senate Photographic Studio Revolving Fund (as established by the amendment made by subsection (a)) and the remainder shall be deposited into the Senate Recording Studio Revolving Fund (as so established).”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/520/tI/s7/c">Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 7(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2259">104 Stat. 2259</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1991-04-01">Apr. 1, 1991</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd0dd260-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/652">Pub. L. 88–652</ref> effective <date date="1965-01-01">Jan. 1, 1965</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/652/s17">section 17 of Pub. L. 88–652</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s291">section 291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddd0dd261-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to Senate Recording Studio and Senate Photographic Studio substituted for “Senate Recording and Photographic Studios” wherever appearing in text pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/304/s108/a">section 108(a) of Pub. L. 96–304</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/s7/d">section 7(d) of Pub. L. 101–520</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s4132/a">section 4132(a) of this title</ref>, and which abolished entity known as Senate Recording and Photographic Studios, established instead Senate Recording Studio and Senate Photographic Studio, and made corresponding transfer of functions. Previously, “Senate Recording and Photographic Studios” had been substituted in text for “Senate Recording Studio” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/304/s108/a">section 108(a) of Pub. L. 96–304</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddd0dd262-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appropriations Acts as Determining Extent of Availability of Funds and Accounts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/53/tI/s107">Pub. L. 104–53, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1995-11-19">Nov. 19, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/522">109 Stat. 522</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/53/tI/s107">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Each fund and account specified in subsection (b) shall be available only to the extent provided in appropriations Acts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The funds and accounts referred to in subsection (a) are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the revolving fund for the House Barber Shops, established by the paragraph under the heading ‘<inline class="small-caps">House Barber Shops Revolving Fund</inline>’ in the matter relating to the House of Representatives in chapter III of title I of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1975 (<ref href="/us/pl/93/554">Public Law 93–554</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/88/1776">88 Stat. 1776</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the revolving fund for the House Beauty Shop, established by the matter under the heading ‘<inline class="small-caps">house beauty shop</inline>’ in the matter relating to administrative provisions for the House of Representatives in the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1970 (<ref href="/us/pl/91/145">Public Law 91–145</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/83/347">83 Stat. 347</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the special deposit account established for the House of Representatives Restaurant by section 208 of the First Supplemental Civil Functions Appropriation Act, 1941 (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s174k">40 U.S.C. 174k</ref> note) [former <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s174k">40 U.S.C. 174k</ref>]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the revolving fund established for the House Recording Studio by section 105(g) of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1957 (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s123b/g">2 U.S.C. 123b(g)</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s4131/g">2 U.S.C. 4131(g)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> This section shall take effect on <date date="1995-10-01">October 1, 1995</date>, and shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning on or after that date.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
