<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd128d53-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503"><num value="4503">§ 4503.</num><heading> Jury and witness service by Senate and House employees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd128d54-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d55-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “employee” means any individual whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d56-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “court of the United States” has the meaning given it by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s451">section 451 of title 28</ref> and includes the United States District Court for the District of the Canal Zone, the District Court of Guam, and the District Court of the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd128d57-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Service as juror or witness in connection with a judicial proceeding; prohibition against reduction of pay</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The pay of an employee shall not be reduced during a period of absence with respect to which the employee is summoned (and permitted to respond to such summons by the appropriate authority of the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), in connection with a judicial proceeding by a court or authority responsible for the conduct of that proceeding, to serve—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d58-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> as a juror; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d59-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> other than as provided in subsection (c) of this section, as a witness on behalf of any party in connection with any judicial proceeding to which the United States, the District of Columbia, or a State or local government is a party;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">in the District of Columbia, a State, territory, or possession of the United States including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Canal Zone, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. For purposes of this subsection, “judicial proceeding” means any action, suit, or other judicial proceeding, including any condemnation, preliminary, informational, or other proceeding of a judicial nature, but does not include an administrative proceeding.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd128d5a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Official duty</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An employee is performing official duty during the period with respect to which he is summoned (and is authorized to respond to such summons by the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), or is assigned by such House, to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d5b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> testify or produce official records on behalf of the United States or the District of Columbia; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d5c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> testify in his official capacity or produce official records on behalf of a party other than the United States or the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd128d5d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on receipt of jury or witness fees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd128d5e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An employee may not receive fees for service—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d5f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as juror in a court of the United States or the District of Columbia; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd128d60-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> as a witness on behalf of the United States or the District of Columbia.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd128d61-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an employee receives an amount (other than travel expenses) for service as a juror or witness during a period in which his pay may not be reduced under subsection (b) of this section, or for which he is performing official duty under subsection (c) of this section, the employee shall remit such amount to the officer who disburses the pay of the employee, which amount shall be covered into the general fund of the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd128d62-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd128d63-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An employee summoned (and authorized to respond to such summons by the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), or assigned by such House, to testify or produce official records on behalf of the United States is entitled to travel expenses. If the case involves an activity in connection with which he is employed, the travel expenses shall be paid from funds otherwise available for the payment of travel expenses of such House in accordance with travel regulations of that House. If the case does not involve such an activity, the department, agency, or independent establishment of the United States on whose behalf he is so testifying or producing records shall pay to the employee his travel expenses out of appropriations otherwise available, and in accordance with regulation applicable, to that department, agency, or independent establishment for the payment of travel expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd128d64-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An employee summoned (and permitted to respond to such summons by the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), or assigned by such House, to testify in his official capacity or produce official records on behalf of a party other than the United States, is entitled to travel expenses, unless any travel expenses are paid to the employee for his appearance by the court, authority, or party which caused him to be summoned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd128d65-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives are authorized to prescribe, for employees of their respective Houses, such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd128d66-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4503/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional consent not conferred for production of official records or to testimony concerning activities related to employment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No provision of this section shall be construed to confer the consent of either House of the Congress to the production of official records of that House or to testimony by an employee of that House concerning activities related to his employment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd128d67-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/563/s6">Pub. L. 91–563, § 6</ref>, <date date="1970-12-19">Dec. 19, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1478">84 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/310/s2">Pub. L. 94–310, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-06-15">June 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/687">90 Stat. 687</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s204/74">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(74)</ref>, (75), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1741">110 Stat. 1741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd128d68-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd128d69-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd128d6a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in subsec. (b), see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd128d6b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s130b">section 130b of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd128d6c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/s204/74">Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(74)</ref>, substituted “Chief Administrative Officer” for “Clerk”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/s204/75">Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(75)</ref>, substituted “House Oversight” for “House Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/310">Pub. L. 94–310</ref> substituted “other than as provided in subsection (c) of this section, as a witness on behalf of any party in connection with any judicial proceeding to which the United States, the District of Columbia, or a State or local government is a party” for “as a witness on behalf of a party other than the United States, the District of Columbia, or a private party”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd128d6d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddd128d6e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on House Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on House Administration of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd128d6f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/310/s4">Pub. L. 94–310, § 4</ref>, <date date="1976-06-15">June 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/687">90 Stat. 687</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/310/s4">“The amendments made by this Act [amending this section and sections 6322 and 8906 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees] shall take effect on <date date="1976-10-01">October 1, 1976</date>, or on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1976-06-15">June 15, 1976</date>], whichever date is later.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddd128d70-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of United States District Court for the District of the Canal Zone</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of the United States District Court for the District of the Canal Zone at end of the “transition period”, being the 30 month period beginning <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, and ending midnight <date date="1982-03-31">Mar. 31, 1982</date>, see Paragraph 5 of Article XI of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and sections 2101 and 2201 to 2203(a) of <ref href="/us/pl/96/70/tII">Pub. L. 96–70, title II</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/493">93 Stat. 493</ref>, formerly classified to sections 3831 and 3841 to 3843, respectively, of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="iddd128d71-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddd128d72-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
