<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd176fa4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s4553"><num value="4553">§ 4553.</num><heading> Gratuities for survivors of deceased House employees; computation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives is on and after <date date="1954-07-02">July 2, 1954</date>, authorized to pay, from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives, a gratuity to the widow, widower, or heirs-at-law, of each deceased employee of the House an amount equal to one month’s salary for each year or part of year of the first six years service of such employee plus one-half of one month’s salary for each year or part of year of such service in excess of six years to and including the eighteenth year of such service. Service computed hereunder shall include all Federal civilian employment, and military service where such service interrupted Federal civilian employment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd176fa5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-07-02/ch455">July 2, 1954, ch. 455</ref>, title I, <ref href="/us/stat/68/403">68 Stat. 403</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s204/70">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(70)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1740">110 Stat. 1740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd176fa6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd176fa7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd176fa8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s125">section 125 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd176fa9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/186">Pub. L. 104–186</ref> substituted “Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives” for “Clerk of the House” and “applicable accounts of the House of Representatives” for “contingent fund of the House”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
