<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddca28d85-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475"><num value="475">§ 475.</num><heading> Powers of Office of Technology Assessment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca28d86-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of public and private personnel and organizations; formation of special ad hoc task forces; contracts with governmental, etc., agencies and instrumentalities; advance, progress, and other payments; utilization of services of voluntary and uncompensated personnel; acquisition, holding, and disposal of real and personal property; promulgation of rules and regulations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Office shall have the authority, within the limits of available appropriations, to do all things necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter, including, but without being limited to, the authority to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca28d87-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> make full use of competent personnel and organizations outside the Office, public or private, and form special ad hoc task forces or make other arrangements when appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca28d88-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> enter into contracts or other arrangements as may be necessary for the conduct of the work of the Office with any agency or instrumentality of the United States, with any State, territory, or possession or any political subdivision thereof, or with any person, firm, association, corporation, or educational institution, with or without reimbursement, without performance or other bonds, and without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca28d89-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> make advance, progress, and other payments which relate to technology assessment without regard to the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca28d8a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> accept and utilize the services of voluntary and uncompensated personnel necessary for the conduct of the work of the Office and provide transportation and subsistence as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>, for persons serving without compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca28d8b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> acquire by purchase, lease, loan, or gift, and hold and dispose of by sale, lease, or loan, real and personal property of all kinds necessary for or resulting from the exercise of authority granted by this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca28d8c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> prescribe such rules and regulations as it deems necessary governing the operation and organization of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca28d8d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping by contractors and other parties entering into contracts and other arrangements with Office; availability of books and records to Office and Comptroller General for audit and examination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Contractors and other parties entering into contracts and other arrangements under this section which involve costs to the Government shall maintain such books and related records as will facilitate an effective audit in such detail and in such manner as shall be prescribed by the Office, and such books and rec­ords (and related documents and papers) shall be available to the Office and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, for the purpose of audit and examination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca28d8e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Operation of laboratories, pilot plants, or test facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Office, in carrying out the provisions of this chapter, shall not, itself, operate any laboratories, pilot plants, or test facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca28d8f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Requests to executive departments or agencies for information, suggestions, estimates, statistics, and technical assistance; duty of executive departments and agencies to furnish information, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Office is authorized to secure directly from any executive department or agency information, suggestions, estimates, statistics, and technical assistance for the purpose of carrying out its functions under this chapter. Each such executive department or agency shall furnish the information, suggestions, estimates, statistics, and technical assistance directly to the Office upon its request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca28d90-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Requests to heads of executive departments or agencies for detail of personnel; reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On request of the Office, the head of any executive department or agency may detail, with or without reimbursement, any of its personnel to assist the Office in carrying out its functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca28d91-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s475/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall, in accordance with such policies as the Board shall prescribe, appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddca28d92-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/484/s6">Pub. L. 92–484, § 6</ref>, <date date="1972-10-13">Oct. 13, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/799">86 Stat. 799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddca28d93-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddca28d94-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddca28d95-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(2), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(3), “section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31” substituted for “section 3648 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s529">31 U.S.C. 529</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
