<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd2a8265-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s5342"><num value="5342">§ 5342.</num><heading> Reimbursement of transportation expenses for employees in office of House Member</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The applicable accounts of the House of Representatives is <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002110">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002110"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “are”.</note> made available after <date date="1965-08-28">August 28, 1965</date>, for reimbursement of transportation expenses incurred by not to exceed two employees in the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico) for one round trip each, or incurred by not to exceed one employee for two round trips, in any calendar year between Washington, District of Columbia, and the place of residence of the Member representing the congressional district involved. Such payment shall be made only upon vouchers approved by the Member containing a certification by him that such travel was performed in line of official duty, but the mileage allowed for any such trip shall not exceed the round trip mileage by the nearest usual route between Washington, District of Columbia, and the Member’s place of residence in the congressional district involved. The Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives shall make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd2a8266-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/147/s3">Pub. L. 89–147, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-08-28">Aug. 28, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/583">79 Stat. 583</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s204/71">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(71)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1740">110 Stat. 1740</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd2a8267-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd2a8268-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd2a8269-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s127a">section 127a of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd2a826a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/186">Pub. L. 104–186</ref> substituted “applicable accounts” for “contingent fund” and “House Oversight” for “House Administration”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd2a826b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddd2a826c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on House Oversight of House of Representatives changed to Committee on House Administration of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Sixth Congress, <date date="1999-01-06">Jan. 6, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
