<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd2ccbd3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s5506"><num value="5506">§ 5506.</num><heading> Appropriations for expenses of House; restrictions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Appropriations made for expenses of the House of Representatives shall not be used for the payment of personal services except upon the express and specific authorization of the House in whose behalf such services are rendered. Nor shall such appropriations be used for any expenses not intimately and directly connected with the routine legislative business of the House of Representatives, and the Government Accountability Office shall apply the provisions of this section in the settlement of the accounts of expenditures from said appropriations incurred for services or materials.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd2ccbd4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1902-02-14/ch17/s1">Feb. 14, 1902, ch. 17, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/32/26">32 Stat. 26</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1921-06-10/ch18">June 10, 1921, ch. 18</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref href="/us/stat/42/24">42 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/186/tII/s204/45">Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(45)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1737">110 Stat. 1737</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd2ccbd5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd2ccbd6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd2ccbd7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s95a">section 95a of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Section was also formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s671">section 671 of Title 31</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on provisions of proviso on <ref href="/us/stat/32/26">32 Stat. 26</ref>, <ref href="/us/act/1902-02-14/ch17">act of Feb. 14, 1902, ch. 17</ref>, the Urgent Deficiency Appropriation Act for the fiscal year 1902, relating to appropriations for contingent expenses of House of Representatives. Provisions of proviso relating to appropriations for expenses of Senate are classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s6505">section 6505 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd2ccbd8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/186">Pub. L. 104–186</ref> substituted “expenses of the House” for “contingent expenses of the House”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd2ccbd9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="iddd2ccbda-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Government Accountability Office” substituted in text for “General Accounting Office” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 108–271</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s702">section 702 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, which redesignated the General Accounting Office and any references thereto as the Government Accountability Office. Previously, “General Accounting Office” substituted in text for “accounting officers of the Treasury” pursuant to act <date date="1921-06-10">June 10, 1921</date>, which transferred powers and duties of Comptroller, six auditors, and certain other employees of the Treasury to General Accounting Office. See section 701 et seq. of Title 31.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
