<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd2f3d15-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s5547"><num value="5547">§ 5547.</num><heading> Emergency expenditures for meals, refreshments, and other support and maintenance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd2f3d16-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s5547/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> At any time on or after <date date="2003-02-20">February 20, 2003</date>, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives may incur obligations and make expenditures out of available appropriations for meals, refreshments, and other support and maintenance for Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives when, in the judgment of the Chief Administrative Officer, such obligations and expenditures are necessary to respond to emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd2f3d17-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s5547/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Nothing in this section may be construed to affect any other authority of the Chief Administrative Officer to incur obligations and make expenditures for the items and services described in subsection (a) for Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd2f3d18-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dH/tI/s107">Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/355">117 Stat. 355</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd2f3d19-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd2f3d1a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd2f3d1b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s130k">section 130k of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003, which is div. H of the Consolidated Appropriations Resolution, 2003.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
