<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd31ae58-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6136"><num value="6136">§ 6136.</num><heading> Transfer of funds from representation allowance of Majority and Minority Leaders of Senate to expense allowance; availability; definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd31ae59-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6136/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of the Senate shall, upon the written request of the Majority or Minority Leader of the Senate, transfer from any available funds in such Leader’s allotment in the Leader’s Representation Allowance (as defined in subsection (b)(1)) for any fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>) to such Leader’s Expense Allowance (as defined in subsection (b)(2)) to such year such amount as is specified in the request. Any funds so transferred for any fiscal year at the request of either such Leader shall be available to such Leader for such year for the same purposes as, and in like manner and subject to the same conditions as, are other funds which are available to him for such year as his expense allowance as Majority or Minority Leader.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd31ae5a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6136/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd31ae5b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6136/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Leader’s Representation Allowance” means the Representation Allowance Account for the Majority and Minority Leaders established by <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s6135">section 6135 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd31ae5c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6136/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Leader’s Expense Allowance”, when used in reference to the Majority or Minority Leader of the Senate, refers to the moneys available, for any fiscal year, to such Leader as an expense allowance and the appropriation account from which such moneys are funded.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd31ae5d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/71/tI/s1">Pub. L. 100–71, title I, § 1</ref>, <date date="1987-07-11">July 11, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/422">101 Stat. 422</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd31ae5e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd31ae5f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd31ae60-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s31a–2a">section 31a–2a of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1987.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
