<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd33f8ed-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6302"><num value="6302">§ 6302.</num><heading> Salaries of Senators</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Salaries of Senators appointed to fill vacancies in the Senate shall commence on the day of their appointment and continue until their successors are elected and qualified: <i>Provided</i>, That when Senators have been elected during a sine die adjournment of the Senate to succeed appointees, the salaries of Senators so elected shall commence on the day following their election.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Salaries of Senators elected during a session to succeed appointees shall commence on the day they qualify: <i>Provided</i>, That when Senators have been elected during a session to succeed appointees, but have not qualified, the salaries of Senators so elected shall commence on the day following the sine die adjournment of the Senate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When no appointments have been made the salaries of Senators elected to fill such vacancies shall commence on the day following their election.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd33f8ee-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/act/1923-02-10/ch68">Feb. 10, 1923, ch. 68</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1225">42 Stat. 1225</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1931-02-06/ch111">Feb. 6, 1931, ch. 111</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/1065">46 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch648">June 19, 1934, ch. 648</ref>, title I, § 1, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1022">48 Stat. 1022</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-02-13/ch6/s1">Feb. 13, 1935, ch. 6, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/22">49 Stat. 22</ref>, 23.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd33f8ef-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd33f8f0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd33f8f1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s36">section 36 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddd33f8f2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1894-07-31/ch174">act July 31, 1894, ch. 174</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/162">28 Stat. 162</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 51.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd33f8f3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-02-13">Feb. 13, 1935</date>, inserted proviso as to commencement of salaries of Senators elected during a sine die adjournment on day following their election and provision as to commencement of salaries of Senators elected during a session to succeed appointees on day they qualify but that upon failure to qualify their salaries are to commence on day following sine die adjournment of Senate and struck out provision that salaries of Senators elected to fill vacancies are to commence on day they qualify.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Act <date date="1934-06-19">June 19, 1934</date>, made nonsubstantive changes in grammar and punctuation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1931—Act <date date="1931-02-06">Feb. 6, 1931</date>, made nonsubstantive changes in grammar and punctuation and struck out “to fill such vacancies” after “When no appointments have been made”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd33f8f4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddd33f8f5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Constitutional Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The first section of amendment XX to the Constitution provides in part: “* * * the terms of Senators and Representatives [shall end] at noon on the 3d day of January, of the years in which such terms would have ended if this article had not been ratified; and the terms of their successors shall then begin.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
