<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddca9b94f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632"><num value="632">§ 632.</num><heading> Annual adoption of concurrent resolution on the budget</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b950-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Content of concurrent resolution on the budget</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On or before April 15 of each year, the Congress shall complete action on a concurrent resolution on the budget for the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of such year. The concurrent resolution shall set forth appropriate levels for the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of such year and for at least each of the 4 ensuing fiscal years for the following—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b951-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> totals of new budget authority and outlays;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b952-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> total Federal revenues and the amount, if any, by which the aggregate level of Federal revenues should be increased or decreased by bills and resolutions to be reported by the appropriate committees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b953-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the surplus or deficit in the budget;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b954-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> new budget authority and outlays for each major functional category, based on allocations of the total levels set forth pursuant to paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b955-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the public debt;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b956-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> for purposes of Senate enforcement under this subchapter, outlays of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.] for the fiscal year of the resolution and for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b957-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> for purposes of Senate enforcement under this subchapter, revenues of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act (and the related provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.]) for the fiscal year of the resolution and for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The concurrent resolution shall not include the outlays and revenue totals of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act or the related provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in the surplus or deficit totals required by this subsection or in any other surplus or deficit totals required by this subchapter.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b958-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional matters in concurrent resolution</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The concurrent resolution on the budget may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b959-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> set forth, if required by subsection (f), the calendar year in which, in the opinion of the Congress, the goals for reducing unemployment set forth in section 4(b) of the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022a/b">15 U.S.C. 1022a(b)</ref>] should be achieved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b95a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> include reconciliation directives described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s641">section 641 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b95b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> require a procedure under which all or certain bills or resolutions providing new budget authority or new entitlement authority for such fiscal year shall not be enrolled until the Congress has completed action on any reconciliation bill or reconciliation resolution or both required by such concurrent resolution to be reported in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s641/b">section 641(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b95c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> set forth such other matters, and require such other procedures, relating to the budget, as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b95d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> include a heading entitled “Debt Increase as Measure of Deficit” in which the concurrent resolution shall set forth the amounts by which the debt subject to limit (in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3101">section 3101 of title 31</ref>) has increased or would increase in each of the relevant fiscal years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b95e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> include a heading entitled “Display of Federal Retirement Trust Fund Balances” in which the concurrent resolution shall set forth the balances of the Federal retirement trust funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b95f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> set forth procedures in the Senate whereby committee allocations, aggregates, and other levels can be revised for legislation if that legislation would not increase the deficit, or would not increase the deficit when taken with other legislation enacted after the adoption of the resolution, for the first fiscal year or the total period of fiscal years covered by the resolution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b960-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> set forth procedures to effectuate pay-as-you-go in the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddca9b961-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> set forth direct loan obligation and primary loan guarantee commitment levels.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b962-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of procedures or matters which have effect of changing any rule of House</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives reports any concurrent resolution on the budget which includes any procedure or matter which has the effect of changing any rule of the House of Representatives, such concurrent resolution shall then be referred to the Committee on Rules with instructions to report it within five calendar days (not counting any day on which the House is not in session). The Committee on Rules shall have jurisdiction to report any concurrent resolution referred to it under this paragraph with an amendment or amendments changing or striking out any such procedure or matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b963-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Views and estimates of other committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 6 weeks after the President submits a budget under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, or at such time as may be requested by the Committee on the Budget, each committee of the House of Representatives having legislative jurisdiction shall submit to the Committee on the Budget of the House and each committee of the Senate having legislative jurisdiction shall submit to the Committee on the Budget of the Senate its views and estimates (as determined by the committee making such submission) with respect to all matters set forth in subsections (a) and (b) which relate to matters within the jurisdiction or functions of such committee. The Joint Economic Committee shall submit to the Committees on the Budget of both Houses its recommendations as to the fiscal policy appropriate to the goals of the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">15 U.S.C. 1021</ref> et seq.]. Any other committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate may submit to the Committee on the Budget of its House, and any joint committee of the Congress may submit to the Committees on the Budget of both Houses, its views and estimates with respect to all matters set forth in subsections (a) and (b) which relate to matters within its jurisdiction or functions. Any Committee <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002026"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> of the House of Representatives or the Senate that anticipates that the committee will consider any proposed legislation establishing, amending, or reauthorizing any Federal program likely to have a significant budgetary impact on any State, local, or tribal government, or likely to have a significant financial impact on the private sector, including any legislative proposal submitted by the executive branch likely to have such a budgetary or financial impact, shall include its views and estimates on that proposal to the Committee on the Budget of the applicable House.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b964-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings and report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b965-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In developing the concurrent resolution on the budget referred to in subsection (a) for each fiscal year, the Committee on the Budget of each House shall hold hearings and shall receive testimony from Members of Congress and such appropriate representatives of Federal departments and agencies, the general public, and national organizations as the committee deems desirable. Each of the recommendations as to short-term and medium-term goals set forth in the report submitted by the members of the Joint Economic Committee under subsection (d) may be considered by the Committee on the Budget of each House as part of its consideration of such concurrent resolution, and its report may reflect its views thereon, including its views on how the estimates of revenues and levels of budget authority and outlays set forth in such concurrent resolution are designed to achieve any goals it is recommending.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b966-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Required contents of report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The report accompanying the resolution shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b967-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a comparison of the levels of total new budget authority, total outlays, total revenues, and the surplus or deficit for each fiscal year set forth in the resolution with those requested in the budget submitted by the President;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b968-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to each major functional category, an estimate of total new budget authority and total outlays, with the estimates divided between discretionary and mandatory amounts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b969-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the economic assumptions that underlie each of the matters set forth in the resolution and any alternative economic assumptions and objectives the committee considered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b96a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> information, data, and comparisons indicating the manner in which, and the basis on which, the committee determined each of the matters set forth in the resolution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b96b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the estimated levels of tax expenditures (the tax expenditures budget) by major items and functional categories for the President’s budget and in the resolution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b96c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> allocations described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s633/a">section 633(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b96d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional contents of report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The report accompanying the resolution may include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b96e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a statement of any significant changes in the proposed levels of Federal assistance to State and local governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b96f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an allocation of the level of Federal revenues recommended in the resolution among the major sources of such revenues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b970-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> information, data, and comparisons on the share of total Federal budget outlays and of gross domestic product devoted to investment in the budget submitted by the President and in the resolution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b971-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the assumed levels of budget authority and outlays for public buildings, with a division between amounts for construction and repair and for rental payments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddca9b972-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/e/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> other matters, relating to the budget and to fiscal policy, that the committee deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b973-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Achievement of goals for reducing unemployment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9b974-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If, pursuant to section 4(c) of the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022a/c">15 U.S.C. 1022a(c)</ref>], the President recommends in the Economic Report that the goals for reducing unemployment set forth in section 4(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022a/b">15 U.S.C. 1022a(b)</ref>] be achieved in a year after the close of the five-year period prescribed by such subsection, the concurrent resolution on the budget for the fiscal year beginning after the date on which such Economic Report is received by the Congress may set forth the year in which, in the opinion of the Congress, such goals can be achieved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9b975-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> After the Congress has expressed its opinion pursuant to paragraph (1) as to the year in which the goals for reducing unemployment set forth in section 4(b) of the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022a/b">15 U.S.C. 1022a(b)</ref>] can be achieved, if, pursuant to section 4(e) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022a/e">15 U.S.C. 1022a(e)</ref>], the President recommends in the Economic Report that such goals be achieved in a year which is different from the year in which the Congress has expressed its opinion that such goals should be achieved, either in its action pursuant to paragraph (1) or in its most recent action pursuant to this paragraph, the concurrent resolution on the budget for the fiscal year beginning after the date on which such Economic Report is received by the Congress may set forth the year in which, in the opinion of the Congress, such goals can be achieved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9b976-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> It shall be in order to amend the provision of such resolution setting forth such year only if the amendment thereto also proposes to alter the estimates, amounts, and levels (as described in subsection (a)) set forth in such resolution in germane fashion in order to be consistent with the economic goals (as described in sections 3(a)(2) and 4(b) of the Employment Act of 1946 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1022/a/2">15 U.S.C. 1022(a)(2)</ref>, 1022a(b)]) which such amendment proposes can be achieved by the year specified in such amendment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b977-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Economic assumptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9b978-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It shall not be in order in the Senate to consider any concurrent resolution on the budget for a fiscal year, or any amendment thereto, or any conference report thereon, that sets forth amounts and levels that are determined on the basis of more than one set of economic and technical assumptions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9b979-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The joint explanatory statement accompanying a conference report on a concurrent resolution on the budget shall set forth the common economic assumptions upon which such joint statement and conference report are based, or upon which any amendment contained in the joint explanatory statement to be proposed by the conferees in the case of technical disagreement, is based.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddca9b97a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Subject to periodic reestimation based on changed economic conditions or technical estimates, determinations under titles III and IV of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s631">2 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq., 651 et seq.] shall be based upon such common economic and technical assumptions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddca9b97b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget Committee’s consultation with committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives shall consult with the committees of its House having legislative jurisdiction during the preparation, consideration, and enforcement of the concurrent resolution on the budget with respect to all matters which relate to the jurisdiction or functions of such committees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcac036c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s632/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Social security point of order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall not be in order in the Senate to consider any concurrent resolution on the budget (or amendment, motion, or conference report on the resolution) that would decrease the excess of social security revenues over social security outlays in any of the fiscal years covered by the concurrent resolution. No change in chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.] shall be treated as affecting the amount of social security revenues unless such provision changes the income tax treatment of social security benefits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcac036d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 93–344, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/306">88 Stat. 306</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/tIII">Pub. L. 95–523, title III</ref>, §§ 303(a), 304, <date date="1978-10-27">Oct. 27, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1905">92 Stat. 1905</ref>, 1906; <ref href="/us/pl/99/177/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1040">99 Stat. 1040</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/tI/s106/d">Pub. L. 100–119, title I, § 106(d)</ref>, title II, § 208(a), <date date="1987-09-29">Sept. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/781">101 Stat. 781</ref>, 786; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5302">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5302</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1462">102 Stat. 1462</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII</ref>, §§ 13112(a)(5), 13203, 13204, 13301(b), 13303(a), (b), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-608">104 Stat. 1388–608</ref>, 1388–615, 1388–616, 1388–623, 1388–625; <ref href="/us/pl/104/4/tI/s102/2">Pub. L. 104–4, title I, § 102(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-03-22">Mar. 22, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/62">109 Stat. 62</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tX/s10105/a">Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10105(a)</ref>–(f)(1), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/679">111 Stat. 679</ref>, 680; <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/dA/tI/s122/1">Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title I, § 122(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/1175">127 Stat. 1175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcac036e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcac036f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcac0370-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Title II of the Social Security Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 401 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (i), is classified generally to Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(4), means <ref href="/us/pl/93/344">Pub. L. 93–344</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/297">88 Stat. 297</ref>, known as the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974, which enacted chapters 17, 17A and 17B, and <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s190a–3">section 190a–3 of this title</ref> and sections 11a, 11c, 11d, 1020a of former Title 31, Money and Finance, amended sections 11, 665, 701, 1020, 1151, 1152, 1153 and 1154 of former Title 31, <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s105">section 105 of Title 1</ref>, General Provisions, sections 190b and 190d of this title, repealed sections 571 and 581c–1 of former Title 31 and sections 66 and 81 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 190a–1, 621, 632, and 682 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s105">section 105 of Title 1</ref>, and section 1020 of former Title 31. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621">section 621 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Employment Act of 1946, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-02-20/ch33">act Feb. 20, 1946, ch. 33</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/23">60 Stat. 23</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 21 (§ 1021 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1021">section 1021 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Congressional Budget Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (g)(3), is titles I through IX of <ref href="/us/pl/93/344">Pub. L. 93–344</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/297">88 Stat. 297</ref>. Titles III and IV of the Act are classified generally to this subchapter (§ 631 et seq.) and subchapter II (§ 651 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621">section 621 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcac0371-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1322">section 1322 of Title 31</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcac0372-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s122/2">Pub. L. 113–67, § 122(2)</ref>, substituted “old-age” for “old age” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s122/1">Pub. L. 113–67, § 122(1)</ref>, substituted “for purposes” for “For purposes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10105/a">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10105(a)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “and for at least each of the 4 ensuing fiscal years” for “, and planning levels for each of the two ensuing fiscal years,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10105/b">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10105(b)</ref>, substituted “and outlays” for “, budget outlays, direct loan obligations, and primary loan guarantee commitments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10105/c/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10105(c)(1)</ref>, added par. (7) and struck out former par. (7) which related to setting forth pay-as-you-go procedures for the Senate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10105/c/2">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10105(c)(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10105/d">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10105(d)</ref>, in first sentence, inserted “or at such time as may be requested by the Committee on the Budget,” after “title 31,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10105/e">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10105(e)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. heading, added pars. (2) and (3), and struck out former last sentence consisting of pars. (1) to (9) which contained requirements for contents of report to accompany the concurrent resolution on the budget.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10105/f/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10105(f)(1)</ref>, inserted heading and substituted “(or amendment, motion, or conference report on the resolution)” for “as reported to the Senate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/4">Pub. L. 104–4</ref> inserted at end “Any Committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate that anticipates that the committee will consider any proposed legislation establishing, amending, or reauthorizing any Federal program likely to have a significant budgetary impact on any State, local, or tribal government, or likely to have a significant financial impact on the private sector, including any legislative proposal submitted by the executive branch likely to have such a budgetary or financial impact, shall include its views and estimates on that proposal to the Committee on the Budget of the applicable House.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13301/b">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13301(b)</ref>, inserted at end: “The concurrent resolution shall not include the outlays and revenue totals of the old age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act or the related provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in the surplus or deficit totals required by this subsection or in any other surplus or deficit totals required by this subchapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13303/a">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13303(a)</ref>, added pars. (6) and (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13203">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13203</ref>, added pars. (5) and (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13204">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13204</ref>, added pars. (7) and (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13112/a/5">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13112(a)(5)</ref>, substituted “Within 6 weeks after the President submits a budget under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>” for “On or before February 25 of each year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13303/b">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13303(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (i) generally, substituting present provisions for former provisions relating to maximum deficit amounts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (e)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> temporarily added par. (10). See Effective and Termination Dates of 1988 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/s208/a">Pub. L. 100–119, § 208(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (g) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (g) read as follows: “The joint explanatory statement accompanying a conference report on a concurrent resolution on the budget shall set forth the common economic assumptions upon which such joint statement and conference report are based, or upon which any amendment contained in the joint explanatory statement to be proposed by the conferees in the case of technical disagreement is based.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/s106/d">Pub. L. 100–119, § 106(d)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—<ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> substituted “Adoption of concurrent resolution on the budget” for “Adoption of first concurrent resolution” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally, substituting provisions relating to content of concurrent resolution on the budget, for provisions relating to action required to be completed by May 15 of each year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> amended subsec. (b) generally, inserting provisions relating to achievement of goals for reducing unemployment and provisions relating to reconciliation directives described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s641">section 641 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally, substituting provisions relating to consideration of procedures or matters which have the effect of changing any rule of the House of Representatives, for provisions relating to submission on or before March 15 of each year of the views and estimates of other committees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally, substituting provisions relating to views and estimates of other committees, for provisions relating to hearings and report in developing the first concurrent resolution on the budget.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> amended subsec. (e) generally, substituting provisions relating to hearings and report in developing the concurrent resolution on the budget, for provisions relating to achievement of goals for reducing unemployment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, §§ 201(b), 275(b)(2)(B), in amending section generally, added subsecs. (f) to (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/s304/a">Pub. L. 95–523, § 304(a)</ref>, added par. (6) and redesignated former par. (6) as (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/s303/a">Pub. L. 95–523, § 303(a)</ref>, which directed insertion in subsec. (c) provisions relating to consideration by the Committee on the Budget of each House respecting short-term and medium-term goals set forth in the Joint Economic Committee report and the reflection of its views in its report and insertion of “also” after “concurrent resolution shall” was executed to subsec. (d) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/523/s304/b">Pub. L. 95–523, § 304(b)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcac0373-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcac0374-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1995 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/4">Pub. L. 104–4</ref> effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, or on the date 90 days after appropriations are made available as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1516">section 1516 of this title</ref>, whichever is earlier, and applicable to legislation considered on and after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/4/s110">section 110 of Pub. L. 104–4</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1511">section 1511 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcac0375-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13306">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13306</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-628">104 Stat. 1388–628</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13306">“Sections 13301, 13302, and 13303 and any amendments made by such sections [amending this section and sections 633 and 642 of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] shall apply with respect to fiscal years beginning on or after <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>. Section 13304 [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare] shall be effective for annual reports of the Board of Trustees issued in or after calendar year 1991.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcac0376-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> effective for fiscal years 1989, 1990, 1991, and 1992, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/s5303">section 5303 of Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcac0377-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> effective <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, and applicable with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1985-09-30">Sept. 30, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/177/s275/a/1">section 275(a)(1) of Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, formerly set out as an Effective and Termination Dates note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s900">section 900 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/112/25/tI/s104/a">Pub. L. 112–25, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-08-02">Aug. 2, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/246">125 Stat. 246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcac0378-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exclusion of Social Security From All Budgets</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13301/a">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13301(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-623">104 Stat. 1388–623</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13301/a">
<inline>“Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the receipts and disbursements of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund shall not be counted as new budget authority, outlays, receipts, or deficit or surplus for purposes of—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the budget of the United States Government as submitted by the President,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the congressional budget, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 [see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s900">section 900 of this title</ref>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcac0379-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Protection of OASDI Trust Funds in House of Representatives</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13302">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13302</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-623">104 Stat. 1388–623</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13302">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to consider any bill or joint resolution, as reported, or any amendment thereto or conference report thereon, if, upon enactment—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such legislation under consideration would provide for a net increase in OASDI benefits of at least 0.02 percent of the present value of future taxable payroll for the 75-year period utilized in the most recent annual report of the Board of Trustees provided pursuant to section 201(c)(2) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401/c/2">42 U.S.C. 401(c)(2)</ref>], and (B) such legislation under consideration does not provide at least a net increase, for such 75-year period, in OASDI taxes of the amount by which the net increase in such benefits exceeds 0.02 percent of the present value of future taxable payroll for such 75-year period,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such legislation under consideration would provide for a net increase in OASDI benefits (for the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration), (B) such net increase, together with the net increases in OASDI benefits resulting from previous legislation enacted during that fiscal year or any of the previous 4 fiscal years (as estimated at the time of enactment) which are attributable to those portions of the 5-year estimating periods for such previous legislation that fall within the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration, exceeds $250,000,000, and (C) such legislation under consideration does not provide at least a net increase, for the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration, in OASDI taxes which, together with net increases in OASDI taxes resulting from such previous legislation which are attributable to those portions of the 5-year estimating periods for such previous legislation that fall within the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration, equals the amount by which the net increase derived under subparagraph (B) exceeds $250,000,000;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such legislation under consideration would provide for a net decrease in OASDI taxes of at least 0.02 percent of the present value of future taxable payroll for the 75-year period utilized in the most recent annual report of the Board of Trustees provided pursuant to section 201(c)(2) of the Social Security Act, and (B) such legislation under consideration does not provide at least a net decrease, for such 75-year period, in OASDI benefits of the amount by which the net decrease in such taxes exceeds 0.02 percent of the present value of future taxable payroll for such 75-year period, or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such legislation under consideration would provide for a net decrease in OASDI taxes (for the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration), (B) such net decrease, together with the net decreases in OASDI taxes resulting from previous legislation enacted during that fiscal year or any of the previous 4 fiscal years (as estimated at the time of enactment) which are attributable to those portions of the 5-year estimating periods for such previous legislation that fall within the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration, exceeds $250,000,000, and (C) such legislation under consideration does not provide at least a net decrease, for the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration, in OASDI benefits which, together with net decreases in OASDI benefits resulting from such previous legislation which are attributable to those portions of the 5-year estimating periods for such previous legislation that fall within the 5-year estimating period for such legislation under consideration, equals the amount by which the net decrease derived under subparagraph (B) exceeds $250,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading><content>In applying paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (a), any provision of any bill or joint resolution, as reported, or any amendment thereto, or conference report thereon, the effect of which is to provide for a net decrease for any period in taxes described in subsection (c)(2)(A) shall be disregarded if such bill, joint resolution, amendment, or conference report also includes a provision the effect of which is to provide for a net increase of at least an equivalent amount for such period in medicare taxes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘OASDI benefits’ means the benefits under the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance programs under title II of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘OASDI taxes’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the taxes imposed under sections 1401(a), 3101(a), and 3111(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1401/a">26 U.S.C. 1401(a)</ref>, 3101(a), 3111(a)], and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the taxes imposed under chapter 1 of such Code [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.] (to the extent attributable to section 86 of such Code [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s86">26 U.S.C. 86</ref>]).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘medicare taxes’ means the taxes imposed under sections 1401(b), 3101(b), and 3111(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The term ‘previous legislation’ shall not include legislation enacted before fiscal year 1991.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The term ‘5-year estimating period’ means, with respect to any legislation, the fiscal year in which such legislation becomes or would become effective and the next 4 fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> No provision of any bill or resolution, or any amendment thereto or conference report thereon, involving a change in chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be treated as affecting the amount of OASDI taxes referred to in paragraph (2)(B) unless such provision changes the income tax treatment of OASDI benefits.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcac037a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Balanced Federal Budgets; Congressional Budget Committee Reports by <date date="1979-04-15">April 15, 1979</date>, 1980, and 1981, of Balanced Fiscal Year Budgets for 1981 and 1982</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/5/s5">Pub. L. 96–5, § 5</ref>, <date date="1979-04-02">Apr. 2, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/8">93 Stat. 8</ref>, which provided that Congress shall balance the Federal budget, that the Budget Committees were to report, by <date date="1979-04-15">April 15, 1979</date>, a fiscal year budget for 1981 that would be in balance, and also a fiscal year budget for 1982 that would be in balance, and by <date date="1980-04-15">April 15, 1980</date>, a fiscal year budget for 1981 that would be in balance, and by <date date="1981-04-15">April 15, 1981</date>, a fiscal year budget for 1982 that would be in balance, and that the Budget Committees were to show the consequences of each budget on each budget function and on the economy, setting forth the effects on revenues, spending, employment, inflation, and national security, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s5/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1068">96 Stat. 1068</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddcac037b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of Congressional Budget Process to Fiscal Year Beginning <date date="1975-07-01">July 1, 1975</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tIX/s906">Pub. L. 93–344, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/332">88 Stat. 332</ref>, provided for application of provisions of this subchapter and sections 602(f), 651, and 652 of this title with respect to the fiscal year beginning <date date="1975-07-01">July 1, 1975</date>, to the extent agreed to by the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tX/s10120/a">Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10120(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/696">111 Stat. 696</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
