<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd38b2af-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6320"><num value="6320">§ 6320.</num><heading> Purchase of office equipment or furnishings by Senators</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38b2b0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6320/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization; conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a United States Senator may purchase, upon leaving office or otherwise ceasing to be a Senator (except by expulsion), any item or items of office equipment or office furnishings provided by the General Services Administration and then currently located and in use in an office of such Senator in the State then represented by such Senator.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38b2b1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6320/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Request by Senator and arrangement for purchase by Sergeant at Arms of Senate; regulations governing purchase; price</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the request of any United States Senator, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate shall arrange for and make the purchase of equipment and furnishings under subsection (a) of this section on behalf of such Senator. Each such purchase shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd38b2b2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6320/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in accordance with regulations which shall be prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, after consultation with the General Services Administration; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd38b2b3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6320/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> at a price equal to the acquisition cost to the Federal Government of the equipment or furnishings so purchased, less allowance for depreciation determined under such regulations, but in no instance less than the fair market value of such items.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38b2b4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6320/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Remittance of amounts received to General Services Administration; disposition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Amounts received by the Federal Government from the sale of items of office equipment or office furnishings under this section shall be remitted to the General Services Administration and credited to the appropriate account or accounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd38b2b5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/462/s2">Pub. L. 93–462, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-10-20">Oct. 20, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1388">88 Stat. 1388</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd38b2b6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd38b2b7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd38b2b8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s59b">section 59b of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
