<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcae73fe-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639"><num value="639">§ 639.</num><heading> Reports, summaries, and projections of Congressional budget actions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcae73ff-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Legislation providing new budget authority or providing increase or decrease in revenues or tax expenditures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcae7400-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Whenever a committee of either House reports to its House a bill or joint resolution, or committee amendment thereto, providing new budget authority (other than continuing appropriations) or providing an increase or decrease in revenues or tax expenditures for a fiscal year (or fiscal years), the report accompanying that bill or joint resolution shall contain a statement, or the committee shall make available such a statement in the case of an approved committee amendment which is not reported to its House, prepared after consultation with the Director of the Congressional Budget Office—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7401-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> comparing the levels in such measure to the appropriate allocations in the reports submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s633/b">section 633(b) of this title</ref> for the most recently agreed to concurrent resolution on the budget for such fiscal year (or fiscal years);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7402-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> containing a projection by the Congressional Budget Office of how such measure will affect the levels of such budget authority, budget outlays, revenues, or tax expenditures under existing law for such fiscal year (or fiscal years) and each of the four ensuing fiscal years, if timely submitted before such report is filed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7403-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> containing an estimate by the Congressional Budget Office of the level of new budget authority for assistance to State and local governments provided by such measure, if timely submitted before such report is filed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcae7404-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Whenever a conference report is filed in either House and such conference report or any amendment reported in disagreement or any amendment contained in the joint statement of managers to be proposed by the conferees in the case of technical disagreement on such bill or joint resolution provides new budget authority (other than continuing appropriations) or provides an increase or decrease in revenues for a fiscal year (or fiscal years), the statement of managers accompanying such conference report shall contain the information described in paragraph (1), if available on a timely basis. If such information is not available when the conference report is filed, the committee shall make such information available to Members as soon as practicable prior to the consideration of such conference report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcae7405-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> CBO <inline class="small-caps">paygo</inline> estimates.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7406-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Chairs of the Committees on the Budget of the House and Senate, as applicable, shall request from the Director of the Congressional Budget Office an estimate of the budgetary effects of PAYGO legislation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7407-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Estimates shall be prepared using baseline estimates supplied by the Congressional Budget Office, consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s907">section 907 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7408-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Director shall not count timing shifts, as that term is defined at <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s932/8">section 932(8) of this title</ref>, in estimates of the budgetary effects of PAYGO Legislation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcae7409-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Up-to-date tabulations of Congressional budget action</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcae740a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall issue to the committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate reports on at least a monthly basis detailing and tabulating the progress of congressional action on bills and joint resolutions providing new budget authority or providing an increase or decrease in revenues or tax expenditures for each fiscal year covered by a concurrent resolution on the budget. Such reports shall include but are not limited to an up-to-date tabulation comparing the appropriate aggregate and functional levels (including outlays) included in the most recently adopted concurrent resolution on the budget with the levels provided in bills and joint resolutions reported by committees or adopted by either House or by the Congress, and with the levels provided by law for the fiscal year preceding the first fiscal year covered by the appropriate concurrent resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcae740b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Committee on the Budget of each House shall make available to Members of its House summary budget scorekeeping reports. Such reports—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae740c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall be made available on at least a monthly basis, but in any case frequently enough to provide Members of each House an accurate representation of the current status of congressional consideration of the budget;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae740d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall include, but are not limited to, summaries of tabulations provided under subsection (b)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae740e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall be based on information provided under subsection (b)(1) without substantive revision.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The chairman of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives shall submit such reports to the Speaker.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcae740f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Five-year projection of Congressional budget action</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the beginning of each fiscal year, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall issue a report projecting for the period of 5 fiscal years beginning with such fiscal year—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7410-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> total new budget authority and total budget outlays for each fiscal year in such period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7411-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> revenues to be received and the major sources thereof, and the surplus or deficit, if any, for each fiscal year in such period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7412-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> tax expenditures for each fiscal year in such period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcae7413-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> entitlement authority for each fiscal year in such period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcae7414-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s639/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Scorekeeping guidelines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Estimates under this section shall be provided in accordance with the scorekeeping guidelines determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s902/d/5">section 902(d)(5) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcae7415-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tIII/s308">Pub. L. 93–344, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/313">88 Stat. 313</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/177/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1051">99 Stat. 1051</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13206">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13206</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-617">104 Stat. 1388–617</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tX/s10110">Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10110</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/685">111 Stat. 685</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/139/tI/s4/b">Pub. L. 111–139, title I, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-02-12">Feb. 12, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/11">124 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/dA/tI/s122/8">Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title I, § 122(8)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/1175">127 Stat. 1175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcae7416-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcae7417-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcae7418-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1329">section 1329 of Title 31</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcae7419-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67">Pub. L. 113–67</ref> made technical amendment to heading in original Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/139/s4/b/1/B">Pub. L. 111–139, § 4(b)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “Reports on” before “Legislation” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/139/s4/b/1/A">Pub. L. 111–139, § 4(b)(1)(A)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/139/s4/b/2">Pub. L. 111–139, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/1/A">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “, new spending authority, or new credit authority,” after “new budget authority” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/4">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(4)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “bill or joint resolution” for “bill or resolution” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/1/D">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(1)(D)</ref>, in introductory provisions, struck out “, new spending authority described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/2">section 651(c)(2) of this title</ref>, or new credit authority,” after “continuing appropriations)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/1/C">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “revenues, or tax expenditures” for “spending authority, revenues, tax expenditures, direct loan obligations, or primary loan guarantee commitments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/1/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(1)(B)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (C) as (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “including an identification of any new spending authority described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/2">section 651(c)(2) of this title</ref> which is contained in such measure and a justification for the use of such financing method instead of annual appropriations;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/1/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(1)(B)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (C) and (D) as (B) and (C), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/4">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(4)</ref>, substituted “bill or joint resolution” for “bill or resolution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/1/D">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(1)(D)</ref>, struck out “, new spending authority described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/2">section 651(c)(2) of this title</ref>, or new credit authority,” after “continuing appropriations)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/4">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(4)</ref>, substituted “bills and joint resolutions” for “bills and resolutions” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/2">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(2)</ref>, struck out “, new spending authority described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/2">section 651(c)(2) of this title</ref>, or new credit authority,” after “new budget authority”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10110/3">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10110(3)</ref>, inserted “and” at end of par. (3), substituted a period for “; and” at end of par. (4), and struck out par. (5) which read as follows: “credit authority for each fiscal year in such period.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13206/a/1">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13206(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “(or fiscal years)” after “fiscal year” in introductory provisions and in subpars. (A) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13206/b">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13206(b)</ref>, inserted “(or fiscal years)” after “fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13206/c">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13206(c)</ref>, substituted “for each fiscal year covered by a concurrent resolution on the budget” for “for a fiscal year” in first sentence, and “the first fiscal year covered by the appropriate concurrent resolution” for “such fiscal year” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, in amending subsec. (a) generally, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted provisions relating to reports on legislation providing new budget authority, new spending authority, or new credit authority, or providing an increase or decrease in revenues or tax expenditures, for provisions relating to reports on legislation providing new budget authority or tax expenditures, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, in amending subsec. (b) generally, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted provisions relating to issuance of reports on a monthly basis and contents of such reports, for provisions relating to issuance of reports on a periodic basis and contents of such reports, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally, adding pars. (4) and (5).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcae741a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcae741b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> effective <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, and applicable with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1985-09-30">Sept. 30, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/177/s275/a/1">section 275(a)(1) of Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, formerly set out as an Effective and Termination Dates note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s900">section 900 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/112/25/tI/s104/a">Pub. L. 112–25, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-08-02">Aug. 2, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/246">125 Stat. 246</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
