<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd38b2bc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6501"><num value="6501">§ 6501.</num><heading> Appointment of consultants by Majority Leader, Minority Leader, Secretary of Senate, and Legislative Counsel of Senate; compensation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38b2bd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6501/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Majority Leader and the Minority Leader, are each authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than 12 individual consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate. The President pro tempore of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than three individual consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this subsection. The President pro tempore emeritus of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of one individual consultant, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this subsection. The Secretary of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than two individual consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of the per diem equivalent of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate. The Legislative Counsel of the Senate (subject to the approval of the President pro tempore) is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than two consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this section. The provisions of sections 8344 and 8468 of title 5 shall not apply to any individual serving in a position under this authority. Expenditures under this authority shall be paid from the contingent fund of the Senate upon vouchers approved by the President pro tempore, President pro tempore emeritus, Majority Leader, Minority Leader, Secretary of the Senate, or Legislative Counsel of the Senate, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38b2be-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6501/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any or all appointments under this section may be at an annual rate of compensation rather than at a daily rate of compensation, but such annual rate shall not be in excess of the highest gross rate of annual compensation which may be paid to employees of a standing committee of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd38b2bf-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6501/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002118">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002118"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “(c)”.</note> Title of position</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each appointing authority under subsection (a) may designate the title of the position of any individual appointed under that subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd38b2c0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/26/tI/s101">Pub. L. 95–26, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1977-05-04">May 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/82">91 Stat. 82</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/94/tI/s110/a">Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 110(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/662">91 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/458/tI">Pub. L. 100–458, title I</ref>, §§ 4, 9, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2161">102 Stat. 2161</ref>, 2162; <ref href="/us/pl/101/302/tIII/s314/a">Pub. L. 101–302, title III, § 314(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/245">104 Stat. 245</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/90/tI/s3">Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 3</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/450">105 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/2">Pub. L. 104–2</ref>, <date date="1995-02-09">Feb. 9, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/45">109 Stat. 45</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/275/tI/s4/a">Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 4(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2433">112 Stat. 2433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/20/tII/s2803">Pub. L. 107–20, title II, § 2803</ref>, <date date="2001-07-24">July 24, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/185">115 Stat. 185</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/68/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/563">115 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dH/tI/s6/a">Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/350">117 Stat. 350</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/8/dG/tI/s2/a">Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/814">123 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/47/dE/tI/s102">Pub. L. 118–47, div. E, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/712">138 Stat. 712</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd38b2c1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd38b2c2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd38b2c3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s61h–6">section 61h–6 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Some section numbers of this title referenced in amendment notes below reflect the classification of such sections prior to their editorial reclassification.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1977.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd38b2c4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/118/47">Pub. L. 118–47</ref> substituted “12 individual consultants” for “nine individual consultants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/8">Pub. L. 111–8</ref> substituted “nine individual consultants” for “eight individual consultants” in first sentence and “three individual consultants” for “two individual consultants” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s6/a/1">Pub. L. 108–7, § 6(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “eight individual consultants” for “six individual consultants” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (C). <ref href="/us/pl/108/7/s6/a/2">Pub. L. 108–7, § 6(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/68">Pub. L. 107–68</ref> substituted “six individual consultants” for “four individual consultants” in first sentence and “not more than two individual consultants” for “one consultant” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/20">Pub. L. 107–20</ref> inserted “The President pro tempore emeritus of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of one individual consultant, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this subsection.” after second sentence and “President pro tempore emeritus,” after “President pro tempore,” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/275/s4/a">Pub. L. 105–275, § 4(a)</ref>, inserted after first sentence “The President pro tempore of the Senate is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of one consultant, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this subsection.” and in penultimate sentence substituted “sections 8344 and 8468” for “section 8344”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/275/s4/b">Pub. L. 105–275, § 4(b)</ref>, substituted “Any or all appointments under this section may be” for “The Majority Leader, and the Minority Leader, in appointing individuals to consultant positions under authority of this section, may appoint one such individual to such position”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/2">Pub. L. 104–2</ref>, which directed the general amendment of <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s61h–6">section 61h–6 of title 2</ref>, was executed by amending <ref href="/us/pl/95/26/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 95–26</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s61h–6">section 61h–6 of title 2</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress, in subsec. (a) striking out provisions regarding appointment of two consultants at daily rate of compensation by President pro tempore of Senate and increasing number of appointments by Majority Leader of Senate from two to four consultants at daily rate of compensation, and in subsec. (b) striking out provisions regarding appointment of one consultant at an annual rate of compensation by President pro tempore of Senate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/90">Pub. L. 102–90</ref> which directed the insertion of “The Legislative Counsel of the Senate (subject to the approval of the President pro tempore) is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of not more than 2 consultants, on a temporary or intermittent basis, at a daily rate of compensation not in excess of that specified in the first sentence of this section.” immediately after the second sentence of this section and which directed the substitution of “, Secretary of the Senate, or Legislative Counsel of the Senate, as the case may be” for “and the Secretary of the Senate, respectively” in the last sentence of this section, was executed by making the insertion and the substitution for “and Secretary of the Senate, respectively”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/302">Pub. L. 101–302</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/458">Pub. L. 100–458</ref> provided for appointment, compensation, and voucher approval of two consultants by President pro tempore of Senate and increased the number of appointments by Minority Leader of Senate from two to four individuals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/94">Pub. L. 95–94</ref> inserted two references to Secretary of Senate.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd38b2c5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd38b2c6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/8/dG/tI/s2/b">Pub. L. 111–8, div. G, title I, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/815">123 Stat. 815</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/8/dG/tI/s2/b">“This section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>] and shall apply to fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd38b2c7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dH/tI/s6/b">Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/350">117 Stat. 350</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/7/dH/tI/s6/b">“This section [amending this section] shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd38b2c8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/68/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-11-12">Nov. 12, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/563">115 Stat. 563</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/68/tI/s101/b">“This section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd38b2c9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/275/tI/s4/c">Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2433">112 Stat. 2433</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/275/tI/s4/c">“This section [amending this section] is effective on and after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd38b2ca-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/302/tIII/s314/b">Pub. L. 101–302, title III, § 314(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/246">104 Stat. 246</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/302/tIII/s314/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall be effective in the case of appointments made after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd38b2cb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/94/tI/s110/b">Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 110(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-05">Aug. 5, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/662">91 Stat. 662</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/94/tI/s110/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="1977-08-01">August 1, 1977</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="iddd38b2cc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Consultants</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dH/tI/s8">Pub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 8</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2222">121 Stat. 2222</ref>, provided that, with respect to fiscal year 2008, the first sentence of this section shall be applied by substituting “nine individual consultants” for “eight individual consultants”.</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/55/tI/s2">Pub. L. 109–55, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="2005-08-02">Aug. 2, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/568">119 Stat. 568</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dG/tI/s2">Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3169">118 Stat. 3169</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/83/tI/s6">Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 6</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1013">117 Stat. 1013</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
