<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd38b2ed-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6506"><num value="6506">§ 6506.</num><heading> Separate accounts for “Secretary of the Senate” and for “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”; establishment within Senate contingent fund; inclusion of funds in existing accounts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd38b2ee-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6506/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Effective <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd38b2ef-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6506/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> there shall be, within the contingent fund of the Senate, a separate account for the “Secretary of the Senate”, and a separate account for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd38b2f0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6506/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the account for “Automobiles and Maintenance”, within the contingent fund of the Senate, is abolished, and funds for the purchase, lease, exchange, maintenance, and operation of vehicles for the Senate shall be included in the separate account, established by paragraph (1), for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddd38b2f1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6506/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the account for “Postage Stamps”, within the contingent fund of the Senate, is abolished; and funds for special delivery postage of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate shall be included in the separate account, established by paragraph (1), for the “Secretary of the Senate”; funds for special delivery postage of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate shall be included in the separate account, established by paragraph (1), for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”; and postage stamps for the Secretaries for the Majority and the Minority and other offices and officers of the Senate, as authorized by law, shall be included in the account for “Miscellaneous Items”, within the contingent fund of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd38b2f2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6506/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any provision of law which was enacted, or any Senate resolution which was agreed to, prior to <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, and which authorizes moneys in the contingent fund of the Senate to be expended by or for the use of the Secretary of the Senate, or his office (whether generally or from a specified account within such fund) may on and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, be construed to authorize such moneys to be expended from the separate account, within such fund, established by subsection (a)(1) for the “Secretary of the Senate”; and any provision of law which was enacted prior to <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, and which authorizes moneys in the contingent fund of the Senate to be expended by or for the use of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, or his office (whether generally or from a specified account within such fund) may on and after <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, be construed to authorize such moneys to be expended from the separate account, within such fund, established by subsection (a)(1) for the “Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd38b2f3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/51/tI/s103">Pub. L. 98–51, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1983-07-14">July 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/266">97 Stat. 266</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd38b2f4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd38b2f5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd38b2f6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s68–3">section 68–3 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Congressional Operations Appropriation Act, 1984, which is title I of the Legislative Branch Appropriation, 1984.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
