<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd3b23fd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6508"><num value="6508">§ 6508.</num><heading> Transfers from appropriations account for expenses of Office of Secretary of Senate and Office of Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd3b23fe-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6508/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of the Senate is authorized, with the approval of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, to transfer, during any fiscal year (1) from the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate, such sums as he shall specify to the Senate appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Secretary”, and (2) from the Senate appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Secretary” to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate, such sums as he shall specify; and any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd3b23ff-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6508/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized, with the approval of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, to transfer, during any fiscal year, from the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, such sums as he shall specify to the appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper”; and any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd3b2400-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/458/tI/s3">Pub. L. 100–458, title I, § 3</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2161">102 Stat. 2161</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/302/tIII/s317">Pub. L. 101–302, title III, § 317</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/247">104 Stat. 247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd3b2401-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd3b2402-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd3b2403-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s68–6">section 68–6 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Congressional Operations Appropriations Act, 1989, which is title I of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1989.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddd3b2404-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in the following prior appropriation act:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/i/tI/s8">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title I, § 8]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-290">101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–295.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd3b2405-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/302">Pub. L. 101–302</ref> designated existing provisions as cl. (1) and added cl. (2).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
