<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb0e5c2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651"><num value="651">§ 651.</num><heading> Budget-related legislation not subject to appropriations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb0e5c3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Controls on certain budget-related legislation not subject to appropriations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall not be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any bill or joint resolution (in the House of Representatives only, as reported), amendment, motion, or conference report that provides—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb0e5c4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> new authority to enter into contracts under which the United States is obligated to make outlays;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb0e5c5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> new authority to incur indebtedness (other than indebtedness incurred under chapter 31 of title 31) for the repayment of which the United States is liable; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb0e5c6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> new credit authority;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless that bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report also provides that the new authority is to be effective for any fiscal year only to the extent or in the amounts provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb0e5c7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Legislation providing new entitlement authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcb0e5c8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Point of order</inline>.—</heading><content>It shall not be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any bill or joint resolution (in the House of Representatives only, as reported), amendment, motion, or conference report that provides new entitlement authority that is to become effective during the current fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcb0e5c9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If any committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate reports any bill or resolution which provides new entitlement authority which is to become effective during a fiscal year and the amount of new budget authority which will be required for such fiscal year if such bill or resolution is enacted as so reported exceeds the appropriate allocation of new budget authority reported under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s633/a">section 633(a) of this title</ref> in connection with the most recently agreed to concurrent resolution on the budget for such fiscal year, such bill or resolution shall then be referred to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or may then be referred to the Committee on Appropriations of the House, as the case may be, with instructions to report it, with the committee’s recommendations, within 15 calendar days (not counting any day on which that House is not in session) beginning with the day following the day on which it is so referred. If the Committee on Appropriations of either House fails to report a bill or resolution referred to it under this paragraph within such 15-day period, the committee shall automatically be discharged from further consideration of such bill or resolution and such bill or resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcb0e5ca-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Committee on Appropriations of each House shall have jurisdiction to report any bill or resolution referred to it under paragraph (2) with an amendment which limits the total amount of new spending authority provided in such bill or resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb0e5cb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcb0e5cc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to new authority described in those subsections if outlays from that new authority will flow—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb0e5cd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> from a trust fund established by the Social Security Act (as in effect on <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s301">42 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb0e5ce-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> from any other trust fund, 90 percent or more of the receipts of which consist or will consist of amounts (transferred from the general fund of the Treasury) equivalent to amounts of taxes (related to the purposes for which such outlays are or will be made) received in the Treasury under specified provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">26 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcb0e5cf-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to new authority described in those subsections to the extent that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb0e5d0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the outlays resulting therefrom are made by an organization which is (i) a mixed-ownership Government corporation (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9101/2">section 9101(2) of title 31</ref>), or (ii) a wholly owned Government corporation (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9101/3">section 9101(3) of title 31</ref>) which is specifically exempted by law from compliance with any or all of the provisions of chapter 91 of title 31, as of <date date="1985-12-12">December 12, 1985</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb0e5d1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the outlays resulting therefrom consist exclusively of the proceeds of gifts or bequests made to the United States for a specific purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddcb0e5d2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s651/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the House of Representatives, subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to new authority described in those subsections to the extent that a provision in a bill or joint resolution, or an amendment thereto or a conference report thereon, establishes prospectively for a Federal office or position a specified or minimum level of compensation to be funded by annual discretionary appropriations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcb0e5d3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 93–344, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/317">88 Stat. 317</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/177/tII/s211">Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1056">99 Stat. 1056</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13207/a/1/F">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13207(a)(1)(F)</ref>, (G), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-617">104 Stat. 1388–617</ref>, 1388–618; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tX/s10116/a/1">Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10116(a)(1)</ref>–(5), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/690">111 Stat. 690</ref>, 691; <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/dA/tI/s122/12">Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title I, § 122(12)</ref>, (13), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/1176">127 Stat. 1176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb0e5d4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcb0e5d5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddcb0e5d6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(A), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 7 (§ 301 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(B), is classified generally to Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcb0e5d7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (c)(2)(A), “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9101/2">section 9101(2) of title 31</ref>”, “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9101/3">section 9101(3) of title 31</ref>”, and “chapter 91 of title 31” were substituted for “section 201 of the Government Corporation Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s856">31 U.S.C. 856</ref>]”, “section 101 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s846">31 U.S.C. 846</ref>]”, and “that Act”, respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1351">section 1351 of Title 31</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcb0e5d8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s122/12">Pub. L. 113–67, § 122(12)</ref>, substituted “section 633(a)” for “section 633(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/113/67/s122/13">Pub. L. 113–67, § 122(13)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/1/A">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Budget-related legislation not subject to appropriations” for “Bills providing new spending authority” as section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/1/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (a). Text read as follows: “It shall not be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report, as reported to its House which provides new spending authority described in subsection (c)(2)(A) or (B) of this section, unless that bill, resolution, conference report, or amendment also provides that such new spending authority as described in subsection (c)(2)(A) or (B) of this section is to be effective for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/2/A">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “new” before “entitlement” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/2/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(2)(B)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “It shall not be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report, as reported to its House, which provides new spending authority described in subsection (c)(2)(C) of this section which is to become effective before the first day of the fiscal year which begins during the calendar year in which such bill or resolution is reported.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/2/C">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “new entitlement authority” for “new spending authority described in subsection (c)(2)(C) of this section” and “of the Senate or may then be referred to the Committee on Appropriations of the House, as the case may be,” for “of that House”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/5">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/3">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(3)</ref>, struck out subsec. (c) which defined terms “new spending authority” and “spending authority”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/5">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/4/A">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(4)(A)</ref>, which directed substitution of “new authority described in those subsections if outlays from that new authority will flow” for “new spending authority if the budget authority for outlays which result from such new spending authority is derived”, was executed by making the substitution for “new spending authority if the budget authority for outlays which will result from such new spending authority is derived” in introductory provisions to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10116/a/4/B">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10116(a)(4)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (3) as (2), substituted “new authority described in those subsections” for “new spending authority” in introductory provisions, and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall not apply to new spending authority which is an amendment to or extension of chapter 67 of title 31, or a continuation of the program of fiscal assistance to State and local governments provided by that chapter, to the extent so provided in the bill or resolution providing such authority.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13207/a/1/F">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13207(a)(1)(F)</ref>, substituted “bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report” for “bill, resolution, or conference report” and struck out “(or any amendment which provides such new spending authority)” after “subsection (c)(2)(A) or (B) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s13207/a/1/G">Pub. L. 101–508, § 13207(a)(1)(G)</ref>, substituted “bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report, as reported to its House” for “bill or resolution” and struck out “(or any amendment which provides such new spending authority)” after “subsection (c)(2)(C) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally, inserting provisions relating to applicability to conference reports.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, in amending section generally, reenacted subsec. (b) without change.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, in amending subsec. (c) generally, added pars. (2)(D) and (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, in amending subsec. (d) generally, reenacted pars. (1) and (2) without change, and inserted reference to <date date="1985-12-12">December 12, 1985</date>, in par. (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcb32ec9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddcb32eca-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref> effective <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, and applicable with respect to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1985-09-30">Sept. 30, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/177/s275/a/1">section 275(a)(1) of Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, formerly set out as an Effective and Termination Dates note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s900">section 900 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/112/25/tI/s104/a">Pub. L. 112–25, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-08-02">Aug. 2, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/246">125 Stat. 246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddcb32ecb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tIX/s905/c">Pub. L. 93–344, title IX, § 905(c)</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/331">88 Stat. 331</ref> (formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s621">section 621 of this title</ref>), provided that except as provided in <ref href="/us/pl/93/344/s906">section 906 of Pub. L. 93–344</ref> (formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s632">section 632 of this title</ref>) this section shall take effect on the first day of the second regular session of the Ninety-fourth Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
