<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb32f6e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d"><num value="658d">§ 658d.</num><heading> Legislation subject to point of order</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32f6f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall not be in order in the Senate or the House of Representatives to consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb32f70-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any bill or joint resolution that is reported by a committee unless the committee has published a statement of the Director on the direct costs of Federal mandates in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s658b/f">section 658b(f) of this title</ref> before such consideration, except this paragraph shall not apply to any supplemental statement prepared by the Director under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s658c/d">section 658c(d) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb32f71-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> any bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report that would increase the direct costs of Federal intergovernmental mandates by an amount that causes the thresholds specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s658c/a/1">section 658c(a)(1) of this title</ref> to be exceeded, unless—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb32f72-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report provides new budget authority or new entitlement authority in the House of Representatives or direct spending authority in the Senate for each fiscal year for such mandates included in the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report in an amount equal to or exceeding the direct costs of such mandate; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb32f73-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report includes an authorization for appropriations in an amount equal to or exceeding the direct costs of such mandate, and—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f74-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> identifies a specific dollar amount of the direct costs of such mandate for each year up to 10 years during which such mandate shall be in effect under the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion or conference report, and such estimate is consistent with the estimate determined under subsection (e) for each fiscal year;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f75-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> identifies any appropriation bill that is expected to provide for Federal funding of the direct cost referred to under clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f76-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f77-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> provides that for any fiscal year the responsible Federal agency shall determine whether there are insufficient appropriations for that fiscal year to provide for the direct costs under clause (i) of such mandate, and shall (no later than 30 days after the beginning of the fiscal year) notify the appropriate authorizing committees of Congress of the determination and submit either—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddcb32f78-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> a statement that the agency has determined, based on a re-estimate of the direct costs of such mandate, after consultation with State, local, and tribal governments, that the amount appropriated is sufficient to pay for the direct costs of such mandate; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddcb32f79-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> legislative recommendations for either implementing a less costly mandate or making such mandate ineffective for the fiscal year;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f7a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> provides for expedited procedures for the consideration of the statement or legislative recommendations referred to in subclause (I) by Congress no later than 30 days after the statement or recommendations are submitted to Congress; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f7b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><chapeau> provides that such mandate shall—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddcb32f7c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> in the case of a statement referred to in subclause (I)(aa), cease to be effective 60 days after the statement is submitted unless Congress has approved the agency’s determination by joint resolution during the 60-day period;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddcb32f7d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> cease to be effective 60 days after the date the legislative recommendations of the responsible Federal agency are submitted to Congress under subclause (I)(bb) unless Congress provides otherwise by law; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="iddcb32f7e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/a/2/B/iii/III/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> in the case that such mandate that has not yet taken effect, continue not to be effective unless Congress provides otherwise by law.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32f7f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of subsection (a)(2)(B)(iii) shall not be construed to prohibit or otherwise restrict a State, local, or tribal government from voluntarily electing to remain subject to the original Federal intergovernmental mandate, complying with the programmatic or financial responsibilities of the original Federal intergovernmental mandate and providing the funding necessary consistent with the costs of Federal agency assistance, monitoring, and enforcement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32f80-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Committee on Appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32f81-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb32f82-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall not apply to any bill or resolution reported by the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or the House of Representatives; except</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb32f83-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> shall apply to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f84-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any legislative provision increasing direct costs of a Federal intergovernmental mandate contained in any bill or resolution reported by the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f85-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any legislative provision increasing direct costs of a Federal intergovernmental mandate contained in any amendment offered to a bill or resolution reported by the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or House of Representatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f86-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any legislative provision increasing direct costs of a Federal intergovernmental mandate in a conference report accompanying a bill or resolution reported by the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or House of Representatives; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="iddcb32f87-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any legislative provision increasing direct costs of a Federal intergovernmental mandate contained in any amendments in disagreement between the two Houses to any bill or resolution reported by the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or House of Representatives.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32f88-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain provisions stricken in Senate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon a point of order being made by any Senator against any provision listed in paragraph (1)(B), and the point of order being sustained by the Chair, such specific provision shall be deemed stricken from the bill, resolution, amendment, amendment in disagreement, or conference report and may not be offered as an amendment from the floor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32f89-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations of applicability to pending legislation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, in the Senate, the presiding officer of the Senate shall consult with the Committee on Governmental Affairs, to the extent practicable, on questions concerning the applicability of this part to a pending bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32f8a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations of Federal mandate levels</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, in the Senate, the levels of Federal mandates for a fiscal year shall be determined based on the estimates made by the Committee on the Budget.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcb32f8b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tIV/s425">Pub. L. 93–344, title IV, § 425</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/4/tI/s101/a/2">Pub. L. 104–4, title I, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-03-22">Mar. 22, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/56">109 Stat. 56</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb32f8c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcb32f8d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="iddcb32f8e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, <date date="2004-10-09">Oct. 9, 2004</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddcb32f8f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, or on the date 90 days after appropriations are made available as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1516">section 1516 of this title</ref>, whichever is earlier, and applicable to legislation considered on and after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/4/s110">section 110 of Pub. L. 104–4</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1511">section 1511 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
