<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb32fa1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g"><num value="658g">§ 658g.</num><heading> Clarification of application</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32fa2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This part applies to any bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report that reauthorizes appropriations, or that amends existing authorizations of appropriations, to carry out any statute, or that otherwise amends any statute, only if enactment of the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb32fa3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> would result in a net reduction in or elimination of authorization of appropriations for Federal financial assistance that would be provided to State, local, or tribal governments for use for the purpose of complying with any Federal intergovernmental mandate, or to the private sector for use to comply with any Federal private sector mandate, and would not eliminate or reduce duties established by the Federal mandate by a corresponding amount; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb32fa4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> would result in a net increase in the aggregate amount of direct costs of Federal intergovernmental mandates or Federal private sector mandates other than as described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32fa5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct costs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32fa6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this part, the direct cost of the Federal mandates in a bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report that reauthorizes appropriations, or that amends existing authorizations of appropriations, to carry out a statute, or that otherwise amends any statute, means the net increase, resulting from enactment of the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report, in the amount described under paragraph (2)(A) over the amount described under paragraph (2)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32fa7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amounts referred to under paragraph (1) are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb32fa8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the aggregate amount of direct costs of Federal mandates that would result under the statute if the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report is enacted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb32fa9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the aggregate amount of direct costs of Federal mandates that would result under the statute if the bill, joint resolution, amendment, motion, or conference report were not enacted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb32faa-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s658g/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension of authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, in the case of legislation to extend authorization of appropriations, the authorization level that would be provided by the extension shall be compared to the authorization level for the last year in which authorization of appropriations is already provided.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcb59fab-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tIV/s428">Pub. L. 93–344, title IV, § 428</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/4/tI/s101/a/2">Pub. L. 104–4, title I, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1995-03-22">Mar. 22, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/59">109 Stat. 59</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb59fac-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddcb59fad-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="iddcb59fae-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, or on the date 90 days after appropriations are made available as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1516">section 1516 of this title</ref>, whichever is earlier, and applicable to legislation considered on and after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/4/s110">section 110 of Pub. L. 104–4</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1511">section 1511 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
