<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb59fbb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a"><num value="661a">§ 661a.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fbc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “direct loan” means a disbursement of funds by the Government to a non-Federal borrower under a contract that requires the repayment of such funds with or without interest. The term includes the purchase of, or participation in, a loan made by another lender and financing arrangements that defer payment for more than 90 days, including the sale of a government <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002028">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002028"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be capitalized.</note> asset on credit terms. The term does not include the acquisition of a federally guaranteed loan in satisfaction of default claims or the price support loans of the Commodity Credit Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fbd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “direct loan obligation” means a binding agreement by a Federal agency to make a direct loan when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fbe-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “loan guarantee” means any guarantee, insurance, or other pledge with respect to the payment of all or a part of the principal or interest on any debt obligation of a non-Federal borrower to a non-Federal lender, but does not include the insurance of deposits, shares, or other withdrawable accounts in financial institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fbf-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “loan guarantee commitment” means a binding agreement by a Federal agency to make a loan guarantee when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower, the lender, or any other party to the guarantee agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fc0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fc1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “cost” means the estimated long-term cost to the Government of a direct loan or loan guarantee or modification thereof, calculated on a net present value basis, excluding administrative costs and any incidental effects on governmental receipts or outlays.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fc2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The cost of a direct loan shall be the net present value, at the time when the direct loan is disbursed, of the following estimated cash flows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb59fc3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> loan disbursements;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb59fc4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> repayments of principal; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb59fc5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> payments of interest and other payments by or to the Government over the life of the loan after adjusting for estimated defaults, prepayments, fees, penalties, and other recoveries;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">including the effects of changes in loan terms resulting from the exercise by the borrower of an option included in the loan contract.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fc6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> The cost of a loan guarantee shall be the net present value, at the time when the guaranteed loan is disbursed, of the following estimated cash flows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb59fc7-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> payments by the Government to cover defaults and delinquencies, interest subsidies, or other payments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb59fc8-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> payments to the Government including origination and other fees, penalties and recoveries;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">including the effects of changes in loan terms resulting from the exercise by the guaranteed lender of an option included in the loan guarantee contract, or by the borrower of an option included in the guaranteed loan contract.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fc9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The cost of a modification is the difference between the current estimate of the net present value of the remaining cash flows under the terms of a direct loan or loan guarantee contract, and the current estimate of the net present value of the remaining cash flows under the terms of the contract, as modified.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fca-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> In estimating net present values, the discount rate shall be the average interest rate on marketable Treasury securities of similar maturity to the cash flows of the direct loan or loan guarantee for which the estimate is being made.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fcb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> When funds are obligated for a direct loan or loan guarantee, the estimated cost shall be based on the current assumptions, adjusted to incorporate the terms of the loan contract, for the fiscal year in which the funds are obligated.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fcc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “credit program account” means the budget account into which an appropriation to cover the cost of a direct loan or loan guarantee program is made and from which such cost is disbursed to the financing account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fcd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “financing account” means the non-budget account or accounts associated with each credit program account which holds balances, receives the cost payment from the credit program account, and also includes all other cash flows to and from the Government resulting from direct loan obligations or loan guarantee commitments made on or after <date date="1991-10-01">October 1, 1991</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fce-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “liquidating account” means the budget account that includes all cash flows to and from the Government resulting from direct loan obligations or loan guarantee commitments made prior to <date date="1991-10-01">October 1, 1991</date>.<p style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">These accounts shall be shown in the budget on a cash basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fcf-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “modification” means any Government action that alters the estimated cost of an outstanding direct loan (or direct loan obligation) or an outstanding loan guarantee (or loan guarantee commitment) from the current estimate of cash flows. This includes the sale of loan assets, with or without recourse, and the purchase of guaranteed loans. This also includes any action resulting from new legislation, or from the exercise of administrative discretion under existing law, that directly or indirectly alters the estimated cost of outstanding direct loans (or direct loan obligations) or loan guarantees (or loan guarantee commitments) such as a change in collection procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fd0-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “current” has the same meaning as in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s900/c/9">section 900(c)(9) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb59fd1-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s661a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddcb59fd2-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tV/s502">Pub. L. 93–344, title V, § 502</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13201/a">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13201(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-610">104 Stat. 1388–610</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tX/s10117/a">Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10117(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/692">111 Stat. 692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb59fd3-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcb59fd4-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="iddcb59fd5-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/93/344/s502">section 502 of Pub. L. 93–344</ref>, title V, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/321">88 Stat. 321</ref>, was set out as a note under section 1020 of former Title 31, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s5/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1068">96 Stat. 1068</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcb59fd6-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10117/a/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10117(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and financing arrangements that defer payment for more than 90 days, including the sale of a government asset on credit terms” after “another lender”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10117/a/2">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10117(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “or modification thereof” after “or loan guarantee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10117/a/3">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10117(a)(3)</ref>, added subpars. (B) and (C) and struck out former subpars. (B) and (C) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) The cost of a direct loan shall be the net present value, at the time when the direct loan is disbursed, of the following cash flows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) loan disbursements;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) repayments of principal; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) payments of interest and other payments by or to the Government over the life of the loan after adjusting for estimated defaults, prepayments, fees, penalties and other recoveries.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(C) The cost of a loan guarantee shall be the net present value when a guaranteed loan is disbursed of the cash flow from—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) estimated payments by the Government to cover defaults and delinquencies, interest subsidies, or other payments, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the estimated payments to the Government including origination and other fees, penalties and recoveries.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10117/a/4">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10117(a)(4)</ref>, amended subpar. (D) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (D) read as follows: “Any Government action that alters the estimated net present value of an outstanding direct loan or loan guarantee (except modifications within the terms of existing contracts or through other existing authorities) shall be counted as a change in the cost of that direct loan or loan guarantee. The calculation of such changes shall be based on the estimated present value of the direct loan or loan guarantee at the time of modification.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10117/a/5">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10117(a)(5)</ref>, inserted “the cash flows of” after “similar maturity to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (5)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10117/a/6">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10117(a)(6)</ref>, added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (9) to (11). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10117/a/7">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10117(a)(7)</ref>, added pars. (9) and (10) and redesignated former par. (9) as (11).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
