<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd3fdf4b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6629"><num value="6629">§ 6629.</num><heading> Purchase, lease, exchange, maintenance, and operation of vehicles out of account for Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of Senate within Senate contingent fund; authorization of appropriations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>) there is authorized to be appropriated to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, such funds (which shall be in addition to funds authorized to be so appropriated for other purposes) as may be necessary for the purchase, lease, exchange, maintenance, and operation of vehicles as follows: one for the Vice President, one for the President pro tempore of the Senate, one for the Majority Leader of the Senate, one for the Minority Leader of the Senate, one for the Majority Whip of the Senate, one for the Minority Whip of the Senate, one for the attending physician, one as authorized by Senate Resolution 90 of the 100th Congress <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002120">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002120"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> such number as is needed for carrying mails, and for official use of the offices of the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, the Secretary for the Majority, and the Secretary for the Minority, and such additional number as is otherwise specifically authorized by law.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="iddd3fdf4c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/88/tI/s192">Pub. L. 99–88, title I, § 192</ref>, <date date="1985-08-15">Aug. 15, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/349">99 Stat. 349</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/i/tI/s3/a">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title I, § 3(a)]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-290">101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–294.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd3fdf4d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd3fdf4e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddd3fdf4f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Senate Resolution 90 of the 100th Congress, referred to in text, which was agreed to <date date="1987-01-28">Jan. 28, 1987</date>, provided in part for the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate to provide, by lease or purchase, and maintain an automobile for the former President pro tempore of the Senate.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd3fdf50-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s68–5">section 68–5 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1985.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd3fdf51-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref> substituted “one for the attending physician, one as authorized by Senate Resolution 90 of the 100th Congress” for “and” and inserted “, and such additional number as is otherwise specifically authorized by law”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="iddd3fdf52-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="iddd3fdf53-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/i/tI/s3/b">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title I, § 3(b)]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-290">101 Stat. 1329–290</ref>, 1329–294, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/202/s101/i/tI/s3/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall be effective in the case of fiscal years ending after <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
