<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddd424f91-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635"><num value="6635">§ 6635.</num><heading> Office of Senate Health Promotion</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd424f92-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to establish an Office of Senate Health Promotion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd424f93-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Fees, assessments, and charges</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd424f94-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In carrying out this section, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to establish, or provide for the establishment of, exercise classes and other health services and activities on a continuing and regular basis. In providing for such classes, services, and activities, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized to impose and collect fees, assessments, and other charges to defray the costs involved in promoting the health of Members, officers, and employees of the Senate. For purposes of this section, the term “employees of the Senate” shall have such meaning as the Sergeant at Arms, by regulation, may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddd424f95-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> All fees, assessments, and charges imposed and collected by the Sergeant at Arms pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be deposited in the revolving fund established pursuant to subsection (c) and shall be available for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd424f96-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Senate Health Promotion Revolving Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund within the contingent fund of the Senate to be known as the Senate Health Promotion Revolving Fund (hereinafter referred to in this section as the “fund”). The fund shall consist of all amounts collected or received by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate as fees, assessments, and other charges for activities and services to carry out the provisions of this section. All moneys in the fund shall be available without fiscal year limitation for disbursement by the Secretary of the Senate for promoting the health of Members, officers, and employees of the Senate. On or before December 31 of each year, the Secretary of the Senate shall withdraw from the fund and deposit in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts all moneys in excess of $5,000 in the fund at the close of the preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd424f97-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Vouchers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Disbursements from the revolving fund shall be made upon vouchers signed by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd424f98-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of provisions prohibiting sales, advertisements, or solicitations in Capitol grounds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s5104/c">section 5104(c) of title 40</ref> shall not be applicable to any class, service, or other activity carried out pursuant to the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddd424f99-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s6635/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall be carried out in accordance with regulations which shall be promulgated by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate and subject to approval at the beginning of each Congress by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddd424f9a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/163/tI/s4">Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 4</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1044">103 Stat. 1044</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/90/tI/s2">Pub. L. 102–90, title I, § 2</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/450">105 Stat. 450</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddd424f9b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddd424f9c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddd424f9d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s121c">section 121c of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is from the Congressional Operations Appropriations Act, 1990, which is title I of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1990.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (e), “<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s5104/c">section 5104(c) of title 40</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/act/1946-07-31/s4">section 4 of the Act of July 31, 1946</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s193d">40 U.S.C. 193d</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddd424f9e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/90">Pub. L. 102–90</ref> inserted at end “On or before December 31 of each year, the Secretary of the Senate shall withdraw from the fund and deposit in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts all moneys in excess of $5,000 in the fund at the close of the preceding fiscal year.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
