<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb5a041-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682"><num value="682">§ 682.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of sections 682 to 688 of this title—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a042-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> “deferral of budget authority” includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb5a043-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> withholding or delaying the obligation or expenditure of budget authority (whether by establishing reserves or otherwise) provided for projects or activities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddcb5a044-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any other type of Executive action or inaction which effectively precludes the obligation or expenditure of budget authority, including authority to obligate by contract in advance of appropriations as specifically authorized by law;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a045-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “Comptroller General” means the Comptroller General of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a046-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “rescission bill” means a bill or joint resolution which only rescinds, in whole or in part, budget authority proposed to be rescinded in a special message transmitted by the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s683">section 683 of this title</ref>, and upon which the Congress completes action before the end of the first period of 45 calendar days of continuous session of the Congress after the date on which the President’s message is received by the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a047-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> “impoundment resolution” means a resolution of the House of Representatives or the Senate which only expresses its disapproval of a proposed deferral of budget authority set forth in a special message transmitted by the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s684">section 684 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a048-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s682/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> continuity of a session of the Congress shall be considered as broken only by an adjournment of the Congress sine die, and the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain shall be excluded in the computation of the 45-day period referred to in paragraph (3) of this section and in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s683">section 683 of this title</ref>, and the 25-day periods referred to in sections 687 and 688(b)(1) of this title. If a special message is transmitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s683">section 683 of this title</ref> during any Congress and the last session of such Congress adjourns sine die before the expiration of 45 calendar days of continuous session (or a special message is so transmitted after the last session of the Congress adjourns sine die), the message shall be deemed to have been retransmitted on the first day of the succeeding Congress and the 45-day period referred to in paragraph (3) of this section and in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s683">section 683 of this title</ref> (with respect to such message) shall commence on the day after such first day.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="iddcb5a049-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tX/s1011">Pub. L. 93–344, title X, § 1011</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/333">88 Stat. 333</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb5a04a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcb5a04b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcb5a04c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1401">section 1401 of Title 31</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
