<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddcb5a04d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683"><num value="683">§ 683.</num><heading> Rescission of budget authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5a04e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal of special message</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the President determines that all or part of any budget authority will not be required to carry out the full objectives or scope of programs for which it is provided or that such budget authority should be rescinded for fiscal policy or other reasons (including the termination of authorized projects or activities for which budget authority has been provided), or whenever all or part of budget authority provided for only one fiscal year is to be reserved from obligation for such fiscal year, the President shall transmit to both Houses of Congress a special message specifying—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a04f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the amount of budget authority which he proposes to be rescinded or which is to be so reserved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a050-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any account, department, or establishment of the Government to which such budget authority is available for obligation, and the specific project or governmental functions involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a051-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the reasons why the budget authority should be rescinded or is to be so reserved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a052-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to the maximum extent practicable, the estimated fiscal, economic, and budgetary effect of the proposed rescission or of the reservation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddcb5a053-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> all facts, circumstances, and considerations relating to or bearing upon the proposed rescission or the reservation and the decision to effect the proposed rescission or the reservation, and to the maximum extent practicable, the estimated effect of the proposed rescission or the reservation upon the objects, purposes, and programs for which the budget authority is provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddcb5a054-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s683/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement to make available for obligation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any amount of budget authority proposed to be rescinded or that is to be reserved as set forth in such special message shall be made available for obligation unless, within the prescribed 45-day period, the Congress has completed action on a rescission bill rescinding all or part of the amount proposed to be rescinded or that is to be reserved. Funds made available for obligation under this procedure may not be proposed for rescission again.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddcb5a055-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/344/tX/s1012">Pub. L. 93–344, title X, § 1012</ref>, <date date="1974-07-12">July 12, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/333">88 Stat. 333</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/tII/s207">Pub. L. 100–119, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1987-09-29">Sept. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/786">101 Stat. 786</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddcb5a056-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddcb5a057-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="iddcb5a058-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1402">section 1402 of Title 31</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 1</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/877">96 Stat. 877</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddcb5a059-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/119">Pub. L. 100–119</ref> inserted at end “Funds made available for obligation under this procedure may not be proposed for rescission again.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
