<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddccb23f9-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d"><num value="907d">§ 907d.</num><heading> Special reconciliation process</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb23fa-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting of resolutions and reconciliation bills and resolutions, in Senate</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb23fb-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Committee alternatives to Presidential order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After the submission of an OMB sequestration update report under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> that envisions a sequestration under section 902 or 903 of this title, each standing committee of the Senate may, not later than October 10, submit to the Committee on the Budget of the Senate information of the type described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s632/d">section 632(d) of this title</ref> with respect to alternatives to the order envisioned by such report insofar as such order affects laws within the jurisdiction of the committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb23fc-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial Budget Committee action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After the submission of such a report, the Committee on the Budget of the Senate may, not later than October 15, report to the Senate a resolution. The resolution may affirm the impact of the order envisioned by such report, in whole or in part. To the extent that any part is not affirmed, the resolution shall state which parts are not affirmed and shall contain instructions to committees of the Senate of the type referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s641/a">section 641(a) of this title</ref>, sufficient to achieve at least the total level of deficit reduction contained in those sections which are not affirmed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb23fd-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Response of committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Committees instructed pursuant to paragraph (2), or affected thereby, shall submit their responses to the Budget Committee no later than 10 days after the resolution referred to in paragraph (2) is agreed to, except that if only one such Committee is so instructed such Committee shall, by the same date, report to the Senate a reconciliation bill or reconciliation resolution containing its recommendations in response to such instructions. A committee shall be considered to have complied with all instructions to it pursuant to a resolution adopted under paragraph (2) if it has made recommendations with respect to matters within its jurisdiction which would result in a reduction in the deficit at least equal to the total reduction directed by such instructions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb23fe-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget Committee action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receipt of the recommendations received in response to a resolution referred to in paragraph (2), the Budget Committee shall report to the Senate a reconciliation bill or reconciliation resolution, or both, carrying out all such recommendations without any substantive revisions. In the event that a committee instructed in a resolution referred to in paragraph (2) fails to submit any recommendation (or, when only one committee is instructed, fails to report a reconciliation bill or resolution) in response to such instructions, the Budget Committee shall include in the reconciliation bill or reconciliation resolution reported pursuant to this subparagraph legislative language within the jurisdiction of the noncomplying committee to achieve the amount of deficit reduction directed in such instructions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb23ff-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Point of order</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">It shall not be in order in the Senate to consider any reconciliation bill or reconciliation resolution reported under paragraph (4) with respect to a fiscal year, any amendment thereto, or any conference report thereon if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddccb2400-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the enactment of such bill or resolution as reported;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddccb2401-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the adoption and enactment of such amendment; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="iddccb2402-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the enactment of such bill or resolution in the form recommended in such conference report,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">would cause the amount of the deficit for such fiscal year to exceed the maximum deficit amount for such fiscal year, unless the low-growth report submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> projects negative real economic growth for such fiscal year, or for each of any two consecutive quarters during such fiscal year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2403-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain amendments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the Senate, an amendment which adds to a resolution reported under paragraph (2) an instruction of the type referred to in such paragraph shall be in order during the consideration of such resolution if such amendment would be in order but for the fact that it would be held to be non-germane on the basis that the instruction constitutes new matter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2404-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/a/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> “Day” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), the term “day” shall mean any calendar day on which the Senate is in session.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2405-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2406-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), in the Senate the provisions of sections 636 and 641 of this title for the consideration of concurrent resolutions on the budget and conference reports thereon shall also apply to the consideration of resolutions, and reconciliation bills and reconciliation resolutions reported under this paragraph and conference reports thereon.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2407-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limit on debate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Debate in the Senate on any resolution reported pursuant to subsection (a)(2), and all amendments thereto and debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to 10 hours.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2408-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on amendments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1"><ref href="/us/usc/t2/s641/d/2">Section 641(d)(2) of this title</ref> shall apply to reconciliation bills and reconciliation resolutions reported under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2409-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Bills and resolutions received from the House</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any bill or resolution received in the Senate from the House, which is a companion to a reconciliation bill or reconciliation resolution of the Senate for the purposes of this subsection, shall be considered in the Senate pursuant to the provisions of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb240a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s907d/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> “Resolution” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “resolution” means a simple, joint, or concurrent resolution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddccb240b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/177/tII/s258C">Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 258C</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tXIII/s13101/g">Pub. L. 101–508, title XIII, § 13101(g)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-600">104 Stat. 1388–600</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
