<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="iddccb2417-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922"><num value="922">§ 922.</num><heading> Judicial review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2418-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb2419-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any Member of Congress may bring an action, in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for declaratory judgment and injunctive relief on the ground that any order that might be issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> violates the Constitution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb241a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any Member of Congress, or any other person adversely affected by any action taken under this title,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002043">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002043"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> may bring an action, in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for declaratory judgment and injunctive relief concerning the constitutionality of this title.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002043">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb241b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any Member of Congress may bring an action, in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for declaratory and injunctive relief on the ground that the terms of an order issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> do not comply with the requirements of this title.<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb241c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A copy of any complaint in an action brought under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) shall be promptly delivered to the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives, and each House of Congress shall have the right to intervene in such action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb241d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Any action brought under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) shall be heard and determined by a three-judge court in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2284">section 2284 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this section or in any other law shall infringe upon the right of the House of Representatives to intervene in an action brought under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) without the necessity of adopting a resolution to authorize such intervention.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb241e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appeal to Supreme Court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any order of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia which is issued pursuant to an action brought under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) shall be reviewable by appeal directly to the Supreme Court of the United States. Any such appeal shall be taken by a notice of appeal filed within 10 days after such order is entered; and the jurisdictional statement shall be filed within 30 days after such order is entered. No stay of an order issued pursuant to an action brought under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) shall be issued by a single Justice of the Supreme Court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb241f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited consideration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the District Court for the District of Columbia and the Supreme Court of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any matter brought under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2420-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Noncompliance with sequestration procedures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddccb2421-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If it is finally determined by a court of competent jurisdiction that an order issued by the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> for any fiscal year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb2422-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> does not reduce automatic spending increases under any program specified in section 906(a) <sup>1</sup> of this title if such increases are required to be reduced by subchapter I of this chapter (or reduces such increases by a greater extent than is so required), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb2423-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not sequester the amount of budgetary resources which is required to be sequestered by such subchapter (or sequesters more than that amount) with respect to any program, project, activity, or account,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the President shall, within 20 days after such determination is made, revise the order in accordance with such determination.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="iddccb2424-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If the order issued by the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> for any fiscal year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb2425-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> does not reduce any automatic spending increase to the extent that such increase is required to be reduced by subchapter I of this chapter,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb2426-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> does not sequester any amount of new budget authority, new loan guarantee commitments, new direct loan obligations, or spending authority which is required to be sequestered by such subchapter I, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="iddccb2427-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> does not reduce any obligation limitation by the amount by which such limitation is required to be reduced under such subchapter,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">on the claim or defense that the constitutional powers of the President prevent such sequestration or reduction or permit the avoidance of such sequestration or reduction, and such claim or defense is finally determined by the Supreme Court of the United States to be valid, then the entire order issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref> for such fiscal year shall be null and void.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2428-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing of relief</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No order of any court granting declaratory or injunctive relief from the order of the President issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>, including but not limited to relief permitting or requiring the expenditure of funds sequestered by such order, shall take effect during the pendency of the action before such court, during the time appeal may be taken, or, if appeal is taken, during the period before the court to which such appeal is taken has entered its final order disposing of such action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb2429-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Preservation of other rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The rights created by this section are in addition to the rights of any person under law, subject to subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="iddccb242a-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee" identifier="/us/usc/t2/s922/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Economic data and assumptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The economic data and economic assumptions used by the Director of OMB in computing the figures specified in any report issued by the Director of OMB under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>, shall not be subject to review in any judicial or administrative proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="iddccb242b-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/177/tII/s274">Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 274</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1098">99 Stat. 1098</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/tI/s102/b/9">Pub. L. 100–119, title I, § 102(b)(9)</ref>, (10), <date date="1987-09-29">Sept. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/774">101 Stat. 774</ref>, 775; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tX/s10211">Pub. L. 105–33, title X, § 10211</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/711">111 Stat. 711</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="iddccb242c-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="iddccb242d-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="iddccb242e-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This title, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), (3), means title II (§ 200 et seq.) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1038">99 Stat. 1038</ref>, known as the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s900">section 900 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t2/s906/a">Section 906(a) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(1)(A), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/111/139/tI">Pub. L. 111–139, title I</ref>, §10(a), <date date="2010-02-12">Feb. 12, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/21">124 Stat. 21</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="iddccb242f-3a6e-11f1-a0f3-db3efcbbb4ee"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(1), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(1)</ref>, substituted “section 904” for “section 902”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(1)</ref>, substituted “section 904” for “section 902(b)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/2">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(2)</ref>, substituted “906(a) of this title if” for “907(1) of this title to the extent that” and inserted “or” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/3">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(3)</ref>, substituted “budgetary resources” for “new budget authority, new loan guarantee commitments, new direct loan obligations, or spending authority”. Directory language directing the striking of “or” after the comma was executed by striking “or” after “account,” and not after “activity,” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/4">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(4)</ref>, struck out subpar. (C) which read as follows: “does not reduce obligation limitations by the amount by which such limitations are required to be reduced under subchapter I of this chapter (or reduces such limitations by more than that amount) with respect to any program, project, activity, or account,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(1)</ref>, substituted “section 904” for “section 902(b)” in introductory and concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(1)</ref>, substituted “section 904” for “section 902”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/5">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (f) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (f) consisting of pars. (1) to (5) relating to alternative procedures for joint reports of directors.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/6">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(6)</ref>, substituted “figures” for “base levels of total revenues and total budget outlays, as” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s904">section 904 of this title</ref>” for “section 901(a)(2)(B) or (c)(2) of this title,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/5">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s10211/5">Pub. L. 105–33, § 10211(5)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/s102/b/9/A">Pub. L. 100–119, § 102(b)(9)(A)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “In the event that any of the reporting procedures described in <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s901">section 901 of this title</ref> are invalidated, then any report of the Directors referred to in section 901(a) or (c)(1) of this title shall be transmitted to the joint committee established under this subsection.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/s102/b/9/B">Pub. L. 100–119, § 102(b)(9)(B)</ref>, substituted “Director of CBO” for “Directors” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/s102/b/9/C">Pub. L. 100–119, § 102(b)(9)(C)</ref>, substituted “section 901(a)(2)(B) or (c)(2)” for “section 901(b) or (c)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/100/119/s102/b/10">Pub. L. 100–119, § 102(b)(10)</ref>, substituted “and economic assumptions” for “, assumptions, and methodologies”, “Director of OMB” for “Comptroller General” in two places, and “section 901(a)(2)(B)” for “section 901(b)”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
