<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idac501f70-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e" identifier="/us/usc/t1/s112"><num value="112">§ 112.</num><heading> Statutes at Large; contents; admissibility in evidence</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Archivist of the United States shall cause to be compiled, edited, indexed, and published, the United States Statutes at Large, which shall contain all the laws and concurrent resolutions enacted during each regular session of Congress; all proclamations by the President in the numbered series issued since the date of the adjournment of the regular session of Congress next preceding; and also any amendments to the Constitution of the United States proposed or ratified pursuant to article V thereof since that date, together with the certificate of the Archivist of the United States issued in compliance with the provision contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s106b">section 106b of this title</ref>. In the event of an extra session of Congress, the Archivist of the United States shall cause all the laws and concurrent resolutions enacted during said extra session to be consolidated with, and published as part of, the contents of the volume for the next regular session. The United States Statutes at Large shall be legal evidence of laws, concurrent resolutions, treaties, international agreements other than treaties, proclamations by the President, and proposed or ratified amendments to the Constitution of the United States therein contained, in all the courts of the United States, the several States, and the Territories and insular possessions of the United States.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idac501f71-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-30/ch388">July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/636">61 Stat. 636</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-23/ch1001/s1">Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1001, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/979">64 Stat. 979</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-31/ch655/s3">Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/710">65 Stat. 710</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/497/tI/s107/d">Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2291">98 Stat. 2291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idac501f72-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idac501f73-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idac501f74-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/497">Pub. L. 98–497</ref> substituted “Archivist of the United States” for “Administrator of General Services” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-10-31">Oct. 31, 1951</date>, substituted “106b of this title” for “205 of the Revised Statutes” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-09-23">Sept. 23, 1950</date>, amended section generally to implement 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 20, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1272">64 Stat. 1272</ref>, which transferred to the Administrator of General Services certain duties formerly performed by the Secretary of State.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idac501f75-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idac501f76-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/497">Pub. L. 98–497</ref> effective <date date="1985-04-01">Apr. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/497/s301">section 301 of Pub. L. 98–497</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s2102">section 2102 of Title 44</ref>, Public Printing and Documents.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idac501f77-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Publishing <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Pub. L. 115–141</ref> in Statutes at Large</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dG/tI/s121/c">Pub. L. 115–141, div. G, title I, § 121(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/662">132 Stat. 662</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/141/dG/tI/s121/c">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end an appendix setting forth the text of the sections of the bill and the bills referred to in subsections (a) [enacting into law from the 115th Congress sections 7130 and 7134 of S. 1460, as placed on the calendar of the Senate on <date date="2017-06-29">June 29, 2017</date>] and (b) [enacting into law from the 115th Congress H.R. 1281, as introduced on <date date="2017-03-01">Mar. 1, 2017</date>, and H.R. 4134, as introduced on <date date="2017-10-25">Oct. 25, 2017</date>], respectively.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idac501f78-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Publishing <ref href="/us/pl/115/31">Pub. L. 115–31</ref> in Statutes at Large</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dG/tIV/s431/b">Pub. L. 115–31, div. G, title IV, § 431(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/502">131 Stat. 502</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/31/dG/tIV/s431/b">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end an appendix setting forth the text of the bills referred to in subsection (a) [enacting into law from the 115th Congress H.R. 2104, as introduced on <date date="2017-04-20">Apr. 20, 2017</date>; S. 131, as ordered to be reported on <date date="2017-03-30">Mar. 30, 2017</date>, by the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and S. 847, as introduced on <date date="2017-04-05">Apr. 5, 2017</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idac529079-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Publishing <ref href="/us/pl/107/206">Pub. L. 107–206</ref> in Statutes at Large</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/206/tIII/s3002/h">Pub. L. 107–206, title III, § 3002(h)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/924">116 Stat. 924</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/206/tIII/s3002/h">“In publishing the Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to section 112, of title 1, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end an appendix setting forth the text of the bill referred to in subsection (a) [set out as a Short Title of 2002 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s101">section 101 of Title 39</ref>, Postal Service].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idac52907a-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Publication of Certain Laws of 106th Congress</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/b">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/b">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end appendixes setting forth the texts of the bills referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law H.R. 5656, H.R. 5657, H.R. 5658, H.R. 5660, H.R. 5661, H.R. 5662, and H.R. 5663 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-12-14">Dec. 14, 2000</date>, and H.R. 5666 and H.R. 5667 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-12-15">Dec. 15, 2000</date>, except that the text of H.R. 5666, as so enacted, shall not include section 123] and the text of any other bill enacted into law by reference by reason of the enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/553/s1/b">Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2762">114 Stat. 2762</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/553/s1/b">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end appendixes setting forth the texts of the bills referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law H.R. 5547 and H.R. 5548 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-10-25">Oct. 25, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/429/s101/a/tV/s595/b">Pub. L. 106–429, § 101(a) [title V, § 595(b)]</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1900">114 Stat. 1900</ref>, 1900A–60, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/429/s101/a/tV/s595/b">“In publishing the Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to section 112, of title 1, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end appendixes setting forth the texts of the bill referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law S. 3140 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-09-28">Sept. 28, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/429/s101/b">Pub. L. 106–429, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1900">114 Stat. 1900</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/429/s101/b">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end an appendix setting forth the text of the bill referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law H.R. 5526 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-10-24">Oct. 24, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s2">Pub. L. 106–398, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s2">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval an appendix setting forth the text of the bill referred to in section 1 [enacting into law H.R. 5408 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-10-06">Oct. 6, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/387/s1/b">Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1549">114 Stat. 1549</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/387/s1/b">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end an appendix setting forth the text of the bill referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law H.R. 5426 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-10-06">Oct. 6, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/377/s1/b">Pub. L. 106–377, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1441">114 Stat. 1441</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/377/s1/b">“In publishing this Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end appendixes setting forth the texts of the bills referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law H.R. 5482 and 5483 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-10-18">Oct. 18, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/346/s101/b">Pub. L. 106–346, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-23">Oct. 23, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1356">114 Stat. 1356</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/346/s101/b">“In publishing the Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112">section 112 of title 1</ref>, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end an appendix setting forth the text of the bill referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law H.R. 5394 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="2000-10-05">Oct. 5, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/b">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/b">“In publishing the Act in slip form and in the United States Statutes at Large pursuant to section 112, of title 1, United States Code, the Archivist of the United States shall include after the date of approval at the end appendixes setting forth the texts of the bills referred to in subsection (a) of this section [enacting into law H.R. 3421, H.R. 3422, H.R. 3423, H.R. 3424, H.R. 3425, H.R. 3426, H.R. 3427 (as amended), H.R. 3428, and S. 1948 of the 106th Congress, as introduced on <date date="1999-11-17">Nov. 17, 1999</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idac52907b-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect of Repeal of Section 73 of Act <date date="1895-01-12">Jan. 12, 1895</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section and <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112a">section 112a of this title</ref> as not affected by the repeal of section 73 of <ref href="/us/act/1895-01-12/ch23">act Jan. 12, 1895, ch. 23</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/28/615">28 Stat. 615</ref>, which related to the same subject matter, see section 56(i) of <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-31/ch655">act Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/729">65 Stat. 729</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
