<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idac574b16-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e" identifier="/us/usc/t1/s211"><num value="211">§ 211.</num><heading> Copies to Members of Congress</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to quotas provided for by <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s210">section 210 of this title</ref> there shall be printed, published, and distributed of the Code of Laws relating to the District of Columbia with tables, index, and other ancillaries, suitably bound and with thumb inserts and other convenient devices to distinguish the parts, and of the supplements to both codes as provided for by sections 202, 203 of this title, ten copies of each for each Member of the Senate and House of Representatives of the Congress in which the original authorized publication is made, for his use and distribution, and in addition for the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a number of bound copies of each equal to ten times the number of members of such committees, and one bound copy of each for the use of each committee of the Senate and House of Representatives.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idac574b17-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e">(<ref href="/us/act/1947-07-30/ch388">July 30, 1947, ch. 388</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/640">61 Stat. 640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idac574b18-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idac574b19-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idac574b1a-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Copies of New Editions for House of Representatives</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/342/s101">Pub. L. 92–342, § 101</ref>, <date date="1972-07-10">July 10, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/447">86 Stat. 447</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/342/s101">“Hereafter, appropriations for authorized printing and binding for the Congress shall not be available under the authority of the Act of <date date="1947-07-30">July 30, 1947</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t1/s211">1 U.S.C. 211</ref>) for the printing, publication, and distribution of more than two copies of new editions of the Code of Laws of the United States and of the Code of the District of Columbia for each Member of the House of Representatives.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idac574b1b-47c4-11f1-8df3-c75a02f6a58e"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Written Requests for Documents</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Copies of District of Columbia Code and Supplements not available to Senators or Representatives unless specifically requested by them, in writing, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/59/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 94–59, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/296">89 Stat. 296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s1317">section 1317 of Title 44</ref>, Public Printing and Documents.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
