<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef95dc08-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303"><num value="200303">§ 200303.</num><heading> Availability of funds</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef95dc09-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Any amounts deposited in the Fund under section 200302 for fiscal year 2020 and each fiscal year thereafter shall be made available for expenditure for fiscal year 2021 and each fiscal year thereafter, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, to carry out the purposes of the Fund (including accounts and programs made available from the Fund pursuant to the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/133/2534">133 Stat. 2534</ref>)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef95dc0a-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Amounts</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts made available under subsection (a) shall be in addition to amounts made available to the Fund under section 105 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</ref> note; <ref href="/us/pl/109/432">Public Law 109–432</ref>) or otherwise appropriated from the Fund.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef95dc0b-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocation Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef95dc0c-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of cost estimates</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President shall submit to Congress detailed account, program, and project allocations of the full amount made available under subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef95dc0d-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for fiscal year 2021, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the Great American Outdoors Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef95dc0e-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for each fiscal year thereafter, as part of the annual budget submission of the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef95dc0f-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternate allocation.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef95dc10-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Appropriations Acts may provide for alternate allocation of amounts made available under subsection (a), including allocations by account, program, and project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef95dc11-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocation by president.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef95dc12-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No alternate allocations</inline>.—</heading><content>If Congress has not enacted legislation establishing alternate allocations by the date on which the Act making full-year appropriations for the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies for the applicable fiscal year is enacted into law, amounts made available under subsection (a) shall be allocated by the President.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef95dc13-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Insufficient alternate allocation</inline>.—</heading><content>If Congress enacts legislation establishing alternate allocations for amounts made available under subsection (a) that are less than the full amount appropriated under that subsection, the difference between the amount appropriated and the alternate allocation shall be allocated by the President.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef95dc14-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recreational public access</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts expended from the Fund under this section shall be consistent with the requirements for recreational public access for hunting, fishing, recreational shooting, or other outdoor recreational purposes under section 200306(c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef95dc15-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall submit to Congress an annual report that describes the final allocation by account, program, and project of amounts made available under subsection (a), including a description of the status of obligations and expenditures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef95dc16-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s3">Pub. L. 113–287, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3172">128 Stat. 3172</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/152/s3/a">Pub. L. 116–152, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-08-04">Aug. 4, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/686">134 Stat. 686</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef95dc17-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idef95dc18-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90; " id="idef95dc19-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:68pt ; max-width:68pt;" />
<html:col style="width:94pt ; max-width:94pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:68.0pt ; max-width:68.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:94.0pt ; max-width:94.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>200303</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t16/s460">16 U.S.C. 460</html:a><html:i>l</html:i>–6.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/pl/88/578/tI/s3">Pub. L. 88–578, title I, § 3</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Sept. 3, 1964</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/78/899">78 Stat. 899</html:a>; <html:a href="/us/pl/100/203/tV/s5201/f/2">Pub. L. 100–203, title V, § 5201(f)(2)</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Dec. 22, 1987</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/101/1330-267">101 Stat. 1330–267</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “or from the special account established under section 460<i>l</i>–6a(i)(1) of this title” are omitted as obsolete.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef95dc1a-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef95dc1b-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Pub. L. 116–94</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2534">133 Stat. 2534</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 105 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dC/tI/s105">section 105 of title I of div. C of Pub. L. 109–432</ref>, which is set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1331">section 1331 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of the Great American Outdoors Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(A), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/152">Pub. L. 116–152</ref>, which was approved <date date="2020-08-04">Aug. 4, 2020</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef95dc1c-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—<ref href="/us/pl/116/152">Pub. L. 116–152</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available for expenditure for the purposes of this chapter only when appropriated for those purposes. The appropriations may be made without fiscal-year limitation. Amounts made available for obligation or expenditure from the Fund may be obligated or expended only as provided in this chapter.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef95dc1d-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef95dc1e-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Allocation of Funds</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/74/dC/tIV/s428">Pub. L. 119–74, div. C, title IV, § 428</ref>, <date date="2026-01-23">Jan. 23, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/164">140 Stat. 164</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/74/dC/tIV/s428">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 45 days of enactment of this Act [<date date="2026-01-23">Jan. 23, 2026</date>], the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate, shall allocate amounts made available for expenditure from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for fiscal year 2026 pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303">section 200303 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, to the agencies and accounts specified, for the projects specified under the accounts titled ‘Land Acquisition Projects’ and ‘Forest Legacy Projects’ in the Forest Service, and in the amounts specified in the table titled ‘Allocation of Funds: Land and Water Conservation Fund Fiscal Year 2026’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 (in the matter preceding division A of this consolidated Act) [<ref href="/us/stat/140/5">140 Stat. 5</ref>]: <i>Provided</i>, That the matter preceding this proviso shall not apply to amounts in any account titled ‘Land Acquisition Projects’ in the Bureau of Land Management, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or National Park Service in such table.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Within 30 days of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall provide to the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations project lists with project data sheets as described in subsection (c)(4), which shall include a sufficient number of projects to total the amounts for the account titled ‘Land Acquisition Projects’ for each of the Bureau of Land Management, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and National Park Service, as specified in the table titled ‘Allocation of Funds: Land and Water Conservation Fund Fiscal Year 2026’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 (in the matter preceding division A of this consolidated Act): <i>Provided</i>, That on the date on which the Secretary of the Interior provides to the Committees on Appropriations such project lists with such project data sheets, the Secretary of the Interior shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations lists of supplementary allocations for Federal land acquisition projects for each of the Bureau of Land Management, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and National Park Service that are prioritized and detailed by account, program, and project, and that total no less than half the full amount allocated to each such account for that land management Agency in the table titled ‘Allocation of Funds: Land and Water Conservation Fund Fiscal Year 2026’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 (in the matter preceding division A of this consolidated Act): <i>Provided further</i>, That expenditure of funds under this paragraph is a reprogramming and shall be subject to section 421 of this Act [<ref href="/us/stat/140/163">140 Stat. 163</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Within 45 days of the date on which a reprogramming is approved pursuant to the last proviso in subparagraph (A), the Secretary of the Interior shall allocate amounts made available for expenditure from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for fiscal year 2026 pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303">section 200303 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, to the account titled ‘Land Acquisition Projects’ for each of the Bureau of Land Management, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and National Park Service, as applicable, in the amounts specified in the table titled ‘Allocation of Funds: Land and Water Conservation Fund Fiscal Year 2026’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 (in the matter preceding division A of this consolidated Act) and for the projects included in the project lists approved by the Committees on Appropriations in accordance with subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> If any portion of a project specified under the accounts titled ‘Land Acquisition Projects’ and ‘Forest Legacy Projects’ in the Forest Service in the table titled ‘Allocation of Funds: Land and Water Conservation Fund Fiscal Year 2026’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 (in the matter preceding division A of this consolidated Act) or for the projects included in the project lists approved by the Committees on Appropriations in accordance with subsection (a)(2)(A) is intended to be carried out within the Federal land unit or project boundary as specified in such table (or any prior allocation table incorporated by reference into a prior Act, as applicable) or project list but outside the specific tracts for the project described in the corresponding project data sheet submitted to the Committees on Appropriations required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1">section 200303(c)(1) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, or paragraph (2), not later than 30 days before the date on which the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture expends amounts on the project, the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate, shall provide written notice to the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations of such expenditure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Neither the President nor his designee may allocate any amounts that are made available for any fiscal year under subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303">section 200303 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, other than in amounts and for projects and activities that are allocated by subsection (a)(1) or in accordance with subsection (a)(2) of this section: <i>Provided</i>, That in any fiscal year, the matter preceding this proviso shall not apply to the allocation of amounts for continuing administration of programs allocated funds from the Land and Water Conservation Fund, which may be allocated only in amounts that are no more than the allocation for such purposes in subsections (a)(1) and (a)(2) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Concurrent with the annual budget submission of the President for fiscal year 2027, the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations a list of supplementary allocations for Federal land acquisition and Forest Legacy Projects at the Forest Service that are in addition to the ‘Submission of Cost Estimates’ required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1">section 200303(c)(1) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, that are prioritized and detailed by account, program, and project, and that total no less than half the full amount allocated to each such account for the Forest Service under the allocations submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1">section 200303(c)(1) of title 54</ref>, United States Code: <i>Provided</i>, That in the event amounts allocated by this Act or any prior Act pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303">section 200303 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, are no longer needed because a project has been completed or can no longer be executed, such amounts must be clearly identified if proposed for reallocation in the annual budget submission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Concurrent with the annual budget submission of the President for fiscal year 2027, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations a list of supplementary allocations for Federal land acquisition projects at the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Bureau of Land Management that are in addition to the ‘Submission of Cost Estimates’ required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1">section 200303(c)(1) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, that are prioritized and detailed by account, program, and project, and that total the full amount allocated to each such account for that land management Agency in the table titled ‘Allocation of Funds: Land and Water Conservation Fund Fiscal Year 2026’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 (in the matter preceding division A of this consolidated Act) [<ref href="/us/stat/140/5">140 Stat. 5</ref>]: <i>Provided</i>, That in the event amounts allocated by this Act or any prior Act pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303">section 200303 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, are no longer needed because a project has been completed or can no longer be executed, such amounts must be clearly identified if proposed for reallocation in the annual budget submission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Federal land acquisition and Forest Legacy projects in the ‘Submission of Cost Estimates’ required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1">section 200303(c)(1) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, in the project lists provided under subsection (a)(2), in the list of supplementary allocations provided under subsection (a)(2), and on the lists of supplementary allocations required by paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be comprised only of projects for which a willing seller has been identified and for which an appraisal or market research has been initiated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Concurrent with the annual budget submission of the President for fiscal year 2027, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each submit to the Committees on Appropriations project data sheets in the same format and containing the same level of detailed information that is found on such sheets in the Budget Justifications annually submitted by the Secretary of the Interior with the President’s Budget for the projects in the ‘Submission of Cost Estimates’ required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1">section 200303(c)(1) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, and in the same format and containing the same level of detailed information that is found on such sheets submitted to the Committees on Appropriations pursuant to section 427 of division D of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/133/2749">133 Stat. 2749</ref>] for the list of supplementary allocations required by paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations quarterly reports on the status of balances of projects and activities funded by the National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund and the Land and Water Conservation Fund, and the status of balances of projects and activities funded by the Land and Water Conservation Fund for amounts allocated pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section, including all uncommitted, committed, and unobligated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> Within 45 days of enactment of this Act [<date date="2026-01-23">Jan. 23, 2026</date>], the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate, shall allocate amounts made available for expenditure from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for fiscal year 2025 pursuant to subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303">section 200303 of title 54</ref>, United States Code, to the agencies and accounts specified, for the projects specified, under the accounts specified, and in the amounts specified in the table titled ‘Allocation of Funds: Land and Water Conservation Fund Fiscal Year 2025 Revisions’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 (in the matter preceding division A of this consolidated Act) [<ref href="/us/stat/140/5">140 Stat. 5</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 30 days of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide to the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations project lists with project data sheets, which shall include a sufficient number of projects to total the amounts for the account titled ‘National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund’ for each of the Bureau of Land Management, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, National Park Service, Bureau of Indian Education, and U.S. Forest Service: <i>Provided</i>, That expenditure of funds under this paragraph is a reprogramming and shall be subject to section 421 of this Act [<ref href="/us/stat/140/163">140 Stat. 163</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Within 45 days of the date on which a reprogramming is approved pursuant to the last proviso in subparagraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall allocate amounts made available for expenditure from the National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund for fiscal year 2026 pursuant to subsection (c) of 200402 of title 54, United States Code, to the account titled ‘National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund’ for each of the Bureau of Land Management, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, National Park Service, Bureau of Indian Education, and U.S. Forest Service as applicable, in the amounts specified and for the projects included in the project lists approved by the Committees on Appropriations in accordance with subparagraph (1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/42/dE/tIV/s430/a">Pub. L. 118–42, div. E, title IV, § 430(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/291">138 Stat. 291</ref>, 292.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dG/tIV/s431/a">Pub. L. 117–328, div. G, title IV, § 431(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4827">136 Stat. 4827</ref>, 4828.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dG/tIV/s431/a">Pub. L. 117–103, div. G, title IV, § 431(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/416">136 Stat. 416</ref>, 417.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dG/tIV/s434/a">Pub. L. 116–260, div. G, title IV, § 434(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1543">134 Stat. 1543</ref>, 1544.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idef95dc1f-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef95dc20-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority for Fiscal Year 2021 Cost Estimates and Annual Reports to the Congress for the Land and Water Conservation Fund</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2020-11-09">Nov. 9, 2020</date>, 85 F.R. 72889, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of the Interior [and] the Secretary of Agriculture</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture are hereby authorized to submit, for their respective agencies:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) the cost estimates to the Congress required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/1/A">54 U.S.C. 200303(c)(1)(A)</ref>, as amended by section 3(a) of the Great American Outdoors Act (<ref href="/us/pl/116/152">Public Law 116–152</ref>) (the “Act”); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) annually, the report to the Congress required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s200303/c/4">54 U.S.C. 200303(c)(4)</ref>, as amended by section 3(a) of the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. (a) Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
