<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefa6a5bf-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s306142"><num value="306142">§ 306142.</num><heading> Application of certain authorities and standards to historic military housing and associated historic properties of the Department of the Navy and the Department of the Air Force</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idefa6a5c0-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s306142/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application of Certain Authority to Navy and Air Force Military Family Housing</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Navy and the Secretary of the Air Force, in satisfaction of requirements under this division, may apply the authority and standards contained in the documents titled “Department <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002029"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “Notice of Issuance of the”.</note> of the Army Program Comment for the Preservation of Pre-1919 Historic Army Housing, Associated Buildings and Structures, and Landscape Features” (published on <date date="2024-06-13">June 13, 2024</date>) (89 Fed. Reg. 50350), “Department <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref> of the Army Program Comment for Inter-War Era Historic Housing, Associated Buildings and Structures, and Landscape Features (1919–1940)” (published on <date date="2020-10-13">October 13, 2020</date>) (85 Fed. Reg. 64491), and “Department <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002029">1</ref> of the Army Program Comment for Vietnam War Era Historic Housing, Associated Buildings and Structures, and Landscape Features (1963–1975)” (published on <date date="2023-05-04">May 4, 2023</date>) (88 Fed. Reg. 28573) to all military housing (including privatized military housing under subchapter IV of chapter 169 of title 10) constructed during the applicable periods.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idefa6a5c1-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s306142/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application of Certain Authority to Inter-war Era Historic Housing</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Navy and the Secretary of the Air Force may apply the authority and standards contained in the document titled “Department <sup>1</sup> of the Army Program Comment for Inter-War Era Historic Housing, Associated Buildings and Structures, and Landscape Features (1919–1940)” (published on <date date="2020-10-13">October 13, 2020</date>) (85 Fed. Reg. 64491) to all military housing (including privatized military housing under subchapter IV of chapter 169 of title 10) constructed during the period beginning on <date date="1941-01-01">January 1, 1941</date>, and ending on <date date="1948-12-31">December 31, 1948</date>, located on a military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy or the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idefa6a5c2-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db" identifier="/us/usc/t54/s306142/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Temporary Application of Certain Authority to Vietnam War Era Navy and Air Force Military Housing</inline>.—</heading><content>During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026 and ending on <date date="2045-12-31">December 31, 2045</date>, the Secretary of the Navy and the Secretary of the Air Force, in satisfaction of requirements under this division, may apply the authority and standards contained in the document titled “Department <sup>1</sup> of the Army Program Comment for Vietnam War Era Historic Housing, Associated Buildings and Structures, and Landscape Features (1963–1975)” (published on <date date="2023-05-04">May 4, 2023</date>) (88 Fed. Reg. 28573) to all military housing (including privatized military housing under subchapter IV of chapter 169 of title 10) constructed after 1975 located on a military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy or the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefa6a5c3-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dB/tXXVIII/s2826/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2826(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1309">139 Stat. 1309</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefa6a5c4-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idefa6a5c5-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idefa6a5c6-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026, referred to in subsec. (c), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, which was approved <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idefa6a5c7-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idefa6a5c8-3a70-11f1-83cd-8a39f388f6db"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Revision of Authorities and Standards and Reports</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dB/tXXVIII/s2826/b">Pub. L. 119–60, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2826(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1310">139 Stat. 1310</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dB/tXXVIII/s2826/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision of Authorities and Standards.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision of authority relating to navy and air force military family housing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation shall revise the authorities and standards contained in the documents specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s306142/a">section 306142(a) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), if determined to be necessary, to provide the Secretary of the Navy and the Secretary of the Air Force authority and standards for the treatment of military housing under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned, including privatized military housing under subchapter IV of chapter 169 of title 10, United States Code, constructed during the applicable periods of such documents that are equivalent to the authority and standards applicable to housing, associated buildings and structures, and landscape features contained in such documents as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision of authority relating to inter-war era historic housing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation shall revise the authorities and standards contained in the document specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s306142/b">section 306142(b) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), if determined to be necessary, to include military housing, including privatized military housing under subchapter IV of chapter 169 of title 10, United States Code, constructed during the period beginning on <date date="1941-01-01">January 1, 1941</date>, and ending on <date date="1948-12-31">December 31, 1948</date>, located on a military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy or the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revision of authority relating to vietnam war era navy and air force military housing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation shall revise the authorities and standards contained in the document specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s306142/c">section 306142(c) of title 54</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), if determined to be necessary, to provide the Secretary of the Navy and the Secretary of the Air Force authority and standards for the treatment of military housing under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned, including privatized military housing under subchapter IV of chapter 169 of title 10, United States Code, constructed after 1975 that are equivalent to the standards applicable to housing, associated buildings and structures, and landscape features contained in that document as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Navy and the Secretary of the Air Force shall adhere to any reporting requirements contained in any program comments revised under subsection (b).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
