<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf6de63c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1408c"><num value="1408c">§ 1408c.</num><heading> Grants-in-aid by Federal Government</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the limitation contained in the last sentence of section 110(d) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1460/d">42 U.S.C. 1460(d)</ref>] or in any other provision of title I [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1450">42 U.S.C. 1450</ref> et seq.] of the Housing Act of 1949 (Public Law 171, Eighty-first Congress), as amended, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development is authorized to allow and credit to such authority as may be created for the Virgin Islands under this Act, as amended, (1) such local grants-in-aid as are otherwise approvable pursuant to the first sentence of said section 110(d) with respect to any slum clearance and urban redevelopment or urban renewal project or projects undertaken by such authority with Federal assistance made available under title I of the Housing Act of 1949, as amended, and (2) such grants-in-aid made or assistance given to the local community by any Federal department or agency pursuant to authority of law other than the Housing Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">42 U.S.C. 1441</ref> et seq.] which would, if made or given by a State or local community, be approvable pursuant to said first sentence of section 110(d) with respect to any such project or projects so undertaken.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idcf6de63d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-07-18/ch466">July 18, 1950, ch. 466</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref href="/us/stat/64/347">64 Stat. 347</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch783">Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 783</ref>, title I, § 107(6)–(9), <ref href="/us/stat/69/638">69 Stat. 638</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s9">Pub. L. 90–19, § 9</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/22">81 Stat. 22</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf6de63e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf6de63f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf6de640-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Housing Act of 1949, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">act July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/413">63 Stat. 413</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 8A (§ 1441 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Title I of the Housing Act of 1949 (Public Law 171, Eighty-first Congress) was classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1450 et seq.) of chapter 8A of Title 42, and was omitted from the Code pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5316">section 5316 of Title 42</ref> which terminated the authority to make grants or loans under such title I after <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">section 1441 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/act/1950-07-18/ch466">act July 18, 1950, ch. 466</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/344">64 Stat. 344</ref>, known as the Territorial Enabling Act of 1950, which enacted this subchapter and sections 480 to 480b, 483a, 483b, 721 to 721b, and 910 to 910b of this title, amended sections 481 to 483 and 722 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 480, 481, and 722 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf6de641-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development” for “Housing and Home Finance Administrators.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Act <date date="1955-08-11">Aug. 11, 1955</date>, included urban renewal proj­ects, and inserted “as amended” after (Public Law 171, Eighty-first Congress), after “this Act”, and after “Housing Act of 1949” in cl. (1).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
