<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf6de6ac-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b"><num value="1421b">§ 1421b.</num><heading> Bill of rights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6ad-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> No law shall be enacted in Guam respecting an establishment of religion or prohibiting the free exercise thereof, or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press, or the right of the people peaceably to assemble and to petition the government for a redress of their grievances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6ae-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> No soldier shall, in time of peace, be quartered in any house, without the consent of the owner, nor in time of war, but in a manner to be prescribed by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6af-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects, against unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated; and no warrant for arrest or search shall issue but upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation, and particularly describing the place to be searched and the person or things to be seized.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> No person shall be subject for the same offense to be twice put in jeopardy of punishment; nor shall he be compelled in any criminal case to be a witness against himself.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> No person shall be deprived of life, liberty, or property without due process of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Private property shall not be taken for public use without just compensation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> In all criminal prosecutions the accused shall have the right to a speedy and public trial; to be informed of the nature and cause of the accusation and to have a copy thereof; to be confronted with the witnesses against him; to have compulsory process for obtaining witnesses in his favor, and to have the assistance of counsel for his defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> Excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive fines imposed, nor cruel and unusual punishments inflicted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, except as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly convicted, shall exist in Guam.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> No bill of attainder, ex post facto law, or law impairing the obligation of contracts shall be enacted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> No person shall be imprisoned for debt.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> The privilege of the writ of habeas corpus shall not be suspended, unless, when in cases of rebellion or invasion or imminent danger thereof, the public safety shall require it.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6b9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content> No qualification with respect to property, income, political opinion, or any other matter apart from citizenship, civil capacity, and residence shall be imposed upon any voter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6ba-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content> No discrimination shall be made in Guam against any person on account of race, language, or religion, nor shall the equal protection of the laws be denied.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6bb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content> No person shall be convicted of treason against the United States unless on the testimony of two witnesses to the same overt act, or on confession in open court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6bc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content> No public money or property shall ever be appropriated, supplied, donated, or used, directly or indirectly, for the use, benefit, or support of any sect, church, denomination, sectarian institution, or association, or system of religion, or for the use, benefit, or support of any priest, preacher, minister, or other religious teacher or dignitary as such.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf6de6bd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content> The employment of children under the age of fourteen years in any occupation injurious to health or morals or hazardous to life or limb is hereby prohibited.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7056be-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content> There shall be compulsory education for all children, between the ages of six and sixteen years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7056bf-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/s"><num value="s">(s)</num><content> No religious test shall ever be required as a qualification to any office or public trust under the government of Guam.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7056c0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/t"><num value="t">(t)</num><content> No person who advocates, or who aids or belongs to any party, organization, or association which advocates, the overthrow by force or violence of the government of Guam or of the United States shall be qualified to hold any public office of trust or profit under the government of Guam.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7056c1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1421b/u"><num value="u">(u)</num><content> The following provisions of and amendments to the Constitution of the United States are hereby extended to Guam to the extent that they have not been previously extended to that territory and shall have the same force and effect there as in the United States or in any State of the United States: article I, section 9, clauses 2 and 3; article IV, section 1 and section 2, clause 1; the first to ninth amendments inclusive; the thirteenth amendment; the second sentence of section 1 of the fourteenth amendment; and the fifteenth and nineteenth amendments.<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All laws enacted by Congress with respect to Guam and all laws enacted by the territorial legislature of Guam which are inconsistent with the provisions of this subsection are repealed to the extent of such inconsistency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf7056c2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-08-01/ch512/s5">Aug. 1, 1950, ch. 512, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/385">64 Stat. 385</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/497/s10">Pub. L. 90–497, § 10</ref>, <date date="1968-09-11">Sept. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/847">82 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf7056c3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf7056c4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf7056c5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (u). <ref href="/us/pl/90/497">Pub. L. 90–497</ref> added subsec. (u).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf7056c6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf7056c7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/90/497/s10">Pub. L. 90–497, § 10</ref>, <date date="1968-09-11">Sept. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/847">82 Stat. 847</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective on date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/90/497">Pub. L. 90–497</ref>, which was approved <date date="1968-09-11">Sept. 11, 1968</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
