<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf7782c7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1469a"><num value="1469a">§ 1469a.</num><heading> Congressional declaration of policy respecting “Insular Areas”</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to minimize the burden caused by existing application and reporting procedures for certain grant-in-aid programs available to the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands (hereafter referred to as “Insular Areas”) it is declared to be the policy of the Congress, notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, that:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7782c8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1469a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any department or agency of the Government of the United States which administers any Act of Congress which specifically provides for making grants to any Insular Area under which payments received may be used by such Insular Area only for certain specified purposes (other than direct payments to classes of individuals) may, acting through appropriate administrative authorities of such department or agency, consolidate any or all grants made to such area for any fiscal year or years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7782c9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1469a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any consolidated grant for any insular area shall not be less than the sum of all grants which such area would otherwise be entitled to receive for such year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7782ca-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1469a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The funds received under a consolidated grant shall be expended in furtherance of the programs and purposes authorized for any of the grants which are being consolidated, which are authorized under any of the Acts administered by the department or agency making the grant, and which would be applicable to grants for such programs and purposes in the absence of the consolidation, but the Insular Areas shall determine the proportion of the funds granted which shall be allocated to such programs and purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7782cb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1469a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Each department or agency making grants-in-aid shall, by regulations published in the Federal Register, provide the method by which any Insular Area may submit (i) a single application for a consolidated grant for any fiscal year period, but not more than one such application for a consolidated grant shall be required by any department or agency unless notice of such requirement is transmitted to the appropriate committees of the United States Congress together with a complete explanation of the necessity for requiring such additional applications and (ii) a single report to such department or agency with respect to each such consolidated grant: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this paragraph shall preclude such department or agency from providing adequate procedures for accounting, auditing, evaluating, and reviewing any programs or activities receiving benefits from any consolidated grant. The administering authority of any department or agency, in its discretion, may <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002006"><num>1</num> See Application of Subsection (d) to Department of the Interior note below.</note> (i) waive any requirement for matching funds otherwise required by law to be provided by the Insular Area involved and (ii) waive the requirement that any Insular Area submit an application or report in writing with respect to any consolidated grant.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf7782cc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/134/tV/s501">Pub. L. 95–134, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1977-10-15">Oct. 15, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1164">91 Stat. 1164</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/348/s9">Pub. L. 95–348, § 9</ref>, <date date="1978-08-18">Aug. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/495">92 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf7782cd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf7782ce-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf7782cf-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/348/s9/1">Pub. L. 95–348, § 9(1)</ref>, in introductory provision inserted “, notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary,” after “Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/348/s9/2">Pub. L. 95–348, § 9(2)</ref>, substituted “Any” for “Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, any”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf7782d0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf7782d1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Maintenance or Level of Effort Requirements; Adjustment or Modification by Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/396/s12/a">Pub. L. 99–396, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/841">100 Stat. 841</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/396/s12/a">“In awarding assistance grants, consolidated under the provisions of title V of the Act entitled ‘An Act to authorize certain appropriations for the territories of the United States, to amend certain Acts related thereto, and for other purposes’ (<ref href="/us/stat/91/1159">91 Stat. 1159</ref>, as amended) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4368b">42 U.S.C. 4368b</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1469a">48 U.S.C. 1469a</ref>], to the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands or the Virgin Islands, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency may, in his discretion, adjust or otherwise modify maintenance or level of effort requirements.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf7782d2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of Subsection (d) to Department of the Interior</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/205/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 96–205, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1980-03-12">Mar. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/90">94 Stat. 90</ref>, as amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/213/s6">Pub. L. 98–213, § 6</ref>, <date date="1983-12-08">Dec. 8, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1460">97 Stat. 1460</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/tVI/s601/b">Pub. L. 98–454, title VI, § 601(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1736">98 Stat. 1736</ref>, provided that this section shall be applied with respect to the Department of the Interior by substituting “shall” for “may” in the last sentence of subsection (d), and adding the following sentence at the end of subsection (d): “Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of American Samoa, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands any department or agency shall waive any requirement for local matching funds under $200,000 (including in-kind contributions) required by law to be provided by American Samoa, Guam, the Virgin Islands, or the Northern Mariana Islands.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idcf79f3d3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf79f3d4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
