<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf7c3db1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b"><num value="1494b">§ 1494b.</num><heading> Enforcement and administration in insular areas</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3db2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> American Samoa</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3db3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> With the approval of the Attorney General of the United States or his designee, law enforcement officers of the Government of American Samoa are authorized to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3db4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> execute and serve warrants, subpoenas, and summons issued under the authority of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3db5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> make arrests without warrant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3db6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> make seizures of property to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951–970">21 U.S.C. 951–970</ref>), and any other applicable narcotics laws of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3db7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States, as appropriate, are authorized to and, upon request of the Government of American Samoa, shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3db8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> train law enforcement officers and other personnel of the Government of American Samoa, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3db9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide by purchase or lease law enforcement equipment and technical assistance to the Government of American Samoa to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or territorial drug or other substance abuse laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dba-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated $350,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of American Samoa to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dbb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior shall provide the Government of American Samoa with a vessel to be used in the enforcement of narcotics and other laws. There are authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for this purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3dbc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Guam</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dbd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States may provide and, upon request of the Government of Guam, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance and equipment to the Government of Guam to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or territorial drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dbe-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Guam to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dbf-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Government of Guam $500,000 for grants to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General for drug abuse law enforcement equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3dc0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Northern Mariana Islands</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dc1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> With the approval of the Attorney General of the United States or his designee, law enforcement officers of the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands are authorized to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3dc2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> execute and serve warrants, subpoenas, and summons issued under the authority of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3dc3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> make arrests without warrant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3dc4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> make seizures of property to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951–970">21 U.S.C. 951–970</ref>), and any other applicable narcotics laws of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dc5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States, as appropriate, are authorized to and, upon request of the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands, shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3dc6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> train law enforcement officers and other personnel of the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf7c3dc7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide, by purchase or lease, law enforcement equipment and technical assistance to the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or commonwealth drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dc8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated $125,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dc9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Federal personnel and equipment assigned to Guam pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall also be available to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title in the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3dca-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Puerto Rico</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dcb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated for grants to the Government of Puerto Rico $7,000,000 for fiscal year 1989 and $2,000,000 annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Puerto Rico to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Executive Director of the White House Task Force on Puerto Rico in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dcc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The United States Customs Service should station an aerostat in Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dcd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Equipment provided to the Government of Puerto Rico pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made available upon request to the Federal agencies involved in drug interdiction in Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dce-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dcf-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States may provide and, upon request of the Government of Puerto Rico, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance and equipment to the Government of Puerto Rico to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or commonwealth drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out subparagraph (A). Funds appropriated under this subparagraph shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3dd1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Virgin Islands</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated for grants to the Government of the Virgin Islands, $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1990 and annually thereafter to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The United States Coast Guard shall station a patrol vessel in St. Croix, Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States may provide and, upon request of the Government of the Virgin Islands, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance and equipment to the Government of the United States Virgin Islands to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other Federal or territorial drug or other substance abuse law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out subparagraph (A). Funds appropriated under this subparagraph shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> To assist in the prosecution of the violation of the narcotics laws of the United States, the Attorney General of the United States shall assign the necessary personnel to serve in the office of the United States Attorney for the Virgin Islands appointed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1617">section 1617 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dd8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Effective fiscal year 1989, there are authorized to be appropriated for a grant to the Government of the Virgin Islands $2,500,000 to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services for a substance abuse facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3dd9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Palau</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3dda-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services are authorized to and, upon request of the Government of Palau, shall provide appropriate training, technical assistance, and equipment to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title and any other applicable Federal or insular drug or other substance abuse laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3ddb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Palau to be expended in accordance with a plan to be approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education, State, and Health and Human Services to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf7c3ddc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1494b/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To the extent not prohibited under the Constitution of Palau, upon written request of the President of Palau, the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secret Service, the Immigration and Naturalization Service, and the Customs Service are authorized to investigate any United States criminal laws which are applicable in Palau in cooperation with law enforcement agencies of Palau.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf7c3ddd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/570/tV/s5004">Pub. L. 99–570, title V, § 5004</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-155">100 Stat. 3207–155</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tIX">Pub. L. 100–690, title IX</ref>, §§ 9302–9305, 9306(b), 9307, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4536-4538">102 Stat. 4536–4538</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf7c3dde-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf7c3ddf-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf7c3de0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Import and Export Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(C), (c)(1)(C), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1285">84 Stat. 1285</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter II (§ 951 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 21, Food and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951">section 951 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3), (b)(2), (c)(3), (d)(1), (e)(1), and (f)(1), (2), was in the original “this Act”, and was translated as reading “this subtitle” meaning subtitle A of title V of <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref> to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1494">section 1494 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf7c3de1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9302/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9302(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretaries of Education and” for “Secretary of” and inserted “, as appropriate,” after “States”, “and, upon request of the Government of American Samoa, shall” after “are authorized to”, “and other personnel” after “officers”, and “or other substance” after “drug”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9302/2">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9302(2)</ref>, substituted “$350,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of American Samoa to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services” for “$700,000” and “sections 1494 to 1494c of this title” for “this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9302/3">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9302(3)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9303/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9303(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretaries of Education and” for “Secretary of” and inserted “and, upon request of the Government of Guam, shall provide appropriate training,” after “may provide” and “or other substance” after “drug”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9303/2">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9303(2)</ref>, substituted “$500,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Guam to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title, to” for “$1,000,000 to carry out paragraph (1). Funds appropriated under this paragraph shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9303/3">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9303(3)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9304/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9304(1)</ref>, substituted “The Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services of the United States, as appropriate, are authorized to and, upon request of the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands, shall” for “The Attorney General of the United States and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as appropriate, are authorized to” in introductory provisions, inserted “and other personnel” after “officers” in subpar. (A), and inserted “or other substance” after “drug” in subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9304/2">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9304(2)</ref>, substituted “$125,000 for fiscal year 1989 and annually thereafter for grants to the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services” for “$250,000” and “sections 1494 to 1494c of this title” for “this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9305/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9305(1)</ref>, substituted “Puerto Rico $7,000,000 for fiscal year 1989 and $2,000,000 annually thereafter for grants to the Government of Puerto Rico to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Executive Director of the White House Task Force on Puerto Rico in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to remain available until expended.” for “Puerto Rico—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) $3,300,000 for the purchase of 2 helicopters;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) $3,500,000 for the purchase of an aircraft; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) $1,000,000 for the purchase and maintenance of 5 high-speed vessels.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Sums appropriated under this paragraph shall remain available until expended.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9305/2">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9305(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretaries of Education and” for “Secretary of” and inserted “and, upon request of the Government of Puerto Rico, shall provide appropriate training,” after “may provide” and “or other substance” after “drug”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9306/b/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9306(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Virgin Islands, $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1990 and annually thereafter to carry out the purposes of sections 1494 to 1494c of this title to be expended in accordance with a plan approved by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Education and Health and Human Services, to remain available until expended.” for “Virgin Islands—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) $3,000,000 for 2 patrol vessels, tracking equipment, supplies, and agents, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) $1,000,000 for programs to prevent and treat narcotics abuse, such sums to remain available until expended.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9306/b/2">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9306(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “shall” for “should”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9306/b/3">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9306(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “Secretaries of Education and” for “Secretary of” and inserted “and, upon request of the Government of the Virgin Islands, shall provide appropriate training,” after “may provide” and “or other substance” after “drug”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9306/b/4">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9306(b)(4)</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s9307">Pub. L. 100–690, § 9307</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf7c3de2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idcf7c3de3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of the functions, personnel, assets, and obligations of the United States Secret Service, including the functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 381, 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf7c3de4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service, transfer of functions, and treatment of related references, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1551">section 1551 of Title 8</ref>, Aliens and Nationality.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
