<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf7c3e1d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1541"><num value="1541">§ 1541.</num><heading> Organization and status</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3e1e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1541/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition and territorial designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter and the name “Virgin Islands” as used in this chapter, shall apply to and include the territorial domain, islands, cays, and waters acquired by the United States through cession of the Danish West Indian Islands by the convention between the United States of America and His Majesty the King of Denmark entered into <date date="1916-08-04">August 4, 1916</date>, and ratified by the Senate on <date date="1916-09-07">September 7, 1916</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/39/1706">39 Stat. 1706</ref>). The Virgin Islands as above described are declared an unincorporated territory of the United States of America.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7c3e1f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1541/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Powers and legal status of government; capital and seat of government</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The government of the Virgin Islands shall have the powers set forth in this chapter and shall have the right to sue by such name and in cases arising out of contract, to be sued: <i>Provided</i>, That no tort action shall be brought against the government of the Virgin Islands or against any officer or employee thereof in his official capacity without the consent of the legislature constituted by this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The capital and seat of government of the Virgin Islands shall be located at the city of Charlotte Amalie, in the island of Saint Thomas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7eae20-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1541/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative supervision by Secretary of the Interior</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The relations between such government and the Federal Government in all matters not the program responsibility of another Federal department or agency shall be under the general administrative supervision of the Secretary of the Interior.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf7eae21-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s2">July 22, 1954, ch. 558, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/497">68 Stat. 497</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/496/s13">Pub. L. 90–496, § 13</ref>, <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/842">82 Stat. 842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf7eae22-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf7eae23-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf7eae24-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558">act July 22, 1954, ch. 558</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/497">68 Stat. 497</ref>, known as the Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands, which enacted this chapter, amended sections 104 and 111 of Title 21, Food and Drugs, and section 3350 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code (see <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7652/b/3">section 7652(b)(3) of Title 26</ref>), and enacted provisions set out as notes under this section. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf7eae25-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/496">Pub. L. 90–496</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf7eae26-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf7eae27-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of provisions of section necessary to authorize the holding of an election for Governor and Lieutenant Governor on <date date="1970-11-03">Nov. 3, 1970</date>, effective <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, and all other amendments of provisions of section, unless otherwise expressly provided by <ref href="/us/pl/90/496">Pub. L. 90–496</ref>, effective <date date="1971-01-04">Jan. 4, 1971</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/496/s16">section 16 of Pub. L. 90–496</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1591">section 1591 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcf7eae28-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s34">Act July 22, 1954, ch. 558, § 34</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/510">68 Stat. 510</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s34">“This Act [see Short Title note below] shall take effect upon its approval [<date date="1954-07-22">July 22, 1954</date>], but until its provisions shall severally become operative as herein provided, the corresponding legislative, executive, and judicial functions of the existing government shall continue to be exercised as now provided by law or ordinance, and the incumbents of all offices under the government of the Virgin Islands shall continue in office until their successors are appointed and have qualified unless sooner removed by competent authority. The enactment of this Act shall not affect the term of office of the judge of the District Court of the Virgin Islands in office on the date of its enactment [<date date="1954-07-22">July 22, 1954</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idcf7eae29-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1968 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/90/496/s17">Pub. L. 90–496, § 17</ref>, <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/842">82 Stat. 842</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/90/496/s17">“This Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s336">section 336 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, amending this section and sections 1561, 1572, 1573, 1574, 1575, 1591, 1593, 1595, 1597, 1599, and 1641 of this title, repealing sections 1594, 1596, and 1632 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1591">section 1591 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Virgin Islands Elective Governor Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idcf7eae2a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1959 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/86/289/s1">Pub. L. 86–289, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-16">Sept. 16, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/568">73 Stat. 568</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/86/289/s1">“That this Act [amending sections 1573, 1597, and 1617 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Virgin Islands Organic Act Amendments of 1959’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idcf7eae2b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s1">Act July 22, 1954, ch. 558, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/497">68 Stat. 497</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s1">“This Act [enacting this chapter, amending sections 104 and 111 of Title 21, Food and Drugs, and sections 3350 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code (see <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7652/b/3">section 7652(b)(3) of Title 26</ref>), and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] may be cited as the ‘Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idcf7eae2c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s36">Act July 22, 1954, ch. 558, § 36</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/510">68 Stat. 510</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s36">“If any clause, sentence, paragraph, or part of this Act [see Short Title note above], or the application thereof to any person, or circumstances, is held invalid, the application thereof to other persons, or circumstances, and the remainder of the Act, shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf7eae2d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Virgin Islands of the United States Centennial Commission</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/224">Pub. L. 114–224</ref>, <date date="2016-09-29">Sept. 29, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/921">130 Stat. 921</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/224">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Virgin Islands of the United States Centennial Commission Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> ESTABLISHMENT.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“There is established a commission to be known as the ‘Virgin Islands of the United States Centennial Commission’ (in this Act referred to as the ‘Commission’).</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> DUTIES OF COMMISSION.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Commission shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> plan, develop, and carry out such activities as the Commission determines to be appropriate to commemorate the 100th anniversary of the Virgin Islands of the United States becoming an unincorporated territory of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> provide advice and assistance to Federal, State, and local governmental agencies, as well as civic groups to carry out activities to commemorate the 100th anniversary of the Virgin Islands of the United States becoming an unincorporated territory of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> submit to the President and Congress the reports required pursuant to section 7.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> MEMBERSHIP.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Number and Appointment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Commission shall be composed of 8 members as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Assistant Secretary of the Interior for Insular Affairs or a designee of the Assistant Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> One member appointed by the Governor of the Virgin Islands of the United States or a designee of the Governor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Two Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> One Member of the House of Representatives appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Two Members of the Senate appointed by the majority leader of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> One Member of the Senate appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading><content>Each member of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for Appointment</inline>.—</heading><content>All members of the Commission shall be appointed not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-09-29">Sept. 29, 2016</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Vacancies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A vacancy on the Commission shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not affect the powers of the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rates of Pay</inline>.—</heading><content>Members shall not receive compensation for the performance of duties on behalf of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Travel Expenses</inline>.—</heading><content>Each member of the Commission shall be reimbursed for travel and per diem in lieu of subsistence expenses during the performance of duties of the Commission while away from home or regular place of business of the member, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Quorum</inline>.—</heading><content>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum to conduct business, but two or more members may hold hearings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Chairperson</inline>.—</heading><content>The chairperson of the Commission shall be selected by a majority vote of the members of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> DIRECTOR AND STAFF OF COMMISSION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director and Staff</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission shall appoint an executive director and such other additional personnel as are necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Certain Civil Service Laws</inline>.—</heading><content>The executive director and staff of the Commission may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other staff may not exceed the rate payable for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Detail of Federal Employees</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon request of the Commission, the Secretary of the Interior or the Archivist of the United States may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the Department of the Interior or the National Archives and Records Administration, respectively[,] to the Commission to assist the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Experts and Consultants</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may procure such temporary and intermittent services from experts and consultants as are necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Volunteer and Uncompensated Services</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1342">section 1342 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Commission may accept and use voluntary and uncompensated services as the Commission determines necessary.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6">“SEC. 6.</num><heading> POWERS OF COMMISSION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hearings</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Mails</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other Federal agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Obtaining Official Data</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may secure directly from any Federal agency information necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission. Upon request of the chairperson of the Commission, the head of that Federal agency shall furnish that information to the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Gifts, Bequests, Devises</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of money, services, or property, both real and personal, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Available Space</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon the request of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall make available to the Commission, at a normal rental rate for Federal agencies, such assistance and facilities as may be necessary for the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contract Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Commission may enter into contracts with and compensate the Federal Government, State and local governments, private entities, or individuals to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7">“SEC. 7.</num><heading> REPORTS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than January 31 of each year, and annually thereafter until the final report is submitted pursuant to subsection (b), the Commission shall submit to the President and the Congress a report on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the activities of the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the revenue and expenditures of the Commission, including a list of each gift, bequest, or devise to the Commission with a value of more than $250, including the identity of the donor of each gift, bequest, or devise.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2018-01-31">January 31, 2018</date>, the Commission shall submit a final report to the President and the Congress containing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a summary of the activities of the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a final accounting of funds received and expended by the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="8">“SEC. 8.</num><heading> ANNUAL AUDIT.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Inspector General of the Department of the Interior—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> may perform an audit of the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall make the results of any such audit available to the public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> shall transmit such results to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform [now Committee on Oversight and Accountability] of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="9">“SEC. 9.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this Act:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal agency</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Federal agency’ has the meaning given the term ‘agency’ in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s551">section 551 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="10">“SEC. 10.</num><heading> TERMINATION.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Commission shall terminate on <date date="2018-09-30">September 30, 2018</date>, or may terminate at an earlier date determined by the Commission after the final report is submitted pursuant to section 7(b).</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="11">“SEC. 11.</num><heading> NO ADDITIONAL FUNDS AUTHORIZED.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“No Federal funds are authorized or may be obligated to carry out this Act.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf7eae2e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Approval of Proposed Constitution for United States Virgin Islands</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/21">Pub. L. 97–21</ref>, <date date="1981-07-09">July 9, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/105">95 Stat. 105</ref>, set out the text of the Constitution for the United States Virgin Islands and provided that the Constitution is approved for submission to the people of the Virgin Islands in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/94/584">Public Law 94–584</ref>, set out as a note preceding this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf7eae2f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Submerged Lands, Conveyance to Territory</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Conveyance of submerged lands to the government of the Virgin Islands, see section 1701 et seq. of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
