<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf7eae57-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1571"><num value="1571">§ 1571.</num><heading> Legislature</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7eae58-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1571/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation and unicameral character</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The legislative power and authority of the Virgin Islands shall be vested in a legislature, consisting of one house, to be designated the “Legislature of the Virgin Islands”, herein referred to as the legislature.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf7eae59-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1571/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition; legislative districts; method of elections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The legislature shall be composed of members to be known as senators. The number of such senators shall be determined by the laws of the Virgin Islands. The apportionment of the legislature shall be as provided by the laws of the Virgin Islands: <i>Provided</i>, That such apportionment shall not deny to any person in the Virgin Islands the equal protection of the law: <i>And provided further</i>, That every voter in any district election or at large election shall be permitted to vote for the whole number of persons to be elected in that district election or at large election as the case may be. Until the legislature shall provide otherwise, four members shall be elected at large, five shall be elected from the District of Saint Thomas, five from the District of Saint Croix, and one from the District of Saint John, as those Districts were constituted on <date date="1954-07-22">July 22, 1954</date>,</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf7eae5a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s5">July 22, 1954, ch. 558, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/498">68 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/548/s1">Pub. L. 89–548, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-08-30">Aug. 30, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/371">80 Stat. 371</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/364/s1">Pub. L. 106–364, § 1</ref>, <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1408">114 Stat. 1408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf7eae5b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf7eae5c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf7eae5d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/364">Pub. L. 106–364</ref> struck out “fifteen” after “composed of” in first sentence and inserted “The number of such senators shall be determined by the laws of the Virgin Islands.” after first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/548">Pub. L. 89–548</ref> raised from eleven to fifteen the total number of senators in the legislature, substituted provision that the legislature be apportioned according to the laws of the Virgin Islands for provisions spelling out the division of the Virgin Islands into districts, the composition of each such district, and the district and at-large representation breakdown of the senators in the legislature, struck out provision for the casting of a ballot for two candidates by each elector in at-large elections and the drawing of lots to determine placement on the ballot in at-large elections, prohibited apportionment in a way which would deny equal protection of the law, and provided for temporary apportionment until the legislature provided otherwise from the districts as constituted on <date date="1954-07-22">July 22, 1954</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf7eae5e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf7eae5f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1966 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/548/s2">Pub. L. 89–548, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-08-30">Aug. 30, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/371">80 Stat. 371</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/89/548/s2">“This Act [amending this section] shall be effective with respect to the legislature to be elected at the regular general election in November 1966, and thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
