<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf80f8c0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575"><num value="1575">§ 1575.</num><heading> Legislative procedure</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf80f8c1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Quorum and method of voting on bills</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The number of members of the legislature needed to constitute a quorum shall be determined by the laws of the Virgin Islands. No bill shall become a law unless it shall have been passed at a meeting, at which a quorum was present, by the affirmative vote of a majority of the members present and voting, which vote shall be by yeas and nays.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf80f8c2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enacting clause of acts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The enacting clause of all acts shall be as follows: “Be it enacted by the Legislature of the Virgin Islands”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf80f8c3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Governor’s message and budget</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Governor shall submit at the opening of each regular session of the legislature a message on the state of the Virgin Islands and a budget of estimated receipts and expenditures, which shall be the basis of the appropriation bills for the ensuing fiscal year, which shall commence on the first day of July or such other date as the Legislature of the Virgin Islands may determine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf80f8c4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval and disapproval of bills</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every bill passed by the legislature shall, before it becomes a law, be presented to the Governor. If the Governor approves the bill, he shall sign it. If the Governor disapproves the bill, he shall, except as hereinafter provided, return it, with his objections, to the legislature within ten days (Sundays excepted) after it shall have been presented to him. If the Governor does not return the bill within such period, it shall be a law in like manner as if he had signed it, unless the legislature by adjournment prevents its return, in which case it shall be a law if signed by the Governor within thirty days after it shall have been presented to him; otherwise it shall not be a law. When a bill is returned by the Governor to the legislature with his objections, the legislature shall enter his objections at large on its journal and, upon motion of a member of the legislature, proceed to reconsider the bill. If, after such reconsideration, two-thirds of all the members of the legislature pass the bill, it shall be a law. If any bill presented to the Governor contains several items of appropriation of money, he may object to one or more of such items, or any part or parts, portion or portions thereof, while approving the other items, parts, or portions of the bill. In such a case he shall append to the bill, at the time of signing it, a statement of the items, or parts or portions thereof, to which he objects, and the items, or parts or portions thereof, so objected to shall not take effect, unless the legislature, after reconsideration upon motion of a member thereof, passes such items, parts, or portions so objected to by a vote of two-thirds of all the members of the legislature.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf80f8c5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of prior appropriations upon failure to pass appropriation bills</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If at the termination of any fiscal year the legislature shall have failed to pass appropriation bills providing for payment of the obligations and necessary current expenses of the government of the Virgin Islands for the ensuing fiscal year, then the several sums appropriated in the last appropriation bills for the objects and purposes therein specified, so far as the same may be applicable, shall be deemed to be reappropriated item by item.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf80f8c6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Journal of proceedings; contents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The legislature shall keep a journal of its proceedings and publish the same. Every bill passed by the legislature and the yeas and nays on any question shall be entered on the journal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf80f8c7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1575/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Transmittal of laws to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A listing of all laws enacted by the legislature each year shall be transmitted with the annual report to Congress required pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1591">section 1591 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf80f8c8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s9">July 22, 1954, ch. 558, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/501">68 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/496">Pub. L. 90–496</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/837">82 Stat. 837</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/134/tIII/s301/b">Pub. L. 95–134, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-15">Oct. 15, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1163">91 Stat. 1163</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/348/s4/c/1">Pub. L. 95–348, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-08-18">Aug. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/490">92 Stat. 490</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/470/tII/s206/d">Pub. L. 96–470, title II, § 206(d)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-19">Oct. 19, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2244">94 Stat. 2244</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/364/s2">Pub. L. 106–364, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1408">114 Stat. 1408</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf80f8c9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf80f8ca-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf80f8cb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/364">Pub. L. 106–364</ref> amended first sentence generally. Prior to amendment, first sentence read as follows: “The quorum of the legislature shall consist of eight of its members.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/470">Pub. L. 96–470</ref> substituted provision requiring a listing of all laws enacted by the legislature each year be transmitted with the annual report to Congress required by <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1591">section 1591 of this title</ref> for provision requiring copies of all laws enacted by the legislature be transmitted within 15 days of their enactment by the Governor to the Secretary of the Interior and by the Secretary annually to Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/348">Pub. L. 95–348</ref> inserted provision authorizing the Virgin Islands Legislature to determine other dates on which the fiscal year shall commence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/134">Pub. L. 95–134</ref> inserted “, unless the legislature, after reconsideration upon motion of a member thereof, passes such items, parts, or portions so objected to by a vote of two-thirds of all the members of the legislature” after “shall not take effect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/496/s2">Pub. L. 90–496, § 2</ref>, increased the quorum requirement from seven to eight members.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/90/496/s3">Pub. L. 90–496, § 3</ref>, inserted requirement that when a bill is returned by the Governor to the legislature, a motion of a member of the legislature is necessary for the legislature to reconsider the bill, and substituted provisions that if, after reconsideration by the legislature, two-thirds of all the members of the legislature pass a bill returned by the Governor, it shall be a law for provisions that if, after reconsideration by the legislature, two-thirds of all the members of the legislature agree to pass the bill, it shall be presented anew to the Governor for his approval, provisions that if the Governor does not approve the bill, the bill shall be sent to the President of the United States for his approval, provisions that if the President disapproves the bill, the bill shall be returned to the Governor, stating the President’s disapproval, and it shall not be a law, and provisions that if the President neither approves nor disapproves the bill within 90 days after it was sent to him by the Governor, the bill shall be a law as if the President had signed it.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf80f8cc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf80f8cd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/90/496/s2">Pub. L. 90–496, § 2</ref>, <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/837">82 Stat. 837</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 2 is effective on the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/90/496">Pub. L. 90–496</ref>, which was approved <date date="1968-08-23">Aug. 23, 1968</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of provisions of section necessary to authorize the holding of an election for Governor and Lieutenant Governor on <date date="1970-11-03">Nov. 3, 1970</date>, effective <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, and all other amendments of provisions of section, unless otherwise expressly provided by <ref href="/us/pl/90/496">Pub. L. 90–496</ref>, effective <date date="1971-01-04">Jan. 4, 1971</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/496/s16">section 16 of Pub. L. 90–496</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1591">section 1591 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
