<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf836a43-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1613"><num value="1613">§ 1613.</num><heading> Relations between courts of United States and courts of Virgin Islands; review by United States Court of Appeals for Third Circuit; reports to Congress; rules</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The relations between the courts established by the Constitution or laws of the United States and the courts established by local law with respect to appeals, certiorari, removal of causes, the issuance of writs of habeas corpus, and other matters or proceedings shall be governed by the laws of the United States pertaining to the relations between the courts of the United States, including the Supreme Court of the United States, and the courts of the several States in such matters and proceedings.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idcf836a44-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-07-22/ch558/s23">July 22, 1954, ch. 558, § 23</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/506">68 Stat. 506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/tVII/s704">Pub. L. 98–454, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1739">98 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s17/a/4">Pub. L. 103–437, § 17(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4595">108 Stat. 4595</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/226/s1">Pub. L. 112–226, § 1</ref>, <date date="2012-12-28">Dec. 28, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1606">126 Stat. 1606</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf836a45-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf836a46-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf836a47-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—<ref href="/us/pl/112/226">Pub. L. 112–226</ref> substituted a period for “: <i>Provided</i>, That for the first fifteen years following the establishment of the appellate court authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1611/a">section 1611(a) of this title</ref>, the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit shall have jurisdiction to review by writ of certiorari all final decisions of the highest court of the Virgin Islands from which a decision could be had. The Judicial Council of the Third Circuit shall submit reports to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives at intervals of five years following the establishment of such appellate court as to whether it has developed sufficient institutional traditions to justify direct review by the Supreme Court of the United States from all such final decisions. The United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit shall have jurisdiction to promulgate rules necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” before “of the House”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/454">Pub. L. 98–454</ref> amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to the relations between local law courts and already established courts under the Constitution or laws of the United States with respect to appeals, certiorari, etc. and providing that the Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit shall have jurisdiction to review all final decisions from the highest court of the Virgin Islands for fifteen years after the appellate court is established for former provisions relating to the jurisdiction of inferior courts, transfer of actions, status as committing court, bail and rules.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf836a48-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf836a49-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2012 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"> Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/226">Pub. L. 112–226</ref> applicable to cases commenced on or after <date date="2012-12-28">Dec. 28, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/226/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 112–226</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1260">section 1260 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf836a4a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/454">Pub. L. 98–454</ref> effective on ninetieth day following <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/s1005">section 1005 of Pub. L. 98–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1424">section 1424 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
