<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf85dae2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1666"><num value="1666">§ 1666.</num><heading> Extension of scientific, technical, and other assistance; grant-in-aid program restriction; limitations on expenditures</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request of the Secretary of the Interior—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf85dae3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1666/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> the head of any Federal department, agency, or corporation may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, extend to American Samoa, without reimbursement, such scientific, technical, and other assistance under any program which it administers as, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Interior, will promote the welfare of American Samoa. The provisions of the preceding sentence shall not apply to financial assistance under any grant-in-aid program. The Secretary of the Interior shall not request assistance pursuant to this subsection which will involve nonreimbursable costs as estimated for him in advance by the heads of the departments, agencies, and corporations concerned in excess of an aggregate of $150,000 in any one fiscal year;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf85dae4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1666/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> the Secretary of Agriculture may extend to American Samoa the benefits of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcf85dae5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1666/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare may extend to American Samoa the benefits of the Vocational Education Act of 1946, the Hospital Survey and Construction Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291">42 U.S.C. 291</ref> et seq.], and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246">section 246 of title 42</ref>, all as amended.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf85dae6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/688/s1">Pub. L. 87–688, § 1</ref>, <date date="1962-09-25">Sept. 25, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/586">76 Stat. 586</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/e/tVII/s709/a/7">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(e) [title VII, § 709(a)(7)]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-233">110 Stat. 3009–233</ref>, 3009–312; <ref href="/us/pl/106/78/tVII/s752/b/18">Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(18)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1170">113 Stat. 1170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf85dae7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf85dae8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf85dae9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, as amended, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-06-04/ch281">act June 4, 1946, ch. 281</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/230">60 Stat. 230</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 13 (§ 1751 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">section 1751 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Vocational Education Act of 1946, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-08/ch541">act June 8, 1936, ch. 541</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1488">49 Stat. 1488</ref>, which was classified to sections 15h to 15q, 15aa to 15jj, and 15aaa to 15ggg of Title 20, Education, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/90/576/s103">section 103 of Pub. L. 90–576</ref>, title I, <date date="1968-10-16">Oct. 16, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1091">82 Stat. 1091</ref>. See section 2301 et seq. of Title 20.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Hospital Survey and Construction Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-13/ch958">act Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 958</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1041">60 Stat. 1041</ref>, which added a title VI to the Public Health Service Act, and was classified to subchapter IV (§ 291 et seq.) of chapter 6A of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Such title VI was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/88/443/s3/a">Pub. L. 88–443, § 3(a)</ref> <date date="1964-08-18">Aug. 18, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/447">78 Stat. 447</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf85daea-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/78">Pub. L. 106–78</ref> substituted “Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act” for “National School Lunch Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/208">Pub. L. 104–208</ref> struck out “the Library Services Act,” after “the Vocational Education Act of 1946,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf85daeb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idcf85daec-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions and offices (relating to education) of Secretary and Department of Health, Education, and Welfare to Secretary and Department of Education, and termination of certain offices and positions and redesignation of Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare as Secretary of Health and Human Services, see sections 3441, 3503, and 3508 of Title 20, Education.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
