<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf88244f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1692"><num value="1692">§ 1692.</num><heading> Comprehensive annual financial report by chief executives of governments of the Marshall Islands, Federated States of Micronesia, Palau, and Northern Mariana Islands; contents; other reports</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The chief executives of the governments of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, Palau, and the Northern Mariana Islands shall prepare, publish, and submit to the Congress and the Secretary of the Interior a comprehensive annual financial report in conformance with the standards of the National Council on Governmental Accounting within one hundred and twenty days after the close of the fiscal year. The comprehensive annual financial report shall include statistical data as set forth in the standards of the National Council on Governmental Accounting relating to the physical, economic, social, and political characteristics of the government, and any other information required by the Congress. The chief executives shall also make such other reports at such other times as may be required by the Congress or under applicable Federal laws. This section is not subject to termination under section 502(a)(3) of the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States of America (<ref href="/us/stat/90/263">90 Stat. 263</ref>, 268).</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idcf882450-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/257/s5">Pub. L. 92–257, § 5</ref>, <date date="1972-03-21">Mar. 21, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/88">86 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/357/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 97–357, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-19">Oct. 19, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1707">96 Stat. 1707</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tIX/s901/p">Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901(p)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3291">112 Stat. 3291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf882451-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf882452-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf882453-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 502(a)(3) of the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States of America, referred to in text, is contained in <ref href="/us/pl/94/241/s1">section 1 of Pub. L. 94–241</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf882454-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> struck out “The chief executives shall transmit the comprehensive annual financial report to the Inspector General of the Department of the Interior who shall audit it and report his findings to the Congress.” after “required by the Congress.” and “The chief executives shall submit to the Congress, the Secretary of the Interior, the High Commissioner of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the cognizant Federal auditors a written statement of actions taken or contemplated on Federal audit recommendations within sixty days after the issuance date of the audit report.” after “applicable Federal law.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/357">Pub. L. 97–357</ref> substituted provisions relating to preparation, etc., by the chief executives of the governments of the Marshall Islands, etc., of a comprehensive annual financial report to be submitted to the Congress and the Secretary of the Interior and transmitted to the Inspector General of the Interior Department, preparation of other congressionally required reports, submission of a written statement of actions taken or contemplated on Federal audit recommendations, and prohibition of termination of this section under the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States, for provisions relating to an annual report by the High Commissioner of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands on the administration of sections 1688 to 1693 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf882455-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf882456-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in the 1st sentence of this section relating to the requirement that the chief executives submit a comprehensive annual financial report to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and the 1st item on page 116 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf882457-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exception to Requirement that Statement be Submitted to High Commissioner of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/357/tII/s203/e">Pub. L. 97–357, title II, § 203(e)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-19">Oct. 19, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1708">96 Stat. 1708</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/357/tII/s203/e">“Nothing in this section [adding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681b">section 1681b of this title</ref>, amending this section, and repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681c">section 1681c of this title</ref>] shall be construed as requiring the Governor of the Northern Mariana Islands to submit any statement or report to the High Commissioner of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
