<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf8f5017-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1803"><num value="1803">§ 1803.</num><heading> Financial assistance to Government of Northern Mariana Islands</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to section 701 of the foregoing Covenant, enactment of this section shall constitute a commitment and pledge of the full faith and credit of the United States for the payment of $228 million at guaranteed annual amounts of direct grant assistance for the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands for an additional period of seven fiscal years after the expiration of the initial seven-year period specified in section 702 of said Covenant, which assistance shall be provided according to the schedule of payments contained in the Agreement of the Special Representatives on Future United States Financial Assistance for the Government of the Northern Mariana Islands, executed <date date="1985-07-10">July 10, 1985</date>, between the special representative of the President of the United States and the special representatives of the Governor of the Northern Mariana Islands. The islands of Rota and Tinian shall each receive no less than a ⅛ share and the island of Saipan shall receive no less than a ¼ share of annualized capital improvement project funds, which shall be no less than 80 per centum of the capital development funds identified in the schedule of payments in paragraph 2 of part II of the Agreement of the Special Representatives. Funds shall be granted according to such regulations as are applicable to such grants.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idcf8f5018-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/241/s3">Pub. L. 94–241, § 3</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/396/s10">Pub. L. 99–396, § 10</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/840">100 Stat. 840</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf8f5019-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf8f501a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf8f501b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Covenant, referred to in text, is the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States of America, which is contained in <ref href="/us/pl/94/241/s1">section 1 of Pub. L. 94–241</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idcf8f501c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf8f501d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf8f501e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Economic Development Loan Funds for Capital Improvement Projects</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/396/s2">Pub. L. 99–396, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-08-27">Aug. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/838">100 Stat. 838</ref>, authorized use of up to $4,000,000 of funds reserved for use by the economic development loan fund, as established under section 702(c) of the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States of America, <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1801">48 U.S.C. 1801</ref> note, for capital improvement projects, if such funds became available for use by the economic development loan fund, and were not obligated for economic development loans.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
