<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf940b03-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821"><num value="1821">§ 1821.</num><heading> District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf940b04-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; judicial circuit; terms of court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established for and within the Northern Mariana Islands a court of record to be known as the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands. The Northern Mariana Islands shall constitute a part of the same judicial circuit of the United States as Guam. Terms of court shall be held on Saipan and at such other places and at such times as the court may designate by rule or order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf940b05-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment, tenure, removal, compensation, etc., of District Court judge; appointment of United States attorney and United States marshal</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf940b06-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President shall, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, appoint a judge for the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands who shall hold office for the term of ten years and until his successor is chosen and qualified, unless sooner removed by the President for cause. The judge shall receive a salary payable by the United States which shall be at the rate prescribed for judges of the United States district courts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf940b07-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Chief Judge of the Ninth Judicial Circuit of the United States may assign justices of the High Court of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands or judges of courts of record of the Northern Mariana Islands who are licensed attorneys in good standing or a circuit or district judge of the ninth circuit, including a judge of the District Court of Guam who is appointed by the President or a recalled senior judge of the District Court of Guam or of the District Court of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Chief Justice of the United States may assign any other United States circuit or district judge with the consent of the judge so assigned and of the chief judge of his circuit to serve temporarily as a judge in the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands whenever such an assignment is necessary for the proper dispatch of the business of the court. Such judges shall have all the powers of a judge of the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands, including the power to appoint any person to a statutory position, or to designate a depository of funds or a newspaper for publication of legal notices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf940b08-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a United States attorney and United States marshal for the Northern Mariana Islands to whose offices the provisions of chapters 35 and 37 of title 28, respectively, shall apply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcf940b09-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the President appoints a judge for the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands or a United States attorney or a United States marshal for the Northern Mariana Islands who at that time is serving in the same capacity in another district, the appointment shall, without prejudice to a subsequent appointment, be for the unexpired term of such judge or officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcf940b0a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1821/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of Federal rules and statutory requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where appropriate, and except as otherwise provided in articles IV and V of the Covenant approved by the Act of <date date="1976-03-24">March 24, 1976</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/90/263">90 Stat. 263</ref>), the provisions of part II of title 18 and of titles <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002026"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> 28, the rules of practice and procedure heretofore or hereafter promulgated and made effective by the Congress or the Supreme Court of the United States pursuant to titles 11, 18, and 28 shall apply to the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands and appeals therefrom; except that the terms “Attorney for the government” and “United States attorney”, as used in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, shall, when applicable to cases arising under the laws of the Northern Mariana Islands, include the Attorney General of the Northern Mariana Islands or such other person or persons as may be authorized by the laws of the Northern Mariana Islands to act therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcf940b0b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/157/s1">Pub. L. 95–157, § 1</ref>, <date date="1977-11-08">Nov. 8, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1265">91 Stat. 1265</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/tIX/s901">Pub. L. 98–454, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1744">98 Stat. 1744</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf940b0c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf940b0d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf940b0e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Covenant, referred to in subsec. (c), is the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States of America, which is contained in <ref href="/us/pl/94/241/s1">section 1 of Pub. L. 94–241</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1976-03-24">March 24, 1976</date>, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/241">Pub. L. 94–241</ref>, <date date="1976-03-24">Mar. 24, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/263">90 Stat. 263</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1801 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, referred to in subsec. (c), are set out in the Appendix to Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idcf940b0f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1694">section 1694 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf940b10-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/s901/a">Pub. L. 98–454, § 901(a)</ref>, substituted “for a term of ten years” for “for a term of eight years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/s901/b">Pub. L. 98–454, § 901(b)</ref>, inserted “or a recalled senior judge of the District Court of Guam or of the District Court of the Northern Mariana Islands” after “President” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/s901/c">Pub. L. 98–454, § 901(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “The provisions of chapters 43 and 49 of title 28, and the rules heretofore or hereafter promulgated and made effective by the Congress or the Supreme Court of the United States pursuant to titles 11, 18, and 28 shall apply to the District Court for the Northern Mariana Islands and appeals therefrom where appropriate, except as otherwise provided in articles IV and V of the covenant provided by the Act of <date date="1976-03-24">March 24, 1976</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/90/263">90 Stat. 263</ref>). The terms ‘attorney for the government’ and ‘United States attorney’ as used in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (rule 54(c)) shall, when applicable to cases arising under the laws of the Northern Mariana Islands, include the attorney general of the Northern Mariana Islands or any other person or persons as may be authorized by the laws of the Northern Marianas to act therein.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf940b11-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf940b12-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/454">Pub. L. 98–454</ref> effective on ninetieth day following <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/s1005">section 1005 of Pub. L. 98–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1424">section 1424 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idcf940b13-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1825">section 1825 of this title</ref> and Effective Date of Constitution note thereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf940b14-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension of Term of District Judges</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Extension of term of district court judges to ten years applicable to judges holding office on <date date="1984-10-05">Oct. 5, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/454/s1004">section 1004 of Pub. L. 98–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1424b">section 1424b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idcf940b15-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf940b16-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
