<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfa2638c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1907"><num value="1907">§ 1907.</num><heading> Limitations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfa2638d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1907/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of Chapter 11 of title 18 shall apply in full to any individual who has served as the President’s Personal Representative for Micronesian Status Negotiations or who is or was an officer or employee of the Office for Micronesian Status Negotiations or who is or was assigned or detailed to that Office or who served on the Micronesia Interagency Group, except that for the purposes of this section, clauses (i) and (ii) of section 207(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002035">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002035"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of such title shall read as follows: “(i) having been so employed, within three years after his employment has ceased, knowingly acts as agent or attorney for, or otherwise represents, any other person (except the United States), in any formal or informal appearance before, or, with the intent to influence, makes any oral or written communication on behalf of any other person (except the United States) to, or (ii) having been so employed and as specified in subsection (d) of this section, within three years after his employment has ceased, knowingly represents or aids, counsels, advises, consults, or assists in representing any other person (except the United States) by personal presence at any formal or informal appearance before—”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfa2638e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1907/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective upon the date of the termination of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands with respect to Palau, the Office for Micronesian Status Negotiations is abolished and no department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States shall thereafter contribute funds for the support of such Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfa2638f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/239/tI/s107">Pub. L. 99–239, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1986-01-14">Jan. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1797">99 Stat. 1797</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcfa26390-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcfa26391-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcfa26392-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t18/s207">Section 207 of title 18</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/101/194/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 101–194, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-30">Nov. 30, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1716">103 Stat. 1716</ref>, and, as so amended, subsec. (b) of that section no longer contains cls. (i) and (ii). For text of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s207">section 207 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, as it appeared prior to amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/194">Pub. L. 101–194</ref>, see Effective Date of 1989 Amendment; Effect on Employment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s207">section 207 of Title 18</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idcfa26393-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idcfa26394-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcfa26395-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands with respect to Palau, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
