<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfbca201-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933"><num value="1933">§ 1933.</num><heading> Supplemental provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca202-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Civic Action Teams</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfbca203-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In recognition of the special development needs of Palau and the Marshall Islands, the United States shall make available United States military Civic Action Teams for use in Palau or the Marshall Islands under terms and conditions mutually agreed upon by the Government of the United States and the Governments of Palau or the Marshall Islands, as appropriate. The Government of Palau may use the amount of $250,000 annually from current account funds provided pursuant to section 211 of the Compact to defray expenditures attendant to the operation of the Civic Action Teams made available pursuant to this subsection. The Government of the Marshall Islands may use the amount of $250,000 annually from current account funds provided under section 211 of Title Two of the Compact of Free Association with the Marshall Islands to defray expenditures attendant to the operation of the Civic Action Teams made available pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfbca204-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For expenditures that the Department of Defense makes pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may accept up to the amount of $250,000 in annual funds from the Government of Palau as specified in paragraph (1). Funds accepted by the Secretary from the Government of Palau under this paragraph shall be credited to and merged with appropriations available to the Department of Defense and shall be used to defray expenditures attendant to the operation of the United States military Civic Action Team in Palau. Funds so credited and merged shall be available for the same time period as the appropriations to which the funds are credited and merged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca205-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Inventory and study of natural, historic, and other resources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall conduct, upon request of Palau, the Federated States of Micronesia or the Marshall Islands, and through the Director of the National Park Service, a comprehensive inventory and study of the most unique and significant natural, historical, cultural, and recreational resources of Palau, the Federated States of Micronesia or the Marshall Islands. Areas or sites exhibiting such qualities shall be described and evaluated with the objective of the preservation of their values and their careful use and appreciation by the public, along with a determination of their potential for attracting tourism. Alternative methodologies for such preservation and use shall be developed for each area or site (including continued assistance from the National Park Service); current or impending damage or threats to the resources of such areas or sites shall be identified and evaluated; and authorities needed to properly protect and allow for public use and appreciation shall be identified and discussed. Such inventory and study shall be conducted in full cooperation and consultation with affected governmental officials and the interested public. A full report on such inventory and study shall be transmitted to Palau or the Federated States of Micronesia or the Marshall Islands, the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate no later than two complete calendar years after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>. The inventory and study shall also identify areas or sites which, if they were located in the United States, would qualify to be listed on the Registry of Natural Landmarks and the National Register of Historic Places.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca206-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca207-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Peleliu and Angaur</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture, after appropriate studies conducted in consultation with the Government of Palau, shall report to the President and the Congress concerning the feasibility and cost of rehabilitating and restoring the fertility of the topsoil of the islands of Peleliu and Angaur. Upon the request of the Government of Palau, the President shall make the report of the Secretary of Agriculture available to the Government of Palau. Technical assistance to accomplish such rehabilitation and restoration, if feasible, may be provided to the Government of Palau on a nonreimbursable basis, subject to the availability of appropriated funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca208-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Power generation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Neither the Secretary of the Treasury nor any other officer or agent of the United States shall pay or transfer any portion of the sum and amounts payable to the Government of Palau pursuant to this joint resolution to any party other than the Government of Palau, except under the procedures established by the Compact and its related agreements. No funds appropriated pursuant to the Compact, this Act, or any other Act for grants or other assistance to Palau may be used to satisfy any obligation or expense incurred by Palau prior to <date date="1986-11-14">November 14, 1986</date>, with respect to any contract or debt related to any electrical generating plant or related facilities entered into or incurred by Palau which has not been specifically authorized by Congress in advance, except that the Government of Palau may use any portion of the annual grant under section 211(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002040"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “of the Compact”.</note> not required to be devoted to the energy needs of those parts of Palau not served by its central power generating facilities and any portion of the funds under section 212(b) of the Compact for such purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca209-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Amounts appropriated to be paid pursuant to section 177 of Article I of Title One or Articles I and III of Title Two of the Compact of Free Association with the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands, as set forth in Title II of the Compact of Free Association Act of 1985, or pursuant to section 103(h), 103(k), or 105(m) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1903/h">48 U.S.C. 1903(h)</ref>, (k), 1905(m)] (<ref href="/us/pl/99/239">Public Law 99–239</ref>), or pursuant to Article I of Title Two of the Compact with Palau, as set forth in Title II of this joint resolution, or section 104(<i>l</i>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002041">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002041"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this joint resolution shall not be reduced, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Public Law 99–177</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/366">Public Law 99–366</ref>, and other law enacted to implement <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Public Law 99–177</ref>, or any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca20a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Understandings, interpretations, and policy statements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress reaffirms all of the understandings, interpretations, and policy statements contained in <ref href="/us/pl/99/239">Public Law 99–239</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/99/1770">99 Stat. 1770</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1901">48 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq., 2001 et seq.]. Congressional Resolution 4–60 adopted by the 4th Congress of the Federated States of Micronesia on <date date="1986-03-26">March 26, 1986</date> and Resolution No. 62 adopted by the Nitijela of the Marshall Islands on <date date="1986-02-18">February 18, 1986</date> do not exclude, limit or modify any provision of the Compact of Free Association as approved by the United States. To the extent that any understandings, interpretations, and policy statements contained in such Resolutions are inconsistent with the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/99/239">Public Law 99–239</ref>, the United States does not concur therein. The President shall take such steps, including but not limited to, communicating with the Governments of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands, as may be necessary to preserve all rights of the United States in connection with interpretation and implementation of such Public Law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca20b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional provisions relating to Title Three of Compact</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfbca20c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Government of the United States recognizes and respects the scarcity and special importance of land in Palau. In making any designation of land pursuant to section 322 of the Compact, the Government of the United States shall follow the policy of requesting the minimum area necessary to accomplish the required security and defense purpose, of requesting only the minimum interest in real property necessary to support such purpose, and of requesting first to satisfy the requirement through public real property, where available, rather than through private real property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfbca20d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Armed Forces of other nations invited to use military areas and facilities in Palau pursuant to section 312 of the Compact shall be permitted only as it is incident to the authority and under the control of the United States. The activities of such third country forces shall be subject to the same limitations and restrictions applicable to the authority of the United States under the terms of the Compact.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfbca20e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Government of the United States considers “Exclusive use” areas established for the United States pursuant to Title Three of the Compact to be “within the jurisdiction of Palau,” as that term is used in section 324 of the Compact.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca20f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds appropriated for the Compact of Free Association, <ref href="/us/pl/99/239">Public Law 99–239</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1901">48 U.S.C. 1901</ref> et seq., 2001 et seq.], or this joint resolution, in the act of making supplemental appropriations for fiscal year 1986, shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca210-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to contract or make payments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfbca211-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content>, (2) Omitted</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfbca212-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No authority under this subsection to enter into contracts or to make payments shall be effective except to the extent and in such amounts as provided in advance in appropriations Acts. Any provision of this subsection which authorizes the enactment of new budget authority shall be effective only for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfbca213-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s1933/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Departments of Energy and Interior are directed to provide the Committees on Appropriations of the House and Senate with a report by December 1 of each fiscal year detailing how funds were spent during the previous fiscal year for the special medical care and logistical support program for Rongelap and Utrik and for the agriculture and food programs for Eniwetok and Bikini as referenced in <ref href="/us/pl/99/239/s103/h">Section 103(h) of Public Law 99–239</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1903/h">48 U.S.C. 1903(h)</ref>]. The report shall also specify the anticipated needs during the current and following fiscal years in order to meet the radiological health care and logistical support program for Rongelap and Utrik and the planting, agricultural maintenance, and food programs for Eniwetok and Bikini. It is the sense of the Congress that the special medical care and logistical support program for Rongelap and Utrik and for the agriculture and food programs for Eniwetok and Bikini described in <ref href="/us/pl/99/239/s103/h">section 103(h) of Public Law 99–239</ref> represent special and continuing moral commitments of the United States which will be annually funded to the extent of the need of the populations of such atolls for such assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfbca214-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/658/tI/s104">Pub. L. 99–658, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3675">100 Stat. 3675</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/219/tI/s105">Pub. L. 101–219, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1989-12-12">Dec. 12, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1871">103 Stat. 1871</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tXII/s1253">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XII, § 1253</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/402">122 Stat. 402</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcfbca215-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcfbca216-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcfbca217-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Compact, referred to in text, is the Compact of Free Association between the United States and the Government of Palau, which is contained in <ref href="/us/pl/99/658/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 99–658</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1931">section 1931 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Compact of Free Association with the Marshall Islands and the Compact of Free Association with the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (f), respectively, are contained in the Compact of Free Association, which is contained in <ref href="/us/pl/99/239/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 99–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This joint resolution and this Act, referred to in subsecs. (e), (f), and (i), is <ref href="/us/pl/99/658">Pub. L. 99–658</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3672">100 Stat. 3672</ref>, as amended, which is classified generally to this part. Title II of this joint resolution enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1934">section 1934 of this title</ref> and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1931">section 1931 of this title</ref>. Section 104 of this joint resolution, which is classified to this section, does not contain a subsec. (<i>l</i>). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Compact of Free Association Act of 1985 and <ref href="/us/pl/99/239">Public Law 99–239</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (f), (g), and (i), is <ref href="/us/pl/99/239">Pub. L. 99–239</ref>, <date date="1986-01-14">Jan. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1770">99 Stat. 1770</ref>, as amended, which is classified principally to part A of subchapter I of this chapter and chapter 19 (§ 2001 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Public Law 99–177</ref>, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/99/177">Pub. L. 99–177</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1037">99 Stat. 1037</ref>, as amended. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/366">Public Law 99–366</ref>, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/99/366">Pub. L. 99–366</ref>, <date date="1986-07-31">July 31, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/773">100 Stat. 773</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Compact of Free Association, referred to in subsecs. (g) and (i), probably means the Compact of Free Association between the Government of the United States and the Governments of the Marshall Islands and the Federated States of Micronesia, which is contained in <ref href="/us/pl/99/239/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 99–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1901">section 1901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idcfbca218-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/99/658/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 99–658</ref>. Subsec. (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/658/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 99–658</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1905">section 1905 of this title</ref>. Subsec. (j)(1) and (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/658/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 99–658</ref> amended sections 460ff–3 and 460ff–5 of Title 16, Conservation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcfbca219-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/181">Pub. L. 110–181</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/219">Pub. L. 101–219</ref> amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) read as follows: “Neither the Secretary of the Treasury nor any other officer or agent of the United States shall pay or transfer any portion of the sums and amounts payable to the Government of Palau pursuant to this joint resolution to any party other than the Government of Palau. The provisions of section 174(a) of the Compact shall apply with respect to any action based on a contract or debt related to any electrical generating plant or related facilities entered into or incurred by Palau prior to the date of enactment of this joint resolution.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcfbca21a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idcfbca21b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Natural Resources of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Third Congress, <date date="1993-01-05">Jan. 5, 1993</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
