<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfc63f47-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2123"><num value="2123">§ 2123.</num><heading> Executive Director and staff of Oversight Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f48-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2123/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Executive Director</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board shall have an Executive Director who shall be appointed by the Chair with the consent of the Oversight Board. The Executive Director shall be paid at a rate determined by the Oversight Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f49-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2123/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With the approval of the Chair, the Executive Director may appoint and fix the pay of additional personnel as the Executive Director considers appropriate, except that no individual appointed by the Executive Director may be paid at a rate greater than the rate of pay for the Executive Director unless the Oversight Board provides for otherwise. The staff shall include a Revitalization Coordinator appointed pursuant to subchapter V of this chapter. Any such personnel may include private citizens, employees of the Federal Government, or employees of the territorial government, provided, however, that the Executive Director may not fix the pay of employees of the Federal Government or the territorial government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f4a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2123/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of certain employment and procurement laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Executive Director and staff of the Oversight Board may be appointed and paid without regard to any provision of the laws of the covered territory or the Federal Government governing appointments and salaries. Any provision of the laws of the covered territory governing procurement shall not apply to the Oversight Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f4b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2123/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff of Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request of the Chair, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, and in accordance with the Intergovernmental Personnel Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3371–337">5 U.S.C. 3371–337</ref>5), any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Oversight Board to assist it in carrying out its duties under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f4c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2123/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff of territorial government</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request of the Chair, the head of any department or agency of the covered territory may detail, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Oversight Board to assist it in carrying out its duties under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfc63f4d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/187/tI/s103">Pub. L. 114–187, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/557">130 Stat. 557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcfc63f4e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcfc63f4f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcfc63f50-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter V of this chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “Title V of this Act”, meaning title V of <ref href="/us/pl/114/187">Pub. L. 114–187</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/596">130 Stat. 596</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter V of this chapter. For complete classification of title V to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Intergovernmental Personnel Act of 1970, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/648">Pub. L. 91–648</ref>, <date date="1971-01-05">Jan. 5, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1909">84 Stat. 1909</ref>, which enacted sections 3371 to 3376 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and chapter 62 (§ 4701 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, amended <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1304">section 1304 of Title 5</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246">section 246 of Title 42</ref>, repealed sections 1881 to 1888 of Title 7, Agriculture, and <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s869b">section 869b of Title 20</ref>, Education, and enacted provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3371">section 3371 of Title 5</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4701">section 4701 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (d) and (e), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/114/187">Pub. L. 114–187</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/549">130 Stat. 549</ref>, known as the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act and also as PROMESA, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
