<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfc63f51-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124"><num value="2124">§ 2124.</num><heading> Powers of Oversight Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f52-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings and sessions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board may, for the purpose of carrying out this chapter, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Oversight Board considers appropriate. The Oversight Board may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before it.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f53-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Powers of members and agents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any member or agent of the Oversight Board may, if authorized by the Oversight Board, take any action that the Oversight Board is authorized to take by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f54-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Obtaining official data</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f55-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> From Federal government</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding sections 552 (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), 552a (commonly known as the Privacy Act of 1974), and 552b (commonly known as the Government in the Sunshine Act) of title 5, the Oversight Board may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable it to carry out this chapter, with the approval of the head of that department or agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f56-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> From territorial government</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Oversight Board shall have the right to secure copies, whether written or electronic, of such records, documents, information, data, or metadata from the territorial government necessary to enable the Oversight Board to carry out its responsibilities under this chapter. At the request of the Oversight Board, the Oversight Board shall be granted direct access to such information systems, records, documents, information, or data as will enable the Oversight Board to carry out its responsibilities under this chapter. The head of the entity of the territorial government responsible shall provide the Oversight Board with such information and assistance (including granting the Oversight Board direct access to automated or other information systems) as the Oversight Board requires under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f57-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Obtaining creditor information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc63f58-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon request of the Oversight Board, each creditor or organized group of creditors of a covered territory or covered territorial instrumentality seeking to participate in voluntary negotiations shall provide to the Oversight Board, and the Oversight Board shall make publicly available to any other participant, a statement setting forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc63f59-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the name and address of the creditor or of each member of an organized group of creditors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc63f5a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the nature and aggregate amount of claims or other economic interests held in relation to the issuer as of the later of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f5b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the date the creditor acquired the claims or other economic interests or, in the case of an organized group of creditors, the date the group was formed; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f5c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the date the Oversight Board was formed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc63f5d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, an organized group shall mean multiple creditors that are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f5e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> acting in concert to advance their common interests, including, but not limited to, retaining legal counsel to represent such multiple entities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f5f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not composed entirely of affiliates or insiders of one another.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc63f60-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Oversight Board may request supplemental statements to be filed by each creditor or organized group of creditors quarterly, or if any fact in the most recently filed statement has changed materially.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f61-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Gifts, bequests, and devises</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board may accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of services or property, both real and personal, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Oversight Board. Gifts, bequests, or devises of money and proceeds from sales of other property received as gifts, bequests, or devises shall be deposited in such account as the Oversight Board may establish and shall be available for disbursement upon order of the Chair, consistent with the Oversight Board’s bylaws, or rules and procedures. All gifts, bequests or devises and the identities of the donors shall be publicly disclosed by the Oversight Board within 30 days of receipt.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f62-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Subpoena power</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f63-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Oversight Board may issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, records, correspondence, memoranda, papers, documents, electronic files, metadata, tapes, and materials of any nature relating to any matter under investigation by the Oversight Board. Jurisdiction to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of such materials shall be governed by the statute setting forth the scope of personal jurisdiction exercised by the covered territory, or in the case of Puerto Rico, 32 L.P.R.A. App. III. R. 4. 7., as amended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f64-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to obey a subpoena</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a person refuses to obey a subpoena issued under paragraph (1), the Oversight Board may apply to the court of first instance of the covered territory. Any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court in accordance with civil contempt laws of the covered territory.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f65-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Service of subpoenas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The subpoena of the Oversight Board shall be served in the manner provided by the rules of procedure for the courts of the covered territory, or in the case of Puerto Rico, the Rules of Civil Procedure of Puerto Rico, for subpoenas issued by the court of first instance of the covered territory.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f66-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to enter into contracts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Executive Director may enter into such contracts as the Executive Director considers appropriate (subject to the approval of the Chair) consistent with the Oversight Board’s bylaws, rules, and regulations to carry out the Oversight Board’s responsibilities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f67-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to enforce certain laws of the covered territory</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board shall ensure the purposes of this chapter are met, including by ensuring the prompt enforcement of any applicable laws of the covered territory prohibiting public sector employees from participating in a strike or lockout. In the application of this subsection, with respect to Puerto Rico, the term “applicable laws” refers to 3 L.P.R.A. 1451q and 3 L.P.R.A. 1451r, as amended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f68-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Voluntary agreement certification</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f69-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Oversight Board shall issue a certification to a covered territory or covered territorial instrumentality if the Oversight Board determines, in its sole discretion, that such covered territory or covered territorial instrumentality, as applicable, has successfully reached a voluntary agreement with holders of its Bond Claims to restructure such Bond Claims—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f6a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> except as provided in subparagraph (C), if an applicable Fiscal Plan has been certified, in a manner that provides for a sustainable level of debt for such covered territory or covered territorial instrumentality, as applicable, and is in conformance with the applicable certified Fiscal Plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f6b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> except as provided in subparagraph (C), if an applicable Fiscal Plan has not yet been certified, in a manner that provides, in the Oversight Board’s sole discretion, for a sustainable level of debt for such covered territory or covered territorial instrumentality; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f6c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> notwithstanding subparagraphs (A) and (B), if an applicable Fiscal Plan has not yet been certified and the voluntary agreement is limited solely to an extension of applicable principal maturities and interest on Bonds issued by such covered territory or covered territorial instrumentality, as applicable, for a period of up to one year during which time no interest will be paid on the Bond Claims affected by the voluntary agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f6d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effectiveness</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The effectiveness of any voluntary agreement referred to in paragraph (1) shall be conditioned on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f6e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Oversight Board delivering the certification described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f6f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the agreement of a majority in amount of the Bond Claims of a covered territory or a covered territorial instrumentality that are to be affected by such agreement, provided, however, that such agreement is solely for purposes of serving as a Qualifying Modification pursuant to subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002050">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002050"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> 2231(g) of this title and shall not alter existing legal rights of holders of Bond Claims against such covered territory or covered territorial instrumentality that have not assented to such agreement until an order approving the Qualifying Modification has been entered pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2231/m/1/D">section 2231(m)(1)(D) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f70-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Preexisting voluntary agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any voluntary agreement that the territorial government or any territorial instrumentality has executed before <date date="2016-05-18">May 18, 2016</date>, with holders of a majority in amount of Bond Claims that are to be affected by such agreement to restructure such Bond Claims shall be deemed to be in conformance with the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f71-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Restructuring filings</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f72-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (3), before taking an action described in paragraph (2) on behalf of a debtor or potential debtor in a case under subchapter III, the Oversight Board must certify the action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f73-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions described</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The actions referred to in paragraph (1) are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f74-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the filing of a petition; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63f75-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the submission or modification of a plan of adjustment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f76-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Condition for plans of adjustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Oversight Board may certify a plan of adjustment only if it determines, in its sole discretion, that it is consistent with the applicable certified Fiscal Plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f77-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil actions to enforce powers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board may seek judicial enforcement of its authority to carry out its responsibilities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f78-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f79-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/l/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Acts prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any officer or employee of the territorial government who prepares, presents, or certifies any information or report for the Oversight Board or any of its agents that is intentionally false or misleading, or, upon learning that any such information is false or misleading, fails to immediately advise the Oversight Board or its agents thereof in writing, shall be subject to prosecution and penalties under any laws of the territory prohibiting the provision of false information to government officials, which in the case of Puerto Rico shall include 33 L.P.R.A. 4889, as amended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f7a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/l/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative discipline</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to any other applicable penalty, any officer or employee of the territorial government who knowingly and willfully violates paragraph (1) or takes any such action in violation of any valid order of the Oversight Board or fails or refuses to take any action required by any such order, shall be subject to appropriate administrative discipline, including (when appropriate) suspension from duty without pay or removal from office, by order of the Governor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f7b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/l/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Report by Governor on disciplinary actions taken</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a violation of paragraph (2) by an officer or employee of the territorial government, the Governor shall immediately report to the Oversight Board all pertinent facts together with a statement of the action taken thereon.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f7c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Electronic reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board may, in consultation with the Governor, ensure the prompt and efficient payment and administration of taxes through the adoption of electronic reporting, payment and auditing technologies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f7d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative support services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the request of the Oversight Board, the Administrator of General Services or other appropriate Federal agencies shall promptly provide to the Oversight Board, on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Oversight Board to carry out its responsibilities under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f7e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigation of disclosure and selling practices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board may investigate the disclosure and selling practices in connection with the purchase of bonds issued by a covered territory for or on behalf of any retail investors including any underrepresentation of risk for such investors and any relationships or conflicts of interest maintained by such broker, dealer, or investment adviser is as provided in applicable laws and regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f7f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2124/p"><num value="p" class="bold">(p)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings of any investigation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board shall make public the findings of any investigation referenced in subsection (<i>o</i>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfc63f80-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/187/tI/s104">Pub. L. 114–187, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/558">130 Stat. 558</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcfc63f81-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcfc63f82-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcfc63f83-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (c), (g), (h), (k), and (n), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/114/187">Pub. L. 114–187</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/549">130 Stat. 549</ref>, known as the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act and also as PROMESA, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
