<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfc63f89-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2126"><num value="2126">§ 2126.</num><heading> Treatment of actions arising from chapter</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f8a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2126/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2124/f/2">section 2124(f)(2) of this title</ref> (relating to the issuance of an order enforcing a subpoena), and subchapter III (relating to adjustments of debts), any action against the Oversight Board, and any action otherwise arising out of this chapter, in whole or in part, shall be brought in a United States district court for the covered territory or, for any covered territory that does not have a district court, in the United States District Court for the District of Hawaii.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f8b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2126/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appeal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any order of a United States district court that is issued pursuant to an action brought under subsection (a) shall be subject to review only pursuant to a notice of appeal to the applicable United States Court of Appeals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f8c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2126/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing of relief</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except with respect to any orders entered to remedy constitutional violations, no order of any court granting declaratory or injunctive relief against the Oversight Board, including relief permitting or requiring the obligation, borrowing, or expenditure of funds, shall take effect during the pendency of the action before such court, during the time appeal may be taken, or (if appeal is taken) during the period before the court has entered its final order disposing of such action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f8d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2126/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited consideration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the applicable United States District Court, the applicable United States Court of Appeals, and, as applicable, the Supreme Court of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any matter brought under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63f8e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2126/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of Oversight Board certifications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be no jurisdiction in any United States district court to review challenges to the Oversight Board’s certification determinations under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfc63f8f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/187/tI/s106">Pub. L. 114–187, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/562">130 Stat. 562</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcfc63f90-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcfc63f91-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcfc63f92-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (d), and (e), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/114/187">Pub. L. 114–187</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/549">130 Stat. 549</ref>, known as the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act and also as PROMESA, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
