<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfc63ff5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143"><num value="2143">§ 2143.</num><heading> Effect of finding of noncompliance with Budget</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63ff6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 15 days after the last day of each quarter of a fiscal year (beginning with the fiscal year determined by the Oversight Board), the Governor shall submit to the Oversight Board a report, in such form as the Oversight Board may require, describing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc63ff7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the actual cash revenues, cash expenditures, and cash flows of the territorial government for the preceding quarter, as compared to the projected revenues, expenditures, and cash flows contained in the certified Budget for such preceding quarter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc63ff8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any other information requested by the Oversight Board, which may include a balance sheet or a requirement that the Governor provide information for each covered territorial instrumentality separately.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63ff9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial action by Oversight Board</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63ffa-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Oversight Board determines, based on reports submitted by the Governor under subsection (a), independent audits, or such other information as the Oversight Board may obtain, that the actual quarterly revenues, expenditures, or cash flows of the territorial government are not consistent with the projected revenues, expenditures, or cash flows set forth in the certified Budget for such quarter, the Oversight Board shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63ffb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> require the territorial government to provide such additional information as the Oversight Board determines to be necessary to explain the inconsistency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc63ffc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the additional information provided under subparagraph (A) does not provide an explanation for the inconsistency that the Oversight Board finds reasonable and appropriate, advise the territorial government to correct the inconsistency by implementing remedial action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63ffd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadlines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Oversight Board shall establish the deadlines by which the territorial government shall meet the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63ffe-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc63fff-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Inconsistency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the territorial government fails to provide additional information under subsection (b)(1)(A), or fails to correct an inconsistency under subsection (b)(1)(B), prior to the applicable deadline under subsection (b)(2), the Oversight Board shall certify to the President, the House of Representatives Committee on Natural Resources, the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Governor, and the Legislature that the territorial government is inconsistent with the applicable certified Budget, and shall describe the nature and amount of the inconsistency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc64000-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Correction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Oversight Board determines that the territorial government has initiated such measures as the Oversight Board considers sufficient to correct an inconsistency certified under paragraph (1), the Oversight Board shall certify the correction to the President, the House of Representatives Committee on Natural Resources, the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Governor, and the Legislature.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc64001-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget reductions by Oversight Board</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Oversight Board determines that the Governor, in the case of any then-applicable certified Instrumentality Budgets, and the Governor and the Legislature, in the case of the then-applicable certified Territory Budget, have failed to correct an inconsistency identified by the Oversight Board under subsection (c), the Oversight Board shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc64002-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> with respect to the territorial government, other than covered territorial instrumentalities, make appropriate reductions in nondebt expenditures to ensure that the actual quarterly revenues and expenditures for the territorial government are in compliance with the applicable certified Territory Budget or, in the case of the fiscal year in which the Oversight Board is established, the budget adopted by the Governor and the Legislature; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc64003-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> with respect to covered territorial instrumentalities at the sole discretion of the Oversight Board—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc64004-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> make reductions in nondebt expenditures to ensure that the actual quarterly revenues and expenses for the covered territorial instrumentality are in compliance with the applicable certified Budget or, in the case of the fiscal year in which the Oversight Board is established, the budget adopted by the Governor and the Legislature or the covered territorial instrumentality, as applicable; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc64005-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc64006-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> institute automatic hiring freezes at the covered territorial instrumentality; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc64007-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> prohibit the covered territorial instrumentality from entering into any contract or engaging in any financial or other transactions, unless the contract or transaction was previously approved by the Oversight Board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc64008-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2143/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of Budget reductions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Oversight Board shall cancel the reductions, hiring freezes, or prohibition on contracts and financial transactions under subsection (d) if the Oversight Board determines that the territorial government or covered territorial instrumentality, as applicable, has initiated appropriate measures to reduce expenditures or increase revenues to ensure that the territorial government or covered territorial instrumentality is in compliance with the applicable certified Budget or, in the case of the fiscal year in which the Oversight Board is established, the budget adopted by the Governor and the Legislature.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfc888f9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/187/tII/s203">Pub. L. 114–187, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/568">130 Stat. 568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
