<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfc889a6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166"><num value="2166">§ 2166.</num><heading> Jurisdiction</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889a7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal subject matter jurisdiction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The district courts shall have—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc889a8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> except as provided in paragraph (2), original and exclusive jurisdiction of all cases under this subchapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc889a9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> except as provided in subsection (b), and notwithstanding any Act of Congress that confers exclusive jurisdiction on a court or courts other than the district courts, original but not exclusive jurisdiction of all civil proceedings arising under this subchapter, or arising in or related to cases under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889aa-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Property jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The district court in which a case under this subchapter is commenced or is pending shall have exclusive jurisdiction of all property, wherever located, of the debtor as of the commencement of the case.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889ab-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Personal jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The district court in which a case under this subchapter is pending shall have personal jurisdiction over any person or entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889ac-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal, remand, and transfer</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889ad-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Removal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A party may remove any claim or cause of action in a civil action, other than a proceeding before the United States Tax Court or a civil action by a governmental unit to enforce the police or regulatory power of the governmental unit, to the district court for the district in which the civil action is pending, if the district court has jurisdiction of the claim or cause of action under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889ae-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Remand</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The district court to which the claim or cause of action is removed under paragraph (1) may remand the claim or cause of action on any equitable ground. An order entered under this subsection remanding a claim or cause of action, or a decision not to remand, is not reviewable by appeal or otherwise by the court of appeals under section 158(d), 1291 or 1292 of title 28 or by the Supreme Court of the United States under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889af-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A district court shall transfer any civil proceeding arising under this subchapter, or arising in or related to a case under this subchapter, to the district court in which the case under this subchapter is pending.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889b0-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Appeal</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc889b1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An appeal shall be taken in the same manner as appeals in civil proceedings generally are taken to the courts of appeals from the district court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc889b2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The court of appeals for the circuit in which a case under this subchapter has venue pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2167">section 2167 of this title</ref> shall have jurisdiction of appeals from all final decisions, judgments, orders and decrees entered under this subchapter by the district court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc889b3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The court of appeals for the circuit in which a case under this subchapter has venue pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2167">section 2167 of this title</ref> shall have jurisdiction to hear appeals of interlocutory orders or decrees if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc889b4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the district court on its own motion or on the request of a party to the order or decree certifies that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc889b5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the order or decree involves a question of law as to which there is no controlling decision of the court of appeals for the circuit or of the Supreme Court of the United States, or involves a matter of public importance;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc889b6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the order or decree involves a question of law requiring the resolution of conflicting decisions; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfc889b7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an immediate appeal from the order or decree may materially advance the progress of the case or proceeding in which the appeal is taken; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfc889b8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the court of appeals authorizes the direct appeal of the order or decree.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc889b9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the district court on its own motion or on the request of a party determines that a circumstance specified in clauses (i), (ii), or (iii) of paragraph (3)(A) exists, then the district court shall make the certification described in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc889ba-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The parties may supplement the certification with a short statement of the basis for the certification issued by the district court under paragraph (3)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc889bb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s2164/d">section 2164(d) of this title</ref>, an appeal of an interlocutory order or decree does not stay any proceeding of the district court from which the appeal is taken unless the district court, or the court of appeals in which the appeal is pending, issues a stay of such proceedings pending the appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idcfc889bc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Any request for a certification in respect to an interlocutory appeal of an order or decree shall be made not later than 60 days after the entry of the order or decree.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfc889bd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2166/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reallocation of court staff</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, the clerk of the court in which a case is pending shall reallocate as many staff and assistants as the clerk deems necessary to ensure that the court has adequate resources to provide for proper case management.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfc889be-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/187/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 114–187, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/580">130 Stat. 580</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
