<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcfcd6af8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213"><num value="2213">§ 2213.</num><heading> Critical Projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6af9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of projects</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6afa-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Project submission</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any Project Sponsor may submit, so long as the Oversight Board is in operation, any existing, ongoing, or proposed project to the Revitalization Coordinator. The Revitalization Coordinator shall require such submission to include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6afb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the impact the project will have on an emergency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6afc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the availability of immediate private capital or other funds, including loan guarantees, loans, or grants to implement, operate, or maintain the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6afd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the cost of the project and amount of Puerto Rico government funds, if any, necessary to complete and maintain the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6afe-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the environmental and economic benefits provided by the project, including the number of jobs to be created that will be held by residents of Puerto Rico and the expected economic impact, including the impact on ratepayers, if applicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6aff-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the status of the project if it is existing or ongoing; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6b00-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> in addition to the requirements found in subparagraphs (A) through (E), the Revitalization Coordinator may require such submission to include any or all of the following criteria that assess how the project will—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcfcd6b01-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> reduce reliance on oil for electric generation in Puerto Rico;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcfcd6b02-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> improve performance of energy infrastructure and overall energy efficiency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcfcd6b03-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> expedite the diversification and conversion of fuel sources for electric generation from oil to natural gas and renewables in Puerto Rico as defined under applicable Puerto Rico laws;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcfcd6b04-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> promote the development and utilization of energy sources found on Puerto Rico;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcfcd6b05-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> contribute to transitioning to privatized generation capacities in Puerto Rico;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcfcd6b06-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> support the Energy Commission of Puerto Rico in achievement of its goal of reducing energy costs and ensuring affordable energy rates for consumers and business; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idcfcd6b07-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/1/F/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> achieve in whole or in part the recommendations, if feasible, of the study in <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s505/d">section 505(d) of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002063">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002063"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> to the extent such study is completed and not inconsistent with studies or plans otherwise required under Puerto Rico laws.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b08-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of relevant Puerto Rico Agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 20 days of receiving a project submission under paragraph (1), the Revitalization Coordinator shall, in consultation with the Governor, identify all Puerto Rico Agencies that will have a role in the permitting, approval, authorizing, or other activity related to the development of such project submission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b09-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited Permitting Process</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b0a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of Expedited Permitting Process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 20 days after receiving a project submission, each Puerto Rico Agency identified in paragraph (1) shall submit to the Revitalization Coordinator the Agency’s Expedited Permitting Process.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b0b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to provide Expedited Permitting Process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a Puerto Rico Agency fails to provide an Expedited Permitting Process within 20 days of receiving a project submission, the Revitalization Coordinator shall consult with the Governor to develop within 20 days an Expedited Permitting Process for the Agency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b0c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/a/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation and prioritization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Revitalization Coordinator shall require Puerto Rico Agencies to implement the Expedited Permitting Process for Critical Projects. Critical Projects shall be prioritized to the maximum extent possible in each Puerto Rico Agency regardless of any agreements transferring or delegating permitting authority to any other Territorial Instrumentality or municipality.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b0d-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Critical Project Report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b0e-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For each submitted project, the Revitalization Coordinator in consultation with the Governor and relevant Puerto Rico Agencies identified in subsection (a)(2) shall develop a Critical Project Report within 60 days of the project submission, which shall include:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6b0f-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An assessment of how well the project meets the criteria in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6b10-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A recommendation by the Governor whether the project should be considered a Critical Project. If the Governor fails to provide a recommendation during the development of the Critical Project Report, the failure shall constitute a concurrence with the Revitalization Coordinator’s recommendation in subparagraph (E).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6b11-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of a project that may affect the implementation of Land-Use Plans, as defined by Puerto Rico Act 550–2004, a determination by the Planning Board will be required within the 60-day timeframe. If the Planning Board determines such project will be inconsistent with relevant Land-Use Plans, then the project will be deemed ineligible for Critical Project designation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6b12-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> In the case of an Energy Project that will connect with the Puerto Rico Electric Power Authority’s transmission or distribution facilities, a recommendation by the Energy Commission of Puerto Rico, if the Energy Commission determines such Energy Project will affect an approved Integrated Resource Plan, as defined under Puerto Rico Act 54–2014. If the Energy Commission determines the Energy Project will adversely affect an approved Integrated Resource Plan, then the Energy Commission shall provide the reasons for such determination and the Energy Project shall be ineligible for Critical Project designation, provided that such determination must be made during the 60-day timeframe for the development of the Critical Project Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idcfcd6b13-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A recommendation by the Revitalization Coordinator whether the project should be considered a Critical Project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b14-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Public involvement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Immediately following the completion of the Critical Project Report, the Revitalization Coordinator shall make such Critical Project Report public and allow a period of 30 days for the submission of comments by residents of Puerto Rico specifically on matters relating to the designation of a project as a Critical Project. The Revitalization Coordinator shall respond to the comments within 30 days of closing the coming <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002064">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002064"><num>2</num> So in original.</note> period and make the responses publicly available.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b15-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission to Oversight Board</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 5 days after the Revitalization Coordinator has responded to the comments under paragraph (2), the Revitalization Coordinator shall submit the Critical Project Report to the Oversight Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idcfcd6b16-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Action by the Oversight Board</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after receiving the Critical Project Report, the Oversight Board, by majority vote, shall approve or disapprove the project as a Critical Project, if the Oversight Board—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfcd6b17-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> approves the project, the project shall be deemed a Critical Project; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idcfcd6b18-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s2213/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> disapproves the project, the Oversight Board shall submit to the Revitalization Coordinator in writing the reasons for disapproval.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idcfcd6b19-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/187/tV/s503">Pub. L. 114–187, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/598">130 Stat. 598</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcfcd6b1a-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcfcd6b1b-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcfcd6b1c-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t48/s505/d">Section 505(d) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(F)(vii), is <ref href="/us/pl/114/187/tV/s505/d">section 505(d) of title V of Pub. L. 114–187</ref>, <date date="2016-06-30">June 30, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/602">130 Stat. 602</ref>, which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1492a">section 1492a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
