<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf5d43e1-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s644a"><num value="644a">§ 644a.</num><heading> Jurisdiction of district court of cases arising on or within Midway, Wake, Johnston, Sand, etc., Islands; laws applicable to jury trials</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The jurisdiction of the United States District Court for the District of Hawaii is extended to all civil and criminal cases arising on or within the Midway Islands, Wake Island, Johnston Island, Sand Island, Kingman Reef, Palmyra Island, Baker Island, Howland Island, Jarvis Island, and, having regard to the special status of Canton and Enderbury Islands pursuant to an agreement of <date date="1939-04-06">April 6, 1939</date>, between the Governments of the United States and of the United Kingdom to set up a regime for their use in common, the said jurisdiction is also extended to all civil and criminal cases arising on or within Canton Island and Enderbury Island: <i>Provided</i>, That such extension to Canton and Enderbury Islands shall in no way be construed to be prejudicial to the claims of the United Kingdom to said islands in accordance with the agreement. All civil acts and deeds consummated and taking place on any of these islands or in the waters adjacent thereto, and all offenses and crimes committed thereon, or on or in the waters adjacent thereto, shall be deemed to have been consummated or committed on the high seas on board a merchant vessel or other vessel belonging to the United States and shall be adjudicated and determined or adjudged and punished according to the laws of the United States relating to such civil acts or offenses on such ships or vessels on the high seas, which laws for the purpose aforesaid are extended over such islands, rocks, and keys.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The laws of the United States relating to juries and jury trials shall be applicable to the trial of such cases before said district court.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idcf5d43e2-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-06-15/ch253">June 15, 1950, ch. 253</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/217">64 Stat. 217</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/3/s14/j">Pub. L. 86–3, § 14(j)</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/11">73 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/624/s19">Pub. L. 86–624, § 19</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/416">74 Stat. 416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf5d43e3-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf5d43e4-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf5d43e5-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/624">Pub. L. 86–624</ref> struck out Kure Island.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref> extended jurisdiction to cases arising on or within Palmyra Island.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf5d43e6-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idcf5d43e7-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1959 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref> effective on admission of the State of Hawaii into the Union, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s91">section 91 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure. Admission of Hawaii into the Union was accomplished <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3309, <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, 25 F.R. 6868, 73 Stat. c74, as required by sections 1 and 7(c) of <ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/4">73 Stat. 4</ref>, set out as notes preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s491">section 491 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf5d43e8-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Canton and Enderbury Islands; Sovereignty of Kiribati</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By a treaty of friendship, TIAS 10777, which entered into force <date date="1983-09-23">Sept. 23, 1983</date>, the United States recognized the sovereignty of Kiribati over Canton Island and Enderbury Island.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
