<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idcf646ff9-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0" identifier="/us/usc/t48/s910"><num value="910">§ 910.</num><heading> Slum clearance and urban redevelopment and renewal projects; powers of government</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The government of Puerto Rico acting through its legislature, may create a public corporate authority or authorities and may authorize such authority or authorities or any other public corporate authority or any municipal corporation or political subdivision, acting directly or through any officer or agency thereof or through a public corporate authority, to undertake slum clearance and urban redevelopment projects and urban renewal projects and to do all things, exercise any and all powers, and to assume and fulfill any and all obligations, duties, responsibilities, and requirements, including but not limited to those relating to planning and zoning, necessary or desirable for receiving Federal assistance under title I of the Housing Act of 1949 (Public Law 171, Eighty-first Congress), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1450">42 U.S.C. 1450</ref> et seq.], or any other law, except that public corporate authorities (as distinct from municipalities or political subdivisions) created or authorized to operate in accordance with this Act, as amended, shall not be given any power of taxation or any power to pledge the full faith and credit of the people of the Territory, or municipality, or political subdivision, as the case may be, for any loan whatever. The Legislature of Puerto Rico may, with respect to any public corporate authority or authorities empowered or which may be empowered to undertake slum clearance and urban redevelopment projects and urban renewal projects, provide for the appointment and terms of office of the members thereof, and for the powers of such authorities, including authority to accept whatever benefits the Federal Government may make available for slum clearance and urban redevelopment projects and urban renewal projects, and authority, notwithstanding any other Federal law, to borrow money and to issue notes, bonds, and other obligations of such character and maturity, with such security, and in such manner as the respective legislatures may provide. Such notes, bonds, and other obligations shall not be a debt of the United States, or of any Territory or municipal corporation or other political subdivision or agency thereof other than the public corporate authority which issued such notes, bonds, or obligations, nor constitute a debt, indebtedness, or the borrowing of money within the meaning of any limitation or restriction on the issuance of notes, bonds, or other obligations contained in any laws of the United States applicable to Puerto Rico, or to any municipal corporation or other political subdivision or agency thereof.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idcf646ffa-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-07-18/ch466">July 18, 1950, ch. 466</ref>, title I, § 101, <ref href="/us/stat/64/344">64 Stat. 344</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch783">Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 783</ref>, title I, § 107(3), (7), (9), <ref href="/us/stat/69/637">69 Stat. 637</ref>, 638.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idcf646ffb-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idcf646ffc-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idcf646ffd-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Housing Act of 1949 (Public Law 171, Eighty-first Congress), as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">act July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/413">63 Stat. 413</ref>. Title I of the Housing Act of 1949 was classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1450 et seq.) of chapter 8A of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and was omitted from the Code pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5316">section 5316 of Title 42</ref> which terminated the authority to make grants or loans under such title I after <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">section 1441 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means <ref href="/us/act/1950-07-18/ch466">act July 18, 1950, ch. 466</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/344">64 Stat. 344</ref>, known as the Territorial Enabling Act of 1950, which enacted sections 480 to 480b, 483a, 483b, 721 to 721b, 910 to 910b, 1408 to 1408e of this title, amended sections 481 to 483 and 722 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 480, 481, and 722 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idcf646ffe-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Puerto Rican Federal Relations Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 101 of act <date date="1950-07-18">July 18, 1950</date>, cited as a credit to this section, as applicable to Alaska and Hawaii, was classified to sections 480 and 721 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idcf646fff-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Act <date date="1955-08-11">Aug. 11, 1955</date>, included urban renewal projects, and inserted “as amended” after “(Public Law 171, Eighty-first Congress)” and after “this Act”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idcf647000-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idcf647001-3a70-11f1-9e44-df1065572ea0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Urban Renewal Activities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Financial assistance available for urban renewal proj­ects, see section 107(1), (2) of act <date date="1955-08-11">Aug. 11, 1955</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
