<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbccf2545-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310"><num value="310">§ 310.</num><heading> Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbccf2546-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network established by order of the Secretary of the Treasury (Treasury Order Numbered 105–08, in this section referred to as “FinCEN”) on <date date="1990-04-25">April 25, 1990</date>, shall be a bureau in the Department of the Treasury.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbccf2547-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19648-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading><content>The head of FinCEN shall be the Director, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19649-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties and powers</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The duties and powers of the Director are as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1964a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Advise and make recommendations on matters relating to financial intelligence, financial criminal activities, and other financial activities to the Under Secretary of the Treasury for Enforcement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1964b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Maintain a government-wide data access service, with access, in accordance with applicable legal requirements, to the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1964c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Information collected by the Department of the Treasury, including report information filed under subchapter II of chapter 53 of this title (such as reports on cash transactions, foreign financial agency transactions and relationships, foreign currency transactions, exporting and importing monetary instruments, and suspicious activities), chapter 2 of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</ref>, and section 21 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1964d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Information regarding national and international currency flows.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1964e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Other records and data maintained by other Federal, State, local, and foreign agencies, including financial and other records developed in specific cases.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1964f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Other privately and publicly available information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19650-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Analyze and disseminate the available data in accordance with applicable legal requirements and policies and guidelines established by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Under Secretary of the Treasury for Enforcement to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19651-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> identify possible criminal activity to appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and foreign law enforcement agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19652-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> support ongoing criminal financial investigations and prosecutions and related proceedings, including civil and criminal tax and forfeiture proceedings;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19653-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> identify possible instances of noncompliance with subchapter II of chapter 53 of this title, chapter 2 of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</ref>, and section 21 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to Federal agencies with statutory responsibility for enforcing compliance with such provisions and other appropriate Federal regulatory agencies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19654-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> evaluate and recommend possible uses of special currency reporting requirements under section 5326;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19655-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> determine emerging trends and methods in money laundering and other financial crimes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19656-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> support the conduct of intelligence or counterintelligence activities, including analysis, to protect against terrorism; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19657-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> support government initiatives against money laundering.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19658-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Establish and maintain a financial crimes communications center to furnish law enforcement authorities with intelligence information related to emerging or ongoing investigations and undercover operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19659-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Furnish research, analytical, and informational services to financial institutions, appropriate Federal regulatory agencies with regard to financial institutions, and appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and foreign law enforcement authorities, in accordance with policies and guidelines established by the Secretary of the Treasury or the Under Secretary of the Treasury for Enforcement, in the interest of detection, prevention, and prosecution of terrorism, organized crime, money laundering, and other financial crimes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1965a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Assist Federal, State, local, Tribal, and foreign law enforcement and regulatory authorities in combatting the use of informal, nonbank networks and payment and barter system mechanisms that permit the transfer of funds or the equivalent of funds without records and without compliance with criminal and tax laws.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1965b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Provide computer and data support and data analysis to the Secretary of the Treasury for tracking and controlling foreign assets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1965c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Coordinate with financial intelligence units in other countries on anti-terrorism and anti-money laundering initiatives, and similar efforts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1965d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Administer the requirements of subchapter II of chapter 53 of this title, chapter 2 of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</ref>, and section 21 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, to the extent delegated such authority by the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1965e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> Promulgate regulations under section 5318(h)(4)(D), as appropriate, to implement the government-wide anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism priorities established by the Secretary of the Treasury under section 5318(h)(4)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1965f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> Communicate regularly with financial institutions and Federal functional regulators that examine financial institutions for compliance with subchapter II of chapter 53 and regulations promulgated under that subchapter and law enforcement authorities to explain the United States Government’s anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism priorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19660-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> Give and receive feedback to and from financial institutions, State bank supervisors, and State credit union supervisors (as those terms are defined in section 6003 of the Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020) regarding the matters addressed in subchapter II of chapter 53 and regulations promulgated under that subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19661-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> Maintain money laundering and terrorist financing investigation financial experts capable of identifying, tracking, and analyzing financial crime networks and identifying emerging threats to support Federal civil and criminal investigations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19662-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/N"><num value="N">(N)</num><content> Maintain emerging technology experts to encourage the development of and identify emerging technologies that can assist the United States Government or financial institutions in countering money laundering and the financing of terrorism.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19663-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/b/2/O"><num value="O">(O)</num><content> Such other duties and powers as the Secretary of the Treasury may delegate or prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd19664-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements Relating to Maintenance and Use of Data Banks</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish and maintain operating procedures with respect to the government-wide data access service and the financial crimes communications center maintained by FinCEN which provide—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19665-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> for the coordinated and efficient transmittal of information to, entry of information into, and withdrawal of information from, the data maintenance system maintained by FinCEN, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19666-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the submission of reports through the Internet or other secure network, whenever possible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19667-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the cataloguing of information in a manner that facilitates rapid retrieval by law enforcement personnel of meaningful data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19668-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a procedure that provides for a prompt initial review of suspicious activity reports and other reports, or such other means as the Secretary may provide, to identify information that warrants immediate action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19669-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of title 5</ref> and the Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978, appropriate standards and guidelines for determining—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1966a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who is to be given access to the information maintained by FinCEN;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1966b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> what limits are to be imposed on the use of such information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1966c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> how information about activities or relationships which involve or are closely associated with the exercise of constitutional rights is to be screened out of the data maintenance system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd1966d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FinCEN Exchange.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd1966e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The FinCEN Exchange is hereby established within FinCEN.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd1966f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The FinCEN Exchange shall facilitate a voluntary public-private information sharing partnership among law enforcement agencies, national security agencies, financial institutions, other relevant private sector entities, and FinCEN to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19670-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> effectively and efficiently combat money laundering, terrorism financing, organized crime, and other financial crimes, including by promoting innovation and technical advances in reporting—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19671-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> under subchapter II of chapter 53 and the regulations promulgated under that subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19672-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> with respect to other anti-money laundering requirements;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19673-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> protect the financial system from illicit use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19674-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> promote national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19675-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19676-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, and once every 2 years thereafter for the next 5 years, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report containing—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19677-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> an analysis of the efforts undertaken by the FinCEN Exchange, which shall include an analysis of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbcd19678-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the results of those efforts; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbcd19679-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the extent and effectiveness of those efforts, including any benefits realized by law enforcement agencies from partnering with financial institutions and other relevant private sector entities, which shall be consistent with standards protecting sensitive information; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1967a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any legislative, administrative, or other recommendations the Secretary may have to strengthen the efforts of the FinCEN Exchange.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1967b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Classified annex</inline>.—</heading><content>Each report under subparagraph (A) may include a classified annex.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd1967c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information sharing requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Information shared under this subsection shall be shared—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1967d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in compliance with all other applicable Federal laws and regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1967e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in such a manner as to ensure the appropriate confidentiality of personal information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1967f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> at the discretion of the Director, with the appropriate Federal functional regulator, as defined in section 6003 of the Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19680-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protection of shared information.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19681-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>FinCEN shall, as appropriate, promulgate regulations that establish procedures for the protection of information shared and exchanged between FinCEN and the private sector in accordance with this section, consistent with the capacity, size, and nature of the financial institution or other relevant private sector entity to which the particular procedures apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19682-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of information.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19683-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use by financial institutions</inline>.—</heading><content>Information received by a financial institution pursuant to this section shall not be used for any purpose other than identifying and reporting on activities that may involve the financing of terrorism, money laundering, proliferation financing, or other financial crimes.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19684-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use by other relevant private sector entities</inline>.—</heading><content>Information received by a relevant private sector entity that is not a financial institution pursuant to this section shall not be used for any purpose other than assisting a financial institution in identifying and reporting on activities that may involve the financing of terrorism, money laundering, proliferation financing, or other financial crimes, or in assisting FinCEN or another agency of the Federal Government in mitigating the risk of the financing of terrorism, money laundering, proliferation financing, or other criminal activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19685-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to create new information sharing authorities or requirements relating to the Bank Secrecy Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd19686-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Hiring Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19687-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Treasury may appoint, without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3318 of title 5, candidates directly to positions in the competitive service, as defined in section 2102 of that title, in FinCEN.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19688-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Primary responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><content>The primary responsibility of candidates appointed under paragraph (1) shall be to provide substantive support in support of the duties described in subparagraphs (A) through (O) of subsection (b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd19689-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FinCEN Domestic Liaisons.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd1968a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of office</inline>.—</heading><content>There is established in FinCEN an Office of Domestic Liaison, which shall be headed by the Chief Domestic Liaison.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd1968b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Location</inline>.—</heading><content>The Office of the Domestic Liaison shall be located in the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd1968c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Chief Domestic Liaison.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd1968d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Chief Domestic Liaison, shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1968e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> report directly to the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1968f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be appointed by the Director, from among individuals with experience or familiarity with anti-money laundering program examinations, supervision, and enforcement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19690-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading><content>The annual rate of pay for the Chief Domestic Liaison shall be equal to the highest rate of annual pay for similarly situated senior executives who report to the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19691-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Staff of office</inline>.—</heading><content>The Chief Domestic Liaison, with the concurrence of the Director, may retain or employ counsel, research staff, and service staff, as the Liaison determines necessary to carry out the functions, powers, and duties under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19692-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Domestic liaisons</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Chief Domestic Liaison, with the concurrence of the Director, shall appoint not fewer than 6 senior FinCEN employees as FinCEN Domestic Liaisons, who shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19693-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> report to the Chief Domestic Liaison;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19694-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> each be assigned to focus on a specific region of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19695-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> be located at an office in such region or co-located at an office of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System in such region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd19696-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Functions of the domestic liaisons.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd19697-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each Domestic Liaison shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19698-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in coordination with relevant Federal functional regulators, perform outreach to BSA officers at financial institutions, including nonbank financial institutions, and persons that are not financial institutions, especially with respect to actions taken by FinCEN that require specific actions by, or have specific effects on, such institutions or persons, as determined by the Director;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd19699-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in accordance with applicable agreements, receive feedback from financial institutions and examiners of Federal functional regulators regarding their examinations under the Bank Secrecy Act and communicate that feedback to FinCEN, the Federal functional regulators, and State bank supervisors;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1969a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> promote coordination and consistency of supervisory guidance from FinCEN, the Federal functional regulators, State bank supervisors, and State credit union supervisors regarding the Bank Secrecy Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1969b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> act as a liaison between financial institutions and their Federal functional regulators, State bank supervisors, and State credit union supervisors with respect to information sharing matters involving the Bank Secrecy Act and regulations promulgated thereunder;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1969c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> establish safeguards to maintain the confidentiality of communications between the persons described in clause (ii) and the Office of Domestic Liaison;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1969d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> to the extent practicable, periodically propose to the Director changes in the regulations, guidance, or orders of FinCEN, including any legislative or administrative changes that may be appropriate to ensure improved coordination and expand information sharing under this paragraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd1969e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> perform such other duties as the Director determines to be appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd1969f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to permit the Domestic Liaisons to have authority over supervision, examination, or enforcement processes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd196a0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Access to documents</inline>.—</heading><content>FinCEN, to the extent practicable and consistent with appropriate safeguards for sensitive enforcement-related, pre-decisional, or deliberative information, shall ensure that the Domestic Liaisons have full access to the documents of FinCEN, as necessary to carry out the functions of the Office of Domestic Liaison.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd196a1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual reports.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd196a2-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection and every 2 years thereafter for 5 years, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the objectives of the Office of Domestic Liaison for the following fiscal year and the activities of the Office during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd196a3-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report required under subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd196a4-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> appropriate statistical information and full and substantive analysis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd196a5-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> information on steps that the Office of Domestic Liaison has taken during the reporting period to address feedback received by financial institutions and examiners of Federal functional regulators relating to examinations under the Bank Secrecy Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3df96-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> recommendations to the Director for such administrative and legislative actions as may be appropriate to address information sharing and coordination issues encountered by financial institutions or examiners of Federal functional regulators; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3df97-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any other information, as determined appropriate by the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3df98-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sensitive information</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding subparagraph (D), FinCEN shall review each report required under subparagraph (A) before the report is submitted to ensure the report does not disclose sensitive information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3df99-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Independence.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3df9a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Each report required under subparagraph (A) shall be provided directly to the committees listed in that subparagraph, except that a relevant Federal functional regulator, State bank supervisor, Office of Management and Budget, or State credit union supervisor shall have an opportunity for review and comment before the submission of the report.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3df9b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in clause (i) may be construed to preclude FinCEN or any other department or agency from reviewing a report required under subparagraph (A) for the sole purpose of protecting—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbcd3df9c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> sensitive information obtained by a law enforcement agency; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idbcd3df9d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> classified information.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3df9e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/7/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Classified information</inline>.—</heading><content>No report required under subparagraph (A) may contain classified information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3df9f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/g/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term “Federal functional regulator” has the meaning given the term in section 6003 of the Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd3dfa0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FinCEN Foreign Financial Intelligence Unit Liaisons.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfa1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of FinCEN shall appoint not fewer than 6 Foreign Financial Intelligence Unit Liaisons, who shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa2-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be knowledgeable about domestic or international anti-money laundering or countering the financing of terrorism laws and regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa3-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> possess a technical understanding of the Bank Secrecy Act, the protocols of the Egmont Group of Financial Intelligence Units, and the Financial Action Task Force and the recommendations issued by that Task Force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa4-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> be co-located in a United States embassy, a similar United States Government facility, or a foreign government facility, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa5-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> facilitate capacity building and perform outreach with respect to anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism regulatory and analytical frameworks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa6-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> establish and maintain relationships with officials from foreign intelligence units, regulatory authorities, ministries of finance, central banks, law enforcement agencies, and other competent authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa7-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> participate in industry outreach engagements with foreign financial institutions and other commercial actors on anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism issues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa8-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> coordinate with representatives of the Department of Justice at United States Embassies who perform similar functions on behalf of the United States Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfa9-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> perform such other duties as the Director determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfaa-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each Foreign Financial Intelligence Unit Liaison appointed under paragraph (1) shall receive compensation at the higher of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfab-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the rate of compensation paid to a Foreign Service officer at a comparable career level serving at the same embassy or facility, as applicable; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfac-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the rate of compensation that the Liaison would have otherwise received.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd3dfad-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protection of Information Obtained by Foreign Law Enforcement and Financial Intelligence Units; Freedom of Information Act.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfae-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfaf-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “foreign anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism authority” means any foreign agency or authority that is empowered under foreign law to regulate or supervise foreign financial institutions (or designated non-financial businesses and professions) with respect to laws concerning anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism and proliferation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfb0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign financial intelligence unit</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “foreign financial intelligence unit” means any foreign agency or authority, including a foreign financial intelligence unit that is a member of the Egmont Group of Financial Intelligence Units, that is empowered under foreign law as a jurisdiction’s national center for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3dfb1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> receipt and analysis of suspicious transaction reports and other information relevant to money laundering, associated predicate offenses, and the financing of terrorism; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3dfb2-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the dissemination of the results of the analysis described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfb3-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign law enforcement authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “foreign law enforcement authority” means any foreign agency or authority that is empowered under foreign law to detect, investigate, or prosecute potential violations of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfb4-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information exchanged with foreign law enforcement authorities, foreign financial intelligence units, and foreign anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism authorities.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfb5-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Department of the Treasury may not be compelled to search for or disclose information exchanged with a foreign law enforcement authority, foreign financial intelligence unit, or foreign anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfb6-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of freedom of information act.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3dfb7-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content><ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/a/3">Section 552(a)(3) of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the “Freedom of Information Act”) shall not apply to any request for records or information exchanged between the Department of the Treasury and a foreign law enforcement authority, foreign financial intelligence unit, or foreign anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism authority.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3dfb8-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specifically exempted by statute</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, this paragraph shall be considered a statute described in subsection (b)(3)(B) of that section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfb9-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Clarification on information limitations and protections.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3dfba-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of this paragraph shall apply only to information necessary to exercise the duties and powers described under subsection (b).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbcd3dfbb-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate confidentiality, classification, and data security requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director, shall ensure that information provided to a foreign law enforcement authority, foreign financial intelligence unit, or foreign anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism authority, is subject to appropriate confidentiality, classification, and data security requirements.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfbc-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings provision</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall authorize the Department of the Treasury to withhold information from Congress, decline to carry out a search for information requested by Congress, or prevent the Department of the Treasury from complying with an order of a court of the United States in an action commenced by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd3dfbd-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Analytical Experts.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfbe-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>FinCEN shall maintain financial experts capable of identifying, tracking, and tracing money laundering and terrorist-financing networks in order to conduct and support civil and criminal anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism investigations conducted by the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfbf-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">FinCEN analytical hub</inline>.—</heading><content>FinCEN, upon a reasonable request from a Federal agency, shall, in collaboration with the requesting agency and the appropriate Federal functional regulator, analyze the potential anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism activity that prompted the request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd3dfc0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfc1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bank secrecy act</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Bank Secrecy Act” has the meaning given the term in section 6003 of the Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfc2-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal functional regulator</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “Federal functional regulator” has the meaning given the term in section 509 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s6809">15 U.S.C. 6809</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfc3-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Financial institution</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “financial institution” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s5312">section 5312 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfc4-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State bank supervisor</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “State bank supervisor” has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfc5-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/k/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State credit union supervisor</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “State credit union supervisor” means a State official described in section 107A(e) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1757a/e">12 U.S.C. 1757a(e)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcd3dfc6-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfc7-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>There are authorized to be appropriated to FinCEN to carry out this section, to remain available until expended—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfc8-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> $136,000,000 for fiscal year 2021;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfc9-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2022; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfca-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbcd3dfcb-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization for funding key technological improvements in mission-critical fincen systems</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>There are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2005 the following amounts, which are authorized to remain available until expended:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfcc-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> BSA <inline class="small-caps">direct</inline>.—</heading><content>For technological improvements to provide authorized law enforcement and financial regulatory agencies with Web-based access to FinCEN data, to fully develop and implement the highly secure network required under <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s362">section 362 of Public Law 107–56</ref> to expedite the filing of, and reduce the filing costs for, financial institution reports, including suspicious activity reports, collected by FinCEN under chapter 53 and related provisions of law, and enable FinCEN to immediately alert financial institutions about suspicious activities that warrant immediate and enhanced scrutiny, and to provide and upgrade advanced information-sharing technologies to materially improve the Government’s ability to exploit the information in the FinCEN data banks, $16,500,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfcd-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advanced analytical technologies</inline>.—</heading><content>To provide advanced analytical tools needed to ensure that the data collected by FinCEN under chapter 53 and related provisions of law are utilized fully and appropriately in safeguarding financial institutions and supporting the war on terrorism, $5,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfce-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Data networking modernization</inline>.—</heading><content>To improve the telecommunications infrastructure to support the improved capabilities of the FinCEN systems, $3,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfcf-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enhanced compliance capability</inline>.—</heading><content>To improve the effectiveness of the Office of Compliance in FinCEN, $3,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbcd3dfd0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s310/l/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Detection and prevention of financial crimes and terrorism</inline>.—</heading><content>To provide development of, and training in the use of, technology to detect and prevent financial crimes and terrorism within and without the United States, $8,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcd3dfd1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tIII/s361/a/2">Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 361(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/329">115 Stat. 329</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVI">Pub. L. 108–458, title VI</ref>, §§ 6101, 6203(a), <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3744">118 Stat. 3744</ref>, 3746; <ref href="/us/pl/111/195/tI/s109/c">Pub. L. 111–195, title I, § 109(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-01">July 1, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1338">124 Stat. 1338</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dF/tLXI">Pub. L. 116–283, div. F, title LXI</ref>, §§ 6101(c), 6102(b), 6103, 6105(a), 6107–6109(a), title LXIII, § 6304, title LXV, § 6509(a), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4551-4553">134 Stat. 4551–4553</ref>, 4555, 4557–4560, 4586, 4633; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dF/tLXI/s6101">Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXI, § 6101</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2382">135 Stat. 2382</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcd3dfd2-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcd3dfd3-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbcd3dfd4-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 2 of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(B)(i), (C)(iii), (I), is chapter 2 (§§ 121–129) of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Pub. L. 91–508</ref>, <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1116">84 Stat. 1116</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 21 (§ 1951 et seq.) of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of chapter 2 to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 21 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(B)(i), (C)(iii), (I), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1829b">section 1829b of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 6003 of the Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2)(L), (d)(4)(C), (g)(8), and (k)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6003">section 6003 of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s5311">section 5311 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is title XI of <ref href="/us/pl/95/630">Pub. L. 95–630</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3697">92 Stat. 3697</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 35 (§ 3401 et seq.) of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3401">section 3401 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s362">Section 362 of Public Law 107–56</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(A), is set out as a note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this subsection, referred to in subsecs. (d)(3)(A) and (g)(7)(A), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, which was approved <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbcd3dfd5-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 310 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s315">section 315 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcd3dfd6-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(2)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6102/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6102(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “Tribal,” after “local,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6102/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6102(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “international” before “terrorism”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(E), (F). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6102/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6102(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “Tribal,” after “local,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(J) to (O). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6101/c">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6101(c)</ref>, added subpars. (J) to (N) and redesignated former subpar. (J) as (O).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6103/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6103(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6101/1">Pub. L. 117–81, § 6101(1)</ref>, inserted “other relevant private sector entities,” after “financial institutions,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6101/2">Pub. L. 117–81, § 6101(2)</ref>, inserted “and other relevant private sector entities” after “financial institutions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6101/3/A">Pub. L. 117–81, § 6101(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “or other relevant private sector entity” after “financial institution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6101/3/B">Pub. L. 117–81, § 6101(3)(B)</ref>, designated existing provisions as cl. (i), inserted cl. (i) heading, and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6105/a">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6105(a)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6107">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6107</ref>, added subsecs. (f) and (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6108">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6108</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6109/a">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6109(a)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j), (k). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6304">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6304</ref>, added subsecs. (j) and (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6103/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6103(1)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (d) as (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6509/a">Pub. L. 116–283, § 6509(a)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “There are authorized to be appropriated for FinCEN $100,419,000 for fiscal year 2011 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2012 and 2013.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/195">Pub. L. 111–195</ref> substituted “$100,419,000 for fiscal year 2011 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2012 and 2013” for “such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2002, 2003, 2004, and 2005”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (c)(1), (2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s6203/a">Pub. L. 108–458, § 6203(a)</ref>, substituted “FinCEN” for “the Network”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s6101">Pub. L. 108–458, § 6101</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. heading, and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcd3dfd7-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcd3dfd8-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s6203/a">section 6203(a) of Pub. L. 108–458</ref> effective as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/56">Pub. L. 107–56</ref>, as of the date of enactment of such Act, and no amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/107/56">Pub. L. 107–56</ref> that is inconsistent with such amendment to be deemed to have taken effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s6205">section 6205 of Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1828">section 1828 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbcd3dfd9-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assessment of Bank Secrecy Act No-Action Letters</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dF/tLXIII/s6305">Pub. L. 116–283, div. F, title LXIII, § 6305</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4587">134 Stat. 4587</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dF/tLXIII/s6305">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director [probably means Director of FinCEN], in consultation with the Attorney General, the Federal functional regulators, State bank supervisors, State credit union supervisors, and other Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall conduct an assessment on whether to establish a process for the issuance of no-action letters by FinCEN [Financial Crimes Enforcement Network of the Department of the Treasury] in response to inquiries from persons concerning the application of the Bank Secrecy Act, the USA PATRIOT Act (<ref href="/us/pl/107/56">Public Law 107–56</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/115/272">115 Stat. 272</ref>), section 8(s) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1818/s">12 U.S.C. 1818(s)</ref>), or any other anti-money laundering or countering the financing of terrorism law (including regulations) to specific conduct, including a request for a statement as to whether FinCEN or any relevant Federal functional regulator intends to take an enforcement action against the person with respect to such conduct.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Analysis</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The assessment required under paragraph (1) shall include an analysis of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a timeline for the process used to reach a final determination by FinCEN, in consultation with the relevant Federal functional regulators, in response to a request by a person for a no-action letter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> whether improvements in current processes are necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> whether a formal no-action letter process would help to mitigate or accentuate illicit finance risks in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> any other matter the Secretary determines is appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report and Rulemakings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the Secretary [of the Treasury], in coordination with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Federal functional regulators, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report that contains all findings and determinations made in carrying out the assessment required under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> propose rulemakings, if appropriate, to implement the findings and determinations described in paragraph (1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “Federal functional regulator” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6305">section 6305 of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s6003">section 6003 of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a Definitions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s5311">section 5311 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbcd3dfda-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Highly Secure Network</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tIII/s362">Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 362</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/332">115 Stat. 332</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVI/s6202/m">Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6202(m)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3746">118 Stat. 3746</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tVI/s6202/m">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary [of the Treasury] shall establish a highly secure network in the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> allows financial institutions to file reports required under subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31, United States Code, chapter 2 of <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</ref> [probably means chapter 2 (§§ 121 to 129) of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/91/508">Pub. L. 91–508</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1951">12 U.S.C. 1951</ref> et seq.)], or section 21 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1829b">12 U.S.C. 1829b</ref>] through the secure network; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> provides financial institutions with alerts and other information regarding suspicious activities that warrant immediate and enhanced scrutiny.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited Development</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall take such action as may be necessary to ensure that the secure network required under subsection (a) is fully operational before the end of the 9-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
