<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd2e8384-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515"><num value="3515">§ 3515.</num><heading> Financial statements of agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e8385-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e8386-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002052">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002052"><num>1</num> So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted</note> Except as provided in subsection (e), not later than March 1 of 2003 and each year thereafter, the head of each covered executive agency shall prepare and submit to the Congress and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget an audited financial statement for the preceding fiscal year, covering all accounts and associated activities of each office, bureau, and activity of the agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e8387-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Each audited financial statement of a covered executive agency under this section shall reflect—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e8388-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the overall financial position of the offices, bureaus, and activities covered by the statement, including assets and liabilities thereof; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e8389-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> results of operations of those offices, bureaus, and activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e838a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall identify components of covered executive agencies that shall be required to have audited financial statements meeting the requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e838b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall prescribe the form and content of the financial statements of covered executive agencies under this section, consistent with applicable accounting and financial reporting principles, standards, and requirements.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e838c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e838d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may exempt a covered executive agency, except an agency described in section 901(b), from the requirements of this section with respect to a fiscal year if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e838e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the total amount of budget authority available to the agency for the fiscal year does not exceed $25,000,000; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e838f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Director determines that requiring an annual audited financial statement for the agency with respect to the fiscal year is not warranted due to the absence of risks associated with the agency’s operations, the agency’s demonstrated performance, or other factors that the Director considers relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e8390-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director shall annually notify the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate of each agency the Director has exempted under this subsection and the reasons for each exemption.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e8391-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> The term “covered executive agency”—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e8392-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> means an executive agency that is not required by another provision of Federal law to prepare and submit to the Congress and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget an audited financial statement for each fiscal year, covering all accounts and associated activities of each office, bureau, and activity of the agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e8393-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3515/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> does not include a corporation, agency, or instrumentality subject to chapter 91 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd2e8394-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/576/tIII/s303/a/1">Pub. L. 101–576, title III, § 303(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2849">104 Stat. 2849</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/356/tIV/s405/a">Pub. L. 103–356, title IV, § 405(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3415">108 Stat. 3415</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/531/s4/a">Pub. L. 106–531, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-22">Nov. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2539">114 Stat. 2539</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/289/s2/a">Pub. L. 107–289, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2049">116 Stat. 2049</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd2e8395-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd2e8396-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd2e8397-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/289/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 107–289, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “(1) Except as provided in subsection (e), not later” for “Not later”, “2003” for “1997”, and “each covered executive agency” for “each executive agency identified in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s901/b">section 901(b) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/289/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 107–289, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “a covered executive agency” for “an executive agency” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/289/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 107–289, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “covered executive agencies” for “executive agencies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/289/s2/a/4">Pub. L. 107–289, § 2(a)(4)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/531/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 106–531, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “Congress and the” before “Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/106/531/s4/a/2">Pub. L. 106–531, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, struck out subsecs. (e) to (h) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(e) The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may waive the application of all or part of subsection (a) for financial statements required for fiscal years 1996 and 1997.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(f) Not later than March 1 of 1995 and 1996, the head of each executive agency identified in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s901/b">section 901(b) of this title</ref> and designated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall prepare and submit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget an audited financial statement for the preceding fiscal year, covering all accounts and associated activities of each office, bureau, and activity of the agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(g) Not later than March 31 of 1995 and 1996, for executive agencies not designated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget under subsection (f), the head of each executive agency identified in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s901/b">section 901(b) of this title</ref> shall prepare and submit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget a financial statement for the preceding fiscal year, covering—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) each revolving fund and trust fund of the agency; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) to the extent practicable, the accounts of each office, bureau, and activity of the agency which performed substantial commercial functions during the preceding fiscal year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(h) For purposes of subsection (g), the term ‘commercial functions’ includes buying and leasing of real estate, providing insurance, making loans and loan guarantees, and other credit programs and any activity involving the provision of a service or thing for which a fee, royalty, rent, or other charge is imposed by an agency for services and things of value it provides.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/356">Pub. L. 103–356</ref> amended section generally, revising and restating as subsecs. (a) to (h) provisions of former subsecs. (a) to (e) which required agency preparation and submission of annual financial statements, provided for form and contents of such statements, and defined term “commercial functions” for purposes of section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd2e8398-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbd2e8399-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, <date date="2004-10-09">Oct. 9, 2004</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbd2e839a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Waiver of Requirement; Resolution Approving Designation of Agencies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/576/tIII/s303/a/2">Pub. L. 101–576, title III, § 303(a)(2)</ref>, (3), (b), <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2849">104 Stat. 2849</ref>, 2850, provided that <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3515/e">section 3515(e) of this title</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/101/576/s303/a/1">section 303(a)(1) of Pub. L. 101–576</ref>, would take effect on date on which a resolution was passed by Congress and approved by the President, provided that Director of Office of Management and Budget could, for fiscal year 1991, waive application of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3515/a">section 3515(a) of this title</ref> with respect to any revolving fund, trust fund, or account of an executive agency, and described and specified procedures for passage of the resolution.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd2e839b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Waiver Authority</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/289/s2/b">Pub. L. 107–289, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2050">116 Stat. 2050</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/289/s2/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may waive the application of all or part of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3515/a">section 3515(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, as amended by this section, for financial statements required for the first 2 fiscal years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-11-07">Nov. 7, 2002</date>] for an agency described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agencies described</inline>.—</heading><content>An agency referred to in paragraph (1) is any covered executive agency (as that term is defined by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3515/f">section 3515(f) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a) of this section) that is not an executive agency identified in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s901/b">section 901(b) of title 31</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd2e839c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Substantial Commercial Functions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/576/tIII/s303/c">Pub. L. 101–576, title III, § 303(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2851">104 Stat. 2851</ref>, directed Director of Office of Management and Budget, not later than 180 days after <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, to determine and report to Congress on which executive agencies or parts thereof perform substantial commercial functions for which financial statements can be prepared practicably under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3515">31 U.S.C. 3515</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd2e839d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Project for Preparation and Audit of Financial Statements; Report to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/576/tIII/s303/d">Pub. L. 101–576, title III, § 303(d)</ref>, (e), <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2851">104 Stat. 2851</ref>, 2852, directed specific departments, administrations, and services by Mar. 31 of 1991, 1992, and 1993 to prepare and submit to Director of Office of Management and Budget financial statements for the preceding fiscal year for the accounts of all of the offices, bureaus, and activities, required each financial statement to be audited in accordance with 31 U.S.C. section 3521(e), (f), (g), and (h), and directed Director of Office of Management and Budget, not later than <date date="1993-06-30">June 30, 1993</date>, to report to Congress on the financial statements including an analysis of the accuracy of the data, the difficulties encountered in preparing the data, the benefits derived from preparation of the financial statements, and the cost associated with preparing and auditing the financial statements.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
