<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd2e839e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516"><num value="3516">§ 3516.</num><heading> Reports consolidation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e839f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e83a0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> With the concurrence of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the head of an executive agency may adjust the frequency and due dates of, and consolidate into an annual report to the President, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and Congress any statutorily required reports described in paragraph (2). Such a consolidated report shall be submitted to the President, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and to appropriate committees and subcommittees of Congress not later than 150 days after the end of the agency’s fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e83a1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The following reports may be consolidated into the report referred to in paragraph (1):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e83a2-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any report by an agency to Congress, the Office of Management and Budget, or the President under section 1116, this chapter, and chapters 9, 33, 37, 75, and 91.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e83a3-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The following agency-specific reports:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd2e83a4-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The biennial financial management improvement plan by the Secretary of Defense under section 2222 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002053">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002053"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 10.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd2e83a5-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The annual report of the Attorney General under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s522">section 522 of title 28</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e83a6-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Any other statutorily required report pertaining to an agency’s financial or performance management if the head of the agency—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd2e83a7-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> determines that inclusion of that report will enhance the usefulness of the reported information to decision makers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd2e83a8-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> consults in advance of inclusion of that report with the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and any other committee of Congress having jurisdiction with respect to the report proposed for inclusion.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e83a9-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A report under subsection (a) that incorporates the agency’s program performance report under section 1116 shall be referred to as a performance and accountability report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e83aa-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A report under subsection (a) that does not incorporate the agency’s program performance report under section 1116 shall contain a summary of the most significant portions of the agency’s program performance report, including the agency’s success in achieving key performance goals for the applicable year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e83ab-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> A report under subsection (a) shall include a statement prepared by the agency’s inspector general that summarizes what the inspector general considers to be the most serious management and performance challenges facing the agency and briefly assesses the agency’s progress in addressing those challenges. The inspector general shall provide such statement to the agency head at least 30 days before the due date of the report under subsection (a). The agency head may comment on the inspector general’s statement, but may not modify the statement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e83ac-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> A report under subsection (a) shall include a transmittal letter from the agency head containing, in addition to any other content, an assessment by the agency head of the completeness and reliability of the performance and financial data used in the report. The assessment shall describe any material inadequacies in the completeness and reliability of the data, and the actions the agency can take and is taking to resolve such inadequacies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd2e83ad-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Homeland Security—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e83ae-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall for each fiscal year submit a performance and accountability report under subsection (a) that incorporates the program performance report under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1116">section 1116 of this title</ref> for the Department of Homeland Security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e83af-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall include in each performance and accountability report an audit opinion of the Department’s internal controls over its financial reporting; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd2e83b0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> shall design and implement Department-wide management controls that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd2e83b1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reflect the most recent homeland security strategy developed pursuant to section 874(b)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd2e83b2-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> permit assessment, by the Congress and by managers within the Department, of the Department’s performance in executing such strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd30f3b3-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/531/s3/a">Pub. L. 106–531, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-22">Nov. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2537">114 Stat. 2537</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/330/s4/a">Pub. L. 108–330, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1277">118 Stat. 1277</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd30f3b4-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd30f3b5-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd30f3b6-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2222">Section 2222 of title 10</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(B)(i), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tX/s1004/h/1">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1004(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2631">116 Stat. 2631</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 874(b)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (f)(3)(A), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s454/b/2">section 454(b)(2) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd30f3b7-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/330">Pub. L. 108–330</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd30f3b8-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbd30f3b9-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, Oct. 9. 2004.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd30f3ba-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Department of Homeland Security Audit Requirement Target</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/217">Pub. L. 112–217</ref>, <date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1591">126 Stat. 1591</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/217">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘DHS Audit Requirement Target Act of 2012’ or the ‘DART Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> IMPROVING FINANCIAL ACCOUNTABILITY AND MANAGEMENT.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘Department’ means the Department of Homeland Security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘financial management systems’ has the meaning given that term under section 806 of the Federal Financial Management Improvement Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3512">31 U.S.C. 3512</ref> note);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the term ‘unqualified opinion’ mean an unqualified opinion within the meaning given that term under generally accepted auditing standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reaching an Unqualified Audit Opinion</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to ensure compliance with the Department of Homeland Security Financial Accountability Act (<ref href="/us/pl/108/330">Public Law 108–330</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/118/1275">118 Stat. 1275</ref>) [see Short Title of 2004 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s101">section 101 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security], and the amendments made by that Act, the Secretary shall take the necessary steps to ensure that the full set of consolidated financial statements of the Department for the fiscal year ending <date date="2013-09-30">September 30, 2013</date>, and each fiscal year thereafter, are ready in a timely manner and in preparation for an audit as part of preparing the performance and accountability reports required under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f">section 3516(f) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, (including submitting the reports not later than <date date="2013-11-15">November 15, 2013</date>, and each year thereafter) in order to obtain an unqualified opinion on the full set of financial statements for the fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress on Progress of Meeting Audit Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In order to ensure progress in implementing the Department of Homeland Security Financial Accountability Act (<ref href="/us/pl/108/330">Public Law 108–330</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/118/1275">118 Stat. 1275</ref>), and the amendments made by that Act, during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2012-12-20">Dec. 20, 2012</date>] and ending on the date on which an unqualified opinion described in subsection (b) is submitted, each report submitted by the Chief Financial Officer of the Department under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s902/a/6">section 902(a)(6) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, shall include a plan—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to obtain an unqualified opinion on the full set of financial statements, which shall discuss plans and resources needed to meet the deadlines under subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that addresses how the Department will eliminate material weaknesses and significant deficiencies in internal controls over financial reporting and provides deadlines for the elimination of such weaknesses and deficiencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to modernize the financial management systems of the Department, including timelines, goals, alternatives, and costs of the plan, which shall include consideration of alternative approaches, including modernizing the existing financial management systems and associated financial controls of the Department and establishing new financial management systems and associated financial controls.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd30f3bb-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Audit Opinion and Internal Controls by Secretary of Homeland Security</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/330/s4/b">Pub. L. 108–330, § 4(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2004-10-16">Oct. 16, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1277">118 Stat. 1277</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/330/s4/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Audit Opinion Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall include audit opinions in performance and accountability reports under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f">section 3516(f) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), only for fiscal years after fiscal year 2005.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assertion of Internal Controls</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall include in the performance and accountability report for fiscal year 2005 submitted by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3516/f">section 3516(f) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, an assertion of the internal controls that apply to financial reporting by the Department of Homeland Security.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd30f3bc-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings and Purposes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/531/s2">Pub. L. 106–531, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-11-22">Nov. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2537">114 Stat. 2537</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/531/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> existing law imposes numerous financial and performance management reporting requirements on agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> these separate requirements can cause duplication of effort on the part of agencies and result in uncoordinated reports containing information in a form that is not completely useful to Congress; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> pilot projects conducted by agencies under the direction of the Office of Management and Budget demonstrate that single consolidated reports providing an analysis of verifiable financial and performance management information produce more useful reports with greater efficiency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of this Act [see Short Title of 2000 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3501">section 3501 of this title</ref>] are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to authorize and encourage the consolidation of financial and performance management reports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to provide financial and performance management information in a more meaningful and useful format for Congress, the President, and the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to improve the quality of agency financial and performance management information; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> to enhance coordination and efficiency on the part of agencies in reporting financial and performance management information.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd30f3bd-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Rule for Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/531/s3/b">Pub. L. 106–531, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-22">Nov. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2538">114 Stat. 2538</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/531/s3/b">“Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3516/a">section 3516(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (a) of this section), the head of an executive agency may submit a consolidated report under such paragraph not later than 180 days after the end of that agency’s fiscal year, with respect to fiscal years 2000 and 2001.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
