<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd3f4c81-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D"><num value="3720D">§ 3720D.</num><heading> Garnishment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c82-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Notwithstanding any provision of State law, the head of an executive, judicial, or legislative agency that administers a program that gives rise to a delinquent nontax debt owed to the United States by an individual may in accordance with this section garnish the disposable pay of the individual to collect the amount owed, if the individual is not currently making required repayment in accordance with any agreement between the agency head and the individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c83-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> In carrying out any garnishment of disposable pay of an individual under subsection (a), the head of an executive, judicial, or legislative agency shall comply with the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c84-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The amount deducted under this section for any pay period may not exceed 15 percent of disposable pay, except that a greater percentage may be deducted with the written consent of the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c85-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The individual shall be provided written notice, sent by mail to the individual’s last known address, a minimum of 30 days prior to the initiation of proceedings, from the head of the executive, judicial, or legislative agency, informing the individual of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd3f4c86-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the nature and amount of the debt to be collected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd3f4c87-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the intention of the agency to initiate proceedings to collect the debt through deductions from pay; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd3f4c88-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an explanation of the rights of the individual under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c89-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The individual shall be provided an opportunity to inspect and copy records relating to the debt.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c8a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The individual shall be provided an opportunity to enter into a written agreement with the executive, judicial, or legislative agency, under terms agreeable to the head of the agency, to establish a schedule for repayment of the debt.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c8b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The individual shall be provided an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with subsection (c) on the determination of the head of the executive, judicial, or legislative agency concerning—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd3f4c8c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the existence or the amount of the debt, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd3f4c8d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of an individual whose repayment schedule is established other than by a written agreement pursuant to paragraph (4), the terms of the repayment schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c8e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> If the individual has been reemployed within 12 months after having been involuntarily separated from employment, no amount may be deducted from the disposable pay of the individual until the individual has been reemployed continuously for at least 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c8f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c90-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A hearing under subsection (b)(5) shall be provided prior to issuance of a garnishment order if the individual, on or before the 15th day following the mailing of the notice described in subsection (b)(2), and in accordance with such procedures as the head of the executive, judicial, or legislative agency may prescribe, files a petition requesting such a hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c91-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the individual does not file a petition requesting a hearing prior to such date, the head of the agency shall provide the individual a hearing under subsection (a)(5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002064">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002064"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be subsection “(b)(5)”.</note> upon request, but such hearing need not be provided prior to issuance of a garnishment order.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c92-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The hearing official shall issue a final decision at the earliest practicable date, but not later than 60 days after the filing of the petition requesting the hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c93-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The notice to the employer of the withholding order shall contain only such information as may be necessary for the employer to comply with the withholding order.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c94-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c95-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An employer may not discharge from employment, refuse to employ, or take disciplinary action against an individual subject to wage withholding in accordance with this section by reason of the fact that the individual’s wages have been subject to garnishment under this section, and such individual may sue in a State or Federal court of competent jurisdiction any employer who takes such action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c96-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The court shall award attorneys’ fees to a prevailing employee and, in its discretion, may order reinstatement of the individual, award punitive damages and back pay to the employee, or order such other remedy as may be reasonably necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c97-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c98-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The employer of an individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c99-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall pay to the head of an executive, judicial, or legislative agency as directed in a withholding order issued in an action under this section with respect to the individual, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd3f4c9a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall be liable for any amount that the employer fails to withhold from wages due an employee following receipt by such employer of notice of the withholding order, plus attorneys’ fees, costs, and, in the court’s discretion, punitive damages.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c9b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c9c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The head of an executive, judicial, or legislative agency may sue an employer in a State or Federal court of competent jurisdiction to recover amounts for which the employer is liable under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c9d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A suit under this paragraph may not be filed before the termination of the collection action, unless earlier filing is necessary to avoid expiration of any applicable statute of limitations period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c9e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an employer shall not be required to vary its normal pay and disbursement cycles in order to comply with this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4c9f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> For the purpose of this section, the term “disposable pay” means that part of the compensation of any individual from an employer remaining after the deduction of any amounts required by any other law to be withheld.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd3f4ca0-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s3720D/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall issue regulations to implement this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd3f4ca1-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tIII/s31001">Pub. L. 104–134, title III, § 31001</ref>(<i>o</i>)(1), <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-369">110 Stat. 1321–369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
