<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd715854-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332"><num value="5332">§ 5332.</num><heading> Bulk cash smuggling into or out of the United States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd715855-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Criminal Offense.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd715856-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Whoever, with the intent to evade a currency reporting requirement under section 5316, knowingly conceals more than $10,000 in currency or other monetary instruments on the person of such individual or in any conveyance, article of luggage, merchandise, or other container, and transports or transfers or attempts to transport or transfer such currency or monetary instruments from a place within the United States to a place outside of the United States, or from a place outside the United States to a place within the United States, shall be guilty of a currency smuggling offense and subject to punishment pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd715857-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Concealment on person</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the concealment of currency on the person of any individual includes concealment in any article of clothing worn by the individual or in any luggage, backpack, or other container worn or carried by such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd715858-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalty.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd715859-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Term of imprisonment</inline>.—</heading><content>A person convicted of a currency smuggling offense under subsection (a), or a conspiracy to commit such offense, shall be imprisoned for not more than 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd71585a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Forfeiture</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition, the court, in imposing sentence under paragraph (1), shall order that the defendant forfeit to the United States, any property, real or personal, involved in the offense, and any property traceable to such property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd71585b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedure</inline>.—</heading><content>The seizure, restraint, and forfeiture of property under this section shall be governed by section 413 of the Controlled Substances Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd71585c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Personal money judgment</inline>.—</heading><content>If the property subject to forfeiture under paragraph (2) is unavailable, and the defendant has insufficient substitute property that may be forfeited pursuant to section 413(p) of the Controlled Substances Act, the court shall enter a personal money judgment against the defendant for the amount that would be subject to forfeiture.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd71585d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Civil Forfeiture.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd71585e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Any property involved in a violation of subsection (a), or a conspiracy to commit such violation, and any property traceable to such violation or conspiracy, may be seized and forfeited to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd71585f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedure</inline>.—</heading><content>The seizure and forfeiture shall be governed by the procedures governing civil forfeitures in money laundering cases pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s981/a/1/A">section 981(a)(1)(A) of title 18</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd715860-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s5332/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of certain property as involved in the offense</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subsection and subsection (b), any currency or other monetary instrument that is concealed or intended to be concealed in violation of subsection (a) or a conspiracy to commit such violation, any article, container, or conveyance used, or intended to be used, to conceal or transport the currency or other monetary instrument, and any other property used, or intended to be used, to facilitate the offense, shall be considered property involved in the offense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd715861-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tIII/s371/c">Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 371(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/337">115 Stat. 337</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVI/s6203/h">Pub. L. 108–458, title VI, § 6203(h)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3747">118 Stat. 3747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd715862-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd715863-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd715864-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 413 of the Controlled Substances Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), (4), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s853">section 853 of Title 21</ref>, Food and Drugs.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd715865-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another <ref href="/us/pl/107/56/s371/c">section 371(c) of Pub. L. 107–56</ref> amended the table of sections at the beginning of this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd715866-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s6203/h/1">Pub. L. 108–458, § 6203(h)(1)</ref>, struck out “, subject to subsection (d) of this section” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s6203/h/2">Pub. L. 108–458, § 6203(h)(2)</ref>, struck out “, subject to subsection (d) of this section,” after “may be seized and”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd715867-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd715868-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref> effective as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/56">Pub. L. 107–56</ref>, as of the date of enactment of such Act, and no amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/107/56">Pub. L. 107–56</ref> that is inconsistent with such amendment to be deemed to have taken effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s6205">section 6205 of Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1828">section 1828 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd715869-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Bulk Cash Smuggling Into or Out of the United States</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tIII/s371/a">Pub. L. 107–56, title III, § 371(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/336">115 Stat. 336</ref>, 337, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/56/tIII/s371/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Effective enforcement of the currency reporting requirements of subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31, United States Code, and the regulations prescribed under such subchapter, has forced drug dealers and other criminals engaged in cash-based businesses to avoid using traditional financial institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In their effort to avoid using traditional financial institutions, drug dealers and other criminals are forced to move large quantities of currency in bulk form to and through the airports, border crossings, and other ports of entry where the currency can be smuggled out of the United States and placed in a foreign financial institution or sold on the black market.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The transportation and smuggling of cash in bulk form may now be the most common form of money laundering, and the movement of large sums of cash is one of the most reliable warning signs of drug trafficking, terrorism, money laundering, racketeering, tax evasion and similar crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The intentional transportation into or out of the United States of large amounts of currency or monetary instruments, in a manner designed to circumvent the mandatory reporting provisions of subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31, United States Code,, [sic] is the equivalent of, and creates the same harm as, the smuggling of goods.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The arrest and prosecution of bulk cash smugglers are important parts of law enforcement’s effort to stop the laundering of criminal proceeds, but the couriers who attempt to smuggle the cash out of the United States are typically low-level employees of large criminal organizations, and thus are easily replaced. Accordingly, only the confiscation of the smuggled bulk cash can effectively break the cycle of criminal activity of which the laundering of the bulk cash is a critical part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The current penalties for violations of the currency reporting requirements are insufficient to provide a deterrent to the laundering of criminal proceeds. In particular, in cases where the only criminal violation under current law is a reporting offense, the law does not adequately provide for the confiscation of smuggled currency. In contrast, if the smuggling of bulk cash were itself an offense, the cash could be confiscated as the corpus delicti of the smuggling offense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of this section [enacting this section] are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to make the act of smuggling bulk cash itself a criminal offense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to authorize forfeiture of any cash or instruments of the smuggling offense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to emphasize the seriousness of the act of bulk cash smuggling.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
