<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd8b978a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505"><num value="7505">§ 7505.</num><heading> Regulations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd8b978b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Director, after consultation with the Comptroller General, and appropriate officials from Federal, State, and local governments and nonprofit organizations shall prescribe guidance to implement this chapter. Each Federal agency shall promulgate such amendments to its regulations as may be necessary to conform such regulations to the requirements of this chapter and of such guidance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd8de07c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd8de07d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The guidance prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) shall include criteria for determining the appropriate charges to Federal awards for the cost of audits. Such criteria shall prohibit a non-Federal entity from charging to any Federal awards—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd8de07e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the cost of any audit which is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd8de07f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> not conducted in accordance with this chapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbd8de080-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> conducted in accordance with this chapter when expenditures of Federal awards are less than amounts cited in section 7502(a)(1)(A) or specified by the Director under section 7502(a)(3), except that the Director may allow the cost of limited scope audits to monitor subrecipients in accordance with section 7502(f)(2)(B); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbd8de081-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> more than a reasonably proportionate share of the cost of any such audit that is conducted in accordance with this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd8de082-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The criteria prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not, in the absence of documentation demonstrating a higher actual cost, permit the percentage of the cost of audits performed pursuant to this chapter charged to Federal awards, to exceed the ratio of total Federal awards expended by such non-Federal entity during the applicable fiscal year or years, to such non-Federal entity’s total expenditures during such fiscal year or years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd8de083-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Such guidance shall include such provisions as may be necessary to ensure that small business concerns, qualified HUBZone small business concerns, and business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals will have the opportunity to participate in the performance of contracts awarded to fulfill the audit requirements of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd8de084-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s7505/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Such guidance shall require audit-related information reported under this chapter to be reported in an electronic form in accordance with the data standards established under chapter 64.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd8de085-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/98/502/s2/a">Pub. L. 98–502, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2333">98 Stat. 2333</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/156/s2">Pub. L. 104–156, § 2</ref>, <date date="1996-07-05">July 5, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1403">110 Stat. 1403</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/135/tVI/s604/e/3">Pub. L. 105–135, title VI, § 604(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1997-12-02">Dec. 2, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2634">111 Stat. 2634</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/103/s5/a/2">Pub. L. 116–103, § 5(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-30">Dec. 30, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3270">133 Stat. 3270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd8de086-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd8de087-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd8de088-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/103">Pub. L. 116–103</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/135">Pub. L. 105–135</ref> substituted “small business concerns, qualified HUBZone small business concerns, and” for “small business concerns and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/156">Pub. L. 104–156</ref> reenacted section catchline without change and amended text generally, substituting present provisions for similar provisions relating to regulations, including implementation guidelines for regulations, criteria for determining appropriate charges to programs of Federal financial assistance for cost of audits, and guidelines to ensure that small business concerns and business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals have opportunity to participate in contracts awarded to fulfill audit requirements of this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd8de089-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd8de08a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/135">Pub. L. 105–135</ref> effective <date date="1997-10-01">Oct. 1, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/135/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 105–135</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">section 631 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd8de08b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/103/s5/b">Pub. L. 116–103, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-30">Dec. 30, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3270">133 Stat. 3270</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/103/s5/b">“Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-30">Dec. 30, 2019</date>], the Director [of the Office of Management and Budget] shall issue guidance requiring audit-related information reported under chapter 75 of title 31, United States Code, to be reported in an electronic form consistent with the data standards established under chapter 64 of that title, as added by section 4(a) of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd8de08c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidelines for Acceptance of Audits by State and Local Governments Receiving Federal Assistance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVIII/s808/c">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 808(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2607">110 Stat. 2607</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVIII/s808/c">“The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall issue guidelines to ensure that an audit of indirect costs performed by the Federal Government is accepted by State and local governments that receive Federal funds under contracts, grants, or other Federal assistance programs.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
