<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd92c34c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9703"><num value="9703">§ 9703.</num><heading> Managerial accountability and flexibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c34d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9703/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Beginning with fiscal year 1999, the performance plans required under section 1115 may include proposals to waive administrative procedural requirements and controls, including specification of personnel staffing levels, limitations on compensation or remuneration, and prohibitions or restrictions on funding transfers among budget object classification 20 and subclassifications 11, 12, 31, and 32 of each annual budget submitted under section 1105, in return for specific individual or organization accountability to achieve a performance goal. In preparing and submitting the performance plan under section 1105(a)(29),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002125">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002125"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall review and may approve any proposed waivers. A waiver shall take effect at the beginning of the fiscal year for which the waiver is approved.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c34e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9703/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any such proposal under subsection (a) shall describe the anticipated effects on performance resulting from greater managerial or organizational flexibility, discretion, and authority, and shall quantify the expected improvements in performance resulting from any waiver. The expected improvements shall be compared to current actual performance, and to the projected level of performance that would be achieved independent of any waiver.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c34f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9703/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any proposal waiving limitations on compensation or remuneration shall precisely express the monetary change in compensation or remuneration amounts, such as bonuses or awards, that shall result from meeting, exceeding, or failing to meet performance goals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c350-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9703/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Any proposed waiver of procedural requirements or controls imposed by an agency (other than the proposing agency or the Office of Management and Budget) may not be included in a performance plan unless it is endorsed by the agency that established the requirement, and the endorsement included in the proposing agency’s performance plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c351-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9703/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> A waiver shall be in effect for one or two years as specified by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget in approving the waiver. A waiver may be renewed for a subsequent year. After a waiver has been in effect for three consecutive years, the performance plan prepared under section 1115 may propose that a waiver, other than a waiver of limitations on compensation or remuneration, be made permanent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c352-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9703/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> For purposes of this section, the definitions under section 1115(f) <sup>1</sup> shall apply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd92c353-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/62/s5/a">Pub. L. 103–62, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-03">Aug. 3, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/289">107 Stat. 289</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd92c354-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd92c355-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd92c356-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1105(a)(29), referred to in subsec. (a), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a/28">section 1105(a)(28) of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/104/287/s4/1">Pub. L. 104–287, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3388">110 Stat. 3388</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1115, referred to in subsec. (f), was repealed, and a new section 1115 enacted, by <ref href="/us/pl/111/352/s3">Pub. L. 111–352, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3867">124 Stat. 3867</ref>. As reenacted, definitions in former section 1115(f) are now contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1115/h">section 1115(h) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbd92c357-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another section 9703 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9705">section 9705 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd92c358-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd92c359-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">No provision or amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/103/62">Pub. L. 103–62</ref> to be construed as creating any right, privilege, benefit, or entitlement for any person who is not an officer or employee of the United States acting in such capacity, and no person not an officer or employee of the United States acting in such capacity to have standing to file any civil action in any court of the United States to enforce any provision or amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/103/62">Pub. L. 103–62</ref>, or to be construed as superseding any statutory requirement, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/62/s10">section 10 of Pub. L. 103–62</ref>, set out as a Construction of 1993 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
