<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd92c35a-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9704"><num value="9704">§ 9704.</num><heading> Pilot projects for managerial accountability and flexibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c35b-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9704/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall designate not less than five agencies as pilot projects in managerial accountability and flexibility for fiscal years 1995 and 1996. Such agencies shall be selected from those designated as pilot projects under section 1118 and shall reflect a representative range of Government functions and capabilities in measuring and reporting program performance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c35c-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9704/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Pilot projects in the designated agencies shall include proposed waivers in accordance with section 9703 for one or more of the major functions and operations of the agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd92c35d-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c" identifier="/us/usc/t31/s9704/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> For purposes of this section the definitions under section 1115(f) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002126">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002126"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> shall apply.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd92c35e-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/62/s6/b">Pub. L. 103–62, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-03">Aug. 3, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/290">107 Stat. 290</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/118/190/s6/b">Pub. L. 118–190, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2656">138 Stat. 2656</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd92c35f-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd92c360-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd92c361-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1115, referred to in subsec. (c), was repealed, and a new section 1115 enacted, by <ref href="/us/pl/111/352/s3">Pub. L. 111–352, § 3</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3867">124 Stat. 3867</ref>. As reenacted, definitions in former section 1115(f) are now contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1115/h">section 1115(h) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd92c362-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/118/190">Pub. L. 118–190</ref> redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which read as follows: “The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall include in the report to the President and to the Congress required under section 1118(c)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) an assessment of the benefits, costs, and usefulness of increasing managerial and organizational flexibility, discretion, and authority in exchange for improved performance through a waiver; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) an identification of any significant difficulties experienced by the pilot agencies in preparing proposed waivers.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd92c363-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd92c364-47c4-11f1-bea6-82cea744851c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">No provision or amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/103/62">Pub. L. 103–62</ref> to be construed as creating any right, privilege, benefit, or entitlement for any person who is not an officer or employee of the United States acting in such capacity, and no person not an officer or employee of the United States acting in such capacity to have standing to file any civil action in any court of the United States to enforce any provision or amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/103/62">Pub. L. 103–62</ref>, or to be construed as superseding any statutory requirement, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/62/s10">section 10 of Pub. L. 103–62</ref>, set out as a Construction of 1993 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
