<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd3a0af6c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1109"><num value="1109">§ 1109.</num><heading> Right to be heard</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af6d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1109/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Securities and Exchange Commission may raise and may appear and be heard on any issue in a case under this chapter, but the Securities and Exchange Commission may not appeal from any judgment, order, or decree entered in the case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af6e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1109/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A party in interest, including the debtor, the trustee, a creditors’ committee, an equity security holders’ committee, a creditor, an equity security holder, or any indenture trustee, may raise and may appear and be heard on any issue in a case under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd3a0af6f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2629">92 Stat. 2629</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/27/s11/f">Pub. L. 119–27, § 11(f)</ref>, <date date="2025-07-18">July 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/458">139 Stat. 458</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd3a0af70-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="idd3a0af71-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Section</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/27">Pub. L. 119–27</ref>, §§ 11(f), 20, <date date="2025-07-18">July 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/458">139 Stat. 458</ref>, 466, provided that, effective on the earlier of the date that is 18 months after <date date="2025-07-18">July 18, 2025</date>, or the date that is 120 days after the date on which the primary Federal payment stablecoin regulators issue any final regulations implementing <ref href="/us/pl/119/27">Pub. L. 119–27</ref>, this section is amended by adding at the end the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0 fontsize8"><i>(c) The Comptroller of the Currency or State payment stablecoin regulator (as defined in section 2 of the GENIUS Act) shall raise, and shall appear and be heard on, any issue, including the protection of customers, in a case under this chapter in which the debtor is a permitted payment stablecoin issuer.</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">See 2025 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd3a0af72-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a0af73-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1109 of the House amendment represents a compromise between comparable provisions in the House bill and Senate amendment. As previously discussed the section gives the Securities and Exchange Commission the right to appear and be heard and to raise any issue in a case under chapter 11; however, the Securities and Exchange Commission is not a party in interest and the Commission may not appeal from any judgment, order, or decree entered in the case. Under section 1109(b) a party in interest, including the debtor, the trustee, creditors committee, equity securities holders committee, a creditor, an equity security holder, or an indentured trustee, may raise and may appear and be heard on any issue in a case under chapter 11. Section 1109(c) of the Senate amendment has been moved to subchapter IV pertaining to Railroad Reorganizations.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a0af74-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) provides, in unqualified terms, that any creditor, equity security holder, or an indenture trustee shall have the right to be heard as a party in interest under this chapter in person, by an attorney, or by a committee. It is derived from section 206 of chapter X ([former] <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s606">11 U.S.C. 606</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) provides that the Securities and Exchange Commission may appear by filing an appearance in a case of a public company and may appear in other cases if authorized or requested by the court. As a party in interest in either case, the Commission may raise and be heard on any issue. The Commission may not appeal from a judgment, order, or decree in a case, but may participate in any appeal by any other party in interest. This is the present law under section 208 of chapter X ([former] <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s608">11 U.S.C. 608</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a0af75-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">house report no. 95–595</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1109 authorizes the Securities and Exchange Commission and any indenture trustee to intervene in the case at any time on any issue. They may raise an issue or may appear and be heard on an issue that is raised by someone else. The section, following current law, denies the right of appeal to the Securities and Exchange Commission. It does not, however, prevent the Commission from joining or participating in an appeal taken by a true party in interest. The Commission is merely prevented from initiating the appeal in any capacity.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd3a0af76-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd3a0af77-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/119/27">Pub. L. 119–27</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd3a0af78-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3a0af79-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2025 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/119/27">Pub. L. 119–27</ref> effective on the earlier of the date that is 18 months after <date date="2025-07-18">July 18, 2025</date>, or the date that is 120 days after the date on which the primary Federal payment stablecoin regulators issue any final regulations implementing <ref href="/us/pl/119/27">Pub. L. 119–27</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/119/27/s20">section 20 of Pub. L. 119–27</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5901">section 5901 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
