<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd3a0af7a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110"><num value="1110">§ 1110.</num><heading> Aircraft equipment and vessels</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af7b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af7c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) and subject to subsection (b), the right of a secured party with a security interest in equipment described in paragraph (3), or of a lessor or conditional vendor of such equipment, to take possession of such equipment in compliance with a security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, and to enforce any of its other rights or remedies, under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, to sell, lease, or otherwise retain or dispose of such equipment, is not limited or otherwise affected by any other provision of this title or by any power of the court.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af7d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The right to take possession and to enforce the other rights and remedies described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to section 362 if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a0af7e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> before the date that is 60 days after the date of the order for relief under this chapter, the trustee, subject to the approval of the court, agrees to perform all obligations of the debtor under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a0af7f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> any default, other than a default of a kind specified in section 365(b)(2), under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a0af80-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that occurs before the date of the order is cured before the expiration of such 60-day period;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a0af81-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> that occurs after the date of the order and before the expiration of such 60-day period is cured before the later of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3a0af82-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the date that is 30 days after the date of the default; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idd3a0af83-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the expiration of such 60-day period; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a0af84-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> that occurs on or after the expiration of such 60-day period is cured in compliance with the terms of such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, if a cure is permitted under that agreement, lease, or contract.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af85-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The equipment described in this paragraph—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a0af86-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a0af87-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, appliance, or spare part (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40102">section 40102 of title 49</ref>) that is subject to a security interest granted by, leased to, or conditionally sold to a debtor that, at the time such transaction is entered into, holds an air carrier operating certificate issued pursuant to chapter 447 of title 49 for aircraft capable of carrying 10 or more individuals or 6,000 pounds or more of cargo; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idd3a0af88-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a vessel documented under chapter 121 of title 46 that is subject to a security interest granted by, leased to, or conditionally sold to a debtor that is a water carrier that, at the time such transaction is entered into, holds a certificate of public convenience and necessity or permit issued by the Department of Transportation; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a0af89-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes all records and documents relating to such equipment that are required, under the terms of the security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, to be surrendered or returned by the debtor in connection with the surrender or return of such equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af8a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Paragraph (1) applies to a secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor acting in its own behalf or acting as trustee or otherwise in behalf of another party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af8b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The trustee and the secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor whose right to take possession is protected under subsection (a) may agree, subject to the approval of the court, to extend the 60-day period specified in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af8c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af8d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In any case under this chapter, the trustee shall immediately surrender and return to a secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor, described in subsection (a)(1), equipment described in subsection (a)(3), if at any time after the date of the order for relief under this chapter such secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor is entitled pursuant to subsection (a)(1) to take possession of such equipment and makes a written demand for such possession to the trustee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af8e-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> At such time as the trustee is required under paragraph (1) to surrender and return equipment described in subsection (a)(3), any lease of such equipment, and any security agreement or conditional sale contract relating to such equipment, if such security agreement or conditional sale contract is an executory contract, shall be deemed rejected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a0af8f-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> With respect to equipment first placed in service on or before <date date="1994-10-22">October 22, 1994</date>, for purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a0af90-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “lease” includes any written agreement with respect to which the lessor and the debtor, as lessee, have expressed in the agreement or in a substantially contemporaneous writing that the agreement is to be treated as a lease for Federal income tax purposes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a0af91-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1110/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “security interest” means a purchase-money equipment security interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd3a0af92-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2629">92 Stat. 2629</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s5/c">Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1373">108 Stat. 1373</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 103–394, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4119">108 Stat. 4119</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/181/tVII/s744/b">Pub. L. 106–181, title VII, § 744(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-04-05">Apr. 5, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/177">114 Stat. 177</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/304/s17/b/2">Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1707">120 Stat. 1707</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd3a0af93-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idd3a0af94-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a0af95-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">legislative statements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1110 of the House amendment adopts an identical provision contained in the House bill without modifications contained in the Senate amendment. This section protects a limited class of financiers of aircraft and vessels and is intended to be narrowly construed to prevent secured parties or lessors from gaining the protection of the section unless the interest of such lessor or secured party is explicitly enumerated therein. It should be emphasized that under section 1110(a) a debtor in possession or trustee is given 60 days after the order for relief in a case under chapter 11, to have an opportunity to comply with the provisions of section 1110(a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">During this time the automatic stay will apply and may not be lifted prior to the expiration of the 60-day period. Under section 1110(b), the debtor and secured party or lessor are given an opportunity to extend the 60-day period, but no right to reduce the period is intended. It should additionally be noted that under section 1110(a) the trustee or debtor in possession is not required to assume the executory contract or unexpired lease under section 1110; rather, if the trustee or debtor in possession complies with the requirements of section 1110(a), the trustee or debtor in possession is entitled to retain the aircraft or vessels subject to the normal requirements of section 365. The discussion regarding aircraft and vessels likewise applies with respect to railroad rolling stock in a railroad reorganization under section 1168.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a0af96-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">senate report no. 95–989</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section, to a large degree, preserves the protection given lessors and conditional vendors of aircraft to a certificated air carrier or of vessels to a certificated water carrier under section 116(5) and 116(6) of present Chapter X [section 516(5) and (6) of former title 11]. It is modified to conform with the consolidation of Chapters X and XI [chapters 10 and 11 of former title 11] and with the new chapter 11 generally. It is also modified to give the trustee in a reorganization case an opportunity to continue in possession of the equipment in question by curing defaults and by making the required lease or purchase payments. This removes the absolute veto power over a reorganization that lessors and conditional vendors have under present law, while entitling them to protection of their investment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The section overrides the automatic stay or any power of the court to enjoin taking of possession of certain leased, conditionally sold, or liened equipment, unless, the trustee agrees to perform the debtor’s obligations and cures all prior defaults (other than defaults under ipso facto or bankruptcy clauses) within 60 days after the order for relief. The trustee and the equipment financer are permitted to extend the 60-day period by agreement. During the first 60 days, the automatic stay will apply to prevent foreclosure unless the creditor gets relief from the stay.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effect of this section will be the same if the debtor has granted the security interest to the financer or if the debtor is leasing equipment from a financer that has leveraged the lease and leased the equipment subject to a security interest of a third party.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd3a0af97-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idd3a0af98-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/109/304">Pub. L. 109–304</ref> substituted “vessel documented under chapter 121 of title 46” for “documented vessel (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s30101/1">section 30101(1) of title 46</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/181">Pub. L. 106–181</ref> amended section catchline and text generally, substituting present provisions consisting of subsecs. (a) to (d) for former subsecs. (a) to (c) which contained somewhat similar provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) The right of a secured party with a purchase-money equipment security interest in, or of a lessor or conditional vendor of, whether as trustee or otherwise, aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, appliances, or spare parts, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40102/a">section 40102(a) of title 49</ref>, or vessels of the United States, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t46/s30101">section 30101 of title 46</ref>, that are subject to a purchase-money equipment security interest granted by, leased to, or conditionally sold to, a debtor that is an air carrier operating under a certificate of convenience and necessity issued by the Secretary of Transportation, or a water carrier that holds a certificate of public convenience and necessity or permit issued by the Interstate Commerce Commission, as the case may be, to take possession of such equipment in compliance with the provisions of a purchase-money equipment security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, as the case may be, is not affected by section 362 or 363 of this title or by any power of the court to enjoin such taking of possession, unless—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) before 60 days after the date of the order for relief under this chapter, the trustee, subject to the court’s approval, agrees to perform all obligations of the debtor that become due on or after such date under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, as the case may be; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) any default, other than a default of a kind specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s365/b/2">section 365(b)(2) of this title</ref>, under such security agreement, lease, or conditional sale contract, as the case may be—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(A) that occurred before such date is cured before the expiration of such 60-day period; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(B) that occurs after such date is cured before the later of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3">“(i) 30 days after the date of such default; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3">“(ii) the expiration of such 60-day period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) The trustee and the secured party, lessor, or conditional vendor, as the case may be, whose right to take possession is protected under subsection (a) of this section may agree, subject to the court’s approval, to extend the 60-day period specified in subsection (a)(1) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/272">Pub. L. 103–272</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s40102/a">section 40102(a) of title 49</ref>” for “section 101 of the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">49 U.S.C. 1301</ref>)”, “<ref href="/us/usc/t46/s30101">section 30101 of title 46</ref>” for “subsection B(4) of the Ship Mortgage Act, 1920 (<ref href="/us/usc/t46/s911/4">46 U.S.C. 911(4)</ref>)”, and “Secretary of Transportation” for “Civil Aeronautics Board”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd3a0af99-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3a0af9a-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/181">Pub. L. 106–181</ref> applicable only to fiscal years beginning after <date date="1999-09-30">Sept. 30, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/181/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 106–181</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idd3a3209b-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394">Pub. L. 103–394</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, with this section, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, applicable with respect to any lease, as defined by subsec. (c) of this section, entered into in connection with a settlement of any proceeding in any case pending under this title on <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/394/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 103–394</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a3209c-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Interstate Commerce Commission and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Interstate Commerce Commission abolished and functions of Commission transferred, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, to Surface Transportation Board effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, by <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1302">section 1302 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>. References to Interstate Commerce Commission deemed to refer to Surface Transportation Board, a member or employee of the Board, or Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idd3a3209d-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Aircraft Equipment Settlement Leases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/7">Pub. L. 103–7</ref>, <date date="1993-03-17">Mar. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/36">107 Stat. 36</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/7">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Aircraft Equipment Settlement Leases Act of 1993’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> TREATMENT OF AIRCRAFT EQUIPMENT SETTLEMENT LEASES WITH THE PENSION BENEFIT GUARANTY CORPORATION.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In the case of any settlement of liability under title IV of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1301">29 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.] entered into by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation and one or more other parties, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> such settlement was entered into before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1993-03-17">Mar. 17, 1993</date>],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> at least one party to such settlement was a debtor under title 11 of the United States Code, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an agreement that is entered into as part of such settlement provides that such agreement is to be treated as a lease,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then such agreement shall be treated as a lease for purposes of section 1110 of such title 11.”</continuation>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
