<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idd3a320e2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113"><num value="1113">§ 1113.</num><heading> Rejection of collective bargaining agreements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320e3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The debtor in possession, or the trustee if one has been appointed under the provisions of this chapter, other than a trustee in a case covered by subchapter IV of this chapter and by title I of the Railway Labor Act, may assume or reject a collective bargaining agreement only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320e4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320e5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subsequent to filing a petition and prior to filing an application seeking rejection of a collective bargaining agreement, the debtor in possession or trustee (hereinafter in this section “trustee” shall include a debtor in possession), shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a320e6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> make a proposal to the authorized representative of the employees covered by such agreement, based on the most complete and reliable information available at the time of such proposal, which provides for those necessary modifications in the employees benefits and protections that are necessary to permit the reorganization of the debtor and assures that all creditors, the debtor and all of the affected parties are treated fairly and equitably; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a320e7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide, subject to subsection (d)(3), the representative of the employees with such relevant information as is necessary to evaluate the proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320e8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> During the period beginning on the date of the making of a proposal provided for in paragraph (1) and ending on the date of the hearing provided for in subsection (d)(1), the trustee shall meet, at reasonable times, with the authorized representative to confer in good faith in attempting to reach mutually satisfactory modifications of such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320e9-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> The court shall approve an application for rejection of a collective bargaining agreement only if the court finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a320ea-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the trustee has, prior to the hearing, made a proposal that fulfills the requirements of subsection (b)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a320eb-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the authorized representative of the employees has refused to accept such proposal without good cause; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idd3a320ec-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the balance of the equities clearly favors rejection of such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320ed-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320ee-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon the filing of an application for rejection the court shall schedule a hearing to be held not later than fourteen days after the date of the filing of such application. All interested parties may appear and be heard at such hearing. Adequate notice shall be provided to such parties at least ten days before the date of such hearing. The court may extend the time for the commencement of such hearing for a period not exceeding seven days where the circumstances of the case, and the interests of justice require such extension, or for additional periods of time to which the trustee and representative agree.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320ef-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The court shall rule on such application for rejection within thirty days after the date of the commencement of the hearing. In the interests of justice, the court may extend such time for ruling for such additional period as the trustee and the employees’ representative may agree to. If the court does not rule on such application within thirty days after the date of the commencement of the hearing, or within such additional time as the trustee and the employees’ representative may agree to, the trustee may terminate or alter any provisions of the collective bargaining agreement pending the ruling of the court on such application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320f0-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The court may enter such protective orders, consistent with the need of the authorized representative of the employee to evaluate the trustee’s proposal and the application for rejection, as may be necessary to prevent disclosure of information provided to such representative where such disclosure could compromise the position of the debtor with respect to its competitors in the industry in which it is engaged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320f1-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> If during a period when the collective bargaining agreement continues in effect, and if essential to the continuation of the debtor’s business, or in order to avoid irreparable damage to the estate, the court, after notice and a hearing, may authorize the trustee to implement interim changes in the terms, conditions, wages, benefits, or work rules provided by a collective bargaining agreement. Any hearing under this paragraph shall be scheduled in accordance with the needs of the trustee. The implementation of such interim changes shall not render the application for rejection moot.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idd3a320f2-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370" identifier="/us/usc/t11/s1113/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> No provision of this title shall be construed to permit a trustee to unilaterally terminate or alter any provisions of a collective bargaining agreement prior to compliance with the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idd3a320f3-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s541/a">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 541(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/390">98 Stat. 390</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idd3a320f4-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idd3a320f5-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idd3a320f6-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Railway Labor Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1926-05-20/ch347">act May 20, 1926, ch. 347</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/577">44 Stat. 577</ref>. Title I of the Railway Labor Act is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 151 et seq.) of chapter 8 of Title 45, Railroads. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s151">section 151 of Title 45</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idd3a320f7-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idd3a320f8-3a6f-11f1-8dc6-9561437cf370"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s541/c">Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 541(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/391">98 Stat. 391</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/353/tIII/s541/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting this section] shall become effective upon the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>]; provided that this section shall not apply to cases filed under title 11 of the United States Code which were commenced prior to the date of enactment of this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
